<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nvidia on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/nvidia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nvidia on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/nvidia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure AI Adds GPT-4 and New Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-azure-ai-adds-gpt-4-and-new-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-azure-ai-adds-gpt-4-and-new-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is working on creating guidelines for red teams making sure generative AI is secure and responsible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Blackwell is Out: Should You Upgrade?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-blackwell-is-out-should-you-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-blackwell-is-out-should-you-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/nvidia-rtx-article_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement and digital forensic specialists have long utilized GPUs for password recovery. GPUs excel at this task due to their thousands of parallel processing cores, enabling rapid hash computations. Tools like Elcomsoft Distributed Password Recovery leverage GPU acceleration to significantly outperform traditional CPUs in brute-force attacks. The new NVIDIA Blackwell architecture doubles the number of INT32 compute units compared to Ada and Ampere. How will this architectural change affect password recovery, and is it worth upgrading to a new GPU?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5090 Power Connectors Melting Again</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-power-connectors-melting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-power-connectors-melting-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/rtx-5090-on-fire_1200x630-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a week ago, we published an article about NVIDIA’s new generation of Blackwell-based graphics cards. Despite a noticeable price hike, performance gains in this generation are minimal, with one notable exception: the flagship GeForce RTX 5090 significantly outperforms its predecessor in all key aspects. However, this GPU has also revealed a potential issue that could make its use in workstations running 24/7 problematic and potentially unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-connector&#34;&gt;The New Connector&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the root of the issue, let’s first understand how it arose. Modern GPUs require far more power than what can be delivered through the PCIe slot alone, forcing manufacturers to provide additional power via cables directly from the PSU. Antec, a well-known PSU manufacturer, has published a diagram illustrating the number of cables required to power high-performance graphics cards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner: Samsung Was the Top Semiconductor Vendor Globally in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung Electronics returned to number one partially on the strength of its memory device sales. Intel and NVIDIA followed in the rankings in spots two and three, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Load Balancing: Optimizing Password Recovery Across Heterogeneous Units</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intelligent-load-balancing-optimizing-password-recovery-across-heterogeneous-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intelligent-load-balancing-optimizing-password-recovery-across-heterogeneous-units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/EDPR-4.70-2_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the latest update of Elcomsoft Distributed Password Recovery (EDPR), we’ve introduced a revamped load-balancing feature. The new feature aims to enhance resource utilization on local workstations across diverse hardware configurations. This update has drastically reduced the time required to break passwords in certain hardware configurations, thanks to a refined load distribution algorithm. In this article, we’ll share some technical details on how load balancing leverages a mix of GPUs and CPU cores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Password Breaking A to Z</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/passwords-az.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our blog features numerous articles on breaking passwords and accessing encrypted data, ranging from simple “how-to” guides to comprehensive manuals. However, many of the questions we are frequently asked are not about the technical stuff but rather the very basics of password recovery. Can you break that password? Is it legal? How much time do you think it will take to break this one? We do have the answers, but they require digging through the extensive content of our blog. To address this, we’ve created a comprehensive A to Z article that not only answers many common questions but also links to our previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Chip Export Rule Proposes Limits to Thwart Chinese GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Biden administration states the rule will prevent U.S. chips from passing to China through countries loosely allied or not politically allied with the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: AMD Introduces Radeon RX 9070 Series GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next-generation GPUs will be available from a variety of manufacturers in the first quarter of 2025. Plus, AMD shows upcoming AI chips for mobile performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: NVIDIA Unveils GeForce RTX 50-Series Chips, AI Research Supercomputers, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jensen Huang, NVIDIA’s CEO, unveiled the company’s first flagship desktop GPU series in over two years during his keynote speech.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tech Trends at CES 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI was everywhere at the consumer electronics show, promising everything from self-driving cars to more Copilot+ laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
