<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybercrimenews on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cybercrimenews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybercrimenews on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cybercrimenews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bug in macOS, Gatekeeper’s security can be bypassed by malware.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The macOS operating system was recently patched for a security vulnerability that could be exploited by a threat actor to bypass “myriad foundational macOS security mechanisms” and run arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Wardle described the discovery in a series of tweets on Thursday. According to CVE-2021-30853 (CVSS 5.5), the issue involves a scenario where a rogue macOS app can circumvent Gatekeeper checks, ensuring that only trusted apps can be run and have been notarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese government suspends the Alibaba deal because it did not share the 0-day of Log4j with the government.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) of China temporarily suspended a partnership with Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing subsidiary of the world’s largest e-commerce company, for six months after the company failed to promptly notify the government about a critical security vulnerability affecting the widely used Log4j logging library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reports from 21st Century Business Herald, a Chinese daily business newspaper, revealed the development to Reuters and South China Morning Post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote hacking is possible for Garrett walk-through metal detectors.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A network component in Garrett Metal Detectors contains a number of security flaws that could allow remote attackers to bypass authentication requirements, tamper with metal detector configurations, and even execute arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a disclosure released last week, Cisco Talos noted that an attacker could use this module to remotely monitor statistics on a metal detector, such as whether the alarm has been triggered or how many visitors passed through. “They could also alter device configurations, such as changing the sensitivity level, potentially posing a security risk to users of these metal detectors.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
