<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Extraction Agent and Firewall: Software vs. Hardware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/firewall_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a firewall is essential to secure the installation of the extraction agent when performing low-level extraction from a variety of iOS devices. We developed two solutions: a software-based firewall for macOS and a hardware-based firewall using a Raspberry Pi (or similar microcomputer) with our own custom firmware. This guide will help you choose the best option for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let us clarify that the solutions described in this article are neither traditional nor fully-featured firewalls. Instead, they are designed to restrict internet access to specific endpoints during a critical phase of the sideloading process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
