<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dataprotection on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/dataprotection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dataprotection on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/dataprotection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Eight Lincoln Laboratory technologies named 2020 R&amp;D 100 Award winners&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight technologies developed by MIT Lincoln Laboratory researchers, either wholly or in collaboration with researchers from other organizations, were among the winners of the 2020 R&amp;amp;D 100 Awards. Annually since 1963, these international R&amp;amp;D awards recognize 100 technologies that a panel of expert judges selects as the most revolutionary of the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six of the laboratory’s winning technologies are software systems, a number of which take advantage of artificial intelligence techniques. The software technologies are solutions to difficulties inherent in analyzing large volumes of data and to problems in maintaining cybersecurity. Another technology is a process designed to assure secure fabrication of integrated circuits, and the eighth winner is an optical communications technology that may enable future space missions to transmit error-free data to Earth at significantly higher rates than currently possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Explanation on recent DDoS attacks &amp; why we do not use third-parties for mitigation.&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/explanation-on-recent-ddos-attacks-why-we-do-not-use-third-parties-for-mitigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/explanation-on-recent-ddos-attacks-why-we-do-not-use-third-parties-for-mitigation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta we are building a privacy-first alternative to big tech offerings so that everyone can protect their data online by sending encrypted emails and sharing encrypted events with Tuta Mail and Tuta Calendar. This brings our service to the forefront of all kinds of adversaries. As a consequence, Tuta is regularly being attacked with DDoS attacks. While most of the times, we can fend off these attacks without you noticing, the adversaries changed their attack vectors beginning of December which led to several downtimes during the first week of December. We have now immensely improved our DDoS-protection methods and our systems are capable of fending off these attacks. Now, we would like explain what happened and how we mitigated the attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tuta User Survey 2024: Your guidance for Tuta&#39;s future development&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tuta-user-survey-2024-your-guidance-for-tutas-future-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tuta-user-survey-2024-your-guidance-for-tutas-future-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta, our mission is simple yet important: We want to empower individuals and organizations with secure, private communication tools that protect their data and privacy. In an era where Big Tech dominates the digital landscape, we provide an alternative - a place where your information isn’t the product, but kept secure with quantum-safe encryption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions: Areg Danagoulian on a new arms control tool and the future of nuclear security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Areg Danagoulian, associate professor in the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering, has built a career around nuclear detection technology. His work has focused, among other things, on a system that could greatly improve the current process for verifying compliance of nuclear warheads.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this year, he published new work on physical cryptographic nuclear warhead verification and on active detection of shielded nuclear materials in journals including&lt;/em&gt; Nature Communications &lt;em&gt;and the&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of the National Academy of Science. &lt;em&gt;He has also received a pair of prestigious accolades: a radiation science and technology award from the American Nuclear Society and the honor of being named, along with his team, as the 2019 Arms Control Association (ACA) Arms Control Persons of the Year.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;“This innovation paves the way for more effective arms control agreements, inspections, and enforcement,&amp;quot; said Daryl Kimball, executive director of the ACA. &amp;ldquo;Professor Danagoulian’s MIT team has brought the best science to arms control and provided a creative solution that can reduce nuclear threats and enhance security.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions: Ron Rivest on trusting electronic voting systems</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-ron-rivest-on-trusting-electronic-voting-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-ron-rivest-on-trusting-electronic-voting-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ron Rivest is an MIT Institute Professor in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. He’s an authority on algorithms and an inventor of the RSA public-key cryptosystem, one of the most widely used algorithms to securely transmit data. Since the 1980s, he’s taught students how to use cryptography to help secure voting systems. Then, in 2000, an historic recount in Florida determined the outcome of the U.S. presidential election, and the Caltech / MIT Voting Technology Project was founded with the mission to secure future elections, pulling in Rivest, who has been involved since, as well as other MIT faculty from the Department of Political Science and the MIT Sloan School of Management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best family calendar app for Android | Desktop | iPhone.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-family-calendar-app-for-android-desktop-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-family-calendar-app-for-android-desktop-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing your own busy schedule on top of your family’s sometimes seems impossible. Luckily, this is where a family calendar app is there to help you keep track of upcoming events and meetings. In this guide, we look at the best family agenda to use on any device (iPhone / Android / Desktop) and what features you should look for when choosing a shareable calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Weeks at Tuta: Save 62% On Our Legend Plan! 💎</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-weeks-at-tuta-save-62-on-our-legend-plan-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-weeks-at-tuta-save-62-on-our-legend-plan-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We at Tuta are thrilled to offer an exclusive Black Friday and Cyber Monday discount! You can now upgrade to our Legend Plan - with 62% off for the first year. With this offer, we want to give back not just to our free users constantly spreading privacy, but also to our dear Revolutionary and legacy users who already support our mission so that we can enable everyone to use the web privately!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encryption is non-negotiable: open letter to EU to not undermine privacy.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-is-non-negotiable-open-letter-to-eu-to-not-undermine-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-is-non-negotiable-open-letter-to-eu-to-not-undermine-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta we fight for your right to privacy with encryption. But the EU is still discussing policies and law enforcement demands that threaten to break encryption. If the EU continues down this path, we at Tuta are given two choices - compromise our quantum-safe encryption, or relocate to a region that values and safeguards digital privacy. The answer for us is easy. We&amp;rsquo;d rather leave the EU than break our open source encryption. Now we have signed an open letter and together with more than 50 organizations and companies we call on the EU to uphold strong encryption and privacy rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friends don’t let friends reuse nonces</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/friends-dont-let-friends-reuse-nonces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/friends-dont-let-friends-reuse-nonces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Joe Doyle If you’ve encountered cryptography software, you’ve probably heard the advice to never use a nonce twice—in fact, that’s where the word nonce (number used once) comes from. Depending on the cryptography involved, a reused nonce can reveal encrypted messages, or even leak your secret key! But common knowledge may not cover every […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Friends don’t let friends reuse nonces appeared first on Security Boulevard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gmail ads are getting so invasive. Can they be blocked?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gmail-ads-are-getting-so-invasive-can-they-be-blocked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gmail-ads-are-getting-so-invasive-can-they-be-blocked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No one likes ads, but the free Gmail - a very popular email provider - continues to ignore its users demands at this crucial point. While seemingly the perfect email solution with lots of features and plenty of storage, Gmail shows more advertisements to its users than most email services. This advertising must be stopped!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create a small business email address | With best security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-small-business-email-address-with-best-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-small-business-email-address-with-best-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every SME needs a business email solution to build brand credibility and trust. In this guide, we explore the importance of professional email addresses for small companies and why Tuta Mail is the perfect secure provider to use for your organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to delete your Yahoo email account (on Android | iPhone | PC)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-delete-your-yahoo-email-account-on-android-iphone-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-delete-your-yahoo-email-account-on-android-iphone-pc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo Mail is not known to have the best security or top privacy protections so it continues to lose popularity in 2024. Find out why it&amp;rsquo;s time to delete your Yahoo account - and how you can do so - easily and quickly! In this guide, we walk you through the steps needed for deleting your Yahoo Mail account (and all your data) and present a better alternative - the free Tuta email account - that protects all your data with quantum-safe encryption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to permanently delete an Outlook (and Microsoft) account</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-permanently-delete-an-outlook-and-microsoft-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-permanently-delete-an-outlook-and-microsoft-account/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you wanting to permanently delete your Outlook or Hotmail account? Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re tired of all the ads cluttering your Outlook mailbox, all the spam emails you get daily, or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re simply wanting to create a new email account – either way, deleting your Outlook email account is possible on any device with these simple steps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s a weird, weird quantum world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1994, as Professor Peter Shor PhD ’85 tells it, internal seminars at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs were lively affairs. The audience of physicists was an active and inquisitive bunch, often pelting speakers with questions throughout their talks. Shor, who worked at Bell Labs at the time, remembers several occasions when a speaker couldn’t get past their third slide, as they attempted to address a rapid line of questioning before their time was up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janabel Xia: Algorithms, dance rhythms, and the drive to succeed</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/janabel-xia-algorithms-dance-rhythms-and-the-drive-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/janabel-xia-algorithms-dance-rhythms-and-the-drive-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Senior math major Janabel Xia is a study of a person in constant motion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When she isn’t sorting algorithms and improving traffic control systems for driverless vehicles, she’s dancing as a member of at least four dance clubs. She’s joined several social justice organizations, worked on cryptography and web authentication technology, and created a polling app that allows users to vote anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In her final semester, she’s putting the pedal to the metal, with a green light to lessen the carbon footprint of urban transportation by using sensors at traffic light intersections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerry Emanuel,  David Sabatini, and Peter Shor receive BBVA Frontiers of Knowledge awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBVA Foundation awarded three MIT professors Frontiers of Knowledge Awards for their work in climate change, biology and biomedicine, and quantum computation. Department of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences Professor Kerry A. Emanuel, Department of Biology Professor David Sabatini, and Department of Mathematics Professor Peter Shor were recognized in the 12th edition of this annual award.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kerry Emanuel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emanuel, the Cecil and Ida Green Professor of Atmospheric Science, earned the BBVA’s Climate Change award “for his fundamental contributions to the understanding of tropical cyclones and how they are affected by climate change,” according to the committee’s citation. “By understanding the essential physics of atmospheric convection … he has unraveled the behavior of tropical cyclones — hurricanes and typhoons — as our climate changes.” He was also lauded for “extraordinary effectiveness in communicating the science of climate change to the public and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Is Adding New Cryptography Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is updating SymCrypt, its core cryptographic library, with new quantum-secure algorithms. Microsoft’s details are here. From a news article:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first new algorithm Microsoft added to SymCrypt is called ML-KEM. Previously known as CRYSTALS-Kyber, ML-KEM is one of three post-quantum standards formalized last month by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). The KEM in the new name is short for key encapsulation. KEMs can be used by two parties to negotiate a shared secret over a public channel. Shared secrets generated by a KEM can then be used with symmetric-key cryptographic operations, which aren’t vulnerable to Shor’s algorithm when the keys are of a sufficient size&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT launches new data privacy-focused initiative</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategic use of data is vital for progress in science, commerce, and even politics, but at the same time, citizens are demanding more responsible, respectful use of personal data. Internet users have never felt more helpless about how their data are being used: Surveys show that the vast majority of U.S. adults feel that they have little to no control over the data that the government and private companies collect about them. In response to these concerns, new privacy laws are being enacted in Europe, California, Virginia, and elsewhere around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outlook vs Gmail: Which is best in 2024?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/outlook-vs-gmail-which-is-best-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/outlook-vs-gmail-which-is-best-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve done research and put together a comprehensive review looking at the pros and cons of free Outlook vs Gmail. We will discuss how the two email providers compare to each other, what the main differences between Gmail and Outlook are, and how you can choose an even better, more private email provider.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor receives 2022-2023 Killian Award</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Renowned mathematician and quantum computing pioneer Peter W. Shor PhD ’85 has been named the recipient of MIT’s 2022-2023 James R. Killian Jr. Faculty Achievement Award, the highest honor the Institute faculty can bestow upon one of its members each academic year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Killian Award citation credits Shor, who is the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics, with having made “seminal contributions that have forever shaped the foundations of quantum computing. Indeed, quantum computing exists today, in practice, because of Peter Shor.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor wins Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Shor, the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics at MIT, has been named a recipient of the 2023 Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics. He shares the $3 million prize with three others for “foundational work in the field of quantum information”: David Deutsch at the University of Oxford, Charles Bennett at IBM Research, and Gilles Brassard of the University of Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In announcing the award, the Breakthrough Prize Foundation highlighted Shor’s contributions to the quantum information field, including the eponymous Shor’s algorithm for factoring extremely large numbers, and for an algorithm to correct errors in quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portable technology offers boost for nuclear security, arms control</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/portable-technology-offers-boost-for-nuclear-security-arms-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/portable-technology-offers-boost-for-nuclear-security-arms-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About five years ago, Areg Danagoulian, associate professor in the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering (NSE), became intrigued by a technique developed by researchers at Los Alamos National Laboratory that uses a neutron beam to identify unknown materials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“They could look into a black box containing uranium and say what kind and how much,” says Danagoulian, who directs MIT’s Laboratory of Applied Nuclear Physics (LANPh). “I was thinking about the problem of verifying nuclear material in warheads, and it just dawned on me, this amazing technology could be applied to what we’re working on.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Advice for PQC Migration for TLS 1.3</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/practical-advice-for-pqc-migration-for-tls-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/practical-advice-for-pqc-migration-for-tls-1-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Numerous blogs and articles are urging security professionals to start migrating to quantum-resistant algorithms immediately. This urgency was heightened on August 13, 2024, when NIST finalized the FIPS 203 (ML-KEM), FIPS 204 (ML-DSA), and FIPS 205 (SLH-DSA) standards. In this article, I present a simplified example of a client establishing a TLS 1.3 connection to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Practical Advice for PQC Migration for TLS 1.3 appeared first on Security Boulevard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School of Engineering welcomes new faculty</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The School of Engineering welcomes 15 new faculty members across six of its academic departments. This new cohort of faculty members, who have either recently started their roles at MIT or will start within the next year, conduct research across a diverse range of disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of these new faculty specialize in research that intersects with multiple fields. In addition to positions in the School of Engineering, a number of these faculty have positions at other units across MIT. Faculty with appointments in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) report into both the School of Engineering and the MIT Stephen A. Schwarzman College of Computing. This year, new faculty also have joint appointments between the School of Engineering and the School of Humanities, Arts, and Social Sciences and the School of Science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “last mile” from credentials to employment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academic digital credentials — the cryptographically verifiable assertion that an individual holds a degree, certificate, or other credential — have been available for the better part of a decade. Yet despite the potential value of these data-rich, transportable credentials to graduates, employers, and academic institutions, digital credentials have by no means become the standard in presenting or verifying skills and qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new report from the Digital Credentials Consortium (DCC), housed at MIT Open Learning, explores this gap between the promise of digital credentials and their widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a code-breaking quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most recent email you sent was likely encrypted using a tried-and-true method that relies on the idea that even the fastest computer would be unable to efficiently break a gigantic number into factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers, on the other hand, promise to rapidly crack complex cryptographic systems that a classical computer might never be able to unravel. This promise is based on a quantum factoring algorithm proposed in 1994 by Peter Shor, who is now a professor at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuta Survey Results: Only about half the users use passwords that are long enough.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tuta-survey-results-only-about-half-the-users-use-passwords-that-are-long-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tuta-survey-results-only-about-half-the-users-use-passwords-that-are-long-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta our focus is to keep our users&amp;rsquo; data secure with quantum-safe encryption. To achieve maximum security, the importance of strong, secure passwords that are long enough cannot be overstated. Passwords are the first line of defense to make sure that no unauthorized access can bring harm to your data or yourself. While factors like complexity and unpredictability matter, experts emphasize that length is a critical element in ensuring password security. But do people today know the perfect password length?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UI Improvement for Tuta Calendar</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ui-improvement-for-tuta-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ui-improvement-for-tuta-calendar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like us, your calendar app is your lifeline, and by the way, a private one. It&amp;rsquo;s where you organize everything—from work meetings to social gatherings—and sometimes, it feels like your entire life is neatly packed into those little squares. But, let’s be honest, even the most feature-packed calendar apps can get a little overwhelming. That’s why today, we are excited to talk about a small but mighty UI improvement that will make how you interact with your calendar way faster: a simplified event creation flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What You Need to Know About “Harvest-Now, Decrypt-Later” Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-you-need-to-know-about-harvest-now-decrypt-later-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-you-need-to-know-about-harvest-now-decrypt-later-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As quantum computing leapfrogs at great speed, the spotlight is now on post-quantum cryptography (PQC). Recently, NIST released the first three PQC encryption algorithm standards, urging organizations to test the new algorithms and prepare their cryptographic infrastructures for the inevitable shift to quantum-resistant methods. This push for PQC readiness is driven by a growing concern […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post What You Need to Know About “Harvest-Now, Decrypt-Later” Attacks appeared first on Security Boulevard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working toward a more secure world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/working-toward-a-more-secure-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/working-toward-a-more-secure-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well before arriving on campus, Peninah (Nina) Levine knew what she wanted from her undergraduate education:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I came to MIT to be in an environment that would push me beyond my comfortable limits,” says Levine, a senior majoring in nuclear science and engineering (NSE). “I had to find where my passions lay and forge my own path.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, Levine is well along that path, engaged in a five-year combined undergraduate and master’s program and helping develop technologies for characterizing nuclear material — tools to aid in nuclear weapons verification or to prevent illicit trafficking of nuclear material. Her research is based in the Laboratory for Applied Nuclear Physics, directed by Associate Professor Areg Danagoulian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worst US hack in history: Chinese can monitor all your calls and emails.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/worst-us-hack-in-history-chinese-can-monitor-all-your-calls-and-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/worst-us-hack-in-history-chinese-can-monitor-all-your-calls-and-emails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chinese attackers have infiltrated more than a dozen US telecom providers such as AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon and T-Mobile to monitor US officials, and even politicians like Trump and Harris. The FBI detected this attack by Salt Typhoon months ago, but still can not get the attackers out of the systems. Now, America&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Defence Agency (CISA) calls on everyone to use end-to-end encryption. This is proof that backdoors to encryption must never be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yael Tauman Kalai PhD ’06 awarded 2022 ACM Prize in Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yael-tauman-kalai-phd-06-awarded-2022-acm-prize-in-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yael-tauman-kalai-phd-06-awarded-2022-acm-prize-in-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yael Tauman Kalai PhD ’06, an MIT Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) adjunct professor, member of the MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL), and senior principal researcher at Microsoft Research has been awarded the 2022 ACM Prize in Computing for “breakthroughs in verifiable delegation of computation and fundamental contributions to cryptography” by the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM). The $250,000 prize recognizes early-to-mid-career computer scientists who have made key research contributions to the field, such as Kalai’s influence on modern cryptographic practices. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS launches AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications. The Android Team Awareness Kit (ATAK)—also known as Android Tactical Assault Kit for military use—is a smartphone geospatial infrastructure and situational awareness application. It provides mapping, messaging, and geofencing capabilities to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP High authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP Moderate authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hardening the security of your AWS Elastic Beanstalk Application the Well-Architected way</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hardening-the-security-of-your-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application-the-well-architected-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hardening-the-security-of-your-aws-elastic-beanstalk-application-the-well-architected-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April 7, 2022: This post has been updated with sample Elastic Beanstalk application with hardened security configurations on GitHub. Launching an application in AWS Elastic Beanstalk is straightforward. You define a name for your application, select the platform you want to run it on (for example, Ruby), and upload the source code. The default Elastic Beanstalk configuration […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 7, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: This post has been updated with sample Elastic Beanstalk application with hardened security configurations on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to secure your SaaS tenant data in DynamoDB with ABAC and client-side encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that can help you protect your customers and earn their trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three key security themes from AWS re:Invent 2022</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations. Now in its 11th year, the conference featured 5 keynotes, 22 leadership sessions, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
