<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security-Privacy on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/security-privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security-Privacy on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/security-privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“Apple Inc sent you a payment request” Payoneer invoices; other Microsoft-enabled scams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-inc-sent-you-a-payment-request-payoneer-invoices-other-microsoft-enabled-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-inc-sent-you-a-payment-request-payoneer-invoices-other-microsoft-enabled-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scammers are sending fake payment requests via Payoneer and Microsoft. Here is what you need to know to avoid getting scammed through fraudulent e-mails like these.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post “Apple Inc sent you a payment request” Payoneer invoices; other Microsoft-enabled scams appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kali Linux 2025.1a Release (2025 Theme, &amp; Raspberry Pi)&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-2025-1a-release-2025-theme-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-2025-1a-release-2025-theme-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are kicking off 2025 with &lt;strong&gt;Kali Linux 2025.1a&lt;/strong&gt;! This update builds on existing features, bringing enhancements and improvements to streamline your experience. It is now available to download or upgrade if you’re already running Kali Linux. &lt;em&gt;Kali Linux 2025.1&lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;? What happened to 2025.1? There was a last minute bug discovered in a package after already producing our images. As a result, a re-build was needed, with a fix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a recap of the changelog since our December 2024.4 release:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scammers using new trick in phishing text messages: Google redirects</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scammers-using-new-trick-in-phishing-text-messages-google-redirects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scammers-using-new-trick-in-phishing-text-messages-google-redirects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scammers are bypassing an Apple security feature and exploiting Google redirects. Here is what you need to know to avoid getting scammed through fraudulent text messages like these.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Scammers using new trick in phishing text messages: Google redirects appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kali Linux 2024.4 Release (Python 3.12, Goodbye i386, Raspberry Pi Imager &amp; Kali NetHunter)&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-2024-4-release-python-3-12-goodbye-i386-raspberry-pi-imager-kali-nethunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-2024-4-release-python-3-12-goodbye-i386-raspberry-pi-imager-kali-nethunter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before the year starts to wrap up, we are getting the final 2024 release out! This contains a wide range of updates and changes, which are in already in effect, ready for immediate download, or updating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The summary of the changelog since the 2024.3 release from September is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 3.12&lt;/strong&gt; - New default Python version &lt;em&gt;(Au revoir &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;, hello pipx)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The End Of The i386 Kernel and Images&lt;/strong&gt; - Farewell x86 &lt;em&gt;(images)&lt;/em&gt;, but not goodbye &lt;em&gt;(packages)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deprecations in the SSH Client: DSA keys&lt;/strong&gt; - Reminder about using &lt;code&gt;ssh1&lt;/code&gt; if required&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raspberry Pi Imager Customizations Support&lt;/strong&gt; - Able to alter settings at write time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GNOME 47&lt;/strong&gt; - Now able to synchronize your favorite colors&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kali Forums Refresh&lt;/strong&gt; - New heart of the community home&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kali NetHunter&lt;/strong&gt; - Updates to the app, kernels, installer, store and website!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Tools&lt;/strong&gt; - 14 new shiny toys added &lt;em&gt;(and countless updated!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-python-version-312&#34;&gt;A New Python Version: 3.12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python 3.12 is now the default Python interpreter&lt;/strong&gt;. While it was released upstream a year ago , it took a bit of time to become the default in Debian , and then even more time to make it to Kali Linux , but finally it’s here. Every new version of Python brings along some deprecations or subtle changes of behavior, which in turn breaks some Python packages, and we have to investigate and fix all the issues reported by our QA system. Hence the delay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Kali</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/contributing-to-kali/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/contributing-to-kali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the launch of our brand-new forums, we thought we would update our documentation and explore how everyone can contribute to the growth of Kali Linux. Kali is a multi-platform project that thrives on the the contributions of its community. Whether you’re curious about how you can pitch in or simply want to learn more about how contributions shape our platform, keep reading. For a deeper dive, don’t forget to check out the relevant Kali Docs pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kali Linux On The New Modern WSL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-on-the-new-modern-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kali-linux-on-the-new-modern-wsl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Late last year we had the pleasure of being reached out to by Microsoft in regards to participating in the launch of the new, modern, WSL distribution architecture. In summary, this new architecture allows for easier distribution and installation of WSL distros. For the full explanation of how this works, please view Microsoft’s blog post and their documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the assistance of Microsoft’s WSL team, we are proud to say that we were the first Linux distro to be accepted onto this new modern distribution list. In this blog post we will cover the journey and share how you can try out this new architecture, but if you are just looking for the hands on portion then please see here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end of the i386 kernel and images</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-end-of-the-i386-kernel-and-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-end-of-the-i386-kernel-and-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt; architecture has long been obsolete, and from this week, support for i386 in Kali Linux is going to shrink significantly: i386 kernel and images are going away. Images and releases will no longer be created for this platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-terminology-first&#34;&gt;Some terminology first&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the terms used in Kali Linux to talk about CPU architectures. These terms apply more generally to any Debian-based Linux distribution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;amd64&lt;/code&gt; refers to the x86-64 architecture, ie. the &lt;em&gt;64-bit version of the x86 instruction set&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;i386&lt;/code&gt; refers to the x86 architecture, ie. the &lt;em&gt;original 32-bit x86 architecture&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-changing&#34;&gt;What’s changing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, the &lt;strong&gt;Linux kernel&lt;/strong&gt;: starting version 6.11 (that just landed in Kali rolling), the kernel is no longer built for the i386 architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple chips can leak secrets to hackers; SLAP and FLOP attacks explained</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-chips-can-leak-secrets-to-hackers-slap-and-flop-attacks-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-chips-can-leak-secrets-to-hackers-slap-and-flop-attacks-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Serious flaws in Apple’s M2 and A15 chips—and all later chips—could enable hackers to steal sensitive data from browsers like Safari or Chrome on a victim’s Mac, iPhone, or iPad (or possibly Apple Vision Pro). Here is everything you need to know about how SLAP and FLOP might affect you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Apple chips can leak secrets to hackers; SLAP and FLOP attacks explained appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS 18.3 and macOS Sequoia 15.3 patch first Apple zero-day of 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-18-3-and-macos-sequoia-15-3-patch-first-apple-zero-day-of-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-18-3-and-macos-sequoia-15-3-patch-first-apple-zero-day-of-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple released critically urgent security updates this week for macOS, iOS, iPadOS, visionOS, and tvOS to address a bug that was actively exploited in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post iOS 18.3 and macOS Sequoia 15.3 patch first Apple zero-day of 2025 appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
