<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyberalerts on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyberalerts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyberalerts on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyberalerts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ON Log4j Vulnerability CISA, FBI, and NSA publish a joint advisory.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian, Canadian, New Zealand, U.S., and U.K. cyber security agencies released a joint advisory on Wednesday in response to the widespread exploitation of multiple vulnerabilities in Apache’s Log4j software library by malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“These vulnerabilities, especially Log4Shell, are severe,” the intelligence agencies stated in the new guidance. Cyber threat actors are actively scanning networks for vulnerabilities such as Log4Shell, CVE-2021-45046, and CVE-2021-45105. These vulnerabilities will likely be exploited over an extended period. Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) can be exploited by sending a specially crafted request to a vulnerable system that causes that system to execute arbitrary code. CVE-2021-45046, on the other hand, allows remote code execution in certain non-default configurations, while CVE-2021-45105 could be used by a remote attacker to cause a denial-of-service (DoS) condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote hacking is possible for Garrett walk-through metal detectors.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A network component in Garrett Metal Detectors contains a number of security flaws that could allow remote attackers to bypass authentication requirements, tamper with metal detector configurations, and even execute arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a disclosure released last week, Cisco Talos noted that an attacker could use this module to remotely monitor statistics on a metal detector, such as whether the alarm has been triggered or how many visitors passed through. “They could also alter device configurations, such as changing the sensitivity level, potentially posing a security risk to users of these metal detectors.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
