<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intermediate-Certificates on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/intermediate-certificates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intermediate-Certificates on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/intermediate-certificates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Quality of Publicly Trusted Intermediate CA Certificates with Enhanced Oversight and Automation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improving-the-quality-of-publicly-trusted-intermediate-ca-certificates-with-enhanced-oversight-and-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improving-the-quality-of-publicly-trusted-intermediate-ca-certificates-with-enhanced-oversight-and-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In keeping with our commitment to the security and privacy of individuals on the internet, Mozilla is increasing our oversight and adding automation to our compliance-checking of publicly trusted intermediate CA certificates (“intermediate certificates”). This improvement in automation is important because intermediate certificates play a critical part in the web PKI (Public-Key Infrastructure). Intermediate CA keys directly sign server certificates, and we currently recognize nearly 3,000 intermediate certificates, which chain up to approximately 150 root CA certificates embedded as trust anchors in NSS and Firefox. More specifically, we are updating the Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) and associated guidance, improving the public review of third-party intermediate certificates on the Mozilla dev-security-policy list, and enhancing automation in the Common CA Database (CCADB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
