<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acm on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/acm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acm on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/acm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to tune TLS for hybrid post-quantum cryptography with Kyber</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 30, 2024: The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info. January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 2022 AWS data protection service and cryptography tool launches</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-2022-aws-data-protection-service-and-cryptography-tool-launches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-2022-aws-data-protection-service-and-cryptography-tool-launches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February 28, 2023: We updated this blog to include AWS Wickr. Given the pace of Amazon Web Services (AWS) innovation, it can be challenging to stay up to date on the latest AWS service and feature launches. AWS provides services and tools to help you protect your data, accounts, and workloads from unauthorized access. AWS […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 28, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; We updated this blog to include AWS Wickr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the pace of Amazon Web Services (AWS) innovation, it can be challenging to stay up to date on the latest AWS service and feature launches. AWS provides services and tools to help you protect your data, accounts, and workloads from unauthorized access. AWS data protection services provide encryption capabilities, key management, and sensitive data discovery. Last year, we saw growth and evolution in AWS data protection services as we continue to give customers features and controls to help meet their needs. Protecting data in the AWS Cloud is a top priority because we know you trust us to help protect your most critical and sensitive asset: your data. This post will highlight some of the key AWS data protection launches in the last year that security professionals should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
