<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National-Institute-of-Standards-and-Technology-Nist-Software-Assurance-Metrics on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/national-institute-of-standards-and-technology-nist-software-assurance-metrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National-Institute-of-Standards-and-Technology-Nist-Software-Assurance-Metrics on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/national-institute-of-standards-and-technology-nist-software-assurance-metrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BSides København – Meaningful Metrics in Information Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next BSides København will take place on 9 November 2024. There is one presentation in the schedule about the use of metrics in information security. Computers allow us to create documents, charts, and statistical values easily from any data collection we like. Therefore, the World Wide Web is full of graphs, tables with numbers, predictions, and all kinds of results. The problem is that not everything you can count is a suitable metric tied to real-life observations. Finding a metric is a science on its own. This presentation will give you some examples of how to measure meaningful attributes of computer systems and networks. You will also get to know the term metric more closely. Using proper metrics and assessing customer-provided reports will help you immensely when dealing with information security decisions. The&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
