<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devsecops on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/devsecops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devsecops on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/devsecops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Software Testing: Ensuring Reliability in the Next Computing Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;As &lt;strong&gt;quantum computing&lt;/strong&gt; continues to evolve, ensuring software reliability has become a critical challenge. Our latest article explores key aspects of quantum software testing, from bug patterns and testing methodologies to quantum software deployment and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Rajiv Chopra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-software-testing&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantum Software Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum software testing is the process of executing a quantum program to find the faults. This ensures that the quantum software is correct, reliable and performs well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why we need a better approach to DevSecOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-we-need-a-better-approach-to-devsecops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-we-need-a-better-approach-to-devsecops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A genuine collaborative approach between teams will deliver the security the industry requires.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1-click RCE possible by combining vulnerabilities in Voyager PHP</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/1-click-rce-possible-by-combining-vulnerabilities-in-voyager-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/1-click-rce-possible-by-combining-vulnerabilities-in-voyager-php/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chaining the Voyager PHP flaws together could let attackers steal sensitive GitHub project files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the DevOps use Cases?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-are-the-devops-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-are-the-devops-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-102.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps practices have transformed the way organizations develop, test, and deliver software. By bringing together development and operations teams, DevOps enables automation, collaboration, and continuous improvement throughout the software development lifecycle (SDLC). As companies strive for greater efficiency, faster delivery times, and higher-quality software, DevOps has found applications across a variety of industries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we will explore several real-world &lt;strong&gt;DevOps use cases&lt;/strong&gt;, showcasing how organizations are leveraging DevOps to solve specific challenges. Each use case demonstrates the core features and benefits of DevOps in different business contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why we need a unified approach to Kubernetes environments</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-we-need-a-unified-approach-to-kubernetes-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-we-need-a-unified-approach-to-kubernetes-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A unified Kubernetes approach promises simplified operations, enhanced security, and more efficient threat detection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Ireland Salary Guide reveals latest emerging employment trends</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generative AI adoption accelerates – nearly 70% of businesses encourage their staff to use AI for routine tasks and enhanced productivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High demand for skilled professionals – 27% of businesses plan to expand permanent roles, with another 68% maintaining headcount across professional services in 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rising salary expectations across generations – 68% of Gen Z professionals are becoming more insistent on higher pay, compared to just 22% of Gen X and 10% of Baby Boomers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Robert Half, the world’s first and largest specialised talent solutions and business consulting firm, has published its inaugural 2025 Ireland Salary Guide, offering essential insights into hiring and remuneration trends. The study analyses labour market dynamics, benefits and incentives, as well as starting salaries for a wide array of roles in diverse professional sectors throughout Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Security Strategies for the Gen AI Era</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;generative-ai-is-evolvingis-your-security-strategy-keeping-pace&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI is Evolving—Is Your Security Strategy Keeping Pace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; has quickly become a pivotal element in &lt;strong&gt;digital transformation&lt;/strong&gt; across industries, driving automation, enhancing customer interactions, and accelerating software development. But with these advancements come new and complex security challenges. Companies are rushing to adopt &lt;strong&gt;generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; to stay competitive, yet many haven’t adapted their cybersecurity practices to handle the emerging threats. When companies designed their cybersecurity policies and controls, few, if any, had generative AI on their bingo card. As a result, we’re seeing organisations unprepared for the unique vulnerabilities this technology introduces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI decreases human-generated content, limiting data for training AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of ChatGPT has led to a decrease in human-generated content with people asking and answering fewer questions online, according to new research from Corvinus University of Budapest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content and discussions online are used by people to learn new things and solve problems, and essential for training AI, particularly Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johannes Wachs, Associate Professor at Corvinus University, and colleagues from UCL and LMU Munich investigated the impact of ChatGPT on the generation of open data on Stack Overflow, an online Q&amp;amp;A platform for computer programmers and an essential source of training data for LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin will reach $100k before Trump takes office</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Donald Trump heads back to the White House, a University of Sussex professor who has been successfully predicting bitcoin (BTC) prices since 2021, is forecasting unprecedented highs which may breach $100k per token.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prof Carol Alexander of the University of Sussex Business School says bitcoin’s rapid rise in the immediate wake of the US election is likely to continue before Trump’s inauguration on 20th January 2025. She also believes the lesser-known currencies ether (ETH) and dogecoin (DOGE) will keep moving in the same direction, especially with the latter’s links to key Trump ally Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing organisational sustainability with carbon management dashboards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan. However, driving down energy consumption and rolling out energy projects is the responsibility of more than one department in an organisation. Many people – from engineers to investors and from management to staff – need to be brought together to make success happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How devops works?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-39-1024x468.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-devops-a-modern-approach-to-software-development&#34;&gt;Introduction to DevOps: A Modern Approach to Software Development&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps is a set of practices, tools, and cultural philosophies that aim to improve collaboration and productivity between software development (Dev) and IT operations (Ops) teams. The goal of DevOps is to shorten the development lifecycle and provide continuous delivery with high software quality. By emphasizing automation, collaboration, and monitoring, DevOps ensures that applications can be developed, tested, and deployed faster, more reliably, and with greater stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How open-source is shaping the future of innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-source technology&lt;/strong&gt; has significantly shaped how industries approach complex technical challenges and foster innovation. It has expanded beyond software to impact hardware and systems design, opening up new pathways for researchers, engineers, and tech enthusiasts to develop advanced solutions. This collective approach fuels innovation and contributes to sustainable development by creating accessible, adaptable tools that solve real-world problems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-awards--summit-2025-enter-the-ai-awards-and-be-a-part-of-the-future&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;democratising-open-source-technology-and-science&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Democratising open-source technology and science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open-source technology fundamentally changes how we access and utilise high-tech tools. Traditionally, advanced instruments like oscilloscopes, signal generators, and spectrum analysers were accessible primarily to well-funded research labs. With open-source tools such as Red Pitaya’s “pocket lab,” engineers and students can now access powerful measurement and testing capabilities in a compact, cost-effective format. This allows universities, startups, and even independent researchers and enthusiasts to innovate without being restricted by cost or proprietary limitations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The partnership that will prevent vape sales to minors</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johnston Retail Services has partnered with Privately SA to bring the AgeAI app to Ireland, helping to prevent vape sales to minors and avoid the risk of costly fines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20 November 2024 – Stores across Ireland can now benefit from a pioneering AI solution that can estimate someone’s age with almost 100% accuracy, thanks to a new partnership between Dublin’s Johnston Retail Services and SafetyTech company Privately SA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privately’s AgeAI app provides automated and highly accurate facial age estimation, removing the guesswork from age checks and mitigating the risk of fines for selling vapes to children. It is 100% anonymous, with no images transmitted or stored, GDPR certified, and helps protect staff by reducing the need for unnecessary ID checks for adults who are a source of major conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tricentis launches qTest Copilot to empower QA Organisations to Ship Quality Software Faster</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tricentis, a global leader in continuous testing and quality engineering, today announced the expansion of its test management and analytics platform, TricentisqTest, with the launch of Tricentis qTest Copilot. The latest addition to its suite of generative AI-powered Tricentis Copilot solutions, qTest Copilot harnesses the power of generative AI to simplify and accelerate test case generation, allowing for greater test coverage and higher-quality software releases.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;qTest Copilot is a generative AI assistant that automatically drafts test cases and test steps based on source documents and user requirements, offering considerable time-saving benefits when compared to manual approaches. Embedded into the newest version of the qTest platform, qTest Copilot combines Tricentis’ scalable and unified test management technology, with new AI-augmented features to allow QA and developer teams to greatly accelerate software delivery. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for The European Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, November 20, 2024&lt;/strong&gt; – The &lt;strong&gt;winners of the European Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking a remarkable evening of celebration for exceptional achievements in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, a leader in industry events for over 17 years, this prestigious awards ceremony took place on November 19, 2024, in London, where companies, teams, and individuals came together to honour excellence and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for the North American Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toronto, Canada&lt;/strong&gt; – The winners of the &lt;strong&gt;North American Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking an inspiring evening dedicated to recognising excellence in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, the awards ceremony took place on &lt;strong&gt;November 27, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, in Toronto, Canada, and gathered industry leaders and professionals to celebrate the outstanding achievements of companies, teams, and individuals across North America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The program, encompassing &lt;strong&gt;16 categories&lt;/strong&gt;, provided a platform for businesses of all sizes and sectors to showcase their innovation, technical skills, and commitment to quality. Participants embarked on a journey that culminated in an unforgettable awards evening, where achievements were recognised, and connections within the software testing community were strengthened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to thrive in an AI-powered workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-will-your-role-work-with-ai&#34;&gt;How Will Your Role Work with AI? &lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Hugo Farinha, co-founder of Virtuoso QA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Integrating AI sensitively into the workplace while acknowledging the perceptions, negative and positive, around the impact AI may have is going to be an essential skill for the C-suite over the next few years. The landscape will shift, putting greater emphasis on certain skills that will be needed to cover the requirements of working alongside AI, and others better suited for areas where human involvement is still essential… &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eight AI trends to prioritise in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author: Richard Farrell, CIO at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Netcall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2024 saw the adoption of &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI (GenAI)&lt;/strong&gt; accelerate, it also witnessed significant debates and challenges surrounding its use within business from security and data privacy perspectives, with questions surrounding its true value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As CIOs prepare to tackle AI in 2025, Richard Farrell, CIO of Netcall, shares the top trends that must be prioritised in the year ahead to ensure successful adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Generative AI for Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Neha Khandelwal, Software Design Assurance Engineering Manager, Zebra Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Root Cause Analysis (RCA) is a critical yet time-consuming process in the realm of software quality assurance (QA). It requires meticulous investigation to pinpoint the underlying cause of defects, often involving sifting through logs, analysing code, and correlating various system behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QA teams spend significant effort identifying the root cause, which can delay resolutions and increase downtime. As systems grow more complex, traditional RCA methods become less efficient, demanding advanced tools to assist in automating and streamlining the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 DevOps Trends for 2025 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/devops-e1734453914491-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Experts provide insight into the rise of FinOps, how APIs will force a rise in DevSecOps, and how low-code, no-code is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How observability, application security, and AI enhance DevOps and platform engineering maturity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps and platform engineering are essential disciplines that provide immense value in the realm of cloud-native technology and software delivery. However, these practices cannot stand alone. Rather, they must be bolstered by additional technological investments to ensure reliability, security, and efficiency. One of these key investments includes observability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Observability of applications and infrastructure serves as a critical foundation for DevOps and platform engineering, offering a comprehensive view into system performance and behavior. It goes beyond traditional monitoring—metrics, logs, and traces—to encompass topology mapping, code-level details, and user experience metrics that provide real-time insights. This real-time awareness enables teams to rapidly detect and resolve issues: both indispensable capabilities for maintaining the agility and reliability that are central to DevOps and platform engineering processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSA guide 2024: AI and security are top concerns for organizations in every industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/17619_RC_BlogImage_RSA-Guide_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RSA guide, DevSecOps transformation and vulnerability management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is top of mind for security teams across every industry. As more organizations adopt generative AI and cloud-native technologies, IT teams confront more challenges with securing their high-performing cloud applications in the face of expanding attack surfaces. According to McKinsey’s State of AI in 2023 report, 40% of respondents said their organizations plan to increase their overall AI investment because of advancements in generative AI. But only 21% said their organizations have established policies governing employees’ use of generative AI technologies. Moreover, in addition to managing cloud spend and resource utilization, organizations must also now consider the cost and carbon impact of developing and using generative AI models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
