<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iphone on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/iphone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iphone on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;iPhone &amp; Android Users: A Major Privacy Upgrade is Coming Soon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-android-users-a-major-privacy-upgrade-is-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-android-users-a-major-privacy-upgrade-is-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This breakthrough will finally allow secure, encrypted messaging between different mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear Apple: add “Disappearing Messages” to iMessage right now</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a cryptography blog and I always feel the need to apologize for any post that isn’t “straight cryptography.” I’m actually getting a little tired of apologizing for it (though if you want some hard-core cryptography content, there’s plenty here and here.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have to remind my colleagues that out in the real world, our job is not to solve exciting mathematical problems: &lt;em&gt;it’s to help people communicate securely&lt;/em&gt;. And people, at this very moment, need a lot of help. Many of my friends are Federal employees or work for contractors, and they’re terrified that they’re going to lose their job based on speech they post online. Unfortunately, “online” to many people includes thoughts sent over private text messages — so even private conversations are becoming chilled. And while this is hardly the worst thing happening to people in this world, it’s something that’s happening to my friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything you can do with the buttons on your iPhone or iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/everything-you-can-do-with-the-buttons-on-your-iphone-or-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/everything-you-can-do-with-the-buttons-on-your-iphone-or-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your iPhone and iPad each have several buttons, and you can do many things with them; some might even surprise you. This is the complete guide to using every button on iPad and iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Everything you can do with the buttons on your iPhone or iPad appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 16e Review: An iPhone That’s Good Enough for Most People</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-16e-review-an-iphone-thats-good-enough-for-most-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-16e-review-an-iphone-thats-good-enough-for-most-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 16e is not the best iPhone, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post iPhone 16e Review: An iPhone That’s Good Enough for Most People appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.K. asks to backdoor iCloud Backup encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m supposed to be finishing a wonky series on proof systems (here and here) and I promise I will do that this week. In the midst of this I’ve been a bit distracted by world events.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week the Washington Post published a bombshell story announcing that the U.K. had filed “technical capability notices” demanding that Apple modify the encryption used in their Advanced Data Protection (ADP) system for iCloud. For those who don’t know about ADP, it’s a system that enables full “end-to-end” encryption for iCloud backups, including photos and other data. This means that your backup data should be encrypted under your phone’s passcode — and critically, neither Apple nor hackers can access it. The U.K. request would secretly weaken that feature for at least some users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Heck Is Apple Doing With Its Hardware and Software? – Intego Mac Podcast, Episode 386</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-heck-is-apple-doing-with-its-hardware-and-software-intego-mac-podcast-episode-386/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-heck-is-apple-doing-with-its-hardware-and-software-intego-mac-podcast-episode-386/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s latest bevy of hardware releases feature processor upgrades and some processor naming confusion. The new iPhone 16e is Apple&amp;rsquo;s least expensive iPhone, and it just may be all the phone you need. And why do the new iPads not support Apple&amp;rsquo;s most advertised feature?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post What the Heck Is Apple Doing With Its Hardware and Software? – Intego Mac Podcast, Episode 386 appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Lock Apps on iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set your iPad into kiosk mode and pass it around without worrying about someone opening other apps or accessing unwanted content through an accessibility feature called Guided Access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Personal Note-Taking Assistant Is Just $39.99 for Life</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record, transcribe, summarize, and keep all your notes organized with this powerful app for Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of iOS Passcode Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-evolution-of-ios-passcode-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-evolution-of-ios-passcode-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/passcodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Apple has continuously refined its security mechanisms to deter unauthorized access to their devices. One of the most significant aspects of this evolution is the increasingly sophisticated passcode protection system in iOS devices. This article explores how the delay between failed passcode attempts has evolved over time, highlighting changes that have made iOS screen lock protection more secure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-stages&#34;&gt;Early Stages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of iOS, passcode attempts were practically unlimited. The delay between failed attempts would increase over time, but in extreme cases, the wait time could reach absurd numbers -sometimes even displaying “Next attempt in 100 million years.” There are plenty of screenshots of these exaggerated lockout periods available on the net.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
