<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ccas on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/ccas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ccas on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/ccas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Signing Certificates are being used by new BLISTER malware to avoid detection.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to researchers, evasive malware exploits valid code-signing certificates to evade security measures and deploy Cobalt Strike and BitRAT payloads through compromised systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elastic Security experts have dubbed the binary “Blister,” with malware samples that have zero to negligible detections on VirusTotal. At the time of writing, the infection vector, as well as the ultimate objectives of the intrusion, are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; One remarkable aspect of the attacks is that they rely on a valid code signing certificate issued by Sectigo. The malware has been observed to be signed by the certificate in question dating back to September 15, 2021. The company said that Elastic reached out to it to ensure that abused certificates were revoked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to recall an email in Outlook</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-recall-an-email-in-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-recall-an-email-in-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you made a mistake in an email and need to recall it, see how to unsend an email in Outlook.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why someone may want to recall an email, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a simple mistake, the wrong recipient, or something more serious, like leaking confidential data. Fortunately, Microsoft Outlook users need not fret on such an occasion as Outlook has a built-in and easy-to-use recall feature to help unsend emails. However, there are caveats to the process, so it is important to consider a few factors before taking advantage of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ON Log4j Vulnerability CISA, FBI, and NSA publish a joint advisory.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian, Canadian, New Zealand, U.S., and U.K. cyber security agencies released a joint advisory on Wednesday in response to the widespread exploitation of multiple vulnerabilities in Apache’s Log4j software library by malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“These vulnerabilities, especially Log4Shell, are severe,” the intelligence agencies stated in the new guidance. Cyber threat actors are actively scanning networks for vulnerabilities such as Log4Shell, CVE-2021-45046, and CVE-2021-45105. These vulnerabilities will likely be exploited over an extended period. Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) can be exploited by sending a specially crafted request to a vulnerable system that causes that system to execute arbitrary code. CVE-2021-45046, on the other hand, allows remote code execution in certain non-default configurations, while CVE-2021-45105 could be used by a remote attacker to cause a denial-of-service (DoS) condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remotely Controlled Vehicles Over Starlink</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/starboat_feat.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern remote control (RC) radios are capable of incredible range, but they’re still only made for line-of-sight use. What if you want to control a vehicle that’s 100s of kilometers away, or even on the other side of the planet? Cellular is an option, but is obviously limited by available infrastructure — good luck getting a cell signal in the middle of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what if you could beam your commands down from space? That’s what [Thingify] was looking to test when they put together an experimental RC boat using a Starlink Mini for communications. Physically, there was no question it would work on the boat. After all, it was small, light, and power-efficient enough. But would the network connection be up to the task of controlling the vehicle in real-time?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During early ground testing, the Mini version of the Starlink receiver worked very well. Despite being roughly 1/4 the size of its predecessor, the smaller unit met or exceeded its performance during benchmarks on bandwidth, latency, and signal strength. As expected, it also drew far less power: the Mini’s power consumption peaked at around 33 watts, compared to the monstrous 180 W for the larger receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the water, there was even more good news. The bandwidth was more than enough to run a high-resolution video feedback to the command center. Most of the time the boat was moving autonomously between waypoints, but when [Thingify] switched over to manual control, the latency was low enough that maneuvering wasn’t a problem. We wouldn’t recommend manually piloting a high-speed aircraft over Starlink, but for a boat that’s cruising along at 4 km/h, the lag didn’t even come into play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside? Starlink is a fairly expensive proposition; you’d need to have a pretty specific mission in mind to justify the cost. The Mini receiver currently costs $599 USD (though it occasionally goes on sale), and you’ll need at least a $50 per month plan to go with it. While this puts it out of the price range for recreational RC, [Thingify] notes that it’s not a bad deal if you’re looking to explore uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
