<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber-Crime on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-crime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyber-Crime on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detailed Guide to SOAR and SIEM</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is SOAR?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR stands for &lt;strong&gt;Security Orchestration, Automation, and Response&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a cybersecurity tool designed to simplify and enhance the efficiency of IT teams by automating responses to various security threats. With SOAR, organizations can customize workflows to meet their specific needs, allowing IT teams to save time, reduce manual effort, and focus on critical tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-features-of-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features of SOAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR connects multiple security tools into a unified system, enabling smoother workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding the Backbone of the Global Economy: OT/ICS Security in the Oil and Gas Industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oil and gas industry is an essential pillar of the global economy, enabling energy production, transportation, and storage that fuel every aspect of modern life. At the core of these operations lie Operational Technology (OT) and Industrial Control Systems (ICS), critical systems responsible for monitoring and controlling key industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the industry embraces digitization to improve efficiency and productivity, the reliance on OT/ICS has grown. However, this digital transformation comes at a cost—these systems have become prime targets for cyberattacks, with increasingly severe consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Technology &amp; National Security Reflection Series Paper 10: International Responsibility for Hacker-for-Hire Operations: The BellTrox Problem&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anmol Dhawan* About the Author: The author is a 2021 graduate of National Law University, Delhi. Editor’s Note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author’s contribution serves as an adapted reflection to the following […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Signing Certificates are being used by new BLISTER malware to avoid detection.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to researchers, evasive malware exploits valid code-signing certificates to evade security measures and deploy Cobalt Strike and BitRAT payloads through compromised systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elastic Security experts have dubbed the binary “Blister,” with malware samples that have zero to negligible detections on VirusTotal. At the time of writing, the infection vector, as well as the ultimate objectives of the intrusion, are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; One remarkable aspect of the attacks is that they rely on a valid code signing certificate issued by Sectigo. The malware has been observed to be signed by the certificate in question dating back to September 15, 2021. The company said that Elastic reached out to it to ensure that abused certificates were revoked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka Police arrests Turkish ATM hacker six months after escaping from Agartala</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Counter-Terrorism and Transnational Crime Unit apprehended Turkish national Hakan Zanburkan in Bangladesh on Tuesday. Agartala’s Govind Ballabh Pant (GBP) Hospital and Agartala Government Medical College (AGMC) were able to eject Hakan’s captive with the aid of the local folks from Tripura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several other members of an international ATM card cloning syndicate were also arrested in Bangladesh alongside him on Thursday, according to a police officer at Agartala. Agartala’s AGMC and GBP Hospitals had allowed the under-trial Hakan to escape through a window during a health check-up while security lapses existed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology and National Security Law Reflection Series Paper 5: Legality of Cyber Weapons Under International Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Siddharth Gautam* About the Author: The author is a 2020 graduate of National Law University, Delhi.  Editor’s note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author reflects upon the following question:  What are cyber weapons? […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from First Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Earlier this month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the proceedings of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, which has been tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Fourth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Last month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the Fourth Session of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Fourth Substantive Session (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction  In Part I of this two-part blog series, we provided our readers a brief overview and observations from the discussions pertaining to the second reading of the provisions on criminalisation of offences under the proposed convention during the Fourth Session of the Ad-hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we will […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week I of the Fifth Substantive Session.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction Last month from April 11-21, 2023, the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communications Technologies (ICTs) for Criminal Purpose held its Fifth Session in Vienna. As we reported earlier, the negotiating process has reached a pivotal stage, wherein the Member Countries […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week II of the Fifth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal In Part I of the two-part blog series, we briefed our readers on the developments that took place in the first week of the Fifth Session of the Ad-Hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we aim to capture the key discussion on provisions on (i) technical assistance, (ii) preventative measures, (iii) […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Anatomy of Cyber Enabled Crimes and their Governance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Digital systems and Information Communication Technology (ICT) play an increasingly central role in our lives. Technological advancement has created new opportunities for cybercriminals to exploit vulnerabilities in digital systems and networks. The resulting cybercrimes can affect everyone, from government and multinational corporations to individuals. As technology continues to make deeper inroads into our lives, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zloader Banking a new Malware attack can be bypass Microsoft Signature Verification.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ZLoader malware campaign is exploiting a nine-year-old flaw in Microsoft’s digital signature verification to steal credentials and sensitive information using remote monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Check Point Research, which has been tracking the sophisticated infection chain since November 2021, it has been attributed to a cybercriminal group dubbed MalSmoke, citing similarities with previous attacks. “The infection chain incorporates legitimate remote management software (RMM) to gain access to the target machine.” After injecting its payload into a signed DLL, the malware further evades the system’s defenses by exploiting Microsoft’s digital signature verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;SOC as a Service Market by Component, Service Type (Prevention, Detection, &amp; Incident Response),&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-as-a-service-market-by-component-service-type-prevention-detection-incident-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-as-a-service-market-by-component-service-type-prevention-detection-incident-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The SOC as a Service market place is actually projected to grow from USD 471 million in 2020 to USD 1,656 million by 2025, at a Compound Annual Growth Rate (CAGR) of 28.6 % throughout the forecast period. The escalating venture capital funding and increasing investments in SOC as a Service know-how to operate the market development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By component, services segment to develop at a greater cagr throughout the forecast period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare reports record-breaking HTTP-request DDoS attack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-reports-record-breaking-http-request-ddos-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-reports-record-breaking-http-request-ddos-attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare reports thwarting the largest known HTTP-request distributed denial of service attack in history, approximately three times larger than any other previously reported.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The attack in July reached 17.2 million requests per second, the company wrote in a blog post. For scale, the entirety of the Cloudflare network typically sees around 25 million requests per second in normal traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While that is the largest attack the company has recently seen of the type, Patrick Donahue, product manager at Cloudflare, told SC Media that the botnet behind it has broken previously reported records several times in just the last month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security Operation Center Guidelines for best practices SOC Design</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-security-operation-center-guidelines-for-best-practices-soc-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-security-operation-center-guidelines-for-best-practices-soc-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber Security is become most needed services for all business and industries in 2024. Every business is concerned about Cyber Security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security operations (SecOps) leaders face a multifaceted challenge: detecting elusive and novel threats using outdated tools, mitigating the risks posed by unexplored dark data, and managing the resource-intensive nature of staying ahead of evolving cyber threats, all while contending with a talent shortage in the field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to these challenges, organizations rely on Security Operations Centers (SOCs) as a cornerstone of their security strategy. A SOC serves as a centralized hub manned by dedicated experts equipped with a suite of sophisticated tools aimed at fortifying defenses against an array of threats. These experts employ proactive measures to identify and address system vulnerabilities, swiftly detecting, analyzing, and responding to potential threats in near real-time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft announces recipients of academic grants for AI research on combating phishing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day in the ever-changing technology landscape, we see boundaries shift as new ideas challenge the old status quo. This constant shift is observed in the increasingly sophisticated and connected tools, products, and services people and organizations use on a daily basis, but also in the security that needs to be built into these technologies to protect them against adversaries intent on abusing the same technologies for nefarious purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft, we are committed to harnessing the immense potential of AI to help solve many of our technology concerns today. We believe that working on the “bleeding edge” offers one of the best ways to serve our customers and the broader ecosystem, and AI is key to advancing our understanding and technical capabilities in many complex areas of cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a cyberattack?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-cyberattack&#34;&gt;What is a cyberattack?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks aim to damage or gain control or access to important documents and systems within a business or personal computer network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks are distributed by individuals or organizations for political, criminal, or personal intentions to destroy or gain access to classified information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of cyberattacks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Malware&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attack&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phishing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQL injection attacks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cross-site scripting (XSS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Botnets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using reliable software and a solid cyber strategy can lower the chances of a business or personal database being affected by a cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp, Facebook, Instagram server down in Pakistan?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whatsapp-facebook-instagram-server-down-in-pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whatsapp-facebook-instagram-server-down-in-pakistan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook-owned social media platforms, WhatsApp, Facebook, and Instagram are facing a worldwide outage, according to Downdetector, which offers real-time status and outage information for all kinds of services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.https://d-31038805491725975734.ampproject.net/2109102127000/frame.html&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downdetector showed that WhatsApp outage was reported at 8:23 pm (Pakistan Standard Time) and it shot up to 1,082 complaints by 8:38 pm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The website mentioned that the Instagram outage was reported first at 7:59 pm, while Facebook went down almost around the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube disrupted in Pakistan as former PM Imran Khan streams speech</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtube-disrupted-in-pakistan-as-former-pm-imran-khan-streams-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtube-disrupted-in-pakistan-as-former-pm-imran-khan-streams-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NetBlocks metrics confirm the disruption of YouTube on multiple internet providers in Pakistan on Sunday 21 August 2022. The disruption comes as former Prime Minister Imran Khan makes a live broadcast to the public, despite a ban issued by the Pakistan Electronic Media Regulatory Authority (PEMRA).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.cybercrimeswatch.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/youtube-banned-pakistan-2022-1024x1024.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Real-time network data show the disruption in effect on some but not all mobile and fixed-line internet providers in Pakistan during the live-streamed speech. Access was restored after the speech concluded. The study is taken from a sample size of 100 measurements from 14 vantage points across Pakistan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
