<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Company-and-Culture on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/company-and-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Company-and-Culture on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/company-and-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Named Gold Winner for Cloud Security in 2025 Globee Cybersecurity Awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-named-gold-winner-for-cloud-security-in-2025-globee-cybersecurity-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-named-gold-winner-for-cloud-security-in-2025-globee-cybersecurity-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Gold-Medal-Award-blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point is honored to be featured as a Gold Winner for Cloud Security in the 2025 Globee Cybersecurity Awards. Check Point’s CloudGuard platform distinguished itself for its preventive approach to cloud security, focusing on stopping cyber attacks before they infiltrate cloud environments in the first place. CloudGuard’s end-to-end suite of advanced cloud security solutions, including web application firewall (WAF), automated network security, cloud detection and response (CDR), and code security, enables organizations to enact a unique, AI-powered approach that prioritizes risk management and threat prevention, reducing overall risk profiles for organizations globally. The Globee® Awards for Cybersecurity spotlight the […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Software Collaborates with AppDirect to Offer Streamlined Cyber Security Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shifting-Paradigms-Cloud-Security-in-the-Post-Pandemic-Era-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security in the Post-Pandemic Era&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point Software and AppDirect, a B2B subscription commerce platform, have unveiled a strategic collaboration, allowing businesses to effortlessly obtain Check Point’s AI-powered cyber security solutions through the AppDirect marketplace. This partnership offers a unified procurement experience, ensuring more customers have access to the highest level of security they deserve. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, worldwide cyber attacks on organizations surged considerably in 2024. On average, organizations faced 1,673 attacks each week, marking a substantial 44% increase from the year before. As cyber attacks continue to escalate annually, it is crucial for every business to utilize advanced […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
