<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Comprehensive on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/comprehensive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Comprehensive on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/comprehensive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2024: Security, identity, and compliance recap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-security-identity-and-compliance-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-security-identity-and-compliance-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent 2024 was held in Las Vegas December 2–6, with over 54,000 attendees participating in more than 2,300 sessions and hands-on labs. The conference was a hub of innovation and learning hosted by AWS for the global cloud computing community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we cover on-demand sessions and major security, identity, and compliance announcements that were unveiled leading up to and during the conference. Whether you missed the event or want to revisit the key takeaways, we’ve compiled the essential information for you to provide a comprehensive overview of the latest developments in AWS security, identity, and compliance. This year’s event put best practices for zero trust, generative AI–driven security, identity, and access management, DevSecOps, network and infrastructure security, data protection, and threat detection and incident response at the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitwarden vs 1Password: Battle of the Best – Who Wins?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitwarden-vs-1password-battle-of-the-best-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitwarden-vs-1password-battle-of-the-best-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitwarden and 1Password are two of the top password managers. Find out which password manager is the best for you using this comprehensive comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build Your First AI Application Using LlamaIndex!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-your-first-ai-application-using-llamaindex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-your-first-ai-application-using-llamaindex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we will explore how to build a Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) application using LlamaIndex, an innovative framework to help you build large language model (LLM) powered applications. By the end of this guide, you will have a clear understanding of the components involved and a hands-on demo that will help you implement your own RAG application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;complexity-of-ai-application-development&#34;&gt;Complexity of AI Application Development&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Farticles%2Frrkl9n7yvob8hqo1f1mt.png&#34; alt=&#34;AI Application Development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building AI applications is inherently complex. It involves integrating multiple data sources, managing data flows, and ensuring that every component works seamlessly together. From data collection to model training, each step requires specialized knowledge and considerable effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Click Up Power BI Connector: Linking Project Management with Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/click-up-power-bi-connector-linking-project-management-with-data-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/click-up-power-bi-connector-linking-project-management-with-data-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-11-1024x564.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The integration of project management tools with data visualization platforms has become increasingly crucial. One of such integrations that’s garnering attention is the &lt;strong&gt;Click Up Power BI connector.&lt;/strong&gt; While Click Up provides excellent task and project management capabilities, integrating it with Power BI unlocks more advanced reporting, insights and visualization functionality to take effectiveness to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;powerful combination&lt;/strong&gt; allows businesses to transform their project data into actionable insights, enabling data-driven decision-making and improved project management.    &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerizing workloads on image mode for RHEL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous articles, we introduced bootable containers, discussed how to debug image mode for Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), which is built upon this new technology, and explained how to create CI/CD pipelines to automate the experience. In this article, we provide a comprehensive view of how you can manage workloads on image mode systems and set up a build pipeline to automate the experience of building, deploying, and managing Linux systems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debuginfod project update 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debuginfod-project-update-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debuginfod-project-update-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been five years since we first introduced &lt;code&gt;debuginfod&lt;/code&gt;, a tool for distributing debugging resources such as executables, debug information, and source files. Since then we have continued to improve &lt;code&gt;debuginfod&lt;/code&gt; as well as tools that make use of &lt;code&gt;debuginfod&lt;/code&gt;, such as GDB and Valgrind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article we&amp;rsquo;ll review some of the notable updates and enhancements to &lt;code&gt;debuginfod&lt;/code&gt; over the past year as well as the scale at which public &lt;code&gt;debuginfod&lt;/code&gt; servers are operating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating reduction of vulnerability classes: a key step in CISA’s “Secure by Design” pledge</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, securing software systems has never been more critical. Cyber threats continue to exploit systemic vulnerabilities in widely used technologies, leading to widespread damage and disruption. That said, the United States Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency (CISA) helped shape best practices for the technology industry with their Secure-by-Design pledge. Cloudflare signed this pledge on May 8, 2024, reinforcing our commitment to creating resilient systems where security is not just a feature, but a foundational principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical Patterns in Enterprise Ways of Working: Key Lessons from Industrial Revolutions Past</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a compelling keynote address at the 2024 Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit, Jon Smart, former head of ways of working at Barclays and author of &lt;em&gt;Sooner, Safer, Happier&lt;/em&gt;, revealed surprising parallels between historical management innovations and modern enterprise challenges. Drawing from extensive research spanning nearly two centuries of industrial evolution, Smart unveiled three critical patterns that continue to shape—and challenge—organizational effectiveness today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart’s presentation, based on his analysis of over 60 historical publications dating from 1776 to 1950, highlighted how modern organizations repeatedly struggle with lessons that were first learned during previous technological revolutions. His research, part of an upcoming book on the centuries-long evolution of working methods, demonstrates that despite technological advancement, core management principles remain remarkably consistent across eras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to implement IAM policy checks with Visual Studio Code and IAM Access Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-implement-iam-policy-checks-with-visual-studio-code-and-iam-access-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-implement-iam-policy-checks-with-visual-studio-code-and-iam-access-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous blog post, we introduced the IAM Access Analyzer custom policy check feature, which allows you to validate your policies against custom rules. Now we’re taking a step further and bringing these policy checks directly into your development environment with the AWS Toolkit for Visual Studio Code (VS Code).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we show how you can integrate IAM Access Analyzer custom policy check capability into VS Code, so you can identify overly permissive IAM policies and fine-tune access controls early in the development process. This proactive approach to security and compliance helps to ensure that your IAM policies are validated before they are deployed, reducing the risk of introducing misconfigurations or granting unintended access. It also saves developer time by providing fast feedback to developers when they write a policy that does not meet organizational standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Tailwind CSS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/learning-tailwind-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/learning-tailwind-css/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-tailwind-css-a-comprehensive-guide-for-beginners&#34;&gt;Learning Tailwind CSS: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tailwind-css&#34;&gt;What is Tailwind CSS?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tailwind CSS is a utility-first CSS framework that allows developers to create custom designs without having to leave their HTML. Unlike traditional CSS frameworks that offer pre-designed components and styles, Tailwind provides a comprehensive set of utility classes (small, single-purpose classes) that you can combine to build any design directly in your markup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of web development, CSS libraries or UI libraries are collections of pre-defined styles and components that help developers style their applications quickly and efficiently. Tailwind CSS distinguishes itself from these by encouraging a utility-first approach, making it exceptionally flexible and adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Password Breaking A to Z</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/passwords-az.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our blog features numerous articles on breaking passwords and accessing encrypted data, ranging from simple “how-to” guides to comprehensive manuals. However, many of the questions we are frequently asked are not about the technical stuff but rather the very basics of password recovery. Can you break that password? Is it legal? How much time do you think it will take to break this one? We do have the answers, but they require digging through the extensive content of our blog. To address this, we’ve created a comprehensive A to Z article that not only answers many common questions but also links to our previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ripple Effect of API Breaches: Analyzing Business Consequences and Mitigation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ripple-effect-of-api-breaches-analyzing-business-consequences-and-mitigation-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ripple-effect-of-api-breaches-analyzing-business-consequences-and-mitigation-strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses rely heavily on Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) for seamless communication and data exchange, the stakes have never been higher. API breaches can lead to significant vulnerabilities, affecting not only the targeted organization but also their customers and partners. Understanding the causes and consequences of these breaches is essential for any business operating in a connected world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://stateofsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Nodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nodes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nodes.jpg&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;High-profile incidents, such as the T-Mobile and Dropbox API breaches, have demonstrated the ripple effect these security lapses can have across various industries, from financial services to healthcare and e-commerce. The repercussions can be devastating, ranging from substantial financial losses to lasting damage to an organization’s reputation. As companies navigate this complex landscape, they must recognize that an API breach is much more than just a technical issue—it can alter the course of a business’s future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusted-relationship cyberattacks and their prevention</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to work with suppliers to reduce the risk of incidents related to supply-chain cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old saying, “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link”, directly applies to enterprise cybersecurity. Businesses these days often rely on dozens or even hundreds of suppliers and contractors, who, in turn, use the services and products of yet more contractors and suppliers. And when these chains involve not raw materials but complex IT products, ensuring their security becomes significantly more challenging. This fact is exploited by attackers, who compromise a link in the chain to reach its end — their main target. Accordingly, it’s essential for business leaders and the heads of IT and information security to understand the risks of supply-chain attacks in order to manage them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your data applications, contained and maintained</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-data-applications-contained-and-maintained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-data-applications-contained-and-maintained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-trusted-open-source-database-containers&#34;&gt;Introducing trusted open source database containers &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/canonical/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto,fl_sanitize,c_fill,w_2560,h_1440/https://ubuntu.com/wp-content/uploads/034c/Your-data-applications-no-button.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s time to stop proclaiming that “cloud native is the future”. Kubernetes has just celebrated its 10 year anniversary, and 76% of respondents to the latest CNCF Annual Survey reported that they have adopted cloud native technologies, like containers, for much or all of their production development and deployment. Cloud native isn’t the future – it’s here and now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data-intensive workloads are no exception. On the contrary, The Voice of Kubernetes Experts Report 2024 found that 97% of organizations are running data workloads on cloud native platforms, with 72% of databases and 67% of analytics services being run on Kubernetes. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detailed Guide to SOAR and SIEM</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is SOAR?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR stands for &lt;strong&gt;Security Orchestration, Automation, and Response&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a cybersecurity tool designed to simplify and enhance the efficiency of IT teams by automating responses to various security threats. With SOAR, organizations can customize workflows to meet their specific needs, allowing IT teams to save time, reduce manual effort, and focus on critical tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-features-of-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features of SOAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR connects multiple security tools into a unified system, enabling smoother workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Google Cloud is using devops in Monitoring and Observability?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-google-cloud-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-google-cloud-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-8-1024x589.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving world of cloud computing, the need for efficiency, speed, and reliability has never been greater. To address these needs, many companies have embraced &lt;strong&gt;DevOps&lt;/strong&gt;, a set of practices that combine development and operations teams to streamline the entire software delivery lifecycle. But while DevOps principles are critical to improving collaboration and accelerating development, they also demand effective tools for &lt;strong&gt;monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;observability&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the health and performance of applications at all stages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to write unit tests and E2E tests for NestJS applications</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-write-unit-tests-and-e2e-tests-for-nestjs-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-write-unit-tests-and-e2e-tests-for-nestjs-applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been writing unit tests and E2E tests for a NestJS project. This is my first time writing tests for a backend project, and I found the process different from my experience with frontend testing, making it challenging to begin. After looking at some examples, I have gained a clearer understanding of how to approach testing, so I plan to write an article to record and share my learning to help others who may be facing similar confusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding the Backbone of the Global Economy: OT/ICS Security in the Oil and Gas Industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oil and gas industry is an essential pillar of the global economy, enabling energy production, transportation, and storage that fuel every aspect of modern life. At the core of these operations lie Operational Technology (OT) and Industrial Control Systems (ICS), critical systems responsible for monitoring and controlling key industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the industry embraces digitization to improve efficiency and productivity, the reliance on OT/ICS has grown. However, this digital transformation comes at a cost—these systems have become prime targets for cyberattacks, with increasingly severe consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hollywood Sign is Not on Fire: Deepfakes Spread During L.A. Wildfires</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-hollywood-sign-is-not-on-fire-deepfakes-spread-during-l-a-wildfires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-hollywood-sign-is-not-on-fire-deepfakes-spread-during-l-a-wildfires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/300x200_Blog_Hollywoodd-300x200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amid the devastation of the Los Angeles County wildfires – scorching an area twice the size of Manhattan – McAfee threat researchers have identified and verified a rise in AI-generated deepfakes and misinformation, including startling but false images of the Hollywood sign engulfed in flames.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;debunking-the-myth-hollywood-sign-safe-amid-wildfire-rumors-on-social-media&#34;&gt;Debunking the Myth: Hollywood Sign Safe Amid Wildfire Rumors on Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Social media and local broadcast news have been flooded with deceptive images claiming the Hollywood sign is engulfed in flames, with many people alleging that the iconic landmark is “surrounded by fire.” &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How DevOps and devops can be implemented together?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-and-devops-can-be-implemented-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-and-devops-can-be-implemented-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-6-1024x580.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps is a set of practices that unifies software development (Dev) and IT operations (Ops), aiming to shorten the system development lifecycle and deliver high-quality software continuously. Implementing DevOps effectively within an organization can lead to faster delivery, more reliable products, and more efficient collaboration between teams. This article will provide a detailed guide on how DevOps can be implemented within an organization and how different approaches, such as incorporating &lt;strong&gt;DevOps best practices&lt;/strong&gt; alongside modern &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; and methodologies, work together for success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
