<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soc on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/soc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soc on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/soc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Medusa Ransomware Detection: The FBI, CISA &amp; Partners Warn of Increasing Attacks by Ransomware Developers and Affiliates Against Critical Infrastructure&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/medusa-ransomware-detection-the-fbi-cisa-partners-warn-of-increasing-attacks-by-ransomware-developers-and-affiliates-against-critical-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/medusa-ransomware-detection-the-fbi-cisa-partners-warn-of-increasing-attacks-by-ransomware-developers-and-affiliates-against-critical-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Medusa-Ransomware_1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Sophos, ransomware recovery costs soared to $2.73 million in 2024, displaying a 500% rise compared to 2023 and underscoring the escalating financial toll of cyberattacks. The FBI, CISA, and MS-ISAC have recently issued a joint advisory on Medusa ransomware, which has impacted over 300 victims across critical infrastructure sectors as of February 2025. Notably, Medusa ransomware is distinct from MedusaLocker and Medusa mobile malware iteration as per the research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-1001 Vulnerability in Medixant RadiAnt DICOM Viewer Enables Threat Actors to Perform Machine-in-the-Middle Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-1001-vulnerability-in-medixant-radiant-dicom-viewer-enables-threat-actors-to-perform-machine-in-the-middle-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-1001-vulnerability-in-medixant-radiant-dicom-viewer-enables-threat-actors-to-perform-machine-in-the-middle-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-1001-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new day, a new menace for cyber defenders. A novel vulnerability in Medixant RadiAnt DICOM Viewer—a popular PACS DICOM viewer for medical imaging—allows hackers to execute machine-in-the-middle (MitM) attacks. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitHub reports that by late 2024, an average of 115 CVEs were disclosed daily, with a 124% rise in cyberattacks exploiting vulnerabilities in Q3 2024. As a result, proactive detection of exploitations remains a top priority for cybersecurity teams worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-24201 Exploitation: Apple Fixes the WebKit Zero-Day Vulnerability Used in Sophisticated Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-24201-exploitation-apple-fixes-the-webkit-zero-day-vulnerability-used-in-sophisticated-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-24201-exploitation-apple-fixes-the-webkit-zero-day-vulnerability-used-in-sophisticated-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-24201_3-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CVE-2025-24201 Exploitation&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the exploitation attempts of the medium-severity vulnerability in Espressif ESP32 Bluetooth chips, leveraged in over 1 billion devices, another security issue in a widely popular product, a cross-platform browser engine, WebKit, poses an increasing threat to organizations and individual users worldwide. Tracked as CVE-2025-24201, the newly uncovered zero-day vulnerability is at risk of exploitation in highly sophisticated attacks with adversaries abusing specially crafted web content to escape the Web Content sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-25730 Vulnerability: Authorization Bypass in Motorola Mobility Droid Razr HD (Model XT926)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-25730-vulnerability-authorization-bypass-in-motorola-mobility-droid-razr-hd-model-xt926/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-25730-vulnerability-authorization-bypass-in-motorola-mobility-droid-razr-hd-model-xt926/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-25730-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CVE-2025-25730 Vulnerability&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the disclosure of CVE-2025-1001, a novel Medixant RadiAnt DICOM Viewer vulnerability, another security issue emerges in the cyber threat landscape. A newly identified flaw, CVE-2025-25730, affects the Mobility Droid Razr HD (Model XT926) and enables nearby unauthorized attackers to access USB debugging, potentially compromising the host device.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With cyber threats evolving at an alarming pace, GitHub reports that by late 2024, an average of 115 CVEs were disclosed daily, while 14% of breaches stemmed from vulnerability exploitation—nearly three times higher than in 2023, according to Verizon. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-27840: Vulnerability Exploitation in Espressif ESP32 Bluetooth Chips Can Lead to Unauthorized Access to Devices</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-27840-vulnerability-exploitation-in-espressif-esp32-bluetooth-chips-can-lead-to-unauthorized-access-to-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-27840-vulnerability-exploitation-in-espressif-esp32-bluetooth-chips-can-lead-to-unauthorized-access-to-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-27840-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CVE-2025-27840 Vulnerability Analysis&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the disclosure of an authorization bypass vulnerability in the Motorola Mobility Droid Razr HD (Model XT926), another major security flaw in a widely used product now threatens global organizations with unauthorized access and potential control over critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ESP32 microchip by Espressif, found in over 1 billion devices as of 2023, contains 29 undocumented HCI (Host Controller Interface) commands that pose security risks. The uncovered vulnerability, tracked as CVE-2025-27840, affects ESP32 Bluetooth chips and can potentially lead to attacks such as device spoofing, unauthorized data access, network pivoting, and persistent threats. Exploiting these hidden commands could compromise device integrity, risking unauthorized control over critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detect Hellсat Ransomware Attacks: New Ransomware-as-a-Service Threat Group Targeting а Variety of High-Profile Organizations Globally</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detect-hell%D1%81at-ransomware-attacks-new-ransomware-as-a-service-threat-group-targeting-%D0%B0-variety-of-high-profile-organizations-globally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detect-hell%D1%81at-ransomware-attacks-new-ransomware-as-a-service-threat-group-targeting-%D0%B0-variety-of-high-profile-organizations-globally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Hell%D1%81at-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware remains a top cybersecurity threat, with attack costs soaring to $2.73 million per incident, nearly $1 million higher than in 2023, according to Sophos. As ransomware operations grow in complexity, new threat groups continue to emerge, seeking massive financial gains. One such group is Hellcat, a newly identified Ransomware-as-a-Service (RaaS) threat group first spotted in late 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hellcat has quickly made a name for itself with high-profile intrusions across various industries, targeting critical national infrastructure, major corporations, and government entities. The group has already claimed responsibility for attacks on breaches at Schneider Electric, Telefónica, Pinger, and Israel’s Knesset. Last week, Orange Group confirmed a security breach in its Romanian operations after a Hellcat affiliate leaked thousands of internal files, including employee records.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation AkaiRyū Attacks Detection: China-Backed MirrorFace APT Targets Central European Diplomatic Institute Using ANEL Backdoor</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-akairyu-attacks-detection-china-backed-mirrorface-apt-targets-central-european-diplomatic-institute-using-anel-backdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-akairyu-attacks-detection-china-backed-mirrorface-apt-targets-central-european-diplomatic-institute-using-anel-backdoor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Operation-AkaiRyu%CC%84_v2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to ESET APT Activity Report Q2 2024-Q3 2024, China-linked threat groups dominate global APT campaigns, with MustangPanda responsible for 12% of activity during the observed quarters of 2024. Another nefarious China-backed APT group tracked as MirrorFace (aka Earth Kasha) has been observed expanding its geographical reach to target the diplomatic agency in the EU using ANEL backdoor. The offensive adversary campaign, which was uncovered in the late summer of 2024, came into the spotlight known as the AkaiRyū operation (Japanese for RedDragon).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC Prime Announces Referral Program for Individual Cyber Defenders</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-announces-referral-program-for-individual-cyber-defenders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-announces-referral-program-for-individual-cyber-defenders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Referral-Program-Goes-Live-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;invite-your-peers-get-20-off-soc-prime-platform-solo-subscriptions&#34;&gt;Invite Your Peers, Get 20% Off SOC Prime Platform Solo Subscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SOC Prime, we foster a strong cybersecurity community by connecting researchers, enterprises, MDR providers, and government organizations. Now, individual security researchers can unlock even more benefits of collaboration and networking through the SOC Prime referral program—sharing the platform with peers and earning exclusive rewards.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity is a collective effort. The strongest defense comes from working together, aligning with threat-informed defense to refine strategies using real-world intelligence and military-grade tactics. By leveraging open standards like MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK®, Sigma, and Roota, organizations gain transparency across tools and techniques, staying ahead of evolving threats. At SOC Prime, we make this process seamless and rewarding for security researchers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UAC-0200 Attack Detection: Cyber-Espionage Activity Targeting Defense Industry Sector and the Armed Forces of Ukraine Using DarkCrystal RAT</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uac-0200-attack-detection-cyber-espionage-activity-targeting-defense-industry-sector-and-the-armed-forces-of-ukraine-using-darkcrystal-rat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uac-0200-attack-detection-cyber-espionage-activity-targeting-defense-industry-sector-and-the-armed-forces-of-ukraine-using-darkcrystal-rat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/UAC-0200_CERT-UA_1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;UAC-0200 Attack Detection&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UAC-0200 hacking group resurfaces in the cyber threat arena. CERT-UA has recently identified a surge in targeted cyber-attacks both against employees of defense industry enterprises and individual members of the Armed Forces of Ukraine leveraging DarkCrystal RAT (DCRAT). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-uac-0200-attacks-covered-in-the-cert-ua14045-alert&#34;&gt;Detect UAC-0200 Attacks Covered in the CERT-UA#14045 Alert&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the latest UAC-0173 attacks leveraging DARKCRYSTAL RAT against Ukrainian notaries, a distinct threat actor – tracked with UAC-0200 identifier – relies on this malware, this time to target the Armed Forces of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncoder: Private Non-Agentic AI for Threat-Informed Detection Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncoder-private-non-agentic-ai-for-threat-informed-detection-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncoder-private-non-agentic-ai-for-threat-informed-detection-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Uncoder-AI-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Uncoder: Private Non-Agentic AI for Threat-Informed Detection Engineering&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOC Prime is excited to announce a major upgrade to Uncoder AI—an industry-first integrated development environment (IDE) and co-pilot for threat-informed detection engineering. The new release introduces a robust set of features designed to enhance how detection rules are created, translated, and optimized, acting as a game-changer for security teams to stay ahead in the evolving cybersecurity landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start Now&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past decade, detection engineering has evolved from a niche skill into a core function of cybersecurity, underscoring the growing demand for specialized expertise across a wide range of technologies. As organizations work to enhance their detection workflows and tackle the increasing complexity of cyber threats, AI and large language models (LLMs) are reshaping the landscape. Uncoder AI blends cutting-edge machine learning and automation with collective industry expertise, acting as a powerful co-pilot for security teams. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0411 Detection: russian Cybercrime Groups Rely on Zero-Day Vulnerability in 7-Zip to Target Ukrainian Organizations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0411-detection-russian-cybercrime-groups-rely-on-zero-day-vulnerability-in-7-zip-to-target-ukrainian-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0411-detection-russian-cybercrime-groups-rely-on-zero-day-vulnerability-in-7-zip-to-target-ukrainian-organizations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-0411-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since a full-scale invasion of Ukraine, cybercriminal groups of russian origin have relentlessly targeted the Ukrainian state bodies and business sectors for espionage and destruction. Recently, cybersecurity researchers uncovered a massive cyber-espionage campaign exploiting a 7-Zip zero-day vulnerability to deliver SmokeLoader malware. The campaign’s ultimate objective was cyber espionage, intensifying the digital frontlines of the ongoing war in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-cve-2025-0411-exploitation-attempts&#34;&gt;Detect CVE-2025-0411 Exploitation Attempts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The increasing volumes of cyber-espionage campaigns against Ukraine and its allies stand out as a significant aspect of the current cyber threat landscape. A recently uncovered large-scale operation further underscores this danger, exploiting a zero-day flaw in the open-source 7-Zip utility widely leveraged by global organizations. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-21293 Detection: PoC Exploit Released for a Privilege Escalation Vulnerability in Active Directory Domain Services</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-21293-detection-poc-exploit-released-for-a-privilege-escalation-vulnerability-in-active-directory-domain-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-21293-detection-poc-exploit-released-for-a-privilege-escalation-vulnerability-in-active-directory-domain-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-21293-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the critical zero-click OLE vulnerability in Microsoft Outlook (CVE-2025-21298), yet another dangerous security threat has come to light. A recently patched privilege escalation vulnerability affecting Active Directory Domain Services (CVE-2025-21293) has taken a dangerous turn. With a proof-of-concept (PoC) exploit now circulating publicly online, the risk of exploitation has significantly increased. This vulnerability opens the door for attackers to gain system-level privileges within an organization’s Active Directory environment, potentially compromising sensitive operations and data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lumma Stealer Detection: Sophisticated Campaign Using GitHub Infrastructure to Spread SectopRAT, Vidar, Cobeacon, and Other Types of Malware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lumma-stealer-detection-sophisticated-campaign-using-github-infrastructure-to-spread-sectoprat-vidar-cobeacon-and-other-types-of-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lumma-stealer-detection-sophisticated-campaign-using-github-infrastructure-to-spread-sectoprat-vidar-cobeacon-and-other-types-of-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Lumma-Stealer-Malware-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lumma Stealer Malware Detection&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lumma Stealer, nefarious info-stealing malware, resurfaces in the cyber threat arena. Defenders recently uncovered an advanced adversary campaign distributing Lumma Stealer through GitHub infrastructure along with other malware variants, including SectopRAT, Vidar, and Cobeacon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-lumma-stealer-sectoprat-vidar-cobeacon-deployed-via-github&#34;&gt;Detect Lumma Stealer, SectopRAT, Vidar, Cobeacon Deployed via GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lumma Stealer is a notorious data-stealing malware that extracts credentials, cryptocurrency wallets, system details, and files while connecting to adversary servers to enable further malicious actions. The latest campaign associated with Lumma Stealer’s GitHub-based delivery poses a growing threat to potentially affected organizations and individual users due to a set of sophisticated evasion techniques and offensive capabilities involving the deployment of other malware, such as SectopRAT, Vidar, and Cobeacon. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TorNet Backdoor Detection: An Ongoing Phishing Email Campaign Uses PureCrypter Malware to Drop Other Payloads</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tornet-backdoor-detection-an-ongoing-phishing-email-campaign-uses-purecrypter-malware-to-drop-other-payloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tornet-backdoor-detection-an-ongoing-phishing-email-campaign-uses-purecrypter-malware-to-drop-other-payloads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/TorNet-Backdoor-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TorNet Backdoor Detection&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Financially motivated hackers are behind an ongoing malicious campaign targeting Poland and Germany. These phishing attacks aim to deploy multiple payloads, including Agent Tesla, Snake Keylogger, and a novel backdoor dubbed TorNet, which is delivered via PureCrypter malware. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-tornet-backdoor&#34;&gt;Detect TorNet Backdoor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A significant rise in phishing campaigns, with a 202% increase in phishing messages over the second half of 2024, indicates that this attack vector continues to be a persistent threat. The emergence of a TorNet backdoor distributed via PureCrypter malware in an ongoing phishing campaign, which uses advanced detection evasion techniques, requires swift and proactive responses from defenders. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-8963, CVE-2024-9379, CVE-2024-8190, and CVE-2024-9380 Detection: CISA and FBI Warn Defenders of Two Exploit Chains Using Critical Ivanti CSA Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-8963-cve-2024-9379-cve-2024-8190-and-cve-2024-9380-detection-cisa-and-fbi-warn-defenders-of-two-exploit-chains-using-critical-ivanti-csa-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-8963-cve-2024-9379-cve-2024-8190-and-cve-2024-9380-detection-cisa-and-fbi-warn-defenders-of-two-exploit-chains-using-critical-ivanti-csa-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2024-8963-CVE-2024-9379-CVE-2024-8190-CVE-2024-9380-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Defenders shed light on a set of vulnerabilities in Ivanti Cloud Service Appliances (CSA) that can be chained for further exploitation. The latest joint alert by CISA and FBI notifies the global defender community of at least two exploit chains using Invanti vulnerabilities tracked as CVE-2024-8963, CVE-2024-9379, CVE-2024-8190, and CVE-2024-9380. Adversaries can take advantage of exploit chains weaponizing the flas to achieve initial access, execute RCE, steal credentials, and deploy malware on targeted networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-21298 Detection: Critical Zero-Click OLE Vulnerability in Microsoft Outlook Results in Remote Code Execution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-21298-detection-critical-zero-click-ole-vulnerability-in-microsoft-outlook-results-in-remote-code-execution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-21298-detection-critical-zero-click-ole-vulnerability-in-microsoft-outlook-results-in-remote-code-execution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2025-21298-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hard on the heels of the disclosure of a denial-of-service (DoS) vulnerability in Windows LDAP, known as CVE-2024-49113 aka LDAPNightmare, another highly critical vulnerability affecting Microsoft products comes to the scene. The recently patched Microsoft Outlook vulnerability tracked as CVE-2025-21298 poses significant email security risks by allowing attackers to perform RCE on Windows devices through a specially crafted email.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-cve-2025-21298-exploitation-attempts-with-free-sigma-rule-from-soc-prime&#34;&gt;Detect CVE-2025-21298 Exploitation Attempts with Free Sigma Rule from SOC Prime&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In January 2025 alone, 2,560 vulnerabilities have been identified, making the beginning of the year a particularly high-risk period due to the surge in vulnerabilities under active exploitation. Notable examples include CVE-2024-49112, CVE-2024-55591, and CVE-2024-49113. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers Exploit AnyDesk Impersonating CERT-UA to Launch Cyber-Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-anydesk-impersonating-cert-ua-to-launch-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-anydesk-impersonating-cert-ua-to-launch-cyber-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/AnyDesk-Misuse-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hackers Exploit AnyDesk Impersonating CERT-UA&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adversaries frequently leverage legitimate tools in their malicious campaigns. The popular AnyDesk remote utility has also been largely exploited by hackers for offensive purposes. Cyber defenders have unveiled the recent misuse of AnyDesk software to connect to targeted computers, masquerading the malicious efforts as CERT-UA activity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-cyber-attacks-exploiting-anydesk-based-on-cert-ua-research&#34;&gt;Detect Cyber-Attacks Exploiting AnyDesk Based on CERT-UA Research&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adversaries often exploit remote management tools for malicious purposes. For instance, the Remote Utilities software has been extensively used in offensive campaigns targeting Ukraine. The latest CERT-UA alert sheds light on the misuse of another legitimate remote access tool, AnyDesk, which lures victims into leveraging the compromised tool under the false claim of conducting a security audit. SOC Prime Platform for collective cyber defense curates a relevant set of detection algorithms that help security engineers define which hosts are used by AnyDesk to minimize the risks of intrusions. Since adversaries know AnyDesk IDs and attempt to connect to hosts impersonating CERT-UA, SOC Prime offers the relevant SOC content to detect these instances with the IDs, which are potentially the targets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-49113 Detection: Windows LDAP Denial-of-Service Vulnerability aka LDAPNightmare Exploited via a Publicly Available PoC</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-49113-detection-windows-ldap-denial-of-service-vulnerability-aka-ldapnightmare-exploited-via-a-publicly-available-poc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-49113-detection-windows-ldap-denial-of-service-vulnerability-aka-ldapnightmare-exploited-via-a-publicly-available-poc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2024-49113-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CVE-2024-49113 aka LDAPNightmare Detection&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the release of the first PoC exploit for a critical RCE vulnerability in the Windows LDAP, known as CVE-2024-49112, another vulnerability in the same software protocol in Windows environments is causing a stir. A discovery of CVE-2024-49113, a new denial-of-service (DoS) vulnerability, also known as LDAPNightmare, is hitting the headlines followed by the news of the release of its publicly accessible PoC. Once exploited, CVE-2024-49113 can disrupt the LDAP service, potentially causing service outages and enabling DoS attacks. Both CVE-2024-49112 and CVE-2024-49113 are considered critical due to LDAP’s broad use within Windows systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC Prime Threat Bounty Digest — December 2024 Results</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-threat-bounty-digest-december-2024-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-threat-bounty-digest-december-2024-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/December-2024_Threat-Bounty-Digest-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detection-content-creation-submission--release&#34;&gt;Detection Content Creation, Submission &amp;amp; Release&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December was another impressive month for the Threat Bounty Program, with the community showcasing a collaborative spirit and detection engineering skills.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the end-of-year hustle, Program members continued actively submitting detections to address emerging threats. In total, 33 new detection rules were successfully released to the SOC Prime Platform after being validated by the team of SOC Prime’s experts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ongoing-changes-and-program-enhancements&#34;&gt;Ongoing Changes and Program Enhancements&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting January 2025, we have temporarily suspended the acceptance of new Threat Bounty detections. While the &lt;strong&gt;Threat Bounty Program activities are on hold&lt;/strong&gt;, we are working on several enhancements to the SOC Prime Platform that aim to improve the overall experience for all users and extend opportunities for Threat Bounty Program members, including submission of content across different formats and additional ways to monetize your work. See details here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-55591 Detection: Critical Zero-Day Vulnerability in Fortinet FortiOS and FortiProxy Actively Exploited in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55591-detection-critical-zero-day-vulnerability-in-fortinet-fortios-and-fortiproxy-actively-exploited-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55591-detection-critical-zero-day-vulnerability-in-fortinet-fortios-and-fortiproxy-actively-exploited-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2024-55591-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, over 700 new vulnerabilities have been identified, continuing the trend of rising security risks for organizations worldwide. Among the most disturbing is CVE-2024-55591, an authentication bypass vulnerability affecting FortiOS and FortiProxy. This critical zero-day flaw exposes FortiGate firewall devices to potential compromise, allowing remote attackers to gain super-admin privileges on the affected systems. Fortinet has confirmed that the vulnerability is actively being exploited in the wild, requiring the immediate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detect Banshee Stealer: Stealthy Apple macOS Malware Evades Detection Using XProtect Encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detect-banshee-stealer-stealthy-apple-macos-malware-evades-detection-using-xprotect-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detect-banshee-stealer-stealthy-apple-macos-malware-evades-detection-using-xprotect-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Banshee-Stealer-1-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New year, new menaces for cyber defenders. Cybersecurity researchers have uncovered a novel variant of the notorious Banshee Stealer, which is increasingly targeting Apple users worldwide. This stealthy infostealer malware employs advanced evasion techniques, successfully slipping past detection by leveraging string encryption from Apple’s XProtect antivirus engine. Going exclusively after macOS users, Banshee is capable of stealing browser credentials, login data, cryptocurrency wallets, and other sensitive information from the files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOC Prime Launches Uncoder AI Solo: New Subscription Plan for Individual Security Experts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-launches-uncoder-ai-solo-new-subscription-plan-for-individual-security-experts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/soc-prime-launches-uncoder-ai-solo-new-subscription-plan-for-individual-security-experts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Uncoder-AI-Solo-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOC Prime announces the launch of Uncoder AI Solo, a new personal subscription plan designed for individual detection engineers, threat hunters, and cybersecurity researchers. Previously exclusive to corporate clients, Uncoder AI is now available to independent professionals via instant Stripe purchase. Subscribe today and enjoy 50% off an annual plan for your yearly Uncoder AI Solo access. Stay tuned and follow us for more exciting updates and upcoming announcements! &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGERBEE Malware Detection: New Backdoor Variant Targets Internet Service Providers and State Bodies in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Eagerbee-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the re-emergence of a more advanced NonEuclid RAT variant in the cyber threat arena, a novel malware iteration known as the Eagerbee backdoor poses an increasing threat to organizations in the Middle East, primarily targeting Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and state agencies. The enhanced EAGERBEE backdoor variant can deploy payloads, scan file systems, and execute command shells, displaying significant evolution of its offensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Message Queues vs. Streaming Systems: Key Differences and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/message-queues-vs-streaming-systems-key-differences-and-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/message-queues-vs-streaming-systems-key-differences-and-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-95-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of data processing and messaging systems, terms like “queue” and “streaming” often come up. While they may sound similar, they serve distinct purposes and can significantly impact how systems handle data. Let’s break down their differences in a straightforward way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-message-queues&#34;&gt;What Are Message Queues?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a coffee shop where customers place orders online or in person. Once an order is processed, the customer is notified to pick it up. In this analogy, orders function like messages in a queue, and the barista processes them one at a time, removing each order from the queue once completed. This is essentially how a message queue operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NonEuclid RAT Detection: Malware Enables Adversaries to Gain Unauthorized Remote Access and Control Over a Targeted System</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/noneuclid-rat-detection-malware-enables-adversaries-to-gain-unauthorized-remote-access-and-control-over-a-targeted-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/noneuclid-rat-detection-malware-enables-adversaries-to-gain-unauthorized-remote-access-and-control-over-a-targeted-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/NonEuclid-RAT-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modern-day cyber threat landscape is marked by the rise in malware variants that give attackers the green light to gain complete remote control over targeted systems, such as a nefarious Remcos RAT spread via a phishing attack vector. At the turn of January 2025, defenders unveiled an emerging stealthy malware dubbed NonEuclid RAT, which is enriched with sophisticated offensive capabilities, like advanced detection evasion techniques, privilege escalation, and ransomware encryption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Event Streaming in Apache Kafka?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-event-streaming-in-apache-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-event-streaming-in-apache-kafka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-101-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Event streaming is a powerful data processing paradigm where events—small, immutable pieces of data—are continuously produced, captured, and processed in real time. Apache Kafka, an open-source distributed event streaming platform, has become the go-to solution for implementing event streaming in modern systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-events-and-streams&#34;&gt;Understanding Events and Streams&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;event&lt;/strong&gt; is a record of an occurrence, such as a user clicking a button, a temperature sensor reporting a reading, or an e-commerce platform logging a purchase. These events are ingested and stored in Kafka as messages.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A &lt;strong&gt;stream&lt;/strong&gt; is an unbounded sequence of these events, organized into &lt;strong&gt;topics&lt;/strong&gt; in Kafka. Each topic serves as a logical channel for related events (e.g., a topic for user activity logs or financial transactions).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Dedication and Innovation: Highlights from SAFECode Day 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-dedication-and-innovation-highlights-from-safecode-day-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-dedication-and-innovation-highlights-from-safecode-day-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://safecode.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/SAFECode_Day_Email_header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 50 SAFECode members and industry leaders came together for a dynamic SAFECode Day 2024! The event featured exciting project updates, lively discussions, and an inspiring keynote from Anne Neuberger, Deputy Assistant to the President, who emphasized the crucial role of cybersecurity in today’s digital landscape. It was great to hear our members share their successes and ideas for enhancing software security. Here are some highlights from the event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>coalesce Function in Splunk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/coalesce-function-in-splunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/coalesce-function-in-splunk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-57-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Splunk &lt;code&gt;coalesce&lt;/code&gt; function returns the first non-null value among its arguments. It’s useful for normalizing data from different sources with varying field names.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, to unify multiple source IP fields into a single &lt;code&gt;src_ip&lt;/code&gt; field:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;| eval src_ip = coalesce(src_ip, sourceip, source_ip, sip, ip)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post coalesce Function in Splunk appeared first on SOC Prime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-49112 Detection: Zero-Click PoC Exploit for a Critical LDAP RCE Vulnerability Can Crush Unpatched Windows Servers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-49112-detection-zero-click-poc-exploit-for-a-critical-ldap-rce-vulnerability-can-crush-unpatched-windows-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-49112-detection-zero-click-poc-exploit-for-a-critical-ldap-rce-vulnerability-can-crush-unpatched-windows-servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/CVE-2024-49112-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2024, vulnerability exploitation accounted for 14% of breach entry points, marking a nearly threefold increase from the previous year—a trend that could persist into 2025. At the turn of January 2025, defenders released the first PoC exploit that can crash unpatched Windows Servers by leveraging a critical RCE vulnerability in the Windows Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) tracked as CVE-2024-49112.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detect-cve-2024-49112-exploitation-attempts&#34;&gt;Detect CVE-2024-49112 Exploitation Attempts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proactive vulnerability detection is expected to remain one of the top cybersecurity priorities in 2025. Security practitioners are increasingly seeking reliable sources of relevant detection content to identify potential threats in real time. The SOC Prime Platform addresses this need by providing the industry’s first CTI-enriched detection rule feed for both emerging and existing threats. Backed by a comprehensive product suite, the platform supports advanced threat detection, AI-powered detection engineering, and automated threat hunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elasticsearch: Cluster Status is RED</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/elasticsearch-cluster-status-is-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/elasticsearch-cluster-status-is-red/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-82-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It happens very rarely, but sometimes your cluster gets red status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Red status means that not only has the primary shard been lost but also that the replica has not been upgraded to primary in its place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as in the case of yellow status, you should not panic and start firing commands without finding out what is happening, as Elasticsearch has mechanisms that can restore the situation automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluentd: How to Use a Parser With Regular Expression (regexp)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fluentd-how-to-use-a-parser-with-regular-expression-regexp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fluentd-how-to-use-a-parser-with-regular-expression-regexp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Fluentd_regexp-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide explains configuring Fluentd to extract structured data from unstructured log messages using the parser plugin with a regular expression (regexp). If you need to extract specific fields, such as log_source and index, from a log message, you can do this as follows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Input Log:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#xA;{&#xA;  &amp;#34;message&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Log source &amp;#39;WinCollect DSM - SRV-AD-001&amp;#39; has stopped emitting events&amp;#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configuration:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filter **&amp;gt;&#xA;  @type parser&#xA;  key_name message&#xA;  reserve_data true&#xA;  &amp;lt;parse&amp;gt;&#xA;    @type regexp&#xA;    expression /&amp;#39;(?&amp;lt;log_source&amp;gt;[^&amp;#39;]+)s-s(?&amp;lt;index&amp;gt;[^&amp;#39;]+)&amp;#39;/&#xA;  &amp;lt;/parse&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/filter&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KRaft: Apache Kafka Without ZooKeeper</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kraft-apache-kafka-without-zookeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kraft-apache-kafka-without-zookeeper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-88-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apache Kafka has been a cornerstone of modern event streaming architectures, enabling reliable and scalable data pipelines for businesses worldwide. Traditionally, Kafka has relied on ZooKeeper for managing metadata, configurations, and cluster coordination. However, the introduction of &lt;strong&gt;KRaft&lt;/strong&gt; (Kafka Raft) marks a significant shift in Kafka’s architecture, eliminating the need for ZooKeeper and simplifying cluster management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/image-69-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-kraft&#34;&gt;What is KRaft?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KRaft stands for Kafka Raft, a new consensus protocol introduced to replace ZooKeeper. It leverages the Raft consensus algorithm to manage metadata and handle leader election natively within Kafka. This eliminates the dependency on an external coordination system, allowing Kafka to function as a self-contained system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigate the Executive Order 14028 Era of Software Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigate-the-executive-order-14028-era-of-software-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigate-the-executive-order-14028-era-of-software-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May 12, 2021 was a pivotal moment in cybersecurity history. The White House published Executive Order 14028 (EO 14028), a landmark document with an aggressive stance designed to advance the cybersecurity conversation1. While the document focuses on US federal government agencies and the companies that supply them, it’s a useful reference for those around the world who want to follow best practices in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the publication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Navigate the Executive Order 14028 Era of Software Security appeared first on SAFECode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New SAFECode Member Council to Ensure Greater Industry Collaboration on Software Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-safecode-member-council-to-ensure-greater-industry-collaboration-on-software-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-safecode-member-council-to-ensure-greater-industry-collaboration-on-software-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oracle’s John Heimann and Siemens Energy’s Manuel Ifland Elected to Lead the Member Council&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WAKEFIELD, Mass. – March 6, 2024 – SAFECode has announced a new Member Council to direct its industry-led efforts to advance software security practices. Chaired by John Heimann, Vice President of Security Program Management at Oracle, and Vice Chaired by Manuel Ifland, Principal Industrial Cybersecurity Consultant at Siemens Energy, the Member Council will manage operations for SAFECode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Joins SAFECode; Raytheon Accepts Board Seat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-joins-safecode-raytheon-accepts-board-seat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-joins-safecode-raytheon-accepts-board-seat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Members Work Together to Improve and Promote&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Effective Software Security Practices&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAKEFIELD, MA. – July 28, 2022&lt;/strong&gt; – The Software Assurance Forum for Excellence in Code (SAFECode) recently welcomed Oracle as an associate member and elevated Raytheon Technologies to a seat on the SAFECode Board of Directors as a charter member. Along with Oracle, other recent new associate members include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudyrion GmbH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imperva&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secure Code Warrior&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Siemens Energy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SAFECode is a non-profit, global industry forum where business leaders and technical experts come together to exchange insights and ideas on creating, improving, and promoting scalable and effective software security programs. Through its Technical Leadership Council and focused working groups, SAFECode members collaborate on ways to address today’s most pressing software security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Post-Quantum Cryptography: Key Takeaways from SAFECode’s Working Group</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/preparing-for-post-quantum-cryptography-key-takeaways-from-safecodes-working-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/preparing-for-post-quantum-cryptography-key-takeaways-from-safecodes-working-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As we mentioned in a previous blog&lt;/em&gt;_, SAFECode’s post-quantum cryptography (PQC) working group has reached a milestone. NIST has standardized its first wave of post-quantum encryption algorithms, and our working group has identified key activities that will enable our members to manage the transition to quantum-resistant cryptography and adapt to the emergence of new algorithms that may be standardized by NIST or other national agencies._&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of wrapping up the working group’s activities for now, working group members Judy Furlong of Dell and Brian Rosenberg of RTX presented a webinar for SAFECode members that shared valuable insights on how organizations can prepare for this crucial transition. The following is a brief summary of the webinar to complement&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;we released a few weeks ago.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rare Сommand in Splunk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rare-%D1%81ommand-in-splunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rare-%D1%81ommand-in-splunk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-84-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;rare&lt;/code&gt; command in Splunk helps you find the least common values in a specific field of your data. This is useful for spotting unusual or infrequent events. By default, the &lt;code&gt;rare&lt;/code&gt; command in Splunk returns the 10 least common values for a specified field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-rare-user-agents&#34;&gt;Find Rare User Agents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To identify the least common user agents in your web access logs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;index=web sourcetype=access_logs | rare user_agent &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This returns 10 of the least common user agents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Kafka Lag: Optimizing Kafka Performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-kafka-lag-optimizing-kafka-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-kafka-lag-optimizing-kafka-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-83-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apache Kafka is a powerful distributed messaging system, but like any system, it can face performance bottlenecks. One of the most common challenges is Kafka lag—the delay between producing and consuming messages. Addressing Kafka lag is crucial for maintaining real-time data pipelines and ensuring optimal performance. In this article, we explore practical strategies to reduce Kafka lag and achieve efficient message processing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-kafka-lag&#34;&gt;What is Kafka Lag?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kafka lag refers to the difference between the latest offset produced and the offset currently consumed by a consumer. It serves as a critical metric to measure how well a consumer group is keeping up with message production. High lag indicates delays in processing, which can disrupt real-time systems and lead to stale or outdated data insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search and Replace Text in SPL Fields with rex</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/search-and-replace-text-in-spl-fields-with-rex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/search-and-replace-text-in-spl-fields-with-rex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/v1-100-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when working with fields in SPL, it can be useful to search for and replace parts of text found in the field. Some reasons for doing this might be:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;– removing white space to reduce the size of the field&lt;br&gt;&#xA;– replacing field separators with characters that look nicer&lt;br&gt;&#xA;– rearranging values in a field in an order that is more appropriate (displaying names as first, last or last, first)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design? The U.S. Government and Requirements for Secure Development</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-by-design-the-u-s-government-and-requirements-for-secure-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-by-design-the-u-s-government-and-requirements-for-secure-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two months have seen the release of three new U.S. Government documents related to software security:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The National Cybersecurity Strategy released in early March covers the landscape of cybersecurity concerns and introduces the concept of shifting the liability for insecure software products and services from consumers to suppliers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In mid-April, The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) of the Department of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the National Security Agency, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and cybersecurity agencies of several other countries, released a paper titled “Shifting the Balance of Cybersecurity Risk: Principles and Approaches for Security-by-Design and -Default.”, which reinforced some aspects of the National Cybersecurity Strategy but also added additional requirements and expectations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And in late April, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and CISA released a “Secure Software Development Attestation Form” that organizations that supply software to the government will be required to complete.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These documents could have a significant impact on the operations of software developers that sell to the government, both in the near term and for the foreseeable future. In this blog, we’ll review some key points of each and discuss their relationship to each other, to the US Presidential Executive Order 14028 released in May 2021 on improving the nation’s cybersecurity, and to the NIST Secure Software Development Framework (SSDF). Then we’ll provide some SAFECode comments on the relationship among the documents, and recommendations on the way that the government should use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities to Support Code Integrity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-capabilities-to-support-code-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-capabilities-to-support-code-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Kelly FitzGerald, Raytheon Technologies; Altaz Valani, Security Compass; Elena Kravchenko, Imperva; Matthew Lyon, Dell Technologies; Ashwini Siddhi, Dell Technologies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our previous blog posts, we defined the code integrity problem statement and the basic principles of code integrity. As our series continues, we will define a framework of layered security capabilities to support code integrity. The framework is based on security capabilities that involve an intersection of tools, people, and processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strela Stealer Attack Detection: New Malware Variant Now Targets Ukraine Alongside Spain, Italy, and Germany</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/strela-stealer-attack-detection-new-malware-variant-now-targets-ukraine-alongside-spain-italy-and-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/strela-stealer-attack-detection-new-malware-variant-now-targets-ukraine-alongside-spain-italy-and-germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/STRELA-STEALER-3-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Strela Stealer Attack Detection&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security experts have uncovered a novel Strela Stealer campaign, which leverages a new iteration of email credential-stealing malware. In this campaign, the updated malware version is enriched with enhanced functionality and is now capable of gathering system configuration data via the “system info” utility. Moreover, Strela Stealer expanded its targets beyond Spain, Italy, and Germany to set eyes on Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;strela-stealer-attacks-detection&#34;&gt;Strela Stealer Attacks Detection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every day, approximately 560,000 new pieces of malware are detected, according to Statista. This highlights the ever-growing attack surface, which poses a significant challenge for cybersecurity defenders. To outscale cyber threats and detect malicious attacks on time, cyber defenders can rely on SOC Prime Platform offering a complete product suite for advanced threat detection and hunting. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PQC Algorithm FIPS are Published  – Now What?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-pqc-algorithm-fips-are-published-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-pqc-algorithm-fips-are-published-now-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Brian Rosenberg, RTX Corporation and Judith Furlong, Dell Technologies with Matthew Lyon, Dell Technologies; Steve Lipner, SAFECode&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We made it – this far! The U.S National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) recently published the Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) for three post-quantum cryptography (PQC) algorithms, marking the end of the beginning of the journey to quantum resiliency. In this blog post, we will briefly recap how we arrived at this point, take a quick look at the standardized algorithms, and point out a few areas of future work and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Executive Order 14028: Attestation and Software Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thoughts-on-executive-order-14028-attestation-and-software-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thoughts-on-executive-order-14028-attestation-and-software-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks, SAFECode has been discussing a number of government initiatives related to software security assurance. This is the first of several blogs that we will be publishing to share our perspective and recommendations for approaches that will help governments and other organizations gain confidence in the software that they acquire and use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the release of Executive Order (EO) 14028 in 2021, SAFECode has been tracking the U.S. Government’s plans and statements about how the portions of the EO dealing with secure software development and supply chain security would be put into action. This brief paper provides a SAFECode perspective on attestation that we believe will be important for software development organizations, end users, and government policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Modeling at Scale</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-modeling-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-modeling-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Threat Modeling Manifesto, Threat Modeling is an activity “for analyzing representations of a system to highlight concerns about security and privacy and if applicable, safety characteristics”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Threat modeling is a crucial activity of the secure development lifecycle (SDL) for identifying and mitigating weaknesses and potential security vulnerabilities. Threat modeling is most effective when performed as part of a Design Phase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the publication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Threat Modeling at Scale appeared first on SAFECode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Kafka as a Fast Correlation Engine</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-kafka-as-a-fast-correlation-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-kafka-as-a-fast-correlation-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Kafka-Streams-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we explore how Kafka Streams can be utilized for filtering and correlating events in real time, effectively transforming Kafka into a high-speed correlation engine. By leveraging the capabilities of &lt;strong&gt;ksqlDB&lt;/strong&gt;, you can deploy content rules and filter alerts directly within Kafka. This approach enables real-time filtration and aggregation of log event flows using an intuitive SQL-like language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;environment-setup&#34;&gt;Environment Setup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our environment includes the following components:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test Kafka Cluster&lt;/strong&gt;: A single-node Kafka cluster operating in KRaft mode (Kafka Raft Metadata mode). KRaft replaces the traditional ZooKeeper setup, simplifying Kafka’s architecture and improving operational efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kafka-UI&lt;/strong&gt;: A graphical user interface for managing and monitoring Kafka clusters. It allows easy visualization and manipulation of topics, schemas, and consumer groups.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ksqlDB Server&lt;/strong&gt;: This component enables real-time stream processing with SQL-like queries. It connects to the Kafka cluster, enabling filtering, transformation, and aggregation of streaming data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ksqlDB CLI&lt;/strong&gt;: A command-line interface for interacting with the ksqlDB server. It allows users to write and execute SQL-like queries, define streams, and interact with data programmatically.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our TEST environment:&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/kafka-test-environment.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
