<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ict on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/ict/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ict on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/ict/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 NIST rules on minimum password length: Aim for 16 characters or more!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta our focus is to keep our users&amp;rsquo; data secure with quantum-safe encryption. To achieve maximum security, the importance of strong, secure passwords that are long enough cannot be overstated. Passwords and the password length are the first line of defense to make sure that no unauthorized access can bring harm to your data or yourself. While factors like complexity and unpredictability matter, experts emphasize that length is a critical element in ensuring password security. But given new threats of quantum computers, what is the optimal minimum password length recommended by NIST and CISA?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous SOC Is a Journey, Not a Destination | Introducing The Autonomous SOC Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about autonomous SOC and how SentinelOne uses a maturity model to frame the shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The autonomous SOC: A well-grounded vision for the future of machine speed, AI-driven cyber defense, or nothing more than a pipe dream? Few concepts in modern security have been as polarizing, with sides painted as distinct camps of “believers” versus “non-believers”, each accompanied by increasingly hyperbolic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SentinelOne, you will hear us and our customers talk about the autonomous SOC and the fundamental shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations. Today, we want to be clear about what we mean when we say that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Influence Ops | Twisting Tales of Volt Typhoon at Home and Abroad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s CVERC attempts to attribute Volt Typhoon activities to the U.S., but the fact-free claims reveal much about the PRC&amp;rsquo;s real agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The latest CVERC report reflects China’s ongoing efforts to undermine support for U.S. surveillance activities by attempting to fuel debate over Section 702.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The CVERC report also draws Microsoft into its crosshairs as part of an ongoing push to remove foreign technology from PRC government systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The report highlights previous intelligence from France and Germany regarding U.S spying in an attempt to deflect attention away from recent incidents of Chinese espionage in Europe, likely as a means to shape narratives amid ongoing political debates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China’s Computer Virus Emergency Response Center has released part three of a running series claiming that the U.S. government is actually behind Volt Typhoon activity, rather than China. The latest CVERC report, whose front page includes an oddly edited photo with the text “Lie to Me,” provides no new evidence of these claims and rehashes old leaked U.S. intelligence documents. However, this CVERC report is not useless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Malware | A Threat Hunter’s Guide to Analysis, Techniques and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about cloud threats, how to hunt for them and how to analyze them in this post based on Alex Delamotte&amp;rsquo;s recent LABScon workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many researchers have noticed, malware in the cloud is different. Perhaps more strikingly different than Windows versus Linux threats, cloud services are targeted through entirely different methods altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At LABScon 2024, I gave a workshop Taxonomy in the Troposphere that outlines categories of cloud threats and how to approach analyzing and hunting them. The workshop structure highlighted three general sections to approach this problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term &lt;em&gt;real-world&lt;/em&gt; data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to learn quickly without needing to venture into the world of data cleaning, but real-world data has problems and is messy. Real-world data needs cleaning before it can give us useful insights, and that’s the subject of this blog post. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with internet addiction</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guten Morgen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Farticles%2Fwsjqfjhcbr5p8ysj2pdw.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Kitty stretchs&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wish I could know who drew the cover image. It&amp;rsquo;s very well done. Would suggest you to check out their work, but sadly not even I know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I wanted to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m going through. This is by no means an exhaustive research made alongside a mental health professional, and I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for anything that will be written here to be of any utility to anybody. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be that. It&amp;rsquo;s merely a blog post of someone who wishes to start 2025 in good spirits, avoiding the pitfalls, so that it becomes the professional it seeks to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPRK IT Workers | A Network of Active Front Companies and Their Links to China</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has identified multiple deceptive websites linked to businesses in China fronting for North Korea&amp;rsquo;s fake IT workers scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has identified unique characteristics of multiple websites, now seized by the US Government, associated with the DPRK IT Worker front companies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that DPRK actors seek to impersonate US based software and technology consulting businesses by copying the online brands of legitimate organizations, seeking to use these for financial objectives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has linked the activity to several active front companies and links these with high confidence to a larger set of organizations being created in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our findings link additional companies, which remain active today, to the DPRK IT Workers scheme.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North Korea operates a global network of IT workers, both as individuals and under front companies, to evade sanctions and generate revenue for the regime. These workers are highly skilled in areas like software development, mobile applications, blockchain, and cryptocurrency technologies. By posing as professionals from other countries using fake identities and forged credentials, they secure remote jobs and freelance contracts with businesses worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Reflection Series on CCG’s Technology and National Security Law and Policy Seminar Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, CCG-NLUD will commence the latest edition of its Seminar Course on Technology and National Security Law and Policy (“the Seminar Course”). The Seminar Course is offered to interested 4th and 5th year students who are enrolled in the B.A. LL.B. (Hons.) programme at the National Law University, Delhi. The course is set […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises – providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data – if paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Web-Based Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally published on Security Boulevard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-people-web-browsers-and-security&#34;&gt;Connecting People, Web Browsers and Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web browser has transformed significantly in recent years, becoming one of the most used tools for work today. However, as organizations adopt hybrid work models and cloud-based operations, securing this work tool has proved a challenge. Security infrastructures haven’t evolved as fast as the browser, making them prone to cyberattacks. With browsers being the primary gateway to the internet, any security lapse can lead to broad opportunities for significant data breaches and operational disruptions. Understanding the risks and implementing robust security measures is crucial for safeguarding the work we do today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Ventures Invests in poolside, Next Generation AI for Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S Ventures invests in poolside, one of the most watched and highest valued startups in generative AI for software engineering today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October 2024, SentinelOne’s venture arm, S Ventures, made a strategic investment in poolside as part of the AI assistive coding startup’s $500 million Series B round. It was one of S Ventures notable recent investments in generative AI (GenAI) start-ups following similar investments in leading foundational and enterprise LLM platforms such as Anthropic and Cohere, as well as Scale, a startup focused on the development and tooling layer of AI, and Galileo, a leading evaluation intelligence platform for AI teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing AWS Lambda | How Misconfigurations Can Lead to Lateral Movement</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how several misconfigurations and user-defined code issues in AWS Lambda could lead to potential credential theft and lateral movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As serverless computing continues to revolutionize the cloud landscape, AWS Lambda has emerged as a pivotal service, offering a Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) model that allows developers to focus solely on code while AWS manages the underlying infrastructure. This shift towards serverless architectures brings new security challenges and considerations that security researchers and professionals must understand and address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology and National Security Law Reflection Series Paper 5: Legality of Cyber Weapons Under International Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Siddharth Gautam* About the Author: The author is a 2020 graduate of National Law University, Delhi.  Editor’s note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author reflects upon the following question:  What are cyber weapons? […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
