<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bitbucket-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/bitbucket-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bitbucket-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/bitbucket-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing step failure strategies in Bitbucket Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-step-failure-strategies-in-bitbucket-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-step-failure-strategies-in-bitbucket-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce a new capability in Bitbucket Pipelines – Step Failure Strategies. This is the first of a set of new features allowing developers to implement more comprehensive logic and control-flow inside their CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Failure Strategies are designed to give you explicit control over how your pipeline behaves in the event that an individual step within the pipeline fails. This initial release will include the &lt;code&gt;ignore&lt;/code&gt; strategy, which is particularly useful for complex pipelines with steps like code styling suggestions or informational tests, where certain steps failing within the pipeline shouldn’t necessarily cause the entire build to fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quickly diagnose issues by viewing previous Pipeline runs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of a new capability in Bitbucket Pipelines that will improve your experience diagnosing issues with your pipeline runs, by allowing you to view and access previous runs within the Pipelines UI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://atlassianblog.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-1-600x491.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The previous pipeline &lt;strong&gt;Runs&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown will not show up if you re-run an entire pipeline, because re-running an entire pipeline creates an entirely separate pipeline record, rather than an additional run on an existing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
