<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From syslog to AWS Firehose: Dynatrace log management innovations that enhance observability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/BAE14229_RC_logs-consumption-blog_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;log management innovations&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding that the first mile of getting data in can often be the hardest, Dynatrace continues to invest in log ingest, offering a range of out-of-the-box solutions within the Dynatrace Platform and apps. We’re excited to announce several log management innovations, including native support for Syslog messages, seamless integration with AWS Firehose, an agentless approach using Kubernetes Platform Monitoring solution with Fluent Bit, a new out-of-the-box ingest dashboard, and OpenPipeline ingest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six causes of major software outages–And how to avoid them</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3d-abstract-beautiful-ba-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;software outages&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recent events have demonstrated, major software outages are an ever-present threat in our increasingly digital world. From business operations to personal communication, the reliance on software and cloud infrastructure is only increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outages can disrupt services, cause financial losses, and damage brand reputations. Understanding the causes of these outages is crucial for preventing them and ensuring smoother, more reliable tech operations. It’s also critical to have a strategy in place to address these outages, including both documented remediation processes and an observability platform to help you proactively identify and resolve issues to minimize customer and business impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “last mile” from credentials to employment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academic digital credentials — the cryptographically verifiable assertion that an individual holds a degree, certificate, or other credential — have been available for the better part of a decade. Yet despite the potential value of these data-rich, transportable credentials to graduates, employers, and academic institutions, digital credentials have by no means become the standard in presenting or verifying skills and qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new report from the Digital Credentials Consortium (DCC), housed at MIT Open Learning, explores this gap between the promise of digital credentials and their widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
