<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Passwords on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/passwords/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Passwords on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/passwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Secure Username</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-secure-username/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-secure-username/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how to create a unique and secure username for your online accounts, and find out why it’s just as important as having a strong password.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The First Password on the Internet&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-first-password-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-first-password-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was created in 1973 by Peter Kirstein:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So from the beginning I put password protection on my gateway. This had been done in such a way that even if UK users telephoned directly into the communications computer provided by Darpa in UCL, they would require a password.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact this was the first password on Arpanet. It proved invaluable in satisfying authorities on both sides of the Atlantic for the 15 years I ran the service ­ during which no security breach occurred over my link. I also put in place a system of governance that any UK users had to be approved by a committee which I chaired but which also had UK government and British Post Office representation&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSidesPDX CTF : SeaQuell</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsidespdx-ctf-seaquell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsidespdx-ctf-seaquell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category:&lt;/strong&gt; Web&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 200&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Our competitors at SeaQuell have uploaded their latest proprietary data to their employee area. We have already compromised their web developer and obtained the source code to their site, here: seaquell.py&#xA;&#xA;Host: a32fcd6eab2d811e784db0a6f99bb55a-829124630.eu-central-1.elb.amazonaws.com&#xA;&#xA;Port: 1589&#xA;&#xA;Seaquell.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The BSidesPDX organizers have made the source code for all of their challenges freely available so that you can run them at home and follow along. You can find more information here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Password Breaking A to Z</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/passwords-az.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our blog features numerous articles on breaking passwords and accessing encrypted data, ranging from simple “how-to” guides to comprehensive manuals. However, many of the questions we are frequently asked are not about the technical stuff but rather the very basics of password recovery. Can you break that password? Is it legal? How much time do you think it will take to break this one? We do have the answers, but they require digging through the extensive content of our blog. To address this, we’ve created a comprehensive A to Z article that not only answers many common questions but also links to our previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
