<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Harmony-Sase on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/harmony-sase/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Harmony-Sase on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/harmony-sase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Manufacturers Can Turn Security Into a Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-manufacturers-can-turn-security-into-a-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-manufacturers-can-turn-security-into-a-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/blog-manufacturers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digitization has significantly changed manufacturing over the past 25 years. The benefits include reducing inventory costs and machine downtime, and boosting throughput and forecasting accuracy. But as digitization has grown in prevalence, so have the security challenges facing manufacturers. This includes ransomware, legacy systems that are hard to patch, and third-party risk, among other types of threats. At the turn of the 21st century, production facilities were using software in various areas, but these systems were rarely integrated, and departments often operated in silos. Robotic assembly lines were already well established – primarily in the automotive industry – but were […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Software Collaborates with AppDirect to Offer Streamlined Cyber Security Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shifting-Paradigms-Cloud-Security-in-the-Post-Pandemic-Era-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security in the Post-Pandemic Era&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point Software and AppDirect, a B2B subscription commerce platform, have unveiled a strategic collaboration, allowing businesses to effortlessly obtain Check Point’s AI-powered cyber security solutions through the AppDirect marketplace. This partnership offers a unified procurement experience, ensuring more customers have access to the highest level of security they deserve. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, worldwide cyber attacks on organizations surged considerably in 2024. On average, organizations faced 1,673 attacks each week, marking a substantial 44% increase from the year before. As cyber attacks continue to escalate annually, it is crucial for every business to utilize advanced […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Organization from GenAI Risks with Harmony SASE</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/eliza1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love it or hate it, large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and other AI tools are reshaping the modern workplace. As AI becomes a critical part of daily work, establishing guardrails and deploying monitoring tools for these tools is critical. That’s where Check Point’s Harmony SASE comes in. We’ve already talked about Browser Security and the clipboard control feature to help define what types of information can’t be shared with LLMs. For monitoring these services, our GenAI Security service shows exactly which AI tools your team is using, who is using them, what kind of information they’re sharing with the […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuing to Pioneer Cyber Security Excellence and Shaping the Future</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shutterstock_2403416063-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a trusted leader in cyber security, Check Point proudly acknowledges its 2024 accolades from leading analysts and research firms. These accolades and recognitions showcase Check Point’s innovation and dedication to protecting the digital world and ensuring digital trust across networks, clouds, and endpoints. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, global attacks against organizations significantly increased in 2024, with organizations experiencing an average of 1,673 attacks weekly—a significant 44% rise compared to the previous year. This increase emphasizes the escalating complexity and frequency of cyber threats, making it crucial for organizations to implement comprehensive security solutions to safeguard […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
