<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eift on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/eift/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eift on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/eift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Implications of Apple’s “Stolen Device Protection”</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/forensic-implications-of-apples-stolen-device-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/forensic-implications-of-apples-stolen-device-protection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/passcodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the release of iOS 17.3, Apple introduced a new security feature called “Stolen Device Protection.” This functionality is designed to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive data in cases where a thief has gained knowledge of an iPhone’s passcode. While this feature significantly enhances security for end users, it simultaneously creates substantial obstacles for digital forensic experts, complicating lawful data extraction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-roadblock-to-logical-extraction&#34;&gt;A Roadblock to Logical Extraction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gaining access to data on Apple devices has historically been most feasible through standard mechanisms leveraged by many forensic tools, including iOS Forensic Toolkit, as part of an advanced logical extraction process. Alternative methods, such as low-level extraction, are either limited to older devices and iOS versions (currently, iOS 16.6.1 is the latest iOS build supported by iOS Forensic Toolkit) or legacy devices. Cloud-based analysis also presents challenges, as it requires full user credentials, and the device passcode is required on top of that to access end-to-end encrypted data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
