<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gitlab on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/gitlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gitlab on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/gitlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to harmonize Agile sprints with product roadmaps&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-harmonize-agile-sprints-with-product-roadmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-harmonize-agile-sprints-with-product-roadmaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture this: Product and Development teams are working in isolation. Product has created a 12-month roadmap and communicated it to internal stakeholders but didn&amp;rsquo;t review it with their development team. Dev starts building the features planned for the upcoming sprint without considering the broader product roadmap, leading to missed opportunities to optimize timing, like running projects in parallel, accounting for team capacity, or building reusable APIs that could serve multiple initiatives. The lack of coordination results in inefficiencies and delayed value delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to scan a full commit history to detect sensitive secrets&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-scan-a-full-commit-history-to-detect-sensitive-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-scan-a-full-commit-history-to-detect-sensitive-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Secrets left exposed in outdated repositories pose significant risk for data breaches. For example, a still-active secret key can be exposed, leaving it vulnerable to exploitation. Secrets include access keys, API tokens, private keys, and other sensitive values.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to use GitLab Secret Detection to scan a repository’s full commit history, including all branches, to detect sensitive secrets. In addition, you will discover how to view the results directly within the GitLab UI without the need for any integration. All it takes is just a couple of lines of code in your &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; pipeline file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tutorial: Security scanning in air-gapped environments&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-security-scanning-in-air-gapped-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-security-scanning-in-air-gapped-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air-gapped environments are computer networks or systems that are physically isolated from unsecured networks, such as the public internet or unsecured local area networks. This isolation is implemented as a security measure to protect sensitive data and critical systems from external cyber threats by providing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enhanced security: By physically isolating systems from external networks, air-gapped environments help prevent remote attacks, malware infections, and unauthorized data access. This is crucial for highly sensitive data and critical systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data protection: Air-gapping provides the strongest protection against data exfiltration since there&amp;rsquo;s no direct connection that attackers could use to steal information.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Critical infrastructure protection: For systems that control vital infrastructure (like power plants, water treatment facilities, or military systems), air-gapping helps prevent potentially catastrophic cyber attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compliance requirements: Many regulatory frameworks require air-gapping for certain types of sensitive data or critical systems, particularly in government, healthcare, and financial sectors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Malware protection: Without network connectivity, systems are protected from network-based malware infections and ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though air-gapped systems are isolated, they can still have vulnerabilities. Regular security scanning helps identify these weaknesses before they can be exploited. In this article, you will learn the different security scanners GitLab provides and how they can be added/updated in a limited-connectivity environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 tips for promoting your open source project</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-tips-for-promoting-your-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-tips-for-promoting-your-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three open source experts offer their advice on sharing open source projects with the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post 5 tips for promoting your open source project appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After months or years of hard work, you’ve just pushed your open source project to GitHub and made it public. Now it’s time to tell the world about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chances are you’d rather spend time writing code than getting the word out about your project. Maybe your project will go viral and you won’t have to spend much time on marketing. But chances are you’re going to need to do some work to build awareness, at least in the early days. Fortunately, there are plenty of people who have been down this path and are willing to help. In this article, experienced maintainers offer their advice on sharing open source projects with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot: The agent awakens</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-copilot-the-agent-awakens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-copilot-the-agent-awakens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introducing agent mode for GitHub Copilot in VS Code, announcing the general availability of Copilot Edits, and providing a first look at our SWE agent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Copilot: The agent awakens appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we introduced GitHub Copilot back in 2021, we had a clear goal: to make developers’ lives easier with an AI pair programmer that helps them write better code. The name reflects our belief that artificial intelligence (AI) isn’t replacing the developer. Instead, it’s always on their side. And like any good first officer, Copilot can also fly by itself: for example, when providing pull request feedback, autofixing security vulnerabilities, or brainstorming on how to implement an issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating cybersecurity threat detections with GitLab CI/CD&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-cybersecurity-threat-detections-with-gitlab-ci-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-cybersecurity-threat-detections-with-gitlab-ci-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post is the second post in a series about GitLab Universal Automated Response and Detection (GUARD).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Writing and deploying security threat detections in an organization’s security information event management platform (SIEM) is a critical component of a successful cybersecurity program. Moving from manual detection engineering to a fully automated process by implementing Detections as Code (DaC) ensures detection consistency, quality, auditing, and automated testing. At GitLab, we’ve embedded DaC capabilities into GUARD, our fully automated detection and response framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How GitLab uses prompt guardrails to help protect customers&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-uses-prompt-guardrails-to-help-protect-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-uses-prompt-guardrails-to-help-protect-customers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine introducing a powerful new AI tool that boosts your team&amp;rsquo;s productivity — accelerating code development, resolving issues faster, and streamlining workflows. The excitement is palpable, but questions about security and compliance quickly arise. How do you manage the risk of AI inadvertently exposing sensitive data or responding to malicious prompts? This is where prompt guardrails play a crucial role.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prompt guardrails are structured safeguards – combining instructions, filters, and context boundaries – designed to guide AI models toward secure and reliable responses. Think of them as safety rails on a bridge, working to keep data and interactions on the correct path while supporting your organization&amp;rsquo;s security protocols. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how GitLab implements these guardrails, the risks they address, and their importance for security-conscious enterprises and compliance-focused teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Improve AI security in GitLab with composite identities&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-ai-security-in-gitlab-with-composite-identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-ai-security-in-gitlab-with-composite-identities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) is quickly becoming the backbone of modern software development, fueling developer efficiency and accelerating innovation. With the emergence of AI agents implementing code based on instructions from humans, we are learning that implementing AI-based features has its own unique set of security challenges. &lt;strong&gt;How do we protect access to the resources AI needs, protect confidentiality, and avoid privilege escalation&lt;/strong&gt;? Few organizations are ready to answer these questions today. At GitLab, we are. We are introducing a new paradigm for identity management: composite identities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Improve security auditing with GitLab Operational Container Scanning&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-security-auditing-with-gitlab-operational-container-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-security-auditing-with-gitlab-operational-container-scanning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conducting security scans is a regular part of any software development process. Whether scanning source code (e.g., Java, Python, or other languages), configuration files (e.g., YAML files), or container images, these scanning tools help development teams be proactive about understanding and addressing security threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, developers run these security scans as part of CI/CD pipelines. By including these scans in CI/CD, every change to a project will be reviewed to see if any vulnerabilities are introduced. Understanding security concerns during development helps to assure that changes are addressed before they are deployed to a live environment, but there are many additional benefits to conducting container vulnerability scans post deployment as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The Co-Create Program: How customers are collaborating to build GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-co-create-program-how-customers-are-collaborating-to-build-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-co-create-program-how-customers-are-collaborating-to-build-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past year, over 800 community members have made more than 3,000 contributions to GitLab. These contributors include team members from global organizations like Thales and Scania, who are helping shape GitLab&amp;rsquo;s future through the Co-Create Program — GitLab&amp;rsquo;s collaborative development program where customers work directly with GitLab engineers to contribute meaningful features to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through workshops, pair programming sessions, and ongoing support, program participants get hands-on experience with GitLab&amp;rsquo;s architecture and codebase while solving issues or improving existing features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 steps to building a natural language search tool</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-steps-to-building-a-natural-language-search-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-steps-to-building-a-natural-language-search-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Empowering humanitarian action with open source: A natural language search tool for UN Resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post 4 steps to building a natural language search tool appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We have a problem. Our current search method for sifting through PDFs is extremely manual and time consuming. Is there an easier way?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, this is one of those questions that really gets me excited. I was tasked with finding a way to transform a cumbersome, archival process into an efficient, intuitive search experience. It’s a way to make a group of people’s lives easier, and because of the organizations they work for, help them be more effective in providing humanitarian assistance to people in need around the world. I couldn’t imagine a better project to be working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity researchers: Digital detectives in a connected world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-researchers-digital-detectives-in-a-connected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-researchers-digital-detectives-in-a-connected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the exciting world of cybersecurity research: what researchers do, essential skills, and actionable steps to begin your journey toward protecting the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cybersecurity researchers: Digital detectives in a connected world appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered yourself a detective at heart? Cybersecurity researchers are digital detectives, uncovering vulnerabilities before malicious actors exploit them. To succeed, they adopt the mindset of an attacker, thinking creatively to predict and outmaneuver threats. Their expertise ensures the internet remains a safer place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Deploy a server using Go with GitLab &#43; Google Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-server-using-go-with-gitlab-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-server-using-go-with-gitlab-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploying an application to the cloud often requires assistance from production or DevOps engineers. GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Google Cloud integration empowers developers to handle deployments independently. In this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to deploy a server to Google Cloud in less than 10 minutes using Go. Whether you’re a solo developer or part of a large team, this setup allows you to deploy applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;youll-learn-how-to&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a new project in GitLab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a Go server utilizing &lt;code&gt;main.go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the Google Cloud integration to create a Service account&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the Google Cloud integration to create Cloud Run via a merge request&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Access your newly deployed Go server&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clean up your environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Owner access on a Google Cloud Platform project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Working knowledge of Golang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Working knowledge of GitLab CI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-by-step-golang-server-deployment-to-google-cloud&#34;&gt;Step-by-step Golang server deployment to Google Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-a-new-blank-project-in-gitlab&#34;&gt;1. Create a new blank project in GitLab.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We decided to call our project &lt;code&gt;golang-cloud-run&lt;/code&gt; for simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;From code to production: A guide to continuous deployment with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-code-to-production-a-guide-to-continuous-deployment-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-code-to-production-a-guide-to-continuous-deployment-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuous deployment is a game-changing practice that enables teams to deliver value faster, with higher confidence. However, diving into advanced deployment workflows — such as GitOps, container orchestration with Kubernetes, or dynamic environments — can be intimidating for teams just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At GitLab, we&amp;rsquo;re committed to making delivery seamless and scalable. By enabling teams to focus on the fundamentals, we empower them to build a strong foundation that supports growth into more complex strategies over time. This guide provides essential steps to begin implementing continuous deployment with GitLab, laying the foundation for your long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Getting started with GitLab: How to import your projects to GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-import-your-projects-to-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-import-your-projects-to-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to our &amp;ldquo;Getting started with GitLab&amp;rdquo; series, where we help newcomers get familiar with the GitLab DevSecOps platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to import your projects to GitLab is an essential skill to make the most of the GitLab DevSecOps platform. You’ve set up your account, invited users, and organized them based on your use case or team structure. Now, you need to bring your existing projects into GitLab and start collaborating. These projects can be local files on your computer or hosted on a different source code management platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Secure, compliant, and AI-powered: Get to know 3 new GitLab features&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-compliant-and-ai-powered-get-to-know-3-new-gitlab-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-compliant-and-ai-powered-get-to-know-3-new-gitlab-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI capabilities are rapidly reshaping how teams build, secure, and deploy applications. As part of our ongoing commitment to helping you navigate the evolving marketplace, GitLab has introduced more than 440 improvements in the past three releases. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to spotlight three standout features making an immediate impact on how teams approach AI-powered DevSecOps. In addition, we announced we are partnering with AWS to launch GitLab Duo with Amazon Q, combining our strengths to transform software development. We&amp;rsquo;re creating an experience, together, that makes AI-powered development feel seamless and upholds the security, compliance, and reliability that enterprises require.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for making a tree view component accessible</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/considerations-for-making-a-tree-view-component-accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/considerations-for-making-a-tree-view-component-accessible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A deep dive on the work that went into making the component that powers repository and pull request file trees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Considerations for making a tree view component accessible appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tree views are a core part of the GitHub experience. You’ve encountered one if you’ve ever navigated through a repository’s file structure or reviewed a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/github-repo-browser.png?w=1024&amp;amp;resize=1024%2C653&#34; alt=&#34;Browsing files on Primer&amp;rsquo;s design repository. A tree view showing the repositories directory structure occupies a quarter of the screen. The other three quarters are taken up by the content of the content subdirectory. The tree view shows expanded and collapsed directories, as well as files nested at multiple levels of depth.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source AI is already finding its way into production</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-ai-is-already-finding-its-way-into-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-ai-is-already-finding-its-way-into-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open source AI models are in widespread use, enabling developers around the world to build custom AI solutions and host them where they choose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Open source AI is already finding its way into production appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source has long driven innovation and the adoption of cutting-edge technologies, from web interfaces to cloud-native computing. The same is true in the burgeoning field of open source artificial intelligence (AI). Open source AI models, and the tooling to build and use them, are multiplying, enabling developers around the world to build custom AI solutions and host them where they choose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New to open source? Here’s everything you need to get started</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-to-open-source-heres-everything-you-need-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-to-open-source-heres-everything-you-need-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our simple guide to finding projects, understanding guidelines, and making an impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post New to open source? Here’s everything you need to get started appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve heard about open source. You know it’s a great way to learn new skills, build up your resume, and give back to the developer community—but maybe you’re not sure where to begin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting involved in open source can raise all sorts of questions: Are there specific contribution guidelines? Or a certain level of involvement required before tackling issues? Don’t worry, we’ve got your back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated: Now in limited availability&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hosted-runners-for-gitlab-dedicated-now-in-limited-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hosted-runners-for-gitlab-dedicated-now-in-limited-availability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated, our single-tenant SaaS solution, have transitioned from beta to limited availability, marking a significant milestone in our commitment to simplifying CI/CD infrastructure management for our customers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;streamlined-cicd-infrastructure-management&#34;&gt;Streamlined CI/CD infrastructure management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing runner infrastructure has traditionally been a complex undertaking, requiring dedicated resources and expertise to maintain optimal performance. Hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated eliminates these challenges by providing a fully managed solution that handles all aspects of runner infrastructure. This allows your teams to focus on what matters most – building and deploying great software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How-to: GitLab Single Sign-on with SAML, SCIM, and Azure’s Entra ID&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-gitlab-single-sign-on-with-saml-scim-and-azures-entra-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-gitlab-single-sign-on-with-saml-scim-and-azures-entra-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase in size, it becomes increasingly difficult and critical to ensure that the right team members have access to the right groups and projects within their development platform. GitLab offers some powerful methods to manage user access, especially now with custom roles, but performing this at scale through a point-and-click user interface can be frustrating. However, all is not lost. You can use Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) and System for Cross-domain Identity Management (SCIM) as a solution. (There are moments where I’m grateful for acronyms.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attacks on Maven proxy repositories</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attacks-on-maven-proxy-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attacks-on-maven-proxy-repositories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how specially crafted artifacts can be used to attack Maven repository managers. This post describes PoC exploits that can lead to pre-auth remote code execution and poisoning of the local artifacts in Sonatype Nexus and JFrog Artifactory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Attacks on Maven proxy repositories appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As someone who’s been breaking the security of Java applications for many years, I was always curious about the supply chain attacks on Java libraries. In 2019, I accidentally discovered an arbitrary file read vulnerability on search.maven.org, a website that is closely tied to the Maven Central Repository. Maven Central is a place where most of the Java libraries are downloaded from and its security is paramount for all companies who develop in Java. If someone is able to infiltrate Maven Central and replace a popular library, they can get the key to the whole kingdom, as almost every large tech company uses Java.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to modernize legacy code with GitHub Copilot with real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Modernizing legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about legacy code—you know, the code that’s old enough to drive and definitely old enough to haunt your dreams. Maybe it’s a sprawling COBOL system or an early version of C++ written back when “Y2K” was a serious concern. Now, decades later, you’re being asked to “look into it” and modernize it (while wondering if you need to send a note to that person who retired a few years ago and may know how this thing works).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That’s a wrap: GitHub Innovation Graph in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thats-a-wrap-github-innovation-graph-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thats-a-wrap-github-innovation-graph-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the latest trends and insights on public software development activity on GitHub with the release of Q2 &amp;amp; Q3 2024 data for the Innovation Graph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post That’s a wrap: GitHub Innovation Graph in 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is our first GitHub Innovation Graph data release in 2025 and our first data release after celebrating the Innovation Graph’s first birthday, so we’d like to reflect a bit on how things have gone so far and share our hopes and dreams for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Guide to fulfilling SOC 2 security requirements with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-fulfilling-soc-2-security-requirements-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-fulfilling-soc-2-security-requirements-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For businesses that handle sensitive customer information, achieving SOC 2 (System and Organization Controls 2) compliance is not just a good practice — it&amp;rsquo;s often a necessity. SOC 2 is a rigorous auditing standard developed by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants that assesses a service organization&amp;rsquo;s controls related to security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While SOC 2 is not legally mandated, it has become increasingly important, in part due to breaches consistently seen in news headlines. Obtaining SOC 2 compliance allows customers to build trust with service organizations because they know their data is being properly stored and security controls have been assessed by a third party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Introducing GitLab Advanced Vulnerability Tracking&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlab-advanced-vulnerability-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlab-advanced-vulnerability-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DevSecOps streamlines software development by allowing teams to ship features quickly and providing short feedback cycles for customers. These short feedback cycles can be used to monitor the impact of a feature from the time it is shipped and to inform developers and product managers about the success or failure of a given deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab, as an agnostic DevSecOps platform, can act as an integration point for different CI/CD tools that often contribute to user-facing functionality. For example, the vulnerability report, which displays all detected vulnerabilities, is visible as a single functionality, but the data in the report may come from a number of different tools in various pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Secure and publish Python packages: A guide to CI integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-and-publish-python-packages-a-guide-to-ci-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-and-publish-python-packages-a-guide-to-ci-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supply chain security is a critical concern in software development. Organizations need to verify the authenticity and integrity of their software packages. This guide will show you how to implement a secure CI/CD pipeline for Python packages using GitLab CI, incorporating package signing and attestation using Sigstore&amp;rsquo;s Cosign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why sign and attest your Python packages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pipeline overview&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complete pipeline implementation: Setting up the environment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Environment configuration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configuration breakdown&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 6 stages&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tutorial: Advanced use case for GitLab Pipeline Execution Policies&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-advanced-use-case-for-gitlab-pipeline-execution-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-advanced-use-case-for-gitlab-pipeline-execution-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pipeline execution policies are a newer addition to the GitLab DevSecOps platform and a powerful mechanism to enforce CI/CD jobs across applicable projects. They enable platform engineering or security teams to inject jobs into developers’ YAML pipeline definition files, guaranteeing that certain CI/CD jobs will execute no matter what a developer defines in their `.gitlab-ci.yml` file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will explain how to utilize pipeline execution policies to create guardrails around the stages or jobs that a developer can use in their pipeline definition. In regulated environments, this may be necessary to ensure developers adhere to a standard set of jobs or stages in their GitLab pipeline. Any job or stage that a developer adds to their pipeline that does not adhere to a corporate standard will cause the pipeline to fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven years of open source: A more secure and diverse ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/seven-years-of-open-source-a-more-secure-and-diverse-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/seven-years-of-open-source-a-more-secure-and-diverse-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore insights into open source community growth, innovation, and inclusivity with an updated survey dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Seven years of open source: A more secure and diverse ecosystem appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seven years ago, we surveyed 5,500 open source contributors to understand the people who use, build, and maintain open source software. This year, we repeated the effort to understand how the open source ecosystem has evolved in the face of the seismic technological and social shifts we’ve seen since 2017. We received 8,400 responses from visitors to open source repositories, and we’re once again sharing the insights with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we evaluate AI models and LLMs for GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-evaluate-ai-models-and-llms-for-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-evaluate-ai-models-and-llms-for-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We share some of the GitHub Copilot team&amp;rsquo;s experience evaluating AI models, with a focus on our offline evaluations—the tests we run before making any change to our production environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How we evaluate AI models and LLMs for GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are so many AI models to choose from these days. From the proprietary foundation models of OpenAI, Google, and Anthropic to the smaller, more open options from the likes of Meta and Mistral. It’s tempting to hop immediately to the latest models. But just because a model is newer doesn’t mean it will perform better for your use case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting the next generation of developers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-the-next-generation-of-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-the-next-generation-of-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s your opportunity to empower the teen in your life to get a start in open source development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Supporting the next generation of developers appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe that software is at the center of human progress and that all software builds on the work of others, especially open source, through an interconnected community of developers. We need to level the playing field to spark innovation on a global level, and that includes helping early developers get the best start possible. We believe that all developers can solve problems, innovate, and create collaboratively through code. This is why we aspire to empower 1 billion individuals to become developers, and work to help break down barriers to entry for those who wish to join the field and participate in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;DevSecOps &#43; Agentic AI: Now on GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate on AWS&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devsecops-agentic-ai-now-on-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devsecops-agentic-ai-now-on-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the GitLab Duo with Amazon Q offering, previously shared at AWS 2024 re:Invent, is now available in Preview (Beta) for GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate users, at no additional cost. This milestone brings AI agentic experiences to organizations that maintain their own GitLab instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-this-mean-for-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-customers&#34;&gt;What does this mean for GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate customers?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beginning in our 17.8 release, GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate customers can now take advantage of the GitLab Duo with Amazon Q Preview (Beta) capabilities. There are three key experiences you will be able to access:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Google Cloud integrations for secure Cloud Run deployments at GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-cloud-integrations-for-secure-cloud-run-deployments-at-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-cloud-integrations-for-secure-cloud-run-deployments-at-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This tutorial is from a recent Arctiq, GitLab, and Google in-person workshop. The goal was to explore common security challenges faced by organizations as they journey to the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will help you learn about the Google Cloud integrations in GitLab. These features are meant to help accelerate and improve security of deployments to Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.ctfassets.net/r9o86ar0p03f/75hahkyZZ8T7tCKDuTZ4eI/6ba8dbc29e97c1440d201b5f9794075e/image2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google integrations list&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google Cloud project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appropriate IAM permissions for security, Artifact Registry, and Cloud Run usage. For this tutorial, ensure you have the &amp;ldquo;Owner&amp;rdquo; role with the aforementioned project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-workload-identity-federation&#34;&gt;Setting up Workload Identity Federation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this step, we configure GitLab to connect Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Workload Identity Federation to reduce the need for service accounts and let the two platforms use short-lived credentials on-demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What the Digital Operational Resilience Act means for banks&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-digital-operational-resilience-act-means-for-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-digital-operational-resilience-act-means-for-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developers play a critical role in ensuring banks remain competitive and compliant. One framework gaining significant attention is DORA. If you’re thinking of the DevOps Research and Assessment (DORA) metrics, this is something different. The Digital Operational Resilience Act is a new regulatory framework focused on safeguarding financial institutions against digital disruptions. For developers, understanding DORA regulations is not just a regulatory necessity; it’s an opportunity to drive innovation and enhance the overall stability of their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documenting and explaining legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/documenting-and-explaining-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/documenting-and-explaining-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to document and explain legacy code with GitHub Copilot with real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Documenting and explaining legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why did the developer bring a flashlight to the legacy codebase? Because every time they tried to refactor it, they found more bugs hiding in the dark corners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is, working with legacy code can also be bad—worse than that joke even! Whether you’ve inherited a decades-old codebase or are revisiting your own past work, working with a legacy codebase can be a time-consuming and overwhelming process—especially if there’s no documentation. Having well-documented code, legacy or otherwise, is critical for maintaining software quality and informing future development work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Availability Report: December 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-december-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-december-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Availability Report: December 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 17 14:17 UTC (lasting 17 minutes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On December 17, 2024, between 14:33 UTC and 14:50 UTC, users experienced intermittent errors and timeouts when accessing github.com. The error rate was 8.5% on average and peaked at 44.3% of requests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-built-the-github-skyline-cli-extension-using-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-built-the-github-skyline-cli-extension-using-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub uses GitHub to build GitHub, and our CLI extensions are no exception. Read on to find out how we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December 2024, we announced gh-skyline, a GitHub CLI extension that allows our developer community to generate a 3D version of their GitHub Contribution Graph into an STL file ready for printing on a 3D printer, just in time to capture all of those contributions!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Deploy a NodeJS Express app with GitLab&#39;s Cloud Run integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-nodejs-express-app-with-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-nodejs-express-app-with-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking to deploy your NodeJS app to Google Cloud with the least maintenance possible? This tutorial will show you how to utilize GitLab’s Google Cloud integration to deploy your NodeJS app in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, deploying an application often requires assistance from production or DevOps engineers. This integration now empowers developers to handle deployments independently. Whether you’re a solo developer or part of a large team, this setup gives everyone the ability to deploy their applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Getting started with GitLab: How to manage users&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-manage-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-manage-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to our &amp;ldquo;Getting started with GitLab&amp;rdquo; series, where we help newcomers get familiar with the GitLab DevSecOps platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensuring a safe, compliant, and collaborative environment starts with the most basic of tasks - managing users. In this tutorial, we show you how to establish project members, assign roles and permissions, and create groups and subgroups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: To follow along with this tutorial, you should have a GitLab account either through GitLab.com or your organization&amp;rsquo;s self-managed instance. If you need help, visit our fundamentals area on GitLab University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git security vulnerabilities announced</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-security-vulnerabilities-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-security-vulnerabilities-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new set of Git releases were published to address a variety of security vulnerabilities. All users are encouraged to upgrade. Take a look at GitHub’s view of the latest round of releases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Git security vulnerabilities announced appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, the Git project released new versions to address a pair of security vulnerabilities, CVE-2024-50349 and CVE-2024-52006, that affect all prior versions of Git.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cve-2024-50349&#34;&gt;CVE-2024-50349&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Git needs to fill in credentials interactively without the use of a credential helper, it prints out the hostname and asks the user to fill in the appropriate username/password pair for that host. However, Git prints out the hostname after URL-decoding it. This allows an attacker to craft URLs containing ANSI escape sequences that may be used to construct an intentionally misleading prompt. The attacker may then tweak the prompt to trick a user into providing credentials for a different Git host back to the attacker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What’s new in Git 2.48.0?&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-48-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-48-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Git project recently released Git 2.48.0. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a few notable highlights from this release, which includes contributions from GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Git team and the wider Git community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meson-build-system&#34;&gt;Meson build system&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, Git could be built using either a Makefile-based build system or an Autoconf-based build system. Git developers have been using mostly the Makefile-based build system, so the Autoconf-based build system has lagged behind in features and maintenance. Another issue was that a lot of Windows developers use integrated development environments (IDEs) that don’t have good support for Makefile- and Autoconf-based build systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Off 2024 winners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/game-off-2024-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/game-off-2024-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Secrets spilled, discovered, and hidden again—Game Off 2024 brought over 500 jaw-dropping submissions that redefined creativity in gaming. From cult quests for free furniture to spellbinding mysteries, these games will have you hooked. Ready to uncover the winners?!?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Game Off 2024 winners appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another year, another incredible GitHub Game Off—and this one was &lt;em&gt;secrets&lt;/em&gt;-ational! With over 500 submissions, participants turned the theme of “secrets” into an extraordinary showcase of creativity, humor, and mind-boggling mechanics. Over the course of a month, developers not only built games but also dove into each other’s creations, reviewing, rating, and leaving comments that ranged from “This is genius!” to “I laughed so hard I fell out of my chair.” From mind-erasing gadgets to cult quests for free furniture, these games had it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Git 2.48</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-48/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.48. Here is GitHub&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the most interesting features and changes introduced since last time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Highlights from Git 2.48 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.48 with features and bug fixes from over 93 contributors, 35 of them new. We last caught up with you on the latest in Git back when 2.47 was released.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab supports banks in navigating regulatory challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-supports-banks-in-navigating-regulatory-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-supports-banks-in-navigating-regulatory-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The risk of cyber attacks in the banking industry has reached unprecedented levels. Studies by the International Monetary Fund reveal that the financial sector is particularly vulnerable to cyber threats, with nearly one-fifth of reported incidents in the past two decades targeting this industry alone. As these threats continue to escalate, they drive the need for a regulatory response, prompting the banking and financial services industry to prepare for significant changes. GitLab enables financial institutions to proactively tackle these challenges, supporting banks on their regulatory journey while ensuring the operational resilience needed to protect the sensitive data pervasive throughout the banking ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to secure your GitHub Actions workflows with CodeQL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-github-actions-workflows-with-codeql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-github-actions-workflows-with-codeql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we secured 75+ GitHub Actions workflows in open source projects, disclosing 90+ different vulnerabilities. Out of this research we produced new support for workflows in CodeQL, empowering you to secure yours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to secure your GitHub Actions workflows with CodeQL appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we secured more than 75 GitHub Actions workflows in open source projects, disclosing more than 90 different vulnerabilities. Out of this research, we produced new support for workflows in CodeQL, empowering you to secure yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Reduce supply chain risk with smarter vulnerability prioritization&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reduce-supply-chain-risk-with-smarter-vulnerability-prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reduce-supply-chain-risk-with-smarter-vulnerability-prioritization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Application Security teams face a constant uphill battle in risk reduction due to the ever-growing number of vulnerabilities. This year alone, 36,000 Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) have been reported — a 25% increase from last year. The sharp rise intensifies the challenge of prioritization in vulnerability management, especially for lean AppSec teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To help, we’ve introduced several new enhancements to our Software Composition Analysis (SCA) solution. These improvements are available for all GitLab Ultimate customers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Streamline the path to CMMC Level 2 compliance with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-the-path-to-cmmc-level-2-compliance-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-the-path-to-cmmc-level-2-compliance-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification (CMMC) Program is a framework developed by the U.S. Department of Defense (DoD) to enforce cybersecurity requirements and protect sensitive unclassified information shared by the DoD with contractors and subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the release of the CMMC final rule, DoD contractors can begin to assess and align their controls and processes to be compliant with CMMC’s requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explains how GitLab customers can leverage the GitLab platform to help satisfy relevant NIST SP 800-171 R2 requirements to achieve CMMC Level 2 compliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building LATAM’s future tech workforce with AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-latams-future-tech-workforce-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-latams-future-tech-workforce-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git Commit 2024 and our new AI course in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Building LATAM’s future tech workforce with AI appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read this post in Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estamos emocionados de celebrar el tercer año de Git Commit, nuestro programa anual dedicado a cerrar la brecha de habilidades tecnológicas y empoderar a estudiantes de todo el país. Este año, también nos enorgullece lanzar Git Commit 101, nuestro primer curso gratuito de IA en línea en español, disponible para estudiantes y educadores durante todo el año.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab&#39;s 2024 bug bounty year in review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlabs-2024-bug-bounty-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlabs-2024-bug-bounty-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s that time again when everyone reflects on the year that just passed, and the Application Security team at GitLab is no different. We run the bug bounty program at GitLab, and every year we summarize our stats for those who are curious. We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where we are without the collaboration of our bug bounty community, and we consider these awards hugely beneficial and money well spent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-bug-bounty-program-by-the-numbers&#34;&gt;GitLab Bug Bounty Program by the numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Awarded over US$1 million in bounties across 275 valid reports.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Received a total of 1,440 reports from 457 researchers in 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our busiest month was July, when we paid out over US$193,000!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Data is accurate as of 31st of December, 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Ultimate guide to CI/CD: Fundamentals to advanced implementation&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ultimate-guide-to-ci-cd-fundamentals-to-advanced-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ultimate-guide-to-ci-cd-fundamentals-to-advanced-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) has revolutionized how software teams create value for their users. Gone are the days of manual deployments and integration headaches — modern development demands automation, reliability, and speed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its core, CI/CD is about creating a seamless pipeline that takes code from a developer&amp;rsquo;s environment all the way to production and incorporates feedback in real time. CI helps teams catch issues early — before they become costly problems — by ensuring that code changes are frequently merged into a shared repository, automatically tested, and validated. CD extends this by automating the deployment process, making releases predictable and stress-free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitBleed – Finding Secrets in Mirrored Git Repositories – CVE-2022-24975</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitbleed-finding-secrets-in-mirrored-git-repositories-cve-2022-24975/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitbleed-finding-secrets-in-mirrored-git-repositories-cve-2022-24975/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to a discrepancy in Git behavior, partial parts of a source code repository are visible when making copies via the “git clone” command. There are additional parts of the repository that only become visible when using the “–mirror” option. This can lead to secrets being exposed via git repositories when not removed properly, and a false sense of security when repositories are scanned for secrets against a cloned, non-mirrored copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;3 signs your team is ready to uplevel security controls in GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-signs-your-team-is-ready-to-uplevel-security-controls-in-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-signs-your-team-is-ready-to-uplevel-security-controls-in-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most teams start with basic security practices, such as branch protection and simple access controls. But, there&amp;rsquo;s often a moment when teams realize they need more. It could be when they land their first enterprise client, when they start handling sensitive data, or when they experience their first security incident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure whether you’re ready to upgrade your security, here are a few signs you’ve outgrown your security needs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;5 GitLab Premium features to help your team scale&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-gitlab-premium-features-to-help-your-team-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-gitlab-premium-features-to-help-your-team-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As development teams grow, what once worked for a small team often becomes a bottleneck. Code standards become inconsistent, operational silos develop, and technical debt accumulates faster. What was a well-oiled machine is now dysfunctional as more team members, projects, and tools are added on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many teams experience these challenges as they grow, but how you handle and address these growing pains can save you time, energy, and money in the long run. In this article, we’ll explore the common pitfalls growing teams face and how successful organizations address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Ask a hacker: A conversation with ahacker1&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ask-a-hacker-a-conversation-with-ahacker1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ask-a-hacker-a-conversation-with-ahacker1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At GitLab we have a tradition: Every year, we invite a bug bounty hunter to join us for an AMA. This year, we met with Alexander Siyou Tan, also known as ahacker1, and did a deep dive into all aspects of bug bounty hunting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-alexander-ahacker1&#34;&gt;About Alexander (ahacker1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexander is passionate about hacking complex SaaS applications, with a particular interest in authorization-based vulnerabilities. Currently, he&amp;rsquo;s focusing on SAML and SSO research. His hacking journey began during the Covid-19 pandemic, when he transitioned from gaming to exploring game hacks and easter eggs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating with GitLab Duo, Part 2: Complex testing&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-2-complex-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-2-complex-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of our three-part series on test generation with GitLab Duo focused on how to automate code testing. Now, we will share the lessons we learned while using AI for test generation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;situations-we-encountered-and-how-we-handled-them&#34;&gt;Situations we encountered and how we handled them&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, we were pleased with the results using GitLab Duo to generate tests on our code. As is the case with any language generation, some cases required minor adjustments such as fixing import paths or editing contents in datasets. For the more complex cases, we had to remember that AI solutions often lack context. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we handled the more complex testing situations with GitLab Duo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating with GitLab Duo, Part 3: Validating testing&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-3-validating-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-3-validating-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous entries in this series, we covered how we used GitLab Duo to generate tests for our code as well as what we learned while using GitLab Duo for generating automated tests. We also shared some of the ways we addressed making changes to GitLab Duo generated tests. This last article in the series will cover a test we ran to validate the impact of GitLab Duo on our team’s automated testing and discuss the impressive results we have achieved thus far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Git command line on Windows with Git Bash&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-command-line-on-windows-with-git-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-command-line-on-windows-with-git-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git commands allow developers to manage different versions of code and collaborate as a team. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a Windows environment, you may have heard of Git Bash, a Bash terminal emulator that includes a Windows-friendly version of Git. Discover everything you need to know about installing Git Bash in this guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-git-bash-work&#34;&gt;How does Git Bash work?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git Bash is an application that you can install on Windows operating systems using Git for Windows. This application acts as an emulator to use the Git version control tool on a Bash command terminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab Duo with Amazon Q: DevSecOps meets agentic AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-with-amazon-q-devsecops-meets-agentic-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-with-amazon-q-devsecops-meets-agentic-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce GitLab Duo with Amazon Q, a joint offering that brings together GitLab&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive AI-powered DevSecOps platform with Amazon Q&amp;rsquo;s autonomous AI agents in a single, integrated solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab Duo with Amazon Q transforms software development by integrating powerful AI agents directly into your daily workflows. Instead of switching between multiple tools, developers can now accelerate key tasks — from feature development to code reviews — all from within GitLab&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive DevSecOps platform. Amazon Q’s AI agents act as intelligent assistants, automating time-consuming tasks like generating code from requirements, creating unit tests, conducting code reviews, and modernizing Java applications. By handling these complex tasks, this joint offering helps teams focus on innovation, while maintaining security and quality standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab names Bill Staples as new CEO&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-names-bill-staples-as-new-ceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-names-bill-staples-as-new-ceo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This message from Sid Sijbrandij and Bill Staples was shared with GitLab team members earlier today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid:&lt;/strong&gt; On today’s earnings call, I announced that I am stepping down as CEO and will remain Executive Chair of the Board. I also introduced GitLab’s new CEO, Bill Staples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Board, we routinely do succession planning. This includes conversations with a number of top executives. We’ve been having these conversations in greater earnest since my cancer returned. Through these discussions, we identified someone uniquely qualified to lead GitLab. I want more time to focus on my cancer treatment and health. My treatments are going well, my cancer is not metastatic, and I&amp;rsquo;m working towards making a full recovery. Stepping down from a role that I love is not easy, but I believe that it is the right decision for GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How GitLab empowers translators with more context&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-empowers-translators-with-more-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-empowers-translators-with-more-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitLab is continuously translated by our global community of translators and proofreaders. Through Crowdin, they help make our product more accessible to the world by translating it into 78 languages. GitLab translation community members are volunteer translators, working professionals who are GitLab users, and even university students contributing to translators as part of their classroom projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-gitlab-open-core-model-supports-translators&#34;&gt;How the GitLab open-core model supports translators&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this community collaboration is powerful, translators often face a crucial challenge: understanding the full context of the text that they are translating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to deploy a PHP app using GitLab&#39;s Cloud Run integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-deploy-a-php-app-using-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-deploy-a-php-app-using-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing PHP application code and ensuring the application is running smoothly in production are often two different skills sets owned by two different engineers. GitLab aims to bridge the gap by enabling the engineer who has written the PHP application code to also deploy it into Google Cloud Platform with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether you own event-driven, long-running services or deploy containerized jobs to process data, Google Cloud Run automatically scales your containers up and down from zero — this means you only pay when your code is running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to leverage GitLab Duo for enhanced security reporting&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-leverage-gitlab-duo-for-enhanced-security-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-leverage-gitlab-duo-for-enhanced-security-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good security reporting is crucial to maintain a good security posture because it provides detailed insights into incidents. With this information, organizations can better understand vulnerabilities, improve defenses, and prevent similar threats in the future. At GitLab, the Security division has created use cases for GitLab Duo to improve reporting capabilities and enhance operational efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-duos-security-capabilities&#34;&gt;GitLab Duo’s security capabilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The GitLab Security division uses GitLab’s built-in incidents to manage and report on security incidents. Incidents are handled, documented, and resolved in GitLab, enabling the use of AI-driven GitLab Duo as an assistant when performing security operations like incident response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ICYMI: Key AI and security insights from our developer community&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/icymi-key-ai-and-security-insights-from-our-developer-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/icymi-key-ai-and-security-insights-from-our-developer-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our November LinkedIn Live broadcast, we brought together field CTOs, developer advocates, and community leaders to discuss industry trends and showcase features making a difference in developer workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 key highlights:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ai-adoption-trends-from-the-field&#34;&gt;1. AI adoption trends from the field&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our field CTOs shared insights on how organizations are embracing AI across their development workflows. For instance, Field CTO Cherry Han highlighted how financial organizations are thinking beyond individual developer tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Modernizing a simple C&#43;&#43; application to Java with GitLab Duo&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-a-simple-c-application-to-java-with-gitlab-duo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-a-simple-c-application-to-java-with-gitlab-duo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Memory unsafe languages are those that do not handle any memory management on behalf of the developer. For example, when programming in C or C++, if you need memory during runtime, you will need to allocate and deallocate the memory yourself, running the risk of ending up with memory leaks in cases when you inadvertently forget to deallocate it. Other languages like Ada and FORTRAN provide some memory management but may not prevent memory leaks. Many organizations, including those in the public sector, have applications that have been developed using languages that are memory unsafe and are often looking to modernize these to a memory safe language, such as Java, Python, JavaScript, or Golang.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Streamline DevSecOps engineering workflows with GitLab Duo&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-devsecops-engineering-workflows-with-gitlab-duo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-devsecops-engineering-workflows-with-gitlab-duo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 9 a.m. somewhere, and a DevOps engineer is starting their day. They check their GitLab todo list to see any mentions or tasks assigned to them, collaborating with other stakeholders in their organization. These tasks can include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;managing infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining the configuration of resources&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining CI/CD pipelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;automating processes for efficiency&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining monitoring and alerting systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ensuring applications are securely built and deployed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;modernizing applications with containerization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To carry out these tasks, DevOps engineers spend a lot of time reading documentation, writing configuration files, and searching for help in forums, issues boards, and blogs. Time is spent studying and understanding concepts, and how tools and technologies work. When they don&amp;rsquo;t work as expected, a lot more time is spent investigating why. New tools are released regularly to solve niche or existing problems differently, which introduces more things to learn and maintain context for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Transform code quality and compliance with automated processes&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/transform-code-quality-and-compliance-with-automated-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/transform-code-quality-and-compliance-with-automated-processes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While manual code review processes may suffice for a small team, as DevSecOps teams scale, the processes create significant bottlenecks that impede software development velocity and quality. Often slow, inconsistent, and frequently failing to catch critical vulnerabilities, the manual approach leads to technical debt and increased security risks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To mitigate risks and drive innovation, organizations must prioritize automated code quality and compliance systems. The financial implications of poor code management are substantial, with technical debt consuming up to 40% of IT budgets (McKinsey Digital: Tech Debt Report) and software vulnerabilities costing an average of $4.88 million per security breach (IBM Cost of a Data Breach Report).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing 150M developers and a new free tier for GitHub Copilot in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-150m-developers-and-a-new-free-tier-for-github-copilot-in-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-150m-developers-and-a-new-free-tier-for-github-copilot-in-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come and join 150M developers on GitHub that can now code with Copilot for free in VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Announcing 150M developers and a new free tier for GitHub Copilot in VS Code appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitHub has a long history of offering free products and services to developers. Starting with free open source and public collaboration, we added free private repos, free minutes for GitHub Actions and GitHub Codespaces, and free package and release storage. Today, we are adding GitHub Copilot to the mix by launching GitHub Copilot Free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing CodeQL Community Packs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-codeql-community-packs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-codeql-community-packs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce the new CodeQL Community Packs, a comprehensive set of queries and models designed to enhance your code analysis capabilities. These packs are tailored to augment…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Announcing CodeQL Community Packs appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce the new CodeQL Community Packs, a comprehensive set of queries and models designed to enhance your code analysis capabilities. These packs are tailored to augment the standard set of CodeQL queries, providing additional resources for security researchers and developers alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance build security and reach SLSA Level 3 with GitHub Artifact Attestations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhance-build-security-and-reach-slsa-level-3-with-github-artifact-attestations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhance-build-security-and-reach-slsa-level-3-with-github-artifact-attestations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how GitHub Artifact Attestations can enhance your build security and help your organization achieve SLSA Level 3. This post breaks down the basics of SLSA, explains the importance of artifact attestations, and provides a step-by-step guide to securing your build process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Enhance build security and reach SLSA Level 3 with GitHub Artifact Attestations appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The need for software build security is more pressing than ever. High-profile software supply chain attacks like SolarWinds, MOVEit, 3CX, and Applied Materials have revealed just how vulnerable the software build process can be. As attackers exploit weaknesses in the build pipeline to inject their malicious components, traditional security measures—like scanning source code, securing production environments and source control allow lists—are no longer enough. To defend against these sophisticated threats, organizations must treat their build systems with the same level of care and security as their production environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Availability Report: November 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-november-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-november-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Availability Report: November 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In November, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 19 10:56 UTC (lasting 1 hour and 7 minutes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 19, 2024, between 10:56:00 UTC and 12:03:00 UTC, the notifications service was degraded and stopped sending notifications to all our dotcom customers. On average, notification delivery was delayed by about one hour. This was due to a database host coming out of a regular maintenance process in read-only mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub’s top blogs of 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/githubs-top-blogs-of-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/githubs-top-blogs-of-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore GitHub’s top blogs of 2024, featuring new tools, AI breakthroughs, and tips to level up your developer game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub’s top blogs of 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As 2024 wraps up, we’re revisiting the highlights of a year packed with innovation, learning, and community. From unlocking the power of AI to mastering essential developer tools, these blogs reflect what makes GitHub the home for all developers. Ready? Let’s jump in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the research: How GitHub Copilot impacts the nature of work for open source maintainers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-the-research-how-github-copilot-impacts-the-nature-of-work-for-open-source-maintainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-the-research-how-github-copilot-impacts-the-nature-of-work-for-open-source-maintainers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interview with economic researchers analyzing the causal effect of GitHub Copilot on how open source maintainers work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Inside the research: How GitHub Copilot impacts the nature of work for open source maintainers appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to share an interview with two researchers that I’ve had the privilege of collaborating with on a recently released paper studying how open source maintainers adjust their work after they start using GitHub Copilot:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Annotated Logger: A Python package to aid in adding metadata to logs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-annotated-logger-a-python-package-to-aid-in-adding-metadata-to-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-annotated-logger-a-python-package-to-aid-in-adding-metadata-to-logs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re open sourcing Annotated Logger, a Python package that helps make logs searchable with consistent metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Introducing Annotated Logger: A Python package to aid in adding metadata to logs appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-is&#34;&gt;What it is&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Annotated Logger is a Python package that allows you to decorate functions and classes, which then log when complete and can request a customized logger object, which has additional fields pre-added. GitHub’s Vulnerability Management team created this tool to make it easier to find and filter logs in Splunk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s latest o1 model now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openais-latest-o1-model-now-available-in-github-copilot-and-github-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openais-latest-o1-model-now-available-in-github-copilot-and-github-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The December 17 release of OpenAI’s o1 model is now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models, bringing advanced coding capabilities to your workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post OpenAI’s latest o1 model now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey devs! We have some exciting news for ya.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, backstory first: in case you missed it, OpenAI launched its o1-preview and o1-mini models back in September, optimized for advanced tasks like coding, science, and math. We brought them to our GitHub Copilot Chat and to GitHub Models so you could start playing with them right away, and y’all seemed to love it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So many tokens, so little time: Introducing a faster, more flexible byte-pair tokenizer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/so-many-tokens-so-little-time-introducing-a-faster-more-flexible-byte-pair-tokenizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/so-many-tokens-so-little-time-introducing-a-faster-more-flexible-byte-pair-tokenizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We released a new open source byte-pair tokenizer that is faster and more flexible than popular alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post So many tokens, so little time: Introducing a faster, more flexible byte-pair tokenizer appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), such as those used by GitHub Copilot, do not operate directly on bytes but on &lt;em&gt;tokens&lt;/em&gt;, which can complicate scaling. In this post, we explain how we solved that challenge at GitHub to support the growing number of Copilot users and features since the first launching Copilot two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering GStreamer secrets</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-gstreamer-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-gstreamer-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll walk you through the vulnerabilities I uncovered in the GStreamer library and how I built a custom fuzzing generator to target MP4 files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Uncovering GStreamer secrets appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll show the results of my recent security research on GStreamer, the open source multimedia framework at the core of GNOME’s multimedia functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll also go through the approach I used to find some of the most elusive vulnerabilities, generating a custom input corpus from scratch to enhance fuzzing results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
