<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws-Well-Architected on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/aws-well-architected/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws-Well-Architected on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/aws-well-architected/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automating AWS Well-Architected Framework validations with Dynatrace CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/aws-light-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | AWS&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace is proud to be the first AWS global tech partner to offer &lt;strong&gt;ready-to-use CloudFormation templates&lt;/strong&gt; for validating the Well-Architected pillars. The Dynatrace CloudFormation templates are now available in the &lt;strong&gt;AWS CloudFormation Public Extensions Registry&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes Well-Architected validation even more accessible for AWS users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace and the AWS Well-Architected Framework ensure continuous optimization of cloud architecture, aligning with the key pillars of operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability. Our previous blog post discussed the importance of integrating Dynatrace with the AWS Well-Architected Framework to enhance your software development lifecycle (SDLC). By leveraging Dynatrace Workflow Automation and the Site Reliability Guardian, organizations can ensure that their applications meet AWS’s best practices across all pillars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
