<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with internet addiction</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guten Morgen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Farticles%2Fwsjqfjhcbr5p8ysj2pdw.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Kitty stretchs&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wish I could know who drew the cover image. It&amp;rsquo;s very well done. Would suggest you to check out their work, but sadly not even I know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I wanted to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m going through. This is by no means an exhaustive research made alongside a mental health professional, and I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for anything that will be written here to be of any utility to anybody. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be that. It&amp;rsquo;s merely a blog post of someone who wishes to start 2025 in good spirits, avoiding the pitfalls, so that it becomes the professional it seeks to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPRK IT Workers | A Network of Active Front Companies and Their Links to China</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has identified multiple deceptive websites linked to businesses in China fronting for North Korea&amp;rsquo;s fake IT workers scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has identified unique characteristics of multiple websites, now seized by the US Government, associated with the DPRK IT Worker front companies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that DPRK actors seek to impersonate US based software and technology consulting businesses by copying the online brands of legitimate organizations, seeking to use these for financial objectives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has linked the activity to several active front companies and links these with high confidence to a larger set of organizations being created in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our findings link additional companies, which remain active today, to the DPRK IT Workers scheme.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North Korea operates a global network of IT workers, both as individuals and under front companies, to evade sanctions and generate revenue for the regime. These workers are highly skilled in areas like software development, mobile applications, blockchain, and cryptocurrency technologies. By posing as professionals from other countries using fake identities and forged credentials, they secure remote jobs and freelance contracts with businesses worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Things First | SentinelOne Is A Fortune Best Workplace for Parents</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents, ranking among the top 70 companies worldwide for working parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wellbeing comes first at SentinelOne – for our customers, our communities, and our colleagues. We are proud to foster a culture of diversity, equality, and understanding for all. Supporting our working parents and the notion of a family’s evolving needs is a key part of that philosophy, and that is why we are extremely proud to be included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive healthcare breaches prompt US cybersecurity rules overhaul</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) has proposed updates to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) to secure patients’ health data following a surge in massive healthcare data leaks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These stricter cybersecurity rules, proposed by the HHS’ Office for Civil Rights (OCR) and expected to be published as a final rule within 60 days, would require healthcare organizations to encrypt protected health information (PHI), implement multifactor authentication, and segment their networks to make it harder for attackers to move laterally through them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
