<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dark Storm Team Claims Responsibility for Cyber Attack on X Platform – What It Means for the Future of Digital Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dark-storm-team-claims-responsibility-for-cyber-attack-on-x-platform-what-it-means-for-the-future-of-digital-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dark-storm-team-claims-responsibility-for-cyber-attack-on-x-platform-what-it-means-for-the-future-of-digital-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shutterstock_1904951575.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a stark reminder of the growing threat posed by hacktivist groups, the pro-Palestinian Dark Storm Team has taken credit for a major distributed denial-of-service (DDoS) attack on X (formerly Twitter). This attack underscores the vulnerability of even the most well-established digital platforms to sophisticated, politically motivated cyber threats. With online platforms playing an increasingly crucial role in global communication, the attack on X is part of a larger campaign of cyber aggression targeting critical infrastructure, government agencies, and major corporations. But who is the Dark Storm Team, and why should organizations worldwide take notice? Who is the Dark Storm […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Growing Danger of Blind Eagle: One of Latin America’s Most Dangerous Cyber Criminal Groups Targets Colombia</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-danger-of-blind-eagle-one-of-latin-americas-most-dangerous-cyber-criminal-groups-targets-colombia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-danger-of-blind-eagle-one-of-latin-americas-most-dangerous-cyber-criminal-groups-targets-colombia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/blog-image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary  Check Point Research (CPR) has uncovered a series of ongoing, targeted cyber campaigns by Blind Eagle (APT-C-36)—one of Latin America’s most dangerous threat actors Days after Microsoft released a fix for CVE-2024-43451, the group began employing a comparable technique involving harmful .url files, showing how attackers can turn security updates into weapons against their victims CPR found over 9,000 infections in just one week Attacks leverage trusted platforms like Google Drive, Dropbox, GitHub, and Bitbucket to distribute payloads, bypassing traditional security defenses The final malware, Remcos RAT, enables data theft, remote execution, and persistent access Blind Eagle’s Cyber […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Centres Can Cut Energy Use By Up To 30% With Just About 30 Lines of Code, Research Shows</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New research has found that data centres can reduce their energy usage by up to 30% simply by altering around 30 lines of code in the Linux kernel’s network stack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
