<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prevents on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/prevents/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prevents on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/prevents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;TS1085: Octal literals are not available when targeting ECMAScript 5 and higher. Use the syntax &#39;{0}&#39;&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ts1085-octal-literals-are-not-available-when-targeting-ecmascript-5-and-higher-use-the-syntax-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ts1085-octal-literals-are-not-available-when-targeting-ecmascript-5-and-higher-use-the-syntax-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ts1085-octal-literals-are-not-available-when-targeting-ecmascript-5-and-higher-use-the-syntax-0&#34;&gt;TS1085: Octal literals are not available when targeting ECMAScript 5 and higher. Use the syntax &amp;lsquo;{0}&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TypeScript is a powerful programming language that builds on JavaScript by adding optional static types. It enhances JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s capabilities, making it easier to write and manage larger codebases. In TypeScript, types (which are essentially categories of values) help developers ensure that their code behaves as expected by catching errors early in the development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerizing workloads on image mode for RHEL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous articles, we introduced bootable containers, discussed how to debug image mode for Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), which is built upon this new technology, and explained how to create CI/CD pipelines to automate the experience. In this article, we provide a comprehensive view of how you can manage workloads on image mode systems and set up a build pipeline to automate the experience of building, deploying, and managing Linux systems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating reduction of vulnerability classes: a key step in CISA’s “Secure by Design” pledge</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, securing software systems has never been more critical. Cyber threats continue to exploit systemic vulnerabilities in widely used technologies, leading to widespread damage and disruption. That said, the United States Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency (CISA) helped shape best practices for the technology industry with their Secure-by-Design pledge. Cloudflare signed this pledge on May 8, 2024, reinforcing our commitment to creating resilient systems where security is not just a feature, but a foundational principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusted-relationship cyberattacks and their prevention</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to work with suppliers to reduce the risk of incidents related to supply-chain cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old saying, “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link”, directly applies to enterprise cybersecurity. Businesses these days often rely on dozens or even hundreds of suppliers and contractors, who, in turn, use the services and products of yet more contractors and suppliers. And when these chains involve not raw materials but complex IT products, ensuring their security becomes significantly more challenging. This fact is exploited by attackers, who compromise a link in the chain to reach its end — their main target. Accordingly, it’s essential for business leaders and the heads of IT and information security to understand the risks of supply-chain attacks in order to manage them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Dockerize a Django App: Step-by-Step Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-dockerize-a-django-app-step-by-step-guide-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-dockerize-a-django-app-step-by-step-guide-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to make sure your web apps work well in different environments is to containerize them. Containers let you work in a more controlled way, which makes development and deployment easier. This guide will show you how to containerize a Django web app with Docker and explain why it’s a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will walk through creating a Docker container for your Django application. Docker gives you a standardized environment, which makes it easier to get up and running and more productive. This tutorial is aimed at those new to Docker who already have some experience with Django. Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
