<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Attack on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/attack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Attack on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/attack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Black Swan’ Event That Could Upend Life in 2025: The World’s Largest Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 futurists, foreign policy analysts and other prognosticators provide Politico readers some explosive potential scenarios for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gary Marcus, author of the book “Taming Silicon Valley”, one of The New Yorker’s recommended books in 2024, warns 2025 could easily see the largest cyberattack in history, taking down, at least for a little while, some sizeable piece of the world’s infrastructure, whether for deliberate ransom or to manipulate people to make money off a short on global markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;12 Months of Fighting Cybercrime &amp; Defending Enterprises | SentinelLABS 2024 Review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From ransomware repurposed for espionage to increased exploitation of cloud platforms, learn about the key trends from SentinelLABS research in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the convergence of cybercrime and nation-state espionage to the strategic misuse of trusted platforms like Microsoft Azure and SaaS APIs, the cybersecurity landscape has grown more complex than ever in 2024. SentinelLABS has been at the forefront of these challenges, analyzing trends, uncovering campaigns, and equipping organizations with actionable intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights | Empowering Customers Through Innovations &amp; Security in Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the latest technologies and innovations for cloud, container, and data security revealed at AWS re:Invent 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week marked another action-packed year at AWS re:Invent for the SentinelOne Team. Year after year, a consistent highlight from the event is the strong sense of community it builds with people from different backgrounds, geographies, and business types – all unified by their interest in innovating and doing business on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;CVE-2024-12854 - &#34;WordPress Garden Gnome Package Plugin Remote Code Execution File Upload Vulnerability&#34;&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12854&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Garden Gnome Package plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the functionality that automatically extracts &amp;lsquo;ggpkg&amp;rsquo; files that have been uploaded in all versions up to, and including, 2.3.0. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;SentinelOne Continues to Set the Standard in MITRE ATT&amp;CK® Evaluations | 100% Detection, Zero Delays and 88% Less Noise&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne achieves 100% detection and zero detection delays in the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK® Evaluations: Enterprise 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In cybersecurity, speed and accuracy are necessities. Every second counts, and every detection could be the difference between resilience and breach. That’s why SentinelOne takes immense pride in protecting our customers, monitoring trillions of signals annually across organizations from SMBs to Fortune 10 enterprises to top government entities and critical infrastructure. With visibility into the most sophisticated threats, we’ve detected and disrupted countless ransomware attacks, thwarted advanced eCrime and nation state adversaries, and ensured operations remain protected against evolving risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ZDI Threat Hunting 2024: Highlights, Trends, &amp; Challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on 2024, it has been an eventful year for the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team. Throughout the year, we identified numerous threat actor campaigns exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities, uncovered additional variants of these vulnerabilities, and discovered even more vulnerabilities through our in-the-wild research. In this blog, we will highlight some of the key achievements of the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team, as well as discuss important in-the-wild vulnerability trends and industry challenges we encountered in 2024 which will continue into 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous SOC Is a Journey, Not a Destination | Introducing The Autonomous SOC Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about autonomous SOC and how SentinelOne uses a maturity model to frame the shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The autonomous SOC: A well-grounded vision for the future of machine speed, AI-driven cyber defense, or nothing more than a pipe dream? Few concepts in modern security have been as polarizing, with sides painted as distinct camps of “believers” versus “non-believers”, each accompanied by increasingly hyperbolic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SentinelOne, you will hear us and our customers talk about the autonomous SOC and the fundamental shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations. Today, we want to be clear about what we mean when we say that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk | Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file &lt;code&gt;zshenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, researchers detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s discovery in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also reported on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to connect the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Malware | A Threat Hunter’s Guide to Analysis, Techniques and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about cloud threats, how to hunt for them and how to analyze them in this post based on Alex Delamotte&amp;rsquo;s recent LABScon workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many researchers have noticed, malware in the cloud is different. Perhaps more strikingly different than Windows versus Linux threats, cloud services are targeted through entirely different methods altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At LABScon 2024, I gave a workshop Taxonomy in the Troposphere that outlines categories of cloud threats and how to approach analyzing and hunting them. The workshop structure highlighted three general sections to approach this problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12853 - WordPress Modula Image Gallery Remote File Upload Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12853&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Modula Image Gallery plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the zip upload functionality in all versions up to, and including, 2.11.10. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13189 - ZeroWdd MyBlog Remote File Permission Bypass Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13189&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical has been found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This affects an unknown part of the file src/main/java/com/wdd/myblog/config/MyBlogMvcConfig.java. The manipulation leads to permission issues. It is possible to initiate the attack remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13190 - ZeroWdd Myblog Xml Injection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13190&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical was found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This vulnerability affects unknown code of the file src/main/resources/mapper/BlogMapper.xml. The manipulation of the argument findBlogList/getTotalBlogs leads to xml injection. The attack can be initiated remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.3 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-51442 - Minidlna Command Injection Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-51442-minidlna-command-injection-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-51442-minidlna-command-injection-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-51442&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 6:15 p.m. | 3 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Command Injection in Minidlna version v1.3.3 and before allows an attacker to execute arbitrary OS commands via a specially crafted minidlna.conf configuration file.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-53995 - SickChill Open Redirect Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-53995-sickchill-open-redirect-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-53995-sickchill-open-redirect-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-53995&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; SickChill is an automatic video library manager for TV shows. A user-controlled `login` endpoint&amp;rsquo;s `next_` parameter takes arbitrary content. Prior to commit c7128a8946c3701df95c285810eb75b2de18bf82, an authenticated attacker may use this to redirect the user to arbitrary destinations, leading to open redirect. Commit c7128a8946c3701df95c285810eb75b2de18bf82 changes the login page to redirect to `settings.DEFAULT_PAGE` instead of to the `next` parameter.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54010 - Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches ICMP and UDP Packet Forwarding Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54010&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability in the firewall component of HPE Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches exists. It could allow an unauthenticated adjacent attacker to conduct a packet forwarding attack against the ICMP and UDP protocol. For this attack to be successful an attacker requires a switch configuration that allows packets routing (at layer 3). Configurations that do not allow network traffic routing are not impacted. Successful exploitation could allow an attacker to bypass security policies, potentially leading to unauthorized data exposure.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.4 | LOW&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-55656 - Redis RedisBloom Probabilistic Data Structures Integer Overflow Information Leak Out-of-Bounds Write</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-55656&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 4:15 p.m. | 5 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; RedisBloom adds a set of probabilistic data structures to Redis. There is an integer overflow vulnerability in RedisBloom, which is a module used in Redis. The integer overflow vulnerability allows an attacker (a redis client which knows the password) to allocate memory in the heap lesser than the required memory due to wraparound. Then read and write can be performed beyond this allocated memory, leading to info leak and OOB write. The integer overflow is in CMS.INITBYDIM command, which initialize a Count-Min Sketch to dimensions specified by user. It accepts two values (width and depth) and uses them to allocate memory in NewCMSketch(). This vulnerability is fixed in 2.2.19, 2.4.12, 2.6.14, and 2.8.2.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0291 - Google Chrome Type Confusion Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0291-google-chrome-type-confusion-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0291-google-chrome-type-confusion-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-0291&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Type Confusion in V8 in Google Chrome prior to 131.0.6778.264 allowed a remote attacker to execute arbitrary code inside a sandbox via a crafted HTML page. (Chromium security severity: High)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22140 - WeGIA SQL Injection Vulnerability (Authenticated)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22140&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A SQL Injection vulnerability was identified in the /html/funcionario/dependente_listar_um.php endpoint, specifically in the id_dependente parameter. This vulnerability allows attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands, compromising the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the database. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22141 - WeGIA Web Manager SQL Injection Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22141-wegia-web-manager-sql-injection-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22141-wegia-web-manager-sql-injection-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22141&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A SQL Injection vulnerability was identified in the /dao/verificar_recursos_cargo.php endpoint, specifically in the cargo parameter. This vulnerability allows attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands, compromising the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the database. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22143 - WeGIA Web Manager Reflected Cross-Site Scripting</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22143-wegia-web-manager-reflected-cross-site-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22143-wegia-web-manager-reflected-cross-site-scripting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22143&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A Reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerability was identified in the listar_permissoes.php endpoint of the WeGIA application. This vulnerability allows attackers to inject malicious scripts in the msg_e parameter. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity 2025 | Preparing for Tomorrow’s Threats, Challenges and Strategic Shifts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore SentinelLabs&amp;rsquo; take on what 2025 may bring for cybersecurity, including emerging trends and actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crystal balls are notoriously fragile, and those who look into them are wise not to become fixated with the shadows cast by their refracted light, yet no business can function without some meaningful sense of what the future might hold. Reading the tea leaves of the past can offer no insight into novel and unexpected events to come, but it can help us prepare for that which is already forming in the shadows. Ultimately, the entire point of intelligence is to enable forward-looking decisions, and this means we’ll hit the mark with some and miss with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberVolk | A Deep Dive into the Hacktivists, Tools and Ransomware Fueling Pro-Russian Cyber Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A loose collective of mostly low-skilled actors, CyberVolk absorbs and adapts a wide array of destructive malware for use against political targets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CyberVolk/GLORIAMIST is a hacktivist collective originating in India with pro-Russia leanings. Between June and October 2024, CyberVolk claimed responsibility for multiple ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The main objective of CyberVolk and related groups is to leverage geopolitical issues to launch and justify attacks on public and government entities, primarily in the service of Russian government interests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a shared codebase used by CyberVolk, AzzaSec and DoubleFace’s ransomware. Additionally, CyberVolk has promoted other ransomware families like HexaLocker and Parano. These groups and the tools they leverage are all closely intertwined.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These hacktivist groups are extremely dynamic and volatile. In-fighting, threats, and inflated political-posturing are common, leading to fragmentation and the rapid re-shaping of the hacktivist threat landscape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CyberVolk is a politically motivated hacktivist collective which launched its own RaaS in June 2024. The group uses both DDoS and ransomware attacks in its efforts to undermine and disrupt the operations of those opposed to Russian interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGERBEE Malware Detection: New Backdoor Variant Targets Internet Service Providers and State Bodies in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Eagerbee-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the re-emergence of a more advanced NonEuclid RAT variant in the cyber threat arena, a novel malware iteration known as the Eagerbee backdoor poses an increasing threat to organizations in the Middle East, primarily targeting Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and state agencies. The enhanced EAGERBEE backdoor variant can deploy payloads, scan file systems, and execute command shells, displaying significant evolution of its offensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens&#34;&gt;Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23037/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hackers are trying to exploit CVE-2024-52875, a critical CRLF injection vulnerability that leads to 1-click remote code execution (RCE) attacks in GFI KerioControl firewall product. KerioControl is a &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (2 hours, 48 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different hacking techniques to be aware of. At the time of publication, the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework identified some 236 hacking techniques across 14 different categories. Luckily, you don’t need to understand all these tactics to stay safe. Many are close variations of the same basic approach. The best cybersecurity tools […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks appeared first on Heimdal Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises – providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data – if paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting AI Infrastructures | Introducing SentinelOne’s AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne’s new AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution helps organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of AI introduces unique security considerations. Misconfigurations in AI infrastructure and unsecured APIs can create weaknesses that cybercriminals will exploit. In this blog post, we dive deep into how SentinelOne’s agentless AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution addresses these challenges by offering AI inventory automation, misconfiguration detection, and attack path analysis to help organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Web-Based Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally published on Security Boulevard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-people-web-browsers-and-security&#34;&gt;Connecting People, Web Browsers and Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web browser has transformed significantly in recent years, becoming one of the most used tools for work today. However, as organizations adopt hybrid work models and cloud-based operations, securing this work tool has proved a challenge. Security infrastructures haven’t evolved as fast as the browser, making them prone to cyberattacks. With browsers being the primary gateway to the internet, any security lapse can lead to broad opportunities for significant data breaches and operational disruptions. Understanding the risks and implementing robust security measures is crucial for safeguarding the work we do today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian internet provider confirms its network was ‘destroyed’ following attack claimed by Ukrainian hackers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a statement on the Russian social media platform VKontakte, the St. Petersburg-based company said the “planned” attack “destroyed” its infrastructure overnight. Nodex added that it was working to restore systems from backups but could not provide a timeline for when operations would fully resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing AWS Lambda | How Misconfigurations Can Lead to Lateral Movement</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how several misconfigurations and user-defined code issues in AWS Lambda could lead to potential credential theft and lateral movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As serverless computing continues to revolutionize the cloud landscape, AWS Lambda has emerged as a pivotal service, offering a Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) model that allows developers to focus solely on code while AWS manages the underlying infrastructure. This shift towards serverless architectures brings new security challenges and considerations that security researchers and professionals must understand and address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best, the Worst and the Ugliest in Cybersecurity | 2024 Edition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we ring in the New Year, SentinelOne reviews and reflects on some of the most formative cyber news stories that occurred in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s almost time to wave goodbye to the year that was 2024, and as we look ahead to 2025 and the challenges that might bring, now is a good time to reflect on the best, the worst and the ugliest cybersecurity news stories over the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is phishing?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During phishing, a target or targets are approached by email, telephone, or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution. This is done to lure individuals into providing sensitive data such as passwords, banking and credit card details, and personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information is then used to access sensitive accounts, resulting in identity theft and financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of phishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; spear phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;search engine phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;email phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Features of Phishing:-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why security teams rely on Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR for managed detection and response</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The expanding attack surface is creating more opportunities for exploitation and adding to the pressure on security leaders and teams. Increasingly, organizations are investing in managed detection and response services (MDR) to bolster their security operations center (SOC) and meet the challenge. Demand is growing rapidly: according to Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan, the market for MDR is expanding at a rate of 35.2% annually.1   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are new vendors launching MDR services regularly, many security teams are turning to Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR, a recognized leader, to deliver comprehensive coverage.1 Employed worldwide by organizations across industries, Microsoft’s team of dedicated experts proactively hunts for cyberthreats and triages, investigates, and responds to incidents on a customer’s behalf around the clock across their most critical assets. Our proven service brings together in-house security professionals and industry-leading protection with Microsoft Defender XDR to help security teams rapidly stop cyberthreats and keep their environments secure.2 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zloader Banking a new Malware attack can be bypass Microsoft Signature Verification.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ZLoader malware campaign is exploiting a nine-year-old flaw in Microsoft’s digital signature verification to steal credentials and sensitive information using remote monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Check Point Research, which has been tracking the sophisticated infection chain since November 2021, it has been attributed to a cybercriminal group dubbed MalSmoke, citing similarities with previous attacks. “The infection chain incorporates legitimate remote management software (RMM) to gain access to the target machine.” After injecting its payload into a signed DLL, the malware further evades the system’s defenses by exploiting Microsoft’s digital signature verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
