<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bug on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/bug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bug on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/bug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug in macOS, Gatekeeper’s security can be bypassed by malware.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The macOS operating system was recently patched for a security vulnerability that could be exploited by a threat actor to bypass “myriad foundational macOS security mechanisms” and run arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Wardle described the discovery in a series of tweets on Thursday. According to CVE-2021-30853 (CVSS 5.5), the issue involves a scenario where a rogue macOS app can circumvent Gatekeeper checks, ensuring that only trusted apps can be run and have been notarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberVolk | A Deep Dive into the Hacktivists, Tools and Ransomware Fueling Pro-Russian Cyber Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A loose collective of mostly low-skilled actors, CyberVolk absorbs and adapts a wide array of destructive malware for use against political targets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CyberVolk/GLORIAMIST is a hacktivist collective originating in India with pro-Russia leanings. Between June and October 2024, CyberVolk claimed responsibility for multiple ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The main objective of CyberVolk and related groups is to leverage geopolitical issues to launch and justify attacks on public and government entities, primarily in the service of Russian government interests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a shared codebase used by CyberVolk, AzzaSec and DoubleFace’s ransomware. Additionally, CyberVolk has promoted other ransomware families like HexaLocker and Parano. These groups and the tools they leverage are all closely intertwined.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These hacktivist groups are extremely dynamic and volatile. In-fighting, threats, and inflated political-posturing are common, leading to fragmentation and the rapid re-shaping of the hacktivist threat landscape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CyberVolk is a politically motivated hacktivist collective which launched its own RaaS in June 2024. The group uses both DDoS and ransomware attacks in its efforts to undermine and disrupt the operations of those opposed to Russian interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti warns hackers are exploiting new vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The company released an advisory and a corresponding blog about two bugs — CVE-2025-0282 and CVE-2025-0283 — and warned that some customers have already seen CVE-2025-0282 exploited in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Ventures Invests in poolside, Next Generation AI for Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S Ventures invests in poolside, one of the most watched and highest valued startups in generative AI for software engineering today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October 2024, SentinelOne’s venture arm, S Ventures, made a strategic investment in poolside as part of the AI assistive coding startup’s $500 million Series B round. It was one of S Ventures notable recent investments in generative AI (GenAI) start-ups following similar investments in leading foundational and enterprise LLM platforms such as Anthropic and Cohere, as well as Scale, a startup focused on the development and tooling layer of AI, and Galileo, a leading evaluation intelligence platform for AI teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall urges admins to patch exploitable SSLVPN bug immediately</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately&#34;&gt;SonicWall urges admins to patch exploitable SSLVPN bug immediately&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23038/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SonicWall is emailing customers urging them to upgrade their firewall&amp;rsquo;s SonicOS firmware to patch an authentication bypass vulnerability in SSL VPN and SSH management that is &amp;ldquo;susceptible to actual ex &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (2 hours, 27 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best, the Worst and the Ugliest in Cybersecurity | 2024 Edition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we ring in the New Year, SentinelOne reviews and reflects on some of the most formative cyber news stories that occurred in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s almost time to wave goodbye to the year that was 2024, and as we look ahead to 2025 and the challenges that might bring, now is a good time to reflect on the best, the worst and the ugliest cybersecurity news stories over the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
