<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What is DevOps Automation? Best Practices &amp; Benefits&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-automation-best-practices-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-automation-best-practices-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about DevOps automation. Discover the steps you should take to automate DevOps workflows and processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21% of CISOs Have Been Pressured Not to Report a Compliance Issue, Research Finds</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/21-of-cisos-have-been-pressured-not-to-report-a-compliance-issue-research-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/21-of-cisos-have-been-pressured-not-to-report-a-compliance-issue-research-finds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CISOs face growing boardroom pressure, compliance challenges, and cyber threats. Discover key insights from Splunk’s latest report on cybersecurity leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CISA Adds Four Vulnerabilities to Catalog for Federal Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cisa-adds-four-vulnerabilities-to-catalog-for-federal-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cisa-adds-four-vulnerabilities-to-catalog-for-federal-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CISA adds four new vulnerabilities to its catalog, urging agencies to remediate risks. Learn about the latest exploits and how they impact enterprise security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Centres Can Cut Energy Use By Up To 30% With Just About 30 Lines of Code, Research Shows</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New research has found that data centres can reduce their energy usage by up to 30% simply by altering around 30 lines of code in the Linux kernel’s network stack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full web support for conditional access policies across Azure DevOps and partner web properties</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that we’ve made significant progress in updating our web authentication stack on Azure DevOps services and partner web properties to utilize Microsoft Entra tokens to handle web sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By replacing our previous cookies with Entra tokens, we’ve deepened the integration we have with Microsoft Entra ID on our web experience. This change allows us to continuously evaluate identity compliance with Entra policies on an hourly basis (the duration of an Entra token).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Fingerprint Authentication to Your Windows 11 Computer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-fingerprint-authentication-to-your-windows-11-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-fingerprint-authentication-to-your-windows-11-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can easily add a fingerprint reader to your computer if one isn&amp;rsquo;t already built in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Lock Apps on iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set your iPad into kiosk mode and pass it around without worrying about someone opening other apps or accessing unwanted content through an accessibility feature called Guided Access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing step failure strategies in Bitbucket Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-step-failure-strategies-in-bitbucket-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-step-failure-strategies-in-bitbucket-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce a new capability in Bitbucket Pipelines – Step Failure Strategies. This is the first of a set of new features allowing developers to implement more comprehensive logic and control-flow inside their CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Failure Strategies are designed to give you explicit control over how your pipeline behaves in the event that an individual step within the pipeline fails. This initial release will include the &lt;code&gt;ignore&lt;/code&gt; strategy, which is particularly useful for complex pipelines with steps like code styling suggestions or informational tests, where certain steps failing within the pipeline shouldn’t necessarily cause the entire build to fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Delivery: The Future of Software Deployment Is Already Here</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/progressive-delivery-the-future-of-software-deployment-is-already-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/progressive-delivery-the-future-of-software-deployment-is-already-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you enjoyed a software update? If you’re struggling to remember, you’re not alone. While engineers can now deploy code changes in seconds, making those changes useful and enjoyable is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Progressive Delivery, a term coined by James Governor in 2018, offers a fresh framework for addressing these challenges. With the upcoming release of Progressive Delivery: How To Build the Right Thing for the Right People at the Right Time by James Governor, Kimberly Harrison, Heidi Waterhouse, and Adam Zimman, let’s explore this transformative approach to software delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter whether your organization is a huge multinational business enterprise or a one-person operation. At some point, your computer networks and systems will be attacked by someone with criminal intent. Cybersecurity attacks, in all their various forms, are inevitable and relentless. This quick glossary, written by Mark W. Kaelin for TechRepublic Premium, explains &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quickly diagnose issues by viewing previous Pipeline runs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of a new capability in Bitbucket Pipelines that will improve your experience diagnosing issues with your pipeline runs, by allowing you to view and access previous runs within the Pipelines UI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://atlassianblog.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-1-600x491.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The previous pipeline &lt;strong&gt;Runs&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown will not show up if you re-run an entire pipeline, because re-running an entire pipeline creates an entirely separate pipeline record, rather than an additional run on an existing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware Payments Decreased by 35% in 2024, Research Finds</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-payments-decreased-by-35-in-2024-research-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-payments-decreased-by-35-in-2024-research-finds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ransomware payments dropped 35% in 2024 due to law enforcement crackdowns and stronger cyber defenses, forcing attackers to adapt with new tactics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform State Mv Command: How to Move Resources</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-state-mv-command-how-to-move-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-state-mv-command-how-to-move-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use the terraform state mv command to move Terraform resources within state files. See use case examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Business Case for Building a Learning Culture in Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-business-case-for-building-a-learning-culture-in-your-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-business-case-for-building-a-learning-culture-in-your-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, we focused on how building high-performing teams is a key differentiator of organizational success. Paramount to long-term success is the ability of your employees and teams to continuously learn, adapt, and innovate—what many have called a learning culture or culture of continuous learning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the guidance paper “How to Thrive (or Fail) in Building a Learning Culture” states, “Organizations that cultivate a culture of learning possess a distinct competitive advantage—one that allows them to stay ahead of the curve, anticipate shifts in the market, and deliver exceptional value to customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update to Azure DevOps Allowed IP addresses</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/update-to-azure-devops-allowed-ip-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/update-to-azure-devops-allowed-ip-addresses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are excited to announce some important upgrades to our networking infrastructure that will enhance the performance and reliability of our service. As part of these infrastructure upgrades, we are introducing new IP addresses that you will need to allow list in your firewall configurations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-changing-and-why&#34;&gt;What’s Changing And Why?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are transitioning from the current set of network edge devices supporting Azure DevOps to new, better-performing network edge devices by May 2025. As part of this transition, we have added new IP addresses to the current published allow list – Allowed address lists and network connections – Azure DevOps | Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform Moved Block to Refactor Resources</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-terraform-moved-block-to-refactor-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-terraform-moved-block-to-refactor-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use the Terraform moved block to move resources in your configuration files. See examples and limitations of this method.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise helps BuzzFeed optimize its mobile development to grow customer engagement - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-helps-buzzfeed-optimize-its-mobile-development-to-grow-customer-engagement-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-helps-buzzfeed-optimize-its-mobile-development-to-grow-customer-engagement-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In conversation with BuzzFeed: Principal Software Engineer Josh Walker shares insights into how Bitrise has freed up BuzzFeed to innovate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Locked Down Public Database Access That Exposed Chat History</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-locked-down-public-database-access-that-exposed-chat-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-locked-down-public-database-access-that-exposed-chat-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research Firm Wiz Research began investigating DeepSeek soon after its generative AI took the tech world by storm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build an Effective Security Operations Center</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-an-effective-security-operations-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-an-effective-security-operations-center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a coordinated security approach is one way to leave no loopholes. By this, we are referring to a cybersecurity architecture that comprises a team and security components working together in sync to provide more effective security operations as opposed to the usual fragmented approach, which often leaves businesses without a coordinated response to threats. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Keeper Password Manager: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-keeper-password-manager-a-comprehensive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-keeper-password-manager-a-comprehensive-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This step-by-step guide shows you how to set up Keeper Password Manager and use it to secure and organize your passwords.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing Resources With Terraform Import Block</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/importing-resources-with-terraform-import-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/importing-resources-with-terraform-import-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we explain the Terraform import block released in HashiCorp Terraform v1.5 and how to use it for different resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding new software on a deadline: Microsoft Visual Studio App Center shutdown - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/onboarding-new-software-on-a-deadline-microsoft-visual-studio-app-center-shutdown-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/onboarding-new-software-on-a-deadline-microsoft-visual-studio-app-center-shutdown-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With just two months to go until the deprecation of Microsoft Visual Studio App Center, here&amp;rsquo;s a resource pack to help you make migration happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform with AWS EventBridge [Step-by-Step Guide]</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-with-aws-eventbridge-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-with-aws-eventbridge-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guide, you’ll learn how to integrate Terraform with AWS EventBridge. See how to manage rules, event buses, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;1Password Review: Features, Pricing &amp; Security&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/1password-review-features-pricing-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/1password-review-features-pricing-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1Password’s top-tier security and sleek user interface make it a solid password manager to try this year. Read our hands-on 1Password review to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kubernetes Control Plane: What It Is &amp; How It Works&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-control-plane-what-it-is-how-it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-control-plane-what-it-is-how-it-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn what Kubernetes control plane is, its purpose, components, and how it works with nodes. Control vs. master vs data plane.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways AI Can Help Organizations Tackle Cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Legacy security measures, while offering a baseline level of protection, heavily rely on predefined signatures and a narrow definition of the “abnormal.” They often follow a reactive approach, can be siloed, limiting information sharing, and lack the scalability to handle the terabytes of data generated by today’s complex IT systems. This is where artificial intelligence &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to provisioning Azure DevOps projects using the Azure DevOps Demo Generator</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/changes-to-provisioning-azure-devops-projects-using-the-azure-devops-demo-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/changes-to-provisioning-azure-devops-projects-using-the-azure-devops-demo-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Azure DevOps Demo Generator is a tool that allows you to create projects in your Azure DevOps organization, complete with pre-filled sample content. This includes source code, work items, iterations, service connections, and build and release pipelines, all based on a template you select.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting &lt;strong&gt;February 28, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, we are eliminating the need for us to authenticate on your behalf. This update will give you greater control over creating new projects and ensure a more secure process. Instead of the previous authentication process, you will run the ADOGenerator project as a console application or executable (.exe) file to create projects in your Azure DevOps organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Protect and Secure Your Data in 10 Ways</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use this comprehensive list of strategies to help you safeguard your company&amp;rsquo;s data from threats and data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use 1Password: A Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-1password-a-guide-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-1password-a-guide-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use 1Password to securely store and manage your passwords. This step-by-step guide will help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measuring What Matters: Using Outcome-Focused Metrics to Build High-Performing Teams in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/measuring-what-matters-using-outcome-focused-metrics-to-build-high-performing-teams-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/measuring-what-matters-using-outcome-focused-metrics-to-build-high-performing-teams-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025 and beyond, the organizations that thrive will be those that shift their focus from activity-based metrics to true outcome-focused measurement. Gone are the days of celebrating features shipped or stories completed. High-performance teams and organizations of the future will be the ones that can demonstrably improve key business and customer outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;outcome-focused-metrics-that-matter&#34;&gt;Outcome-Focused Metrics That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the types of outcome-focused metrics that will define team excellence in the years to come:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Device Computing Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mobile-device-computing-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mobile-device-computing-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mobile devices are a way of life in both the consumer and business realms — and business interests must be protected where the two converge. This customizable policy, written by Scott Matteson for TechRepublic Premium, provides guidelines for the safe and productive use of mobile devices (laptop computers, tablets, smartphones, etc.) by employees. It includes &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now available for Enterprise, too: Apple API authentications on Bitrise - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/now-available-for-enterprise-too-apple-api-authentications-on-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/now-available-for-enterprise-too-apple-api-authentications-on-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using an Apple Enterprise development account? It’s now possible in Bitrise to manage your authentication via API key.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming support lifecycle milestones for older on-premises products</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upcoming-support-lifecycle-milestones-for-older-on-premises-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upcoming-support-lifecycle-milestones-for-older-on-premises-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multiple versions of our on-premises product will reach the end of support on October 14, 2025. Customers are encouraged to start planning and deploying upgrades now to ensure that installed products remain supported and secure, and to take advantage of new capabilities offered in successor products. The latest version of our on-premises product is Azure DevOps Server 2022.2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October 14, 2025, is the date for the end of Extended Support for Team Foundation Server 2015 – meaning it will no longer receive security updates or technical support. Upon end of support, there will be no new updates, free or paid assisted support options or online technical content updates. Upgrading from Team Foundation Server 2015 to Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 is fully supported and we strongly recommend that customers upgrade to the latest version before October 14, 2025, to continue getting security patches and support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50&#43; Ransomware Statistics for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/50-ransomware-statistics-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/50-ransomware-statistics-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the latest ransomware statistics and trends and what they mean for businesses across various industries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing Emails Targeting Australian Firms Rise by 30% in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/phishing-emails-targeting-australian-firms-rise-by-30-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/phishing-emails-targeting-australian-firms-rise-by-30-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the APAC region as a whole, credential phishing attacks rose by 30.5% between 2023 and 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on 15 Years of Books: A Journey Of DevOps, Organizational Wiring, and So Much More!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reflecting-on-15-years-of-books-a-journey-of-devops-organizational-wiring-and-so-much-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reflecting-on-15-years-of-books-a-journey-of-devops-organizational-wiring-and-so-much-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had the delightful experience of reviewing the rough cuts of &lt;em&gt;The Phoenix Project Graphic Novel&lt;/em&gt;, Volume 2. It resurrected so many memories from working on the original book nearly 15 years ago. (The first working drafts that George Spafford and I worked on together were from 2005, so that’s 20 years ago!)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Volume 2 of the graphic novel, which comes out later this year, there are many scenes with Bill and his wife and kids. These scenes were originally written around 2011, right after I left Tripwire. Seeing those blissful scenes of Bill and his young children brings back so many memories!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GhostGPT: Uncensored Chatbot Used by Cyber Criminals for Malware Creation, Scams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ghostgpt-uncensored-chatbot-used-by-cyber-criminals-for-malware-creation-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ghostgpt-uncensored-chatbot-used-by-cyber-criminals-for-malware-creation-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers from Abnormal Security discovered an advert for the chatbot on a cybercrime forum and tested its capabilities by asking it to create a DocuSign phishing email.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Leader’s Guide to Two-Factor Authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-two-factor-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-two-factor-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity threats are multiplying with each passing year. They are growing more sophisticated, as shown by the continued success enjoyed by ransomware and other scams. Two-factor authentication is a time-tested way to minimize the threat of a breach and protect the organization as well as the individual from attacks. Drew Robb, writing for TechRepublic Premium, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring GitHub-hosted runners with Dynatrace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-github-hosted-runners-with-dynatrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-github-hosted-runners-with-dynatrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/github-dark-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | GitHub&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As more organizations embrace DevOps and CI/CD pipelines, GitHub-hosted runners and GitHub Actions have emerged as powerful tools for automating workflows. But as with many other automation tools, it can be difficult to maintain the performance and visibility of these workflows. That’s where Dynatrace business events and automation workflows come into play to provide a comprehensive view of your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore some of the advantages of monitoring GitHub runners using Dynatrace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Sneaky Log’ Microsoft Spoofing Scheme Sidesteps Two-Factor Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sneaky-log-microsoft-spoofing-scheme-sidesteps-two-factor-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sneaky-log-microsoft-spoofing-scheme-sidesteps-two-factor-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The phishing-as-a-service kit from Sneaky Log creates fake authentication pages to farm account information, including two-factor security codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;5 Best Endpoint Detection &amp; Response Solutions for 2025&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-endpoint-detection-response-solutions-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-endpoint-detection-response-solutions-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Endpoint detection and response (EDR) software is the best way to detect, investigate, and respond to advanced attacks. Endpoint detection and response software is a security solution that protects against malware and other threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Developer Velocity: What It is, How to Measure &amp; Improve It&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/developer-velocity-what-it-is-how-to-measure-improve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/developer-velocity-what-it-is-how-to-measure-improve-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about developer velocity, its importance, key factors, measurement challenges, and strategies to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Top Kubernetes Alternatives for Containers in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/13-top-kubernetes-alternatives-for-containers-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/13-top-kubernetes-alternatives-for-containers-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See the list of 13 best Kubernetes alternatives for container orchestration and the features to consider when choosing an alternative to K8s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrowserStack and Bitrise partner to help mobile developers build, test and release apps faster with confidence - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/browserstack-and-bitrise-partner-to-help-mobile-developers-build-test-and-release-apps-faster-with-confidence-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/browserstack-and-bitrise-partner-to-help-mobile-developers-build-test-and-release-apps-faster-with-confidence-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitrise is partnering with BrowserStack to improve your mobile DevOps experience, giving access to best-in-class mobile-first CI/CD and automated mobile device testing, plus an incredible free product offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Clean the DNF and APT Caches in Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-clean-the-dnf-and-apt-caches-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-clean-the-dnf-and-apt-caches-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jack Wallen shows you how to clean the caches for both the DNF and APT package managers, so you can solve package installation problems that arise from corrupt installation metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Secure Username</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-secure-username/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-secure-username/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how to create a unique and secure username for your online accounts, and find out why it’s just as important as having a strong password.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Quickly Give Users sudo Privileges in Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-quickly-give-users-sudo-privileges-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-quickly-give-users-sudo-privileges-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have users that need certain admin privileges on your Linux machines, here&amp;rsquo;s a walk-through of the process for granting full or specific rights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Price Drop: This Complete Ethical Hacking Bundle is Now $35</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/price-drop-this-complete-ethical-hacking-bundle-is-now-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/price-drop-this-complete-ethical-hacking-bundle-is-now-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get a comprehensive, potentially lucrative ethical hacking education with 18 courses on today&amp;rsquo;s top tools and tech. This bundle is just $34.97 for a limited time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Internet Access VPN Review: How Good Is PIA VPN?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/private-internet-access-vpn-review-how-good-is-pia-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/private-internet-access-vpn-review-how-good-is-pia-vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to privacy and security, PIA VPN is among the best. Discover its features, performance, pricing, and more with this in-depth review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Delivery: A New Approach to Modern Software Development</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/progressive-delivery-a-new-approach-to-modern-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/progressive-delivery-a-new-approach-to-modern-software-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s technology leaders face a critical challenge: Software is now embedded in nearly every aspect of our lives, from banking apps to home security systems to medical devices. Users expect these systems to work flawlessly while continuously evolving to meet their changing needs. Yet the gap between software delivery and genuine user value continues to widen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IT Revolution is proud to announce &lt;em&gt;Progressive Delivery: Build the Right Thing for the Right People at the Right Time&lt;/em&gt; arriving in Fall 2025. This book introduces a framework for delivering software that adapts to users’ needs while maintaining stability and control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building High-Performance Teams in 2025: The Flow Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performance-teams-in-2025-the-flow-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performance-teams-in-2025-the-flow-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Organizations face unprecedented challenges in 2025. Competitive pressures demand faster innovation. AI tools are becoming more and more ubiquitous. And leaders continue to demand more results and innovation while still cutting costs. Even with all these demands, many teams are also still struggling with the challenges of misalignment, poor visibility, and coordination overhead that cripple their performance. Talk about kicking us when we’re down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a previous post, we looked at how leaders can help wire their organizations for success by building high-performing teams through slowification, simplification, and amplification. In this post, we’ll look at how the practices of &lt;em&gt;Flow Engineering&lt;/em&gt; and value stream mapping can help teams achieve better clarity, flow, and value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch Management Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-management-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-management-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patching of operating systems, applications, and devices is not usually ranked as a favorite endeavor of IT professionals, but it’s a critical process to ensure secure company operations and reduce downtime and technical support headaches. The purpose of this customizable policy, written by Scott Matteson for TechRepublic Premium, is to provide guidelines for the appropriate &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Cheat Sheet: The Ultimate Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive guide covers essential PowerShell information, including features, system requirements, and how Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s framework extends to task automation and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;16 DevOps Metrics You Should Be Tracking [DORA &amp; Other]&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/16-devops-metrics-you-should-be-tracking-dora-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/16-devops-metrics-you-should-be-tracking-dora-other/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the most important DevOps performance metrics and KPIs, including the 4 key DORA metrics and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Emerging AI Threats Australian Cyber Pros Must Watch in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-emerging-ai-threats-australian-cyber-pros-must-watch-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-emerging-ai-threats-australian-cyber-pros-must-watch-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI cloning and deepfakes rank among the top challenges for Australian cybersecurity professionals in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberGhost VPN Review (2025): Features, Pricing, and Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyberghost-vpn-review-2025-features-pricing-and-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyberghost-vpn-review-2025-features-pricing-and-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this comprehensive review of CyberGhost VPN, we cover its features, pricing, security, and overall performance. Find out if this is the right VPN for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Health Care Cybersecurity: Bridging HIPAA Gaps with Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-health-care-cybersecurity-bridging-hipaa-gaps-with-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-health-care-cybersecurity-bridging-hipaa-gaps-with-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposed HIPAA Security Rule introduces mandatory measures to prevent malicious cyberattacks in health care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch Tuesday: January 2025 Security Update Patches Exploited Elevation of Privilege Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-tuesday-january-2025-security-update-patches-exploited-elevation-of-privilege-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-tuesday-january-2025-security-update-patches-exploited-elevation-of-privilege-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s monthly patches cover Hyper-V NT Kernel Integration VSPs, Git in Visual Studio, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The overall success of a business is often dependent on its ability to effectively share, transfer, and process vast amounts of data. Much of this shared data is sensitive and must be protected wherever it travels on and outside the enterprise network. The best way to accomplish the important task of securing business data is &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Social Engineering Awareness Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/social-engineering-awareness-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/social-engineering-awareness-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent technological advancements have made people and things more interconnected. Unfortunately, people with malicious intent are also taking advantage of this capability. With this, the security of information systems has become more paramount for any organization. The purpose of this customizable Social Engineering Awareness Policy, written by Maria Carrisa Sanchez for TechRepublic Premium, is to &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Enterprise Tech Leadership Summit: Save the Date</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-2025-enterprise-tech-leadership-summit-save-the-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-2025-enterprise-tech-leadership-summit-save-the-date/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This September 23-25, at the 2025 Enterprise Tech Leadership Summit (ETLS) in Las Vegas, we will once again be exploring the impact of GenAI in our organizations. If you’re like me, you’ve experienced firsthand how generative GenAI reshapes our relationship with technology and how much we can benefit from it. Over the past year, I’ve been using it intensely in my daily work, and I’ve come to conclude that its impact will dwarf even the DevOps revolution that transformed our industry over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Considers Banning Ransomware Payments</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-considers-banning-ransomware-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-considers-banning-ransomware-payments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposed mandate intends to discourage criminals from targeting critical national infrastructure and public services, as there will be no financial motivation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Named a Leader in the 2024 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for DevOps Platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/atlassian-named-a-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-devops-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/atlassian-named-a-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-devops-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Naturalist John Muir once said, “The mountains are calling, and I must go…” I could not agree more, John.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something about the joy of tackling tough challenges. For me, that call has taken me from Kilimanjaro in Tanzania to Machu Picchu in Peru to Everest Base Camp in Nepal (I thought about Taylor Swift Eras tour tickets but alas was not brave enough). In my personal journeys, there is no greater joy than realizing the payoff from all your hard work by reaching the summit – except perhaps in being able to share your joy with others who are on the journey with you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian Government Agencies Failing to Keep Up With Cyber Security Change</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australian-government-agencies-failing-to-keep-up-with-cyber-security-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australian-government-agencies-failing-to-keep-up-with-cyber-security-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber security maturity declines among Australian government agencies in 2024, as legacy IT systems hinder progress under the Essential Eight framework.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitwarden vs 1Password: Battle of the Best – Who Wins?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitwarden-vs-1password-battle-of-the-best-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitwarden-vs-1password-battle-of-the-best-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitwarden and 1Password are two of the top password managers. Find out which password manager is the best for you using this comprehensive comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building High-Performing Teams with Team Topologies</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performing-teams-with-team-topologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performing-teams-with-team-topologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To achieve success and rise above competitors in 2025, organizations must focus on building high-performance teams. One strategy to do this is to empower small, long-lived teams as the fundamental building blocks of your organization’s design. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we looked at in the previous blog in our series on high-performing teams, building high-performance teams has less to do with where your teams sit and more with how you build the social circuitry between and within teams. The &lt;em&gt;Team Topologies&lt;/em&gt; approach provides a proven framework for designing and evolving these teams to maximize flow and adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerd vs. Docker: Container Runtimes Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerd-vs-docker-container-runtimes-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerd-vs-docker-container-runtimes-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the difference between popular container runtimes - containerd and Docker and see which is better for your project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical Patterns in Enterprise Ways of Working: Key Lessons from Industrial Revolutions Past</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a compelling keynote address at the 2024 Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit, Jon Smart, former head of ways of working at Barclays and author of &lt;em&gt;Sooner, Safer, Happier&lt;/em&gt;, revealed surprising parallels between historical management innovations and modern enterprise challenges. Drawing from extensive research spanning nearly two centuries of industrial evolution, Smart unveiled three critical patterns that continue to shape—and challenge—organizational effectiveness today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart’s presentation, based on his analysis of over 60 historical publications dating from 1776 to 1950, highlighted how modern organizations repeatedly struggle with lessons that were first learned during previous technological revolutions. His research, part of an upcoming book on the centuries-long evolution of working methods, demonstrates that despite technological advancement, core management principles remain remarkably consistent across eras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Run a Cybersecurity Risk Assessment in 5 Steps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-run-a-cybersecurity-risk-assessment-in-5-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-run-a-cybersecurity-risk-assessment-in-5-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though cybersecurity is on every executive’s checklist today, most struggle with growing compliance burdens, keeping the costs moderate, and bringing team alignment. A cybersecurity assessment is the key to combating the rising threat environment, and it’s prudent to secure systems before a breach cripples your business. Read this guide, written by Avya Chaudhary for TechRepublic &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up an SFTP Server on Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-set-up-an-sftp-server-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-set-up-an-sftp-server-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These steps walk you through the process of setting up an SFTP server on Linux for the secure transfer of files for specialized file transfer-only users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Malware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Malware is an insidious infection that will steal productivity from your enterprise and potentially wreak havoc on your network. To prevent and counteract malware, it’s important to know the terminology surrounding it. This list of terms, written by Mark W. Kaelin for TechRepublic Premium, will help you grasp the vocabulary that describes malware and the &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sideloading Low-Level Extraction Agent with Regular Apple IDs from Windows and Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/EIFT-8.60_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Low-level extraction enables access to all the data stored in the iOS device. Previously, sideloading the extraction agent for imaging the file system and decrypting keychain required enrolling one’s Apple ID into Apple’s paid Developer Program if one used a Windows or Linux PC. Mac users could utilize a regular, non-developer Apple ID. Today, we are bringing this feature to Windows and Linux editions of iOS Forensic Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are several different methods achieving essentially the same goal, modern devices (starting with those based on the chip found in the iPhone Xr/Xs) require the use of a special app called extraction agent. On the device, the extraction agent attempts to acquire the required level of privileges by utilizing a chain of exploits, which is an absolute requirement for accessing the root of the file system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Chip Export Rule Proposes Limits to Thwart Chinese GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Biden administration states the rule will prevent U.S. chips from passing to China through countries loosely allied or not politically allied with the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why developer experience is more important than productivity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-developer-experience-is-more-important-than-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-developer-experience-is-more-important-than-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;featured in TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;on January 29, 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-unhealthy-obsession-with-measuring-developer-productivity&#34;&gt;The unhealthy obsession with measuring developer productivity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s an unhealthy obsession with companies looking for a way to measure developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The desire to measure productivity is understandable; senior leaders have been under pressure to deliver results while capitalizing on their investments in teams and technology. There are no sinister intentions behind measuring developer productivity; leaders genuinely want their teams to be as productive as possible. The problem is that developer productivity is incredibly difficult to measure, resulting in organizations allocating disproportionate effort and resources while trying to find the magic measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;5 Best Linux CentOS Replacement Options &amp; Alternatives&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-linux-centos-replacement-options-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-linux-centos-replacement-options-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s decision to end CentOS is forcing most developers and companies to find an alternative OS. In this guide, learn about the top competitors&amp;rsquo; features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australian IT Sector Maintains Strong Employment Outlook for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australian-it-sector-maintains-strong-employment-outlook-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australian-it-sector-maintains-strong-employment-outlook-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT hiring intentions remain strong, though competition for jobs could be fierce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Password Creation and Storage</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-practices-for-password-creation-and-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-practices-for-password-creation-and-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly half of Americans, 46%, have had a password stolen in the previous year. Out of all the accounts that were breached, more than three-quarters (77%) of those users had their personal information stolen, such as their personal address, credit card number and Social Security Number. Password attacks on businesses can expose even more critical &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Disable IPv6 on Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-disable-ipv6-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-disable-ipv6-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If network troubleshooting leads you to believe there&amp;rsquo;s an issue with IPv6, you may need to shut down that protocol on your Linux machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Run a Command That Requires sudo via SSH</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-run-a-command-that-requires-sudo-via-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-run-a-command-that-requires-sudo-via-ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sudo via SSH lets you run admin commands on a remote server with elevated privileges. Learn the commands with this concise guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Set, Change, and Recover Your MySQL Root Password</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-set-change-and-recover-your-mysql-root-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-set-change-and-recover-your-mysql-root-password/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you never set, forgot, or change your MySQL password, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck. This article walks you through these steps, so you&amp;rsquo;ll never be at a loss for that database root user password.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Use SCP (Secure Copy) With SSH Key Authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-scp-secure-copy-with-ssh-key-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-scp-secure-copy-with-ssh-key-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to use the secure copy command, in conjunction with ssh key authentication, for an even more secure means of copying files to your remote Linux servers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Use the Apache Web Server to Install and Configure a Website</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-the-apache-web-server-to-install-and-configure-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-the-apache-web-server-to-install-and-configure-a-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve never deployed a website with the Apache web server, you&amp;rsquo;re about to learn how.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal ransomware spreads to Linux and VMware ESXi</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/royal-ransomware-spreads-to-linux-and-vmware-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/royal-ransomware-spreads-to-linux-and-vmware-esxi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new Linux version of Royal ransomware is targeting VMware ESXi virtual machines. Learn more about this security threat and how to protect from it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kubectl Patch Command &amp; How to Use It With Examples&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubectl-patch-command-how-to-use-it-with-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubectl-patch-command-how-to-use-it-with-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An overview of the kubectl patch command, including its syntax, how it works, and examples. Kubectl patch vs apply vs edit explained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond DORA Metrics: Five Potential Dimensions Of Value That GenAI Enables for Developers — Especially Creating Option Value!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beyond-dora-metrics-five-potential-dimensions-of-value-that-genai-enables-for-developers-especially-creating-option-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beyond-dora-metrics-five-potential-dimensions-of-value-that-genai-enables-for-developers-especially-creating-option-value/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, the DORA metrics have been instrumental in measuring developer productivity and software delivery performance — my collaboration with Dr. Nicole Forsgren and Jez Humble from 2013 to 2019 remains one of the things I’m most professionally proud of in my career.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working with Steve Yegge (Yes, that Steve Yegge, famous for his work at Amazon, Google, and his depiction of the famous Jeff Bezos “thou shalt communicate only by APIs” memo) and a group of amazing group of researchers and practitioners who are seeking to quantify the value of GenAI for developers. I’m excited that this could potentially build upon the amazing DORA work that continues at Google (hello, Nathen Harvey and Dr. Derek DeBellis!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the 1 Year Anniversary of OpenTofu Releases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-the-1-year-anniversary-of-opentofu-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-the-1-year-anniversary-of-opentofu-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year has passed since OpenTofu’s first stable release! With the celebration of the first anniversary, we’re also marking a new milestone -  the release of version 1.9.0!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Platform Paradox: How Standardization Drives Innovation in Enterprise Technology</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-platform-paradox-how-standardization-drives-innovation-in-enterprise-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-platform-paradox-how-standardization-drives-innovation-in-enterprise-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a compelling analysis of modern enterprise platforms, former Amazon platform architect and enterprise technology veteran Gregor Hohpe challenges conventional wisdom about how organizations can balance standardization with innovation. His insights arrive at a critical moment when enterprises are grappling with unprecedented technological complexity while seeking ways to accelerate development and ensure compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article reviews his recent talk at the 2024 Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit: Platforms: Perfectly Portable Productivity Propellants?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Expert Q&amp;A: Hybrid vs native development, which is best? - Bitrise Blog&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/expert-qa-hybrid-vs-native-development-which-is-best-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/expert-qa-hybrid-vs-native-development-which-is-best-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the hybrid vs. native development debate with insights from top experts. In this Q&amp;amp;A, industry leaders discussed the pros and cons of each approach, covering performance, user experience, developer productivity, and key decision-making factors. Get the insights you need to choose the best path for your app development journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Guide to Kubernetes Scaling: Horizontal, Vertical &amp; Cluster&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-kubernetes-scaling-horizontal-vertical-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-kubernetes-scaling-horizontal-vertical-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to scale Kubernetes? In this guide, you’ll learn about different methods of Kubernetes pod auto-scaling. See examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How AI will change software engineering: Insights from Bitrise&#39;s VP Engineering - Bitrise Blog&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-will-change-software-engineering-insights-from-bitrises-vp-engineering-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-will-change-software-engineering-insights-from-bitrises-vp-engineering-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how AI is reshaping software engineering with insights from Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s VP of Engineering, Arpad Kun. Explore the evolving role of AI, the skills engineers will need in the future, and how AI will enhance rather than replace software development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to Manage Cloud Infrastructure Drift &amp; Best Practices&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-manage-cloud-infrastructure-drift-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-manage-cloud-infrastructure-drift-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing cloud drift can be challenging. In this guide, you’ll learn what drift management is and discover best practices for implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What is DevOps Security? Challenges &amp; Best Practices&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-security-challenges-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-security-challenges-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the role of DevOps security and learn best practices that will help protect your workflows and keep your DevOps environment safe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips and Tricks for Using Kubernetes Helm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-tips-and-tricks-for-using-kubernetes-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-tips-and-tricks-for-using-kubernetes-helm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-06-18-10.41.05-A-simple-illustration-of-a-Kubernetes-Helm-guide.-The-scene-shows-a-clean-and-modern-workspace-with-a-computer-displaying-Kubernetes-Helm-charts.-The-.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Kubernetes Helm Guide&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-kubernetes-helm&#34;&gt;What Is Kubernetes Helm? &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes Helm is a package manager designed to simplify the installation and management of applications on Kubernetes clusters. It handles the process of defining, installing, and upgrading complex Kubernetes applications. Kubernetes Helm packages, known as charts, contain all necessary components to run an application, service, or tool on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Charts are collections of pre-configured Kubernetes resources. They enable users to deploy cohesive applications as one unit, managing dependencies and configurations through a single interface. This approach reduces complexity, enhancing reproducibility and scalability in cloud-native environments. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100&#43; Cloud Security Statistics for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/100-cloud-security-statistics-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/100-cloud-security-statistics-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we present key statistics related to cloud security that really caught our attention in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024: A Year of Innovation and Transformation at IT Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-a-year-of-innovation-and-transformation-at-it-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-a-year-of-innovation-and-transformation-at-it-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on 2024, we’re proud to share a year marked by groundbreaking publications, evolving events, and continued commitment to helping technology leaders succeed. This year saw us not only expand our publishing portfolio in innovative ways but also embrace meaningful change in how we serve our community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll take a moment to catch up on all the things we accomplished this year and look forward to what we have planned for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 DevOps Trends for 2025 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/devops-e1734453914491-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Experts provide insight into the rise of FinOps, how APIs will force a rise in DevSecOps, and how low-code, no-code is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Best Open Source Databases in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-open-source-databases-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-open-source-databases-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/5-dbs.png&#34; alt=&#34;5 databases alexandr kerpinchny, open source&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to running an application smoothly, you need a server and a database. Back in the day, Oracle and SQL Server ruled the database world, but now, it’s like choosing between countless options on Black Friday. Proprietary and open source, relational and NoSQL, on-premise and cloud-based – it’s a lot to take in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This ultimate guide contains the best open-source databases, according to the insights provided by DB-Engines. The list has cool dbs of different types to help users find a suitable solution for their needs. Here is the list of databases that we’ll review:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 DevOps Mistakes that Can Crush ISV Startups</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-devops-mistakes-that-can-crush-isv-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-devops-mistakes-that-can-crush-isv-startups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Devops-300x170.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Industry experts will tell you the best way to evolve your startup ISV into an established ISV is with DevOps — and they’re probably right. DevOps, however, which has only been in the mainstream for a little less than a decade, can be a difficult concept to master, and many software developers—especially startups—are still navigating […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Open Source tools you’ll only find on Windows (and why they’re worth knowing)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-open-source-tools-youll-only-find-on-windows-and-why-theyre-worth-knowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-open-source-tools-youll-only-find-on-windows-and-why-theyre-worth-knowing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-12-19-11.26.19-A-horizontal-image-showcasing-the-concept-of-open-source-tools-for-developers.-The-scene-features-a-vibrant-modern-workspace-with-diverse-developers-.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When people think of open-source software, they often associate it with Linux, known for its vast range of available tools. However, there are several high-quality open-source tools that are developed specifically for Windows. These tools offer advanced, unique features that often don’t have direct equivalents on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll explore &lt;strong&gt;five essential open-source tools available exclusively on Windows&lt;/strong&gt;, diving into their standout features and why every developer should be familiar with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amplifying Leadership Insights in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/amplifying-leadership-insights-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/amplifying-leadership-insights-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to share how IT Revolution is evolving in 2025. While our books and research papers will always be your go-to source for deep insights into digital transformation, DevOps, and organizational leadership, we’re introducing something new to help you quickly find the guidance you need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-best-of-both-worlds-ai-tools--human-expertise&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Best of Both Worlds: AI Tools + Human Expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2025, we’re trying something different. We’ll use AI tools to help us synthesize patterns and connections across our library. But here’s what won’t change: our commitment to quality and human oversight. Every piece we publish will be:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Build Cache Insights Beta - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-build-cache-insights-beta-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-build-cache-insights-beta-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce an open beta for Bitrise Build Cache Insights. This enhancement expands on our existing Build, Test, and Git Insights, enabling you to monitor and optimize your Bitrise Build Cache performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed DevOps Pools (MDP) for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-the-general-availability-of-managed-devops-pools-mdp-for-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-the-general-availability-of-managed-devops-pools-mdp-for-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Managed DevOps Pools for Azure DevOps is now generally available! This milestone marks a significant advancement in our mission to improve developer productivity in the CI/CD loop, reduce your cloud bill for ES infra and to reduce the toil associated with creating and maintaining custom CI/CD infrastructure for your pipelines. If you are new to Managed DevOps Pools, you can read about it in the Managed DevOps Pools documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Intelligence is here. What does it mean for developers, consumers, and innovation? - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-intelligence-is-here-what-does-it-mean-for-developers-consumers-and-innovation-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-intelligence-is-here-what-does-it-mean-for-developers-consumers-and-innovation-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how Apple is redefining generative AI with Apple Intelligence, seamlessly integrating it into iOS to enhance consumer experiences and empower developers. Explore its potential to connect apps, boost innovation, and transform the Apple ecosystem, while addressing challenges like app functionality, integration, and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-adaptive thresholds for AI-driven quality gating</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0146_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;auto-adaptive thresholds&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest release of the Site Reliability Guardian incorporates assistance from Dynatrace Davis® AI to automatically derive appropriate threshold targets and adjust them over time to protect your quality improvements. This process, known as auto-adaptive thresholding, eliminates the need to define a static threshold upfront. Instead, it derives the suitable thresholds from previous validation results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-an-umbrella-for-development-and-operations&#34;&gt;Build an umbrella for Development and Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, the discipline of platform engineering delivers DevSecOps practices to developers to bridge the gaps between development, security, and operations and enhance the developer experience. A key element in platform engineering is the establishment of fast feedback cycles regarding the quality and security measures of new software releases. To provide automated feedback for developers, the concept of quality gates for static code analysis in continuous integration is widely adopted throughout the industry. However, this perspective differs in the continuous deployment practices of various organizations, where the feedback is either delayed or not returned to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating AWS Well-Architected Framework validations with Dynatrace CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/aws-light-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | AWS&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace is proud to be the first AWS global tech partner to offer &lt;strong&gt;ready-to-use CloudFormation templates&lt;/strong&gt; for validating the Well-Architected pillars. The Dynatrace CloudFormation templates are now available in the &lt;strong&gt;AWS CloudFormation Public Extensions Registry&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes Well-Architected validation even more accessible for AWS users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace and the AWS Well-Architected Framework ensure continuous optimization of cloud architecture, aligning with the key pillars of operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability. Our previous blog post discussed the importance of integrating Dynatrace with the AWS Well-Architected Framework to enhance your software development lifecycle (SDLC). By leveraging Dynatrace Workflow Automation and the Site Reliability Guardian, organizations can ensure that their applications meet AWS’s best practices across all pillars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise on AWS: Benefits of using a cloud-native mobile CI/CD solution - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-on-aws-benefits-of-using-a-cloud-native-mobile-ci-cd-solution-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-on-aws-benefits-of-using-a-cloud-native-mobile-ci-cd-solution-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In mobile app development, a seamless and secure CI/CD process is crucial. Bitrise leads the way with its mobile-focused CI/CD platform, automating build, test, and deployment workflows. For organizations facing regional restrictions or compliance challenges, Bitrise on AWS offers the perfect solution—leveraging the power of AWS to meet your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise Release Management introduces CI Agnostic distribution for testing and releasing to stores - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-release-management-introduces-ci-agnostic-distribution-for-testing-and-releasing-to-stores-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-release-management-introduces-ci-agnostic-distribution-for-testing-and-releasing-to-stores-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Release Management&amp;rsquo;s new features streamline distribution for testing and store releases. Plus, you can integrate it with your choice of CI!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise support in December 2024: What to expect - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-support-in-december-2024-what-to-expect-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-support-in-december-2024-what-to-expect-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the holiday season nears and 2024 comes to a close, we want to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re fully informed about Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s operations during this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building High-Performance Teams in 2025: Beyond the Location Debate</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performance-teams-in-2025-beyond-the-location-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-high-performance-teams-in-2025-beyond-the-location-debate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The debate over in-office versus remote work misses a fundamental truth: high-performing teams succeed based on how they’re organized, not where they sit. Through extensive research across industries, Gene Kim and Dr. Steven J. Spear found that three key mechanisms consistently enable team excellence: slowing down to speed up, breaking down complexity, and amplifying problems early.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As they explain in their award-winning book &lt;em&gt;Wiring the Winning Organization&lt;/em&gt;, the leaders of the highest-performing teams will use these three simple mechanisms to “wire their organization for success instead of mediocrity.” &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 Years of Kubernetes: A Journey Through Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-10-years-of-kubernetes-a-journey-through-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-10-years-of-kubernetes-a-journey-through-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-06-03-11.06.16-A-minimal-and-simple-widescreen-image-celebrating-10-years-of-Kubernetes.-The-design-features-a-clean-white-background-with-a-stylized-modern-repres.webp&#34; alt=&#34;10 years of kubernetes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes, the brainchild of Google, has revolutionized container orchestration and cloud-native computing over the past decade. &lt;strong&gt;Its evolution from an internal tool to an industry-standard platform&lt;/strong&gt; is a testament to its robustness and the thriving community behind it. This article delves into the timeline of Kubernetes’ development, its remarkable success, key orchestration patterns, and essential tools that complement it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-timeline-of-major-milestones-10-years-of-kubernetes&#34;&gt;A Timeline of Major Milestones: 10 years of Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To appreciate these 10 years of Kubernetes, we need to understand its significant milestones. From its inception to its current status, each phase brought innovations and improvements that cemented its place in the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Infrastructure Management: Components, Tools, Benefits</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-infrastructure-management-components-tools-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-infrastructure-management-components-tools-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is cloud infrastructure management? Learn about the key components, types, benefits, challenges, tools, technologies, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike incident takeaways: Revisiting vendor quality control and release standards to minimize outage exposure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key learning from the outage caused by the faulty CrowdStrike “Rapid Response” update is how critical it is to understand your vendors’ quality control and release processes. Vendors should not only offer advanced technology to fulfill a business requirement but also demonstrate a strong commitment to reliability, security, and customer support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A variety of events and circumstances can cause an outage. This blog will suggest five areas to consider and questions to ask when evaluating your existing vendors and their risk management strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike update outage: Managing continuous delivery and deployment risk with Dynatrace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-update-outage-managing-continuous-delivery-and-deployment-risk-with-dynatrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-update-outage-managing-continuous-delivery-and-deployment-risk-with-dynatrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/b94c1fe7-371e-4894-a3b8-8a96f593307f-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Site Reliability Guardian, CrowdStrike outage&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After organizations struggled to recover from the CrowdStrike update outage on their Windows hosts in July, teams are now looking for ways to bolster the resiliency of their software update and continuous delivery practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread impact of the CrowdStrike issue demonstrated how critical it is to avoid outages and failures during software deployments to maintain user trust and satisfaction. Traditional deployment techniques that roll out updates or patches directly into full production can present significant risks and lead to potential downtime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delivering a first-class health app with Bitrise: An interview with Maven Clinic - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/delivering-a-first-class-health-app-with-bitrise-an-interview-with-maven-clinic-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/delivering-a-first-class-health-app-with-bitrise-an-interview-with-maven-clinic-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maven Clinic partnered with Bitrise to optimize its mobile development, improving efficiency, automation, and app performance. Learn how Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s mobile-first platform helped Maven streamline release processes and enhance collaboration across teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Evolved: What’s Next?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devops-evolved-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devops-evolved-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Developers and operations teams continue to refine this approach to enhance product quality and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace completes 2024 FedRAMP Moderate reauthorization with Rev.5 transition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0162_1_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;FedRAMP&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-fedramp-moderate-and-transition-to-rev5&#34;&gt;Understanding FedRAMP Moderate and transition to Rev.5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP (Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program) is a government program that provides a standardized approach to security assessment, authorization, and continuous monitoring for cloud products and services for U.S. state and federal agencies. The FedRAMP Moderate baseline is designed to protect sensitive data that, if compromised, could seriously adversely affect operations, assets, or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP Revision 5 (Rev.5) prioritizes customizing security controls for specific risks. It aligns with Cloud Service Providers, providing a baseline while allowing tailored adjustments for individual federal agencies. FedRAMP adopts a threat-based approach to security controls. Rather than a one-size-fits-all model, this methodology tailors controls based on specific threats and risks. The result is a more effective security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace proud to receive the Ally Technology Velocity with Quality award</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-proud-to-receive-the-ally-technology-velocity-with-quality-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-proud-to-receive-the-ally-technology-velocity-with-quality-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Badge_-Technology-Velocity-with-Quality-1-300x159.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to announce that Ally Financial has presented Dynatrace with its Ally Technology Velocity with Quality award. Ally Financial is the home of the nation’s largest all-digital bank and is an industry-leading auto financing business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the second time Ally Financial has presented its Ally Technology Partner Awards. Specifically, the company recognized five third-party suppliers for delivering outstanding service excellence across various criteria that align with Ally’s core values and performance standards. These criteria include operational excellence, security and data privacy, speed to market, and disruptive innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effortless internal and tester build distribution arrives in Bitrise - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effortless-internal-and-tester-build-distribution-arrives-in-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effortless-internal-and-tester-build-distribution-arrives-in-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Build distribution for testing is here to streamline the process of distributing your mobile app builds into the hands of your internal and external testers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empower engineers with the new DevEx enhancements in Jira, Compass, and Bitbucket</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/empower-engineers-with-the-new-devex-enhancements-in-jira-compass-and-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/empower-engineers-with-the-new-devex-enhancements-in-jira-compass-and-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software development has become increasingly complex. Developers are asked to do everything from addressing incidents and configuring cloud services to navigating a sprawl of microservices and components to complying with niche regulations and beyond. This is further compounded by increasing cross-functional collaboration across distributed teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atlassian is committed to helping developers better manage this complexity by bringing disconnected information and teams together in one place. By reducing the toil of information gathering and coordination, we help developers get back to what they love – problem-solving, writing code, and learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fail Fast: when failure is a win</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fail-fast-when-failure-is-a-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fail-fast-when-failure-is-a-win/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/FAIL-FAST-APPROACH.webp&#34; alt=&#34;fail fast approach image&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a world driven by rapid development and continuous innovation, failure isn’t always a setback—in fact, it can be a &lt;strong&gt;winning strategy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about &lt;em&gt;Fail Fast&lt;/em&gt;, a fundamental methodology in software development that aims to quickly identify the limitations and critical issues of a solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-fail-fast&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Fail Fast?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fail Fast&lt;/em&gt; is an approach with a single goal: to find a potential stopping point. If Descartes said &lt;em&gt;Cogito ergo sum&lt;/em&gt; (I think, therefore I am), here we could say &lt;em&gt;Deficio ergo sum&lt;/em&gt; (I fail, therefore I exist).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First DevOps, Now NoOps?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-devops-now-noops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-devops-now-noops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/devops-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Consider what could be possible if you’d fully automate the “Ops” aspect of DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Challenges Threatening the Success of Global DevOps Teams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-challenges-threatening-the-success-of-global-devops-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-challenges-threatening-the-success-of-global-devops-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/devops-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;DevOps promises faster development and easier maintenance, but there are some real-world challenges DevOps teams must contend with daily.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From syslog to AWS Firehose: Dynatrace log management innovations that enhance observability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/BAE14229_RC_logs-consumption-blog_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;log management innovations&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding that the first mile of getting data in can often be the hardest, Dynatrace continues to invest in log ingest, offering a range of out-of-the-box solutions within the Dynatrace Platform and apps. We’re excited to announce several log management innovations, including native support for Syslog messages, seamless integration with AWS Firehose, an agentless approach using Kubernetes Platform Monitoring solution with Fluent Bit, a new out-of-the-box ingest dashboard, and OpenPipeline ingest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Turbulence to Transformation: A CIO’s Journey at Southwest Airlines</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-turbulence-to-transformation-a-cios-journey-at-southwest-airlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-turbulence-to-transformation-a-cios-journey-at-southwest-airlines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Southwest Airlines’ crew scheduling system became overwhelmed during the 2022 holiday season, the company faced what would become a $800 million operational meltdown. CIO Lauren Woods and her technology team hadn’t caused the crisis, but they would need to solve it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I liken it to being like a designated driver at a party,” Woods reflects. “You didn’t bring the Wild Turkey, but all of a sudden you’re responsible for getting everybody home safe.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gain clarity and control with custom git commit status reports - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gain-clarity-and-control-with-custom-git-commit-status-reports-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gain-clarity-and-control-with-custom-git-commit-status-reports-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bring clarity to your CI/CD pipeline with custom Git commit statuses. Define dynamic, target-specific status updates using YAML to track every workflow or pipeline effortlessly. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s feature testing, deployment, or a build cycle, gain clear, actionable insights directly in your Git provider interface—keeping your team informed and your workflows efficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most out of Azure DevOps and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-the-most-out-of-azure-devops-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-the-most-out-of-azure-devops-and-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has two very successful DevSecOps products in the market – GitHub and Azure DevOps. Azure DevOps has a large enterprise customer base that loves the highly customizable enterprise-focused planning and tracking capabilities in Azure Boards, the robust continuous delivery capabilities in Azure Pipelines, the manual and exploratory testing capabilities in Azure Test Plans, and the deep integrations across the suite. GitHub is the world’s largest developer community, with over 100M developers. It also serves over 4M organizations, including 90% of the Fortune 100. It’s beloved by developers and at the forefront of innovation with features like GitHub Copilot, which is transforming every aspect of the software development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting your iOS apps ready for Apple Intelligence - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-your-ios-apps-ready-for-apple-intelligence-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-your-ios-apps-ready-for-apple-intelligence-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, you will learn about the changes Apple Intelligence will bring to Apple’s virtual assistant, Siri, and how you can prepare your iOS app to take advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gRPC in a Cloud-native Environment: Challenge Accepted</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/grpc-in-a-cloud-native-environment-challenge-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/grpc-in-a-cloud-native-environment-challenge-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-02-22-15.27.20-A-landscape-oriented-image-that-embodies-the-concept-of-a-lightweight-proxy-approach-in-a-cloud-native-scenario-with-a-special-focus-on-Kubernetes.-T.webp&#34; alt=&#34;A-landscape-oriented-image-that-embodies-the-concept-of-a-lightweight-proxy-approach-in-a-cloud-native-scenario-with-a-special-focus&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-and-context&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction and Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TeamSystem Pay is a fintech company under the TeamSystem Group, specializing in digital payments and open banking services. Originally developed to meet internal demands, TeamSystem Pay has evolved, &lt;strong&gt;facing the complexities of a cloud-native setting and the strategic considerations inherent in this transition.&lt;/strong&gt; This piece, written together with Davide Pellizzato, Head Of R&amp;amp;D at TeamSystem Payments, delves into the company’s innovative strategy for overcoming communication hurdles within Kubernetes clusters using gRPC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Stakes Communication: The Four Pillars of Effective Leadership Communication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/high-stakes-communication-the-four-pillars-of-effective-leadership-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/high-stakes-communication-the-four-pillars-of-effective-leadership-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve been there before: standing in front of your team, announcing a major technological transformation that you know is crucial for the company’s future. Despite your careful preparation, you can see it in their eyes—skepticism, confusion, or worse, quiet resignation. The change you’re proposing may be exactly what the organization needs, but your message isn’t quite landing the way you hoped.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This scenario plays out in enterprise technology organizations every day, and it’s exactly what Paul Gaffney, former technology executive at Home Depot and Dick’s Sporting Goods, addressed in his powerful talk at the Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit 2024. After decades of driving major technological transformations, Gaffney has discovered that the difference between a change initiative’s success and failure often comes down to one critical skill: the ability to communicate in a way that truly enlists people in your vision.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How observability, application security, and AI enhance DevOps and platform engineering maturity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps and platform engineering are essential disciplines that provide immense value in the realm of cloud-native technology and software delivery. However, these practices cannot stand alone. Rather, they must be bolstered by additional technological investments to ensure reliability, security, and efficiency. One of these key investments includes observability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Observability of applications and infrastructure serves as a critical foundation for DevOps and platform engineering, offering a comprehensive view into system performance and behavior. It goes beyond traditional monitoring—metrics, logs, and traces—to encompass topology mapping, code-level details, and user experience metrics that provide real-time insights. This real-time awareness enables teams to rapidly detect and resolve issues: both indispensable capabilities for maintaining the agility and reliability that are central to DevOps and platform engineering processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Red Hat and Dynatrace intelligently automate your production environment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Blog_-OTP-0100_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Red Hat and Dynatrace integration&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Red Hat and Dynatrace are joining forces to revolutionize day-one and day-two operations. A tight integration between Red Hat Ansible Automation Platform, Dynatrace Davis® AI, and the Dynatrace observability and security platform enables closed-loop remediation to automate the process from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detecting a problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Managing incidents in corresponding tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the root cause and proper countermeasures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Executing corrective actions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keeping relevant stakeholders in the loop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This way, disruptions are minimized, MTTR is significantly decreased, and DevSecOps and SREs collaborate efficiently to boost productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Comments in Terraform Code</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-comments-in-terraform-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-comments-in-terraform-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to effectively comment on Terraform files with single-line and multiline comments. See examples and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Directory in Ansible Step-by-Step</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-directory-in-ansible-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-directory-in-ansible-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to create, manage, and remove directories in Ansible. Step-by-step guide with best practices, permissions, and error handling tips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important updates: Changes to App secrets API - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-updates-changes-to-app-secrets-api-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-updates-changes-to-app-secrets-api-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To manage your secrets more effectively, we&amp;rsquo;ve made a few updates to our API endpoints. Here’s what you need to know to keep your apps running smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important: Switching CDN providers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-switching-cdn-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-switching-cdn-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current content delivery network (CDN) provider Edgio, used by Azure DevOps is retiring. We’re urgently transitioning to a solution served by Akamai and Azure Front Door CDNs to maintain the responsiveness of our services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What this means for you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For most of you, this transition will be seamless. To ensure that you can continue to access Azure DevOps without any interruptions, use the following &lt;strong&gt;Powershell commands&lt;/strong&gt; to validate that your current firewall settings allow connectivity to the new CDN providers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In 2024, Prepare to Shift Down, Not Left</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/in-2024-prepare-to-shift-down-not-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/in-2024-prepare-to-shift-down-not-left/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/DevSecOps-security-kubernetes-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevSecOps-security-kubernetes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Sustainable innovation requires balancing developer capabilities with support from advanced tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiring action: Bitrise and Blood Agents join forces to mobilize blood donations in Ukraine - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inspiring-action-bitrise-and-blood-agents-join-forces-to-mobilize-blood-donations-in-ukraine-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inspiring-action-bitrise-and-blood-agents-join-forces-to-mobilize-blood-donations-in-ukraine-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a life-saving app: learn how Bitrise and Blood Agents partnered to transform blood donation in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Graph Pipelines: build faster, build smarter - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-graph-pipelines-build-faster-build-smarter-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-graph-pipelines-build-faster-build-smarter-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you struggling to keep reducing build times as your project grows in complexity? Got particular workflows that take a long time to complete which needlessly hold up other parts of your build whilst you wait for the next stage? The waiting ends now with Graph Pipelines, a new feature which enables you to reduce overall build time by running CI tasks in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Pull Request Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the world of software development, security is paramount. As developers, we strive to write clean, efficient, and most importantly, secure code. GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps has always been at the forefront of providing tools that make it easier to build and release high-quality software. Today, we’re excited to announce a new feature release that will take your code security to the next level: PR (Pull Request) Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karpenter vs. Cluster Autoscaler – Kubernetes Scaling Tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/karpenter-vs-cluster-autoscaler-kubernetes-scaling-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/karpenter-vs-cluster-autoscaler-kubernetes-scaling-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See the comparison between Karpenter and Cluster Autoscaling and choose the right solution for your Kubernetes scaling strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Cost Optimization: A Developer’s Guide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-cost-optimization-a-developers-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-cost-optimization-a-developers-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/image.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;kubernetes cost optimization&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-kubernetes-cost-optimization&#34;&gt;What Is Kubernetes Cost Optimization? &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes cost optimization involves reducing expenses associated with running applications in Kubernetes environments without compromising performance or availability. It requires a strategic approach to managing &lt;strong&gt;resources such as compute, storage, and networking&lt;/strong&gt;. By optimizing these elements, organizations can ensure they only pay for what they actually use and need, avoiding unnecessary expenses.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cost optimization techniques in Kubernetes include rightsizing pods, selecting appropriate instance types for workloads, implementing auto-scaling, and setting resource quotas. The goal is to strike a balance between cost savings and maintaining application performance. This requires continuous monitoring and adjustment to adapt to changing demands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes with GitHub Actions: CI/CD for Containers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-with-github-actions-ci-cd-for-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-with-github-actions-ci-cd-for-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this step-by-step guide, you’ll learn how to create a GitHub Actions workflow to automate Kubernetes deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft DevLabs Extensions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-devlabs-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-devlabs-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft DevLabs publisher was created as a hub for internal teams at Microsoft to channel their passion for Azure DevOps into experimental extensions. These extensions helped address product gaps and fostered innovation, ultimately benefiting Azure DevOps customers via the public marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2024/12/marketplace.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image marketplace&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over time, as the original creators of these extensions moved on to other things, many extensions became outdated. This led to several problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unresolved Issues and Questions&lt;/strong&gt;: Customer feedback and bug reports were left unaddressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outdated Dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;: Security and dependency updates were not maintained.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Frustration&lt;/strong&gt;: The resulting decline in extension quality negatively impacted the Azure DevOps experience as a whole.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To restore the value of the Microsoft DevLabs publisher, we conducted a review to identify which extensions should be actively maintained and which needed to be deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mitigating Unbundling’s Biggest Risk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mitigating-unbundlings-biggest-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mitigating-unbundlings-biggest-risk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already read Unbundling the Enterprise: APIs, Optionality, and the Science of Happy Accidents you might want to check that off your to-do list before diving into the deep end of the pool. While we’re about to share the risk that was most frequently mentioned by the interviewees we spoke to, along with the primary tools and concepts for how to mitigate that risk, it may be a bit tough for you to fully understand the details of how the various details work together without having first read the book. Either way, you’re here now, so let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Cloud Decisions: Debunking Myths and Mitigating Risks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigating-cloud-decisions-debunking-myths-and-mitigating-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigating-cloud-decisions-debunking-myths-and-mitigating-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Organizations face critical decisions when selecting cloud service providers (CSPs). A recent paper titled Strategic Decision-Making in Cloud Services: De-Risking Cloud Lock-In offers insights for senior technology leaders, particularly those in the United States Government, as they navigate these complex choices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The authors challenge common assumptions about cloud vendor selection and provide practical guidance for making informed decisions that balance flexibility, cost-effectiveness, and risk mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cloud-selection-dilemma&#34;&gt;The Cloud Selection Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The paper begins by highlighting the significance of choosing a CSP, noting that for large enterprises, cloud migrations are multiyear efforts often viewed as irreversible. Organizations typically choose between three common cloud approaches:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the new frontier of developer productivity with AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigating-the-new-frontier-of-developer-productivity-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/navigating-the-new-frontier-of-developer-productivity-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suzie Prince, Head of Product at Atlaasian recently spoke with Abi Noda, CEO at DX, and Andrew Boyagi, Head of DevOps Evangelism at Atlassian, about how AI is changing software development. They shared valuable insights on the best practices for using generative AI (GenAI) tools on your developer teams, how to get value from developer portals, and the latest approaches for measuring developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are five key takeaways from this conversation on strategies for leveraging AI to boost developer productivity and experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Atlassian research on developer experience highlights a major disconnect between developers and leaders</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-atlassian-research-on-developer-experience-highlights-a-major-disconnect-between-developers-and-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-atlassian-research-on-developer-experience-highlights-a-major-disconnect-between-developers-and-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Misalignment between engineers and their leaders is possibly the leading cause of a sub-optimal developer experience and, consequently, poor productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See for yourself here&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we have moved on from a time when a positive developer experience meant buying a few ping-pong tables and ordering pizza on a Friday. Leaders understand that improving developer experience is about removing friction from the developer’s daily work and is a key input to productivity and retaining talent. But how closely do leadership attitudes match with what developers experience?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Expectations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the process may seem slow, we are steadily progressing toward rolling out the New Boards Hub to all customers. Our plan is to deprecate the old Boards experience for all Azure DevOps service users by the end Q1 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rollout is advancing on two fronts. First, we are setting the New Boards Hub as the default experience. Second, for customers who already have the New Boards Hub enabled as the default, we are transitioning groups to exclusively use the New Boards Hub. Removing the option to revert to the old Boards experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No new Azure DevOps OAuth apps beginning March 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-new-azure-devops-oauth-apps-beginning-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-new-azure-devops-oauth-apps-beginning-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting March 3, 2025, we will no longer accept new registrations of Azure DevOps OAuth apps. This is the first step we’ll be taking towards our longer-term vision of sunsetting the Azure DevOps OAuth platform. Moving forward, we’ll be publicly advocating all developers that are building applications on top of Azure DevOps REST APIs to explore the Microsoft Identity platform and registering a new Entra application instead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All existing Azure DevOps OAuth apps will continue working until the official end-of-life date, which we will announce in 2025. In the interim, we offer continued support to all current Azure DevOps OAuth app developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>November Patches for Azure DevOps Server</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/november-patches-for-azure-devops-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/november-patches-for-azure-devops-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are releasing patches that impact our self-hosted product, Azure DevOps Server. We strongly encourage and recommend that all customers use the latest, most secure release of Azure DevOps Server. You can download the latest version of the product, Azure DevOps Server 2022.2 from the Azure DevOps Server download page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following versions of the products have been patched. Check out the links for each version for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observability throughout the software development lifecycle increases delivery performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0207_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, development teams suffer from a lack of automation for time-consuming tasks, the absence of standardization due to an overabundance of tool options, and insufficiently mature DevSecOps processes. This leads to frustrating bottlenecks for developers attempting to build and deliver software. For multinational enterprises, the cost of all that toil, complexity, and frustration multiplies exponentially due to the size of those organizations. In such contexts, platform engineering offers a compelling solution to enable business competitiveness in a manner that significantly enhances the developer experience. A central element of platform engineering teams is a robust Internal Developer Platform (IDP), which encompasses a set of tools, services, and infrastructure that enables developers to build, test, and deploy software applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering restrictive policies and more secure alternatives. PATs can be an enticing vector for unauthorized access, especially when insecurely stored, over-scoped, or set for long durations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining service management with Atlassian customers the NRMA and Domino’s Pizza Enterprises Ltd</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reimagining-service-management-with-atlassian-customers-the-nrma-and-dominos-pizza-enterprises-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reimagining-service-management-with-atlassian-customers-the-nrma-and-dominos-pizza-enterprises-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Atlassian held &lt;em&gt;High Velocity: ITSM&lt;/em&gt;, an event covering ways to reimagine service management to include teams beyond IT. Atlassian customers joined in to discuss their journeys to digital transformation by way of Jira Service Management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During High Velocity’s keynote address, Atlassian Co-Founder Scott Farquhar sat down for a chat with Domino’s Pizza Enterprises Ltd (Domino’s) Group Chief Technology Officer Matthias Hansen and the NRMA’s General Manager of Technology Engineering Andy McCarthy to discuss their ITSM journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliability indicators that matter to your business: SLOs for all data types</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0195_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-at-a-glance-view-of-your-systems-health-and-performance&#34;&gt;An at-a-glance view of your system’s health and performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace guides you in quickly getting the most valuable service level objectives (SLOs) set up in just a few clicks. To provide maximum freedom in selecting the service-level indicators that matter most to your business, Dynatrace combines SLOs with the power of Dynatrace Grail™ data lakehouse, the central data platform with heterogeneous and contextually linked data. Service-level objectives now utilize highly flexible Dynatrace Query Language (DQL) for all Grail data sources. This lets you build your SLOs around the indicators that matter to you and your customers—critical metrics related to availability, failure rates, request response times, or select logs and business events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Build Caching: The key to fast, efficient builds - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-build-caching-the-key-to-fast-efficient-builds-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-build-caching-the-key-to-fast-efficient-builds-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slow build times are a developer’s biggest frustration and a major barrier to innovation. Tamás Bazsonyi, Solutions Engineer at Bitrise, explores how remote caching—the transformative &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; step in build optimization—can cut build times by up to 90% and revolutionize your CI/CD pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSA guide 2024: AI and security are top concerns for organizations in every industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/17619_RC_BlogImage_RSA-Guide_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RSA guide, DevSecOps transformation and vulnerability management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is top of mind for security teams across every industry. As more organizations adopt generative AI and cloud-native technologies, IT teams confront more challenges with securing their high-performing cloud applications in the face of expanding attack surfaces. According to McKinsey’s State of AI in 2023 report, 40% of respondents said their organizations plan to increase their overall AI investment because of advancements in generative AI. But only 21% said their organizations have established policies governing employees’ use of generative AI technologies. Moreover, in addition to managing cloud spend and resource utilization, organizations must also now consider the cost and carbon impact of developing and using generative AI models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six causes of major software outages–And how to avoid them</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3d-abstract-beautiful-ba-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;software outages&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recent events have demonstrated, major software outages are an ever-present threat in our increasingly digital world. From business operations to personal communication, the reliance on software and cloud infrastructure is only increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outages can disrupt services, cause financial losses, and damage brand reputations. Understanding the causes of these outages is crucial for preventing them and ensuring smoother, more reliable tech operations. It’s also critical to have a strategy in place to address these outages, including both documented remediation processes and an observability platform to help you proactively identify and resolve issues to minimize customer and business impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmartBear Delivers Full-Stack Observability Insights for Developers with Back-end Performance Monitoring and Distributed Tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smartbear-delivers-full-stack-observability-insights-for-developers-with-back-end-performance-monitoring-and-distributed-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smartbear-delivers-full-stack-observability-insights-for-developers-with-back-end-performance-monitoring-and-distributed-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/automated-software-testing-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;automated-software-testing&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;BugSnag, a SmartBear solution, unveiled with back-end performance monitoring and OpenTelemetry-native distributed tracing for full end-to-end visibility into app experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacelift Wins 2024 Digital Innovator Award from Intellyx</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spacelift-wins-2024-digital-innovator-award-from-intellyx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spacelift-wins-2024-digital-innovator-award-from-intellyx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intellyx has just revealed we’ve won the Winter 2024 Intellyx Digital Innovator Award, crowning a year of achievement for Spacelift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team Cognitive Load: The Hidden Crisis in Modern Tech Organizations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/team-cognitive-load-the-hidden-crisis-in-modern-tech-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/team-cognitive-load-the-hidden-crisis-in-modern-tech-organizations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“This feels pointless.” “My brain is fried.” “Why can’t I think straight?” These aren’t complaints from factory workers pulling double shifts—they’re increasingly common refrains from software engineers, product managers, and tech leads at some of the world’s most sophisticated companies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the 2024 Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit, organizational psychologist Dr. Laura Weis and team topology expert Manuel Pais presented stark findings: the human brain’s processing capacity has become the hidden bottleneck in technical organizations. Their research reveals that while companies obsess over system performance metrics, they’re largely blind to cognitive overload that costs $322 billion annually in lost productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of DevOps is AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-devops-is-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-devops-is-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/DevOps-AI-AIOps-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps-AI-AIOps&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Uncover how AI-driven code generation reshapes testing, agile planning, and the future of enterprise DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Link in Your Industry 4.0 Strategy: Industrial DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-missing-link-in-your-industry-4-0-strategy-industrial-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-missing-link-in-your-industry-4-0-strategy-industrial-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As manufacturers embrace Industry 4.0, many find that implementing new technologies isn’t enough to achieve the promised benefits of increased efficiency, flexibility, and innovation. Enter Industrial DevOps—a set of principles that can help bridge the gap between your Industry 4.0 technologies and the organizational practices needed to fully leverage them. Here’s what you need to know to integrate Industrial DevOps into your Industry 4.0 strategy:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aligning-industrial-devops-with-industry-40&#34;&gt;Aligning Industrial DevOps with Industry 4.0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Industrial DevOps complements Industry 4.0 by providing a framework for organizing, planning, and executing in a digital manufacturing environment. While Industry 4.0 focuses on technologies like IoT, AI, and digital twins, Industrial DevOps addresses the human and process elements needed to transform those technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Original Disruptor of the Music Industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-original-disruptor-of-the-music-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-original-disruptor-of-the-music-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know. You’re thinking I’m talking about Napster, right? Nope. Napster was launched in 1999. Bobby Diggs and the Wu-Tang Clan introduced unbundling into the music industry 6 years earlier in 1993. While the wild musical styles, grimy beats, no hooks, and raw lyrics might be what hip-hop fans laud when talking about the impact of the Wu-Tang Clan, the savvy business person’s perspective is one of awe when it comes to how The RZA (Bobby Diggs’ stage name, pronounced &lt;em&gt;rizza&lt;/em&gt;) upended traditional music industry models when he insisted upon each individual artist within the Wu-Tang clan retaining the option to sign as independent artists at any other label.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of DevOps Automation assessment: How automated are you?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-devops-automation-assessment-how-automated-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-devops-automation-assessment-how-automated-are-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/devops-concept-with-infi-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The benefits of unified observability and security for BizDevSecOps use cases&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to the scale and complexity of modern cloud-native technology, organizations are increasingly reliant on automation to properly manage their infrastructure and workflows. DevOps automation eliminates extraneous manual processes, enabling DevOps teams to develop, test, deliver, deploy, and execute other key processes at scale. Automation thus contributes to accelerated productivity and innovation across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automation can be particularly powerful when applied to DevOps workflows. According to the Dynatrace 2023 DevOps Automation Pulse report, an average of 56% of end-to-end DevOps processes are automated across organizations of all kinds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Salesforce DevOps 2024: Key Insights from Gearset’s Annual Survey</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-salesforce-devops-2024-key-insights-from-gearsets-annual-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-salesforce-devops-2024-key-insights-from-gearsets-annual-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Survey findings underscore the critical role of unified processes, more training, and continuous improvement in achieving DevOps excellence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Infrastructure as Code (IaC) Scanning Tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-10-infrastructure-as-code-iac-scanning-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-10-infrastructure-as-code-iac-scanning-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the top Infrastructure as Code (IaC) security scanning tools you should use in 2025 to improve your deployments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two feet in a shoe: more than one container in a single Pod</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/two-feet-in-a-shoe-more-than-one-container-in-a-single-pod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/two-feet-in-a-shoe-more-than-one-container-in-a-single-pod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/microservices-digital-transformation-optimized.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;microservices digital transformation. From monolith to microservices concept.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s get it straight: it is wrong to have more than one application container inside a single Pod. There are different reasons behind this statement and I will mention just a few of them. In any cases, the way Kubernetes has been designed brings us to the fact that having just one application container per Pod gives us a lot more flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlock enterprise knowledge with Atlassian Rovo</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unlock-enterprise-knowledge-with-atlassian-rovo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unlock-enterprise-knowledge-with-atlassian-rovo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is critical to unleashing the potential of all teams, and we’re excited to use this revolutionary technology to improve the way teams work. A year ago, we launched Atlassian Intelligence to help teams boost productivity with AI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since then, we’ve turned our attention to using AI to solve the highly complex problem of enterprise search and knowledge discovery. Our goal is to enable you to turn Atlassian and third-party data from across your organization into actionable insights and knowledge-driven decisions. In this age of generative AI, every team member deserves to have superpowers, and we want to make sure we deliver them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unpopular Opinion: Scrum Creates Chaos?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unpopular-opinion-scrum-creates-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unpopular-opinion-scrum-creates-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-03-12-12.01.41-A-digital-painting-in-landscape-format-depicting-a-frustrated-female-software-developer-sitting-at-a-cluttered-desk-surrounded-by-multiple-computer-m.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Perché Scrum fa schifo. L&amp;rsquo;autore crede che genera più problemi di quanti risolve. Metodologia Agile.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The advent of agile methodologies has certainly been a phenomenon similar to the revolution of the 1960s. I believe that it’s some sort of Woodstock of information, which, as often happens in life, I only saw from afar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I continue to meet people who were there and who always stop to tell me that such an event will never happen again &lt;strong&gt;and how the programmers of the past loved each other&lt;/strong&gt;, exchanged flower crowns, etc. Well, in short, the Robert Downey Jr. meme fits perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-entra-profile-information-in-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-entra-profile-information-in-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the ability to use Entra profile information in Azure DevOps. This has been a long-standing feature request from the community (ex. profile, picture, email, and name). Beyond the convenience of configuring profile information in one place and ensuring the accuracy of personal information, using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps provides important security and compliance benefits for Enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today we encourage users in Entra backed organizations to turn on &lt;strong&gt;Entra Profile information&lt;/strong&gt; in Preview Features. When you do, your Azure DevOps profile will become read-only, and information will be populated from Entra instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is CloudOps and How to Implement It in Your Organization?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-cloudops-and-how-to-implement-it-in-your-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-cloudops-and-how-to-implement-it-in-your-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/cloud-hologram-min-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CloudOps benefits and implementation guide.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image by rawpixel.com on Freepik&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-cloudops&#34;&gt;What Is CloudOps? &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CloudOps, or Cloud Operations, is a model for managing and delivering cloud-based services in a reliable, efficient, and scalable manner. It’s a set of &lt;strong&gt;best practices, principles, and tools&lt;/strong&gt; that ensure the smooth functioning of cloud-based platforms and applications. It transcends the traditional boundaries of IT operations, encompassing aspects like automation, monitoring, security, and compliance, thereby providing a holistic approach to cloud management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is OpenTelemetry? An open source standard for logs, metrics, and traces</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/NAM-2379-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is OpenTelemetry? The range of open source observability technologies can be daunting, and it’s easy to get overwhelmed. When it comes to managing complex multicloud environments and the services that run on them, however, it’s important to standardize, which is where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemtery was born from the combination of OpenCensus and OpenTracing and has emerged as the open source telemetry standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Are You on Your DevOps Journey?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-are-you-on-your-devops-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-are-you-on-your-devops-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Can ISVs achieve the benefits of DevOps without increasing developer stress and burnout?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/7-reasons-you-should-use-dbt-core-in-pycharm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/7-reasons-you-should-use-dbt-core-in-pycharm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Inspires Learners, IDEs Drive Them: Computer Science Education Trends 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-inspires-learners-ides-drive-them-computer-science-education-trends-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-inspires-learners-ides-drive-them-computer-science-education-trends-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than 23,991 learners from 16 countries and seven broader regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cs_learning_curve_2024.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than &lt;strong&gt;23,991 learners from 16 countries&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and seven broader&lt;/strong&gt; regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to over a year of collective effort. Dive in to discover what we’ve learned!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.44 Is Here With New UI, Zig Language Support, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.44 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about Fleet […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fleet’s New Islands UI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive. New islands layout The […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing klibs.io: A New Way to Discover Kotlin Multiplatform Libraries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and Android or searching for a Compose Multiplatform calendar component that supports both mobile and web, the challenge isn’t just finding one library – it’s having all of the options clearly presented so you can compare and choose the best fit. Today, we’re excited to introduce klibs.io – our new service designed to make finding Kotlin Multiplatform libraries faster and easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – December Digest</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-december-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-december-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, and let the festive celebrations begin! Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2024.3 Is Here Along With a Special Offer for New Users!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail.  To […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-featured_blog_1280x720_en-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Spring Boot Applications Using Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/testing-spring-boot-applications-using-testcontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/testing-spring-boot-applications-using-testcontainers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing is a crucial part of software development, verifying that a system functions as intended. Developers create unit tests to validate the behavior of individual components, isolating them from external dependencies such as file systems, databases, message brokers, and third-party APIs. However, since many applications rely on these external components, developers write integration tests to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Testing is a crucial part of software development, verifying that a system functions as intended. Developers create unit tests to validate the behavior of individual components, isolating them from external dependencies such as file systems, databases, message brokers, and third-party APIs. However, since many applications rely on these external components, developers write integration tests to ensure an application interacts correctly with its dependencies in a more complete environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ Scala Plugin in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Year in Review Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-year-in-review&#34;&gt;The Year in Review&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you easily augment the code you see in the editor with information about inferred types and other details. We’ve improved Scala 3 support, compiler-based highlighting, and the debugger. We’ve improved auto-completion, both the standard and the AI-powered versions. We’ve introduced support for named tuples, which are still an experimental feature, and we’ve implemented a new way to work with sbt projects. On top of all that, this year, JetBrains joined the Scala Advisory Board. You can read about those changes in our release notes and other blog posts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-mps-2024-3-release-candidate-is-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-mps-2024-3-release-candidate-is-ready/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated System Requirements for  Linux GNU C Library (glibc)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to provide a more secure and stable development environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-clion-the-2025-1-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-clion-the-2025-1-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 The CLion Nova language engine 🛠️ The debugger  🤖 Embedded development 🏗️ Project formats and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>300,000&#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/300000-prometheus-servers-and-exporters-exposed-to-dos-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/300000-prometheus-servers-and-exporters-exposed-to-dos-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Prometheus-blog-main-image-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;300,000&amp;#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this research, we uncovered several vulnerabilities and security flaws within the Prometheus ecosystem. These findings span across three major areas: information disclosure, denial-of-service (DoS), and code execution.  We found that exposed Prometheus servers or exporters, often lacking proper authentication, allowed attackers to easily gather sensitive information, such as credentials and API keys.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Prometheus-blog-main-image-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;300,000&amp;#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-must-see-sessions-at-kubecon-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-must-see-sessions-at-kubecon-north-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-KubeCon-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who’s getting excited? Next week, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation’s flagship conference, KubeCon + CloudNativeCon, will kick off in Salt Lake City, Utah. In its ninth year, the conference has grown into more than just a technical conference—it’s a vibrant community event that offers attendees the tools, relationships, and inspiration to drive innovation in the cloud native ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-KubeCon-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS CDK Risk: Exploiting a Missing S3 Bucket Allowed Account Takeover</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-cdk-risk-exploiting-a-missing-s3-bucket-allowed-account-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-cdk-risk-exploiting-a-missing-s3-bucket-allowed-account-takeover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/AWS-CDK-blog-main-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AWS CDK Risk: Exploiting a Missing S3 Bucket Allowed Account Takeover&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In June 2024, we uncovered a security issue related to the AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK), an open-source project. This discovery adds to the six other vulnerabilities we discovered within AWS services.  The impact of this issue could, in certain scenarios (outlined in the blog), &lt;strong&gt;allow an attacker to gain administrative access to a target AWS account&lt;/strong&gt;, resulting in a full account takeover. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Foreign aliases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-foreign-aliases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-foreign-aliases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In an organisation with many repositories and developers that are frequently shifting the maintenance of OWNERS and OWNERS_ALIASES files can be tedious. In the passing year a couple of functionalities has been added to help with this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreign-aliases&#34;&gt;Foreign aliases&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid maintaining the OWNERS_ALIASES file in many repositories you can now refer to the OWNERS_ALIASES file in another repository. In the Jenkins X project we have the main OWNERS_ALIASES file in the jx-community repository. So in the jx repository the OWNERS_ALIASES file only looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Google Summer of Code 2022 project proposal template ☀️</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-google-summer-of-code-2022-project-proposal-template-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-google-summer-of-code-2022-project-proposal-template-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposal-template&#34;&gt;Proposal template&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-contact-details&#34;&gt;1. Contact details&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full name:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Country:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time zone:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Github ID:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personal blog (optional):&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Twitter/LinkedIn/others:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-gsoc-information&#34;&gt;2. GSOC information&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you participated in the Google Summer of Code previously? Please describe your experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are you applying to any other organizations this year? If so, please list them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How many hours will you devote to your GSoC project each week? Do you have any other commitments during the summer?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you ever contributed code to Jenkins X? If you have, post the Pull Request (PR) links (It’s ok if they have not been merged/approved yet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you plan on contributing to the Jenkins X project after GSoC is finished?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Were you able to install Jenkins X locally on your laptop?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If no, please explain why (Unsupported architecture, missing documentation, time constraints etc)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If yes, how was the installation experience (missing documentation, complexity etc)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you used kubernetes in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible links to the work.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you used golang in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible some code samples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(If you are interested in the UI project) Have you worked with a frontend framework/library in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible some code samples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-project-idea&#34;&gt;3. Project idea&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Repeat this section for as many project ideas as you want (Go in the order most likely to least likely).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Community Bonding Period with Jenkins X</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-community-bonding-period-with-jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-community-bonding-period-with-jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, I am Rajat Gupta, pursuing my bachelor’s in Information Technology. In 2022, I have been selected as a student developer in Google Summer of Code under Jenkins X. We will be building a new UI for Jenkins X. I got this news on May 20th, as I received an email from google.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-started&#34;&gt;How I started&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The technologies needed were &lt;strong&gt;Golang&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;GitOps&lt;/strong&gt;. I used golang only once before, while linting Jenkins X codebase, I only used Kubernetes once before while setting up a k3s cluster to run Jenkins X pipelines. These tasks were necessary to do for all GSoC participants. Apart from that, I was a total beginner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Final Report: Building Jenkins X UI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-building-jenkins-x-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-building-jenkins-x-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jenkins-x-new-ui&#34;&gt;Jenkins X New UI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a web application built with Golang for the backend and Sveltekit for the frontend, both of which are built together and used in the same container. To function properly, it must be installed as a helm chart with Jenkins X CRDs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟 It has light and dark themes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/gsoc-work-report-22/homepage.png&#34; alt=&#34;homepage.png&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/gsoc-work-report-22/pipelinesPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;pipelinesPage.png&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-need-a-new-ui&#34;&gt;Why need a new UI?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good UI is essential for a CI/CD tool, as not everyone is familiar with the CLI. The current UI (jx-pipeline-visualizer) is a read-only UI, the user can view the logs of PipelineActivity but neither can start nor stop the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Final Report: Improving Supply Chain Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-improving-supply-chain-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-improving-supply-chain-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supply chain security is a rising concern in the current software era. Securing the software supply chain encompasses vulnerability remediation and the implementation of controls throughout the software development process. Due to massive increase in attacks on software supply chain and the diversity of its types, Jenkins X has to make efforts to ensure that the build process is secure. As part of securing Jenkins X installation by default I worked on both securing our own components and enabling our users to use these features in their build and release steps..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-hacktoberfest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-hacktoberfest-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that Jenkins X will be participating in Hacktoberfest again this year! Hacktoberfest is a month-long global celebration of open source software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All backgrounds and skill levels are encouraged to participate in Hacktoberfest and join a global community of open source contributors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more about Hacktoberfest and sign up here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;contribute-to-jenkins-x&#34;&gt;Contribute to Jenkins X&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome your contributions to the Jenkins X project!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues labelled “hacktoberfest” generally indicate good first issues. However, all pull requests will count towards your Hacktoberfest challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Improve your changelogs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-improve-your-changelogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-improve-your-changelogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standard part of the Jenkins X pipelines since a long time is the execution of &lt;code&gt;jx changelog create&lt;/code&gt; that takes the commit messages between the release currently being created and the previous one and creates a change log from these. The change log is then stored as a release note in GitHub or other git provider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the last year some improvements have landed in various Jenkins X components to improve the changelogs and their usefulness. So I’ll take this opportunity to describe these improvements and also in general give hints to how to get useful changelogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Introduction to Software Bill Of Materials</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-introduction-to-software-bill-of-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-introduction-to-software-bill-of-materials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before going through Software Bill Of Materials (SBOMs), we need to set the ground for a rising concern in the software industry which is Software Supply Chain Security. Like traditional industries, deploying a piece of a software artifact goes through multiple stages composed of collecting source code components, libraries, tools, and processes used in those stages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/sbom-guide/supply-chain.png&#34; alt=&#34;comparing the different steps in a real world supply chain with software supply chain&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Kubernetes 1.22 - Breaking change!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-kubernetes-1-22-breaking-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-kubernetes-1-22-breaking-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To allow Jenkins X to support Kubernetes 1.22, we had to update our version of Tekton. This updated version of Tekton contains breaking changes that has consequences if you made your own custom Jenkins X pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make sure that your custom pipelines continue to work after this upgrade, you must edit the resource settings in your pipelines. Otherwise your pipelines will most likely not be able to start at all, or if they do, consume a lot of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Migrate to Google Artifact Registry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-migrate-to-google-artifact-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-migrate-to-google-artifact-registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has announced that container registry will be shut down some time after March 18, 2025. For GKE clusters created with version 1.12.0 or later of terraform-google-jx it’s unlikely that anything needs to be done, but for older clusters you should upgrade your cluster while considering our advice regarding migration from container registry to artifact registry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using a Google Service Account to run terraform you need to add the role requirement roles/artifactregistry.admin. See our guide regarding Google Service Account for details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Project ideas for Google Summer of Code 2023 ☀️</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-ideas-for-google-summer-of-code-2023-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-ideas-for-google-summer-of-code-2023-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have put together some project ideas as part of our application to participate in the Google Summer of Code 2023 program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-cd-events-integration-with-jenkins-x&#34;&gt;1. CD events integration with Jenkins X&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cdEvents project standardises the way systems talk to each other, which enables Interoperability between systems so they speak a common language through the cdEvents spec in the event. Creating a capability in Jenkins X that can receive and sent a cdEvent would benefit the project and the DevOps ecosystem in general, by stopping glue code used to integrate systems and power innovation by letting end users swap out tools with no effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Project proposal for Google Season of Docs 2022 📄</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-proposal-for-google-season-of-docs-2022-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-proposal-for-google-season-of-docs-2022-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have put together a project proposal as part of our application to participate in the Google Season of Docs 2022 program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-proposal&#34;&gt;Project proposal&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;better-documentation-for-real-world-use-cases---jenkins-x&#34;&gt;Better documentation for real world use cases - Jenkins X&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X provides automated CI/CD for Kubernetes with Preview Environments on Pull Requests using Cloud Native pipelines from Tekton.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;problem&#34;&gt;Problem&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;End users of Jenkins X are unable to find information on how to use Jenkins X for real world use cases which includes:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Production best practices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scanning images in Jenkins X pipelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to make your app use different configuration/secrets for each environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Observability for your apps, logging, metrics, tracing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tests (Integration, e2e)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Artifact management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Multi cluster&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integration with other tools in the cloud native sector&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;project-scope&#34;&gt;Project scope&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Audit the current Jenkins X documentation and create a friction log&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the friction log as a guide for understanding the gaps in the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interact with the Jenkins X community to create a list of top use cases&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a survey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look at the github issues and slack messages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work with the volunteers to incorporate those changes into the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Establish a feedback loop (the target customers are the end users of Jenkins X) to improve the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;measuring-project-success&#34;&gt;Measuring project success&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decrease in the number of github issues raised by end users on documentation related to common real world use cases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Short 1-2 minute videos on common tasks that end users of Jenkins X would like to perform.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;recommended-skills&#34;&gt;Recommended skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Must have:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Experience with github&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Communication skills to work with the Jenkins X community&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Creating online surveys&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nice to have:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basic experience with docker compose (local development scripts use compose)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Good video editing skills.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some knowledge working with the documentation of other tools in the kubernetes ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;mentorsvolunteers&#34;&gt;Mentors/Volunteers&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ankit D Mohapatra&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christoffer Vig&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mårten Svantesson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tom Hobson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project will take roughly 6 months to complete. Once the technical writer is selected, we will do an orientation to bring him up to speed. This is the timeline we have in mind, but we are flexible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Reconcile with kpt live apply</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-reconcile-with-kpt-live-apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-reconcile-with-kpt-live-apply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of Jenkins X 3 the default last step of reconciling the state of the files in your cluster repository to your cluster has been to execute &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt;. You can find more details about this here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some drawbacks with &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; though. The one that made me start looking for alternatives was that if you remove a resource from your cluster repository it may not be removed from your cluster. The way deletion works with &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; is that it is handed the option &lt;code&gt;--prune&lt;/code&gt; which will remove resources that are not in the manifests. Except that it doesn’t always work as expected. It will only remove certain kinds of resources defined in kubectl. In my case I removed an HorizontalPodAutoscaler from my cluster repository, but it wasn’t removed from my cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Software Bill Of Materials Formats</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-formats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t understand what is Software Bill of Materials (SBOM), please read this blog post first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-sbom-formats-comparison&#34;&gt;Different SBOM formats comparison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) in the U.S. defined minimum requirements for SBOM formats:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the supplier of the software component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the details about the version of the component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including unique identifiers for the component like cryptographic hash functions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including the relationships between all dependencies inside the component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including a timestamp of when and by whom the SBOM report was created or last modified&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this section, we discuss different kinds and formats for SBOM standards and make a brief comparison between them. Three commonly used standards achieved the NTIA minimum requirements for SBOM generation and each one results in a different final SBOM document.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Software Bill Of Materials generation tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-generation-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-generation-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you read this, you have to understand what are SBOMs and what are different formats of SBOMs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-sbom-generation-tools-comparison&#34;&gt;Different SBOM generation tools comparison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you got this far, you already realize the importance of SBOM generation, and also it should meet certain requirements to achieve its purpose. Due to various requirements depending on what standard you’re following, there has to be a way to automatically generate different output formats for different standards. Also, it has to be suited for ci/cd solutions to keep up with the increasing number of releases for each organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-trends-predictions-and-strategies-for-resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-trends-predictions-and-strategies-for-resilience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cloud-Security-trends-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2025, &lt;strong&gt;cloud native security&lt;/strong&gt; is set to undergo transformative progress. As Chief Information Security Officer at Aqua, I’ve seen how rapidly evolving threats and operational demands are driving organizations to redefine their approach to security. The focus is no longer just on adapting to challenges—it’s about deeply embedding security into every facet of development pipelines, runtime environments, and cloud ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cloud-Security-trends-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-uk-cybersecurity-and-resilience-impact-of-the-new-national-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-uk-cybersecurity-and-resilience-impact-of-the-new-national-bill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cyber-Security-and-Resilience-Bill-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the digital landscape rapidly evolves, the need for a robust, adaptive security strategy becomes increasingly critical. Cyber threats are becoming more sophisticated and widespread, necessitating a proactive approach to cybersecurity. The UK&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Security and Resilience Bill represents a significant stride towards fortifying the nation’s defenses against these threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cyber-Security-and-Resilience-Bill-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Theory to Practice: How to Make DevSecOps Work in Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-theory-to-practice-how-to-make-devsecops-work-in-your-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-theory-to-practice-how-to-make-devsecops-work-in-your-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-DevSecOps-Buyers-Guide-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Theory to Practice: How to Make DevSecOps Work in Your Organization&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Houston, we have a problem: implementing DevSecOps isn’t as straightforward as it seems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevSecOps has redefined security in modern software development, becoming the benchmark for organizational success. By embedding security into every phase of the development lifecycle, organizations can deploy faster and collaborate more efficiently while ensuring security at every step. Yet, despite its advantages, according to IDC’s 2024 DevSecOps and Software Supply Chain Security Survey, only 66% of application development teams use DevSecOps methodologies on average. If it were easy to implement, that number would be much closer to 100%. So, what’s holding teams back? Let’s explore the most common challenges—and how to address them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/matrix-unleashes-a-new-widespread-ddos-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/matrix-unleashes-a-new-widespread-ddos-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/matrix-blog-main-text-1200x628.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aqua Nautilus researchers uncovered a new and widespread Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) campaign orchestrated by a threat actor named Matrix. Triggered by activities detected on our honeypots, this investigation dives deep into Matrix’s methods, targets, tools, and overall goals.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/matrix-blog-main-text-1200x628.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aqua Nautilus researchers uncovered a new and widespread Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) campaign orchestrated by a threat actor named Matrix. Triggered by activities detected on our honeypots, this investigation dives deep into Matrix’s methods, targets, tools, and overall goals.   &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-aqua-user-experience-streamlined-vulnerability-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-aqua-user-experience-streamlined-vulnerability-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Aqua-Hub-1200x628-2024%20FINAL-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Aqua Hub update is designed to take the headache out of vulnerability management, addressing common challenges like alert overload and data consistency issues. With this update, teams get a clean, streamlined view of vulnerabilities that cuts through the noise, so they can focus on the critical issues without getting lost in irrelevant details. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Aqua-Hub-1200x628-2024%20FINAL-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Aqua Hub update is designed to take the headache out of vulnerability management, addressing common challenges like alert overload and data consistency issues. With this update, teams get a clean, streamlined view of vulnerabilities that cuts through the noise, so they can focus on the critical issues without getting lost in irrelevant details. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Actors Hijack Misconfigured Servers for Live Sports Streaming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-actors-hijack-misconfigured-servers-for-live-sports-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-actors-hijack-misconfigured-servers-for-live-sports-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Blog-Stream_Ripping-main-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Threat Actors Hijack Misconfigured Servers for Live Sports Streaming&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the ever-evolving world of cybersecurity, Aqua Nautilus researchers deploy honeypots that mimic real-world development environments. During a recent threat-hunting operation, they uncovered a surprising new attack vector: threat actors using misconfigured servers to hijack environments for streaming sports events. By exploiting misconfigured JupyterLab and Jupyter Notebook applications, attackers drop live streaming capture tools and duplicate the broadcast on their illegal server, thus conducting stream ripping. In this blog, we explain how our threat hunting operation helped us uncover this and how we analyzed this attack using Aqua Tracee and Traceeshark.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Alert: TeamTNT’s Docker Gatling Gun Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-alert-teamtnts-docker-gatling-gun-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-alert-teamtnts-docker-gatling-gun-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-TeamTNT-Docker-Gun-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Threat Alert: TeamTNT’s Docker Gatling Gun Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long time no see, Aqua Nautilus researchers have identified a new campaign in the making by TeamTNT, a notorious hacking group. In this campaign, TeamTNT appears to be returning to its roots while preparing for a large-scale attack on cloud native environments. The group is currently targeting exposed Docker daemons to deploy Sliver malware, a cyber worm, and cryptominers, using compromised servers and Docker Hub as the infrastructure to spread their malware.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
