<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The Role of WAF in Fintech &amp; Financial Services&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-role-of-waf-in-fintech-financial-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-role-of-waf-in-fintech-financial-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/CNAPP-Solution-blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The financial sector serves as the backbone of the global economy, making it one of the most targeted industries for cyber attacks. As online banking, mobile transactions, and fintech innovations expand, cyber threats continue to evolve. Cyber criminals continuously exploit vulnerabilities in financial applications, making strong security measures essential for protecting sensitive customer data, transactions, and business operations. To mitigate these risks, efficient web application firewalls (WAFs) have become a crucial security mechanism for financial services. In recent GigaOm Radar for Application and API Security report, GigaOm emphasizes the critical role of integrated security measures in today’s digital landscape. The […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Top Tech Conferences &amp; Events to Add to Your Calendar in 2025&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-tech-conferences-events-to-add-to-your-calendar-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-tech-conferences-events-to-add-to-your-calendar-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great way to stay current with the latest technology trends and innovations is by attending conferences. Read and bookmark our tech events guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the Cloud | How Edge Computing is Unlocking IoT’s Full Potential</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beyond-the-cloud-how-edge-computing-is-unlocking-iots-full-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beyond-the-cloud-how-edge-computing-is-unlocking-iots-full-potential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) is transforming industries like healthcare, manufacturing, smart cities, and even autonomous vehicles—making our daily lives hyperconnected. But as more devices come online, relying solely on cloud computing can lead to slow response times, high bandwidth costs and security risks. The traditional cloud-based infrastructure struggles to keep up with the demands of real-time data processing, low latency, and proactive, preventative security. Before we dive in, let me explain what is edge computing is about and how it applies to IoT. Simply put, edge computing processes data right where it’s generated instead of routing it to remote […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Manufacturers Can Turn Security Into a Competitive Advantage</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-manufacturers-can-turn-security-into-a-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-manufacturers-can-turn-security-into-a-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/blog-manufacturers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digitization has significantly changed manufacturing over the past 25 years. The benefits include reducing inventory costs and machine downtime, and boosting throughput and forecasting accuracy. But as digitization has grown in prevalence, so have the security challenges facing manufacturers. This includes ransomware, legacy systems that are hard to patch, and third-party risk, among other types of threats. At the turn of the 21st century, production facilities were using software in various areas, but these systems were rarely integrated, and departments often operated in silos. Robotic assembly lines were already well established – primarily in the automotive industry – but were […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK government invests £40 million in 5G</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find out the possible benefits and challenges of the U.K. government’s 5G strategy and how it&amp;rsquo;s laying the foundations for 6G.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Virtualization?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtualization lets organizations run multiple isolated workloads from the same hardware platform, saving money, and enabling more efficient scaling. It is also used by cloud providers to deliver on-demand computing resources for multiple customers using shared hardware. It’s what allows businesses to pay for only the cloud computing resources they need and quickly (or even &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Check Point Ranks #1 in Threat Prevention Testing: Miercom 2025 Enterprise &amp; Hybrid Mesh Firewall Report&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-ranks-1-in-threat-prevention-testing-miercom-2025-enterprise-hybrid-mesh-firewall-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-ranks-1-in-threat-prevention-testing-miercom-2025-enterprise-hybrid-mesh-firewall-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-04-at-10.39.26-AM.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the third consecutive year, Check Point ranked #1 for security effectiveness in all categories of the Miercom Enterprise and Hybrid Mesh Firewall Report. This report includes two new metrics: SSE/SASE Threat Prevention and Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEVs). Miercom’s independent, head-to-head stress testing establishes how well a platform can detect and block the latest generations of cyber security threats in real-world scenarios. Blocking at least 99% of cyber attacks is a key objective, because even a 90% block rate can translate to hundreds of costly attacks. Organizations subject to these attacks can face data loss, credential theft, ransomware demands, and […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Security Management for the Hyperconnected World</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-04-at-11.17.57-AM.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Check Point CPO Nataly Kremer announcing new AI capabilities at CPX 2025&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s security approach is siloed. Each deployed security tool is designed to provide a specific type of protection across different areas like the network, endpoints, email, and cloud environments. This hybrid methodology, often requiring dozens of systems, leads to several security and operational challenges for security operations center (SOC) and network operations center (NOC) teams. Adopting a hybrid environment is unavoidable, and Gartner[1] anticipates that “By 2025, over 50% of network firewall deployments will involve more than two deployment factors from the same vendor — up from less than 10% in 2023.” [1]  While the benefits of this new ecosystem are […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPR Finds Threat Actors Already Leveraging DeepSeek and Qwen to Develop Malicious Content</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cpr-finds-threat-actors-already-leveraging-deepseek-and-qwen-to-develop-malicious-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cpr-finds-threat-actors-already-leveraging-deepseek-and-qwen-to-develop-malicious-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/blog-CPR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Check Point Research&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soon after the launch of AI models DeepSeek and Qwen, Check Point Research witnessed cyber criminals quickly shifting from ChatGPT to these new platforms to develop malicious content. Threat actors are sharing how to manipulate the models and show uncensored content, ultimately allowing hackers and criminals to use AI to create malicious content. Called jailbreaking, there are many methods to remove censors from AI models. However, we now see in-depth guides to jailbreaking methods, bypassing anti-fraud protections, and developing malware itself. This blog delves into how threat actors leverage these advanced models to develop harmful content, manipulate AI functionalities through […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Centres Can Cut Energy Use By Up To 30% With Just About 30 Lines of Code, Research Shows</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-centres-can-cut-energy-use-by-up-to-30-with-just-about-30-lines-of-code-research-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New research has found that data centres can reduce their energy usage by up to 30% simply by altering around 30 lines of code in the Linux kernel’s network stack.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner: Samsung Was the Top Semiconductor Vendor Globally in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung Electronics returned to number one partially on the strength of its memory device sales. Intel and NVIDIA followed in the rankings in spots two and three, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Organization from GenAI Risks with Harmony SASE</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/eliza1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love it or hate it, large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and other AI tools are reshaping the modern workplace. As AI becomes a critical part of daily work, establishing guardrails and deploying monitoring tools for these tools is critical. That’s where Check Point’s Harmony SASE comes in. We’ve already talked about Browser Security and the clipboard control feature to help define what types of information can’t be shared with LLMs. For monitoring these services, our GenAI Security service shows exactly which AI tools your team is using, who is using them, what kind of information they’re sharing with the […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Cheat Sheet: A Complete Guide for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get up and running with ChatGPT with this comprehensive cheat sheet. Learn everything from how to sign up for free to enterprise use cases, and start using ChatGPT quickly and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Autonomous Cyber Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Dan-v.1-e1737134156825.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of cyber security is no longer just about reacting to threats; it is about staying perpetually ahead in a world defined by complexity and speed. Autonomous cyber security represents a bold, transformative leap into the future—where intelligent, AI-driven systems operate at the edge of innovation, detecting, preventing, and responding to threats with unparalleled precision. This journey is more than technological advancement—it is a paradigm shift. By creating systems that think, reason, and act autonomously, organizations are poised to outpace adversaries and redefine what it means to be secure in an increasingly digitized world. The further along this journey […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways AI Can Help Organizations Tackle Cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Legacy security measures, while offering a baseline level of protection, heavily rely on predefined signatures and a narrow definition of the “abnormal.” They often follow a reactive approach, can be siloed, limiting information sharing, and lack the scalability to handle the terabytes of data generated by today’s complex IT systems. This is where artificial intelligence &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuing to Pioneer Cyber Security Excellence and Shaping the Future</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shutterstock_2403416063-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a trusted leader in cyber security, Check Point proudly acknowledges its 2024 accolades from leading analysts and research firms. These accolades and recognitions showcase Check Point’s innovation and dedication to protecting the digital world and ensuring digital trust across networks, clouds, and endpoints. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, global attacks against organizations significantly increased in 2024, with organizations experiencing an average of 1,673 attacks weekly—a significant 44% rise compared to the previous year. This increase emphasizes the escalating complexity and frequency of cyber threats, making it crucial for organizations to implement comprehensive security solutions to safeguard […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HT-ML Guard to Automatically Analyze and Secure HTML Files</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/blog-template-2000x700_5-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Highlights: HTML files are being used in phishing attacks, mimicking trusted websites HT-ML Guard is designed to analyze HTML files and accurately determine whether they are malicious, enhancing cyber security defenses. Check Point Harmony Email and Collaboration customers remain protected against this type of attack. HTML files are commonly used in the initial stages of cyber attacks. Cyber criminals craft these files to look legitimate, tempting unsuspecting users into a false sense of security. The main goal of these malicious HTML files is to deceive users into either disclosing sensitive information, such as login credentials and personal details, or downloading […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Leader’s Guide to Edge Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-edge-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-edge-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edge computing allows companies to deliver data processing and analysis capabilities to remote sites like branch offices, retail stores, warehouses, and manufacturing plants. Reducing their reliance on centralized cloud or data center resources can significantly improve performance and operational efficiency at remote (a.k.a., edge) business sites while mitigating security risks and enabling real-time insights. Nicole &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Steps to Address Human Impact of AI Adoption in the Workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this TechRepublic exclusive, Gartner analyst Autumn Stanish provides proactive and compassionate steps IT leaders can take to support employees as they navigate transitions related to AI integration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quick post on Chen’s algorithm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(April 19):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yilei Chen announced the discovery of a bug in the algorithm, which he does not know how to fix. This was independently discovered by Hongxun Wu and Thomas Vidick. At present, the paper does not provide a polynomial-time algorithm for solving LWE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a normal person — that is, a person who doesn’t obsessively follow the latest cryptography news — you probably missed last week’s cryptography bombshell. That news comes in the form of a new e-print authored by Yilei Chen, “Quantum Algorithms for Lattice Problems“, which has roiled the cryptography research community. The result is now being evaluated by experts in lattices and quantum algorithm design (&lt;em&gt;and to be clear, I am not one!&lt;/em&gt;) but if it holds up, it’s going to be quite a bad day/week/month/year for the applied cryptography community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
