<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awskeymanagementservice on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/awskeymanagementservice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awskeymanagementservice on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/awskeymanagementservice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AWS KMS Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) support</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-aws-kms-elliptic-curve-diffie-hellman-ecdh-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-aws-kms-elliptic-curve-diffie-hellman-ecdh-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When using cryptography to protect data, protocol designers often prefer symmetric keys and algorithms for their speed and efficiency. However, when data is exchanged across an untrusted network such as the internet, it becomes difficult to ensure that only the exchanging parties can know the same key. Asymmetric key pairs and algorithms help to solve […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When using cryptography to protect data, protocol designers often prefer symmetric keys and algorithms for their speed and efficiency. However, when data is exchanged across an untrusted network such as the internet, it becomes difficult to ensure that &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; the exchanging parties can know the same key. Asymmetric key pairs and algorithms help to solve this problem by allowing a public key to be shared over an untrusted network. And by using a key agreement scheme, two parties can use each other’s public key in combination with their own private key to each derive the same shared secret.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tune TLS for hybrid post-quantum cryptography with Kyber</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 30, 2024: The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info. January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
