<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdstrike on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/crowdstrike/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crowdstrike on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/crowdstrike/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike incident takeaways: Revisiting vendor quality control and release standards to minimize outage exposure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key learning from the outage caused by the faulty CrowdStrike “Rapid Response” update is how critical it is to understand your vendors’ quality control and release processes. Vendors should not only offer advanced technology to fulfill a business requirement but also demonstrate a strong commitment to reliability, security, and customer support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A variety of events and circumstances can cause an outage. This blog will suggest five areas to consider and questions to ask when evaluating your existing vendors and their risk management strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six causes of major software outages–And how to avoid them</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3d-abstract-beautiful-ba-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;software outages&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recent events have demonstrated, major software outages are an ever-present threat in our increasingly digital world. From business operations to personal communication, the reliance on software and cloud infrastructure is only increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outages can disrupt services, cause financial losses, and damage brand reputations. Understanding the causes of these outages is crucial for preventing them and ensuring smoother, more reliable tech operations. It’s also critical to have a strategy in place to address these outages, including both documented remediation processes and an observability platform to help you proactively identify and resolve issues to minimize customer and business impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
