<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Kotlin: Winners and Community Highlights</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-winners-and-community-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-winners-and-community-highlights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2024 in Kotlin! It was great to see so many of you sharing solutions to algorithmic puzzles and enjoying the holiday coding spirit with experts and the community. From December 1–12, we hosted livestreams with Kotlin Developer Advocate Sebastian Aigner and fantastic guests who shared […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2024 in Kotlin! It was great to see so many of you sharing solutions to algorithmic puzzles and enjoying the holiday coding spirit with experts and the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Steps in Game Development With Rust and Bevy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of us might remember this 15-year-old Abstruse Goose comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/unnamed.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Development vs Computer Science&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Some of us might remember this 15-year-old &lt;em&gt;Abstruse Goose&lt;/em&gt; comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. Many years ago, I did a course on rigid body dynamics that was definitely a part of the theoretical mechanics curriculum, not physics! Then, you’ll probably also need a bit of materials science, optics, and a smattering of other subjects. The good news is you’ll have loads of fun along the way. And while you’re still learning, game development engines and libraries can help you keep on top of some of the accidental complexity and give you enough functionality to implement the things you want, albeit at a fairly basic level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to detect and defeat spam | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-detect-and-defeat-spam-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-detect-and-defeat-spam-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simple tips for fighting spam email.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Hello, this is your distant relative from Nigeria. I’m writing because I have a terminal illness and no other living relatives. My dying wish is to transfer my inheritance of $100 million to you while I still can…”&lt;/em&gt; — we’ve all probably received an email like this at some point during our online existence. Originally known as “Nigerian prince” scams, today they bear the label “419” (after the section of the Nigerian Criminal Code dealing with fraud). These days, however, instead of a “Nigerian prince”, you’re more likely to receive a letter from a fake employee of a bank, online store, or delivery service — or even… the President of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Cheuk Ting Ho – New Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team. My home community […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled to introduce Isabel Garrido to our &lt;em&gt;Featured Content&lt;/em&gt; section – packed with handpicked articles, insights, and thought-provoking reads to keep you inspired. Let’s dive in and explore what’s shaping the technological ecosystem!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – January Digest</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-january-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-january-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-ahead-of-the-trends&#34;&gt;Stay Ahead of the Trends&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cs_learning_curve_2024.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;explore-global-trends-in-tech-education&#34;&gt;Explore Global Trends in Tech Education&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 23,000 learners from 16 countries and 7 regions shared their insights on the future of tech education. What motivates them? What are the most exciting new developments? Get all the answers in our detailed report.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Now Supports Claude Models via Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉 With the rise of high-quality language models, each excelling in different tasks, developers need flexible options to meet diverse challenges. That’s why we’re focused on providing multi-model support, helping you create workflows that fit your needs. Anthropic’s […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Tria stealer intercepts text messages on Android | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-tria-stealer-intercepts-text-messages-on-android-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-tria-stealer-intercepts-text-messages-on-android-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attackers are distributing the Tria stealer under the guise of wedding invitations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting married is certainly one of the most important events in anyone’s life. And in many cultures, it’s customary to invite hundreds of guests to the celebration — including some you barely know. Cybervillains take advantage of such traditions, using wedding invitations as bait to launch attacks on Android smartphone users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s what threat actors have come up with this time, and how to defeat it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models now available in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks. Now, we’ve added access to OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models to offer an even more adaptable and personalized experience with AI Assistant. What’s special about OpenAI o1? OpenAI’s o1 series of models are designed […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts for Paid Plugins</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins. What is the continuity discount? The continuity discount is a […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The biggest supply chain attacks in 2024 | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-biggest-supply-chain-attacks-in-2024-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-biggest-supply-chain-attacks-in-2024-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attacks on supply chains were one of the biggest threats in 2024. We discuss the most notable incidents of last year, and their consequences for the attacked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A supply-chain attack can totally thwart all a targeted company’s efforts to protect its infrastructure. Preventing such attacks is extremely difficult because a significant portion of an attack occurs in infrastructure that’s not within the security team’s control. This makes supply-chain attacks one of the most dangerous threats in recent years, and today we’ll look at some of the biggest that took place in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The JetBrains Platform Gets a New Community Space</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers are constantly trying to improve their work by adopting new approaches requiring tooling adjustments. This is where our incredible community of plugin and extension developers takes the initiative and develops great products, helping to meet the needs of even more users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-php-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-php-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like? To uncover deeper insights and trends shaping the ecosystem, we’ve turned to our in-house expert, Brent […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps. If you’re new to the framework and looking to set up your first Django project, grasping templates is vital. In this guide, you’ll […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is DAST? A Guide to Dynamic Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-dast-a-guide-to-dynamic-application-security-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-dast-a-guide-to-dynamic-application-security-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev. Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective for detecting issues that only occur when an application is running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Productive Java Development With Databases in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/9-tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/9-tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one. Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Create data sources automatically from properties IntelliJ IDEA makes it easy to create a data source for your […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Django Views</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-introduction-to-django-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-introduction-to-django-views/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered.  Gaining a better understanding of views will help […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;An Introduction to Django Views&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;⭐️ Marketplace updates Granular plugin feedback In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories: Aggregated ratings are shown in the Reviews tab. Find more details in our documentation.  Perpetual licenses for paid plugins JetBrains Marketplace now offers perpetual […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-marketplace-updates&#34;&gt;⭐️ Marketplace updates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;granular-plugin-feedback&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granular plugin feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive C&#43;&#43; Projects in Rider</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/faster-debugging-for-massive-c-projects-in-rider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/faster-debugging-for-massive-c-projects-in-rider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for Step Over, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute.  These delays occur in LLDB Debugger, the engine behind Rider’s debugging capabilities for C++ and other native languages. After months of focused […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for &lt;em&gt;Step Over&lt;/em&gt;, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Developer Population Reaches 19.6 Million in 2024: Explore the Updates in Our Data Playground</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/global-developer-population-reaches-19-6-million-in-2024-explore-the-updates-in-our-data-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/global-developer-population-reaches-19-6-million-in-2024-explore-the-updates-in-our-data-playground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, we launched the Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends. What’s New? To make it easier to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Featured-1280x720-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, we launched the &lt;strong&gt;Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground&lt;/strong&gt;, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Banshee stealer infects macOS users | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-the-banshee-stealer-infects-macos-users-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-the-banshee-stealer-infects-macos-users-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The dangerous Banshee stealer for Macs has learned how to bypass built-in macOS security, and continues to evolve. How to protect yourself?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many macOS users believe their operating system is immune to malware, so they don’t need to take extra security precautions. In reality, it’s far from the truth, and new threats keep popping up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-there-viruses-for-macos&#34;&gt;Are there viruses for macOS?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes — and plenty of ’em. Here are some examples of Mac malware we’ve previously covered on Kaspersky Daily and Securelist:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3: Kotlin K2 Mode Updates, Enhanced Logical Code Structure View, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3-kotlin-k2-mode-updates-enhanced-logical-code-structure-view-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3-kotlin-k2-mode-updates-enhanced-logical-code-structure-view-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu.  Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3 We’re covering all of the […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and LinkedIn Partner to Launch a Professional Certificate</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning. With over 1 billion members on the platform and 7 people hired every minute, LinkedIn provides unmatched access to professional growth opportunities. Together, with our expertise in software development and education, we’re combining the best of both worlds: […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JITWatch4i: Analyzing IntelliJ IDEA’s Startup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-ideas-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-ideas-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or C2 compilers and their resulting products – low-level assembly code. For the most part, the Java compilers are black boxes that typically remain closed under normal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/php-annotated-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/php-annotated-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 PHP 8.4 was officially released on November 21, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/ps-featured_blog_1280x720_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;PHP Annotated&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer Advocate – Will Vincent</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:william.vincent@jetbrains.com&#34;&gt;william.vincent@jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;. Background I’m a former Django Board Member and the author of three books on Django. Since 2019, I’ve co-hosted the Django Chat podcast […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/headshot_smile_smaller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:william.vincent@jetbrains.com&#34;&gt;william.vincent@jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware attacks in 2024 | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-attacks-in-2024-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-attacks-in-2024-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biggest and most high-profile ransomware incidents of 2024, and the consequences for targeted organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed a slight drop in the amount of coverage of ransomware on our Kaspersky Daily blog in recent years. Sadly, it’s not that ransomware attacks have stopped. Far from it — such incidents are now so commonplace that they’ve become part of the cyber-furniture. Nevertheless, some ransomware attacks still have the power to shock. In this post, we take you through the ransomware incidents of 2024 that made a lasting impression in terms of scale, impact, or mode of attack…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Conferences and Events in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration. As the IDE of choice for professional development in Java and Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA is built to support developers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What scareware is and how to protect yourself | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-scareware-is-and-how-to-protect-yourself-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-scareware-is-and-how-to-protect-yourself-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We explain what scareware is and why it’s dangerous, with tips for guarding against this threat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine: you’re calmly working away on your computer, when suddenly a scary message appears on the screen: “Your computer is infected with viruses! Install an antivirus immediately!” or “Your data is at risk! Clean your system immediately!” Panic? That’s what the scammers are hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post explains what scareware is and why this threat is dangerous. We also give tips for avoiding falling for scarewarers’ tricks, and protecting you and your family from such attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack 2025 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtrack-2025-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtrack-2025-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our commitment to you We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/yt-featured_blog_1280x720_en-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-commitment-to-you&#34;&gt;Our commitment to you&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that best fits your organization and data governance policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curious About The State of Software Quality?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/curious-about-the-state-of-software-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/curious-about-the-state-of-software-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready. To […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-social_share_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;State of Software Quality Report 2024&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.45 Is Here With Auto-Import for Gradle, Improved Preview for Markdown, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-45-is-here-with-auto-import-for-gradle-improved-preview-for-markdown-and-more-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-45-is-here-with-auto-import-for-gradle-improved-preview-for-markdown-and-more-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.45 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to migrate to SASE and zero trust | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-migrate-to-sase-and-zero-trust-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-migrate-to-sase-and-zero-trust-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SASE components: ZTNA, CASB CSWG, NGFW, SD-WAN, and how they improve network security&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The traditional network security model — with a secure perimeter and encrypted channels for external access to that perimeter — is coming apart at the seams. Cloud services and remote working have challenged the very notion of “perimeter”, while the primary method of accessing the perimeter — VPN — has in recent years become a prime attack vector for intruders. Many high-profile hacks began by exploiting vulnerabilities in VPN solutions: CVE-2023-46805, CVE-2024-21887 and CVE-2024-21893 in Ivanti Connect Secure, and CVE-2023-4966 in Citrix solutions. By compromising a VPN server, which needs to be accessible online, intruders gain privileged access to an enterprise’s internal network and plenty of scope for covert attack development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more developers are using Kotlin for server-side development, building reliable and efficient backend systems. Many of them also share their experiences through articles, videos, and sample projects. If you’re one of these creators, we want to recognize your work! Sharing your knowledge helps others solve real problems, improve their skills, and discover better […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More and more developers are using Kotlin for server-side development, building reliable and efficient backend systems. Many of them also share their experiences through articles, videos, and sample projects. If you’re one of these creators, we want to recognize your work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alret: Programming Prep Guide for the CSAI Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/livestream-alret-programming-prep-guide-for-the-csai-entrance-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/livestream-alret-programming-prep-guide-for-the-csai-entrance-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to study computer science in Europe? Enroll in the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos. Exclusive JetBrains scholarships are up for grabs! Join us on February 11, at 4:00 pm UTC, for a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this program. You’ll get first-hand tips […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/edu-email_photo_650x144-2x_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to study computer science in Europe? Enroll in the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos. Exclusive JetBrains scholarships are up for grabs!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.3.2: uv Package Management Support and More!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pycharm-2024-3-2-uv-package-management-support-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pycharm-2024-3-2-uv-package-management-support-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements! Get the latest version from our download page or update through our free Toolbox App.  Read this blog post to learn more about new features. Support for uv package management Take your environment management to the next level with uv […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;PyCharm 2024.3.2&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to remove metadata from photos, videos, and other files, and why do it at all | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-remove-metadata-from-photos-videos-and-other-files-and-why-do-it-at-all-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-remove-metadata-from-photos-videos-and-other-files-and-why-do-it-at-all-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Metadata can reveal information that should remain confidential. We explain how to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me, you probably share plenty of photos, videos and documents, and send lots of voice messages and emails every single day too. But how often do you stop to consider the additional data contained in these files? For each of these files/media contains metadata — which can reveal a lot of interesting details not meant for prying eyes; for example, a photo’s time and location, a document’s editing history, device information, IP address, geolocation, and much more. So, for example, whenever you post an innocent selfie on social media, you’re also making public a whole ton of extra information that you might not necessarily want others to see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: Top Courses and Projects of 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong.  To mark this impressive milestone, we’re looking back at the most popular JetBrains Academy offerings of 2024 – including JetBrains IDE courses (designed exclusively for IDEs) and Hyperskill projects (available […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Is Now Available on AWS Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS). TeamCity interface Whether you’re already an AWS user or exploring AWS for your next project, TeamCity on AWS Marketplace […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2: Containerfile Support and Updates for Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2-containerfile-support-and-updates-for-dockerfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2-containerfile-support-and-updates-for-dockerfiles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out! With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios. You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Junie, Your Coding Agent by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Blog_1280x720.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But can we go beyond that and boost productivity even further – improve code quality, unlock future innovations, help execute complex tasks, and change the way you work with code? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.4 Bug-Fix Updates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4-bug-fix-updates-are-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4-bug-fix-updates-are-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download.  ReSharper 2024.3.4 For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.4 We’ve also fixed several issues affecting .NET MAUI development: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resharper-202434&#34;&gt;ReSharper 2024.3.4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve fixed local privilege escalation in the ETW Host Service (CVE-2025-23385).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anomaly Detection in Time Series&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making anomaly detection a valuable tool in industries like sales, finance, manufacturing, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0411 – vulnerability in 7-Zip | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0411-vulnerability-in-7-zip-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0411-vulnerability-in-7-zip-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A vulnerability CVE-2025-0411 in the 7-Zip file archiver allows bypassing the Mark-of-the-Web (MOTW) mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability CVE-2025-0411 has been discovered in the popular 7-Zip file archiver software, allowing attackers to bypass the Mark-of-the-Web protection mechanism. CVE-2025-0411 has a 7.0 CVSS rating. The vulnerability was quickly fixed, but since the program doesn’t have an automatic update mechanism, some users may still have a vulnerable version. That’s why we recommend immediately updating the archiver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fixing-unreal-engine-project-issues-with-qodana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fixing-unreal-engine-project-issues-with-qodana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-featured_blog_1280x720_en-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects – from virtual reality prototypes to triple-A games. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to download, install, and update Kaspersky apps for Android | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-download-install-and-update-kaspersky-apps-for-android-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-download-install-and-update-kaspersky-apps-for-android-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to download, install, and update Kaspersky apps for Android from alternative stores.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our security solutions for Android are temporarily unavailable in the official Google Play store. To install Kaspersky apps on Android devices, we recommend using alternative app stores. You can also install our apps manually from the APK files available on our website or in your My Kaspersky account. This post gives in-depth instructions for installing Kaspersky on Android in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing  Perpetual Licenses on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing. Licensing options on JetBrains Marketplace The current licensing schemes available on JetBrains Marketplace include: The licensing type (with or without fallback) and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mps-2024-3-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mps-2024-3-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 What’s new Let’s check out the new features we’ve prepared for you in this release. Top-level folder […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results of Google Summer of Code 2024 With the Kotlin Foundation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/results-of-google-summer-of-code-2024-with-the-kotlin-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/results-of-google-summer-of-code-2024-with-the-kotlin-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains. Join our Slack channel […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1&lt;/strong&gt;, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1&lt;/strong&gt;, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hype and confusion surrounding quantum computers in cryptography</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hype-and-confusion-surrounding-quantum-computers-in-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hype-and-confusion-surrounding-quantum-computers-in-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who claimed quantum supremacy and decryption on quantum computers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers remain a highly exotic technology, used by a very small number of companies for very specific computational tasks. But if you search for “quantum computer news”, you might get the impression that all the major IT players have already armed themselves with quantum technology, and that any day now hackers will start using it to crack encrypted communications and manipulate digital signatures. The reality is both less tense and more complex — but such nuances don’t make the headlines. So, who’s been making all the noise about quantum hacking?…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-1-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-1-is-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we encourage you to try out the new build and share your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-1-is-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-1-is-now-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider.  There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning-using-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is anomaly detection – processes that enable […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is &lt;strong&gt;anomaly detection&lt;/strong&gt; – processes that enable us to identify outliers, data that is outside the bounds of expectation and demonstrate behavior that is out of the norm. In scientific research, anomaly data points could be a cause of technical issues and may need to be discarded when drawing conclusions, or it could lead to new discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dotinsights-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dotinsights-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know? The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing. Fears of disruptions in critical systems like banking and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you know?&lt;/strong&gt; The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-2-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-2-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – v2024.3.2. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – v2024.3.2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever. You can download this version from our website, update directly from […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Named a Customers’ Choice Again for Integrated Development Environment Software</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-named-a-customers-choice-again-for-integrated-development-environment-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-named-a-customers-choice-again-for-integrated-development-environment-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year.  Read the Report A trusted vendor We believe JetBrains’ consistent innovation and developer-first approach have earned […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legitimate Chrome extensions are stealing Facebook passwords</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/legitimate-chrome-extensions-are-stealing-facebook-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/legitimate-chrome-extensions-are-stealing-facebook-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supply-chain attacks use trojanized legitimate Google Chrome extensions for data theft.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right after Christmas, news broke of a multi-stage attack targeting developers of popular Chrome extensions. Ironically, the biggest-name target was a cybersecurity extension created by Cyberhaven — compromised just before the holidays (we’d previously warned about such risks). As the incident investigation unfolded, the list grew to include no fewer than 35 popular extensions, with a combined total of 2.5 million installations. The attackers’ goal was to steal data from the browsers of users who installed trojanized updates of these extensions. The focus of the campaign was on stealing credentials for Meta services to compromise business accounts and display ads at victims’ expense. However, that’s not the only data that malicious extensions can steal from browsers. We explain how the attack works, and what measures you can take to protect yourself against it at different stages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New gadgets unveiled at CES 2025, and their impact on security | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-gadgets-unveiled-at-ces-2025-and-their-impact-on-security-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-gadgets-unveiled-at-ces-2025-and-their-impact-on-security-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity trends at the Consumer Electronics Show: from AI glasses to biometric locks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s premier tech events traditionally takes place every year in Las Vegas in early January. Sure, the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) pays attention to cybersecurity, but by no means is it top of the agenda. Looking for a giant monitor or AI washing machine? You’re in luck! Smart home protection against hackers? Might have to shop around a bit…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support for .env Files: Now Built into PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-env-files-now-built-into-phpstorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-env-files-now-built-into-phpstorm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.env files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code. Previously, developers using PhpStorm had to manually install the .env Files Support plugin, originally created by Adel Faizrakhmanov, to unlock dedicated features for working with these […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-clion-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-clion-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GoLand 2025.1 Early Access Program Has Started!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers. The first EAP build can be downloaded via the Toolbox App, from our website, or as a […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing CodeCanvas 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead! CodeCanvas 2024.3, last year’s final release, went live just before the holidays. To avoid adding to the busy year-end rush, we delayed the announcement until now, ensuring it gets the attention […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passwords 101: don’t enter your passwords just anywhere they’re asked for | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/passwords-101-dont-enter-your-passwords-just-anywhere-theyre-asked-for-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/passwords-101-dont-enter-your-passwords-just-anywhere-theyre-asked-for-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to distinguish a fraudulent site from a real one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever you’re asked to log in to an online service, verify your identity, or download a document through a link, you’re usually required to enter your username and password. This is so common that most of us do it automatically without thinking twice. However, scammers can trick you into giving them passwords for your email, government service websites, banking services, or social networks by mimicking the service’s login form on their own (third-party) website. Don’t fall for it: only the email service itself can ask to verify your email password — no one else! The same applies to government services, banks, and social networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusted-relationship cyberattacks and their prevention</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to work with suppliers to reduce the risk of incidents related to supply-chain cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old saying, “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link”, directly applies to enterprise cybersecurity. Businesses these days often rely on dozens or even hundreds of suppliers and contractors, who, in turn, use the services and products of yet more contractors and suppliers. And when these chains involve not raw materials but complex IT products, ensuring their security becomes significantly more challenging. This fact is exploited by attackers, who compromise a link in the chain to reach its end — their main target. Accordingly, it’s essential for business leaders and the heads of IT and information security to understand the risks of supply-chain attacks in order to manage them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BadRAM: attack using malicious RAM module | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/badram-attack-using-malicious-ram-module-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/badram-attack-using-malicious-ram-module-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Theoretical BadRAM attack on virtualization systems exploits a vulnerability in AMD EPYC processors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers from three European universities recently demonstrated the so-called BadRAM attack. This attack is made possible because of a vulnerability in AMD EPYC processors, and primarily threatens cloud-solution providers and virtualization systems. In the worst-case scenario, the vulnerability could be used to compromise data from highly secure virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, implementing this scenario in practice would be quite difficult. The attack requires physical access to the server, plus the highest level of access to the software. Before discussing the BadRAM attack in detail, we should first understand the concept of a trusted execution environment (TEE).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How vulnerable Ecovacs robot vacuums are being hacked | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-vulnerable-ecovacs-robot-vacuums-are-being-hacked-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-vulnerable-ecovacs-robot-vacuums-are-being-hacked-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How cyberhooligans are hacking vulnerable Ecovacs robot vacuums and lawnmowers to spy on their owners and rain misery upon them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine: you get up in the night for a glass of water, walk across the unlit landing, when out of the darkness a voice starts yelling at you. Not nice, you’d surely agree. But that’s the new reality for owners of vulnerable robot vacuums, which can be commanded by hackers to turn from domestic servants into foul-mouthed louts. And that’s not all: hackers can also control the robot remotely and access its live camera feed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term &lt;em&gt;real-world&lt;/em&gt; data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to learn quickly without needing to venture into the world of data cleaning, but real-world data has problems and is messy. Real-world data needs cleaning before it can give us useful insights, and that’s the subject of this blog post. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge! Featured Content  Greetings, Java Annotated Monthly readers! […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rider-2025-1-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rider-2025-1-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date. With that in mind, let’s dive […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for cyberthreats and trends in 2025 from Kaspersky experts | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/predictions-for-cyberthreats-and-trends-in-2025-from-kaspersky-experts-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/predictions-for-cyberthreats-and-trends-in-2025-from-kaspersky-experts-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What to expect in 2025: the rise of AI, new scams, and a potential social-media ban&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every year, Kaspersky experts briefly turn into soothsayers. No, our colleagues don’t reach for crystal balls, tarot cards or horoscopes to see into the cybersecurity future; their predictions are based on an analysis of the global trends and threats we encounter in our daily work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And they’re often spot-on: for 2024, we predicted a rise in scams tied to play-to-earn (P2E) games, the proliferation of voice deepfakes, and other trends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Courses for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-courses-for-java-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-courses-for-java-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I.  I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake. After months of intensive research and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
