<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Secure on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/secure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Secure on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/secure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 NIST rules on minimum password length: Aim for 16 characters or more!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta our focus is to keep our users&amp;rsquo; data secure with quantum-safe encryption. To achieve maximum security, the importance of strong, secure passwords that are long enough cannot be overstated. Passwords and the password length are the first line of defense to make sure that no unauthorized access can bring harm to your data or yourself. While factors like complexity and unpredictability matter, experts emphasize that length is a critical element in ensuring password security. But given new threats of quantum computers, what is the optimal minimum password length recommended by NIST and CISA?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 reasons you should you use 2FA apps over SMS-based authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2FA over SMS isn&amp;rsquo;t just unreliable, it&amp;rsquo;s also a security risk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MFA, or Multi-Factor Authentication, has proliferated throughout our computing lives over the last decade. It largely began with SMS-based authentication in addition to a password, allowing users to add an extra layer of authentication by forcing users to enter a code sent to their phone upon an attempted login. The truth is, SMS-based authentication was never secure. Due to the inherent technology and the infrastructure around SIM cards, 2FA with SMS is not only inadequate; it also actively compromises your security, and here are 4 reasons why you should use a dedicated 2FA app instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous SOC Is a Journey, Not a Destination | Introducing The Autonomous SOC Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about autonomous SOC and how SentinelOne uses a maturity model to frame the shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The autonomous SOC: A well-grounded vision for the future of machine speed, AI-driven cyber defense, or nothing more than a pipe dream? Few concepts in modern security have been as polarizing, with sides painted as distinct camps of “believers” versus “non-believers”, each accompanied by increasingly hyperbolic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SentinelOne, you will hear us and our customers talk about the autonomous SOC and the fundamental shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations. Today, we want to be clear about what we mean when we say that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0282 (CVSS 9.0): Ivanti Confirms Active Exploitation of Critical Flaw</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0282-cvss-9-0-ivanti-confirms-active-exploitation-of-critical-flaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0282-cvss-9-0-ivanti-confirms-active-exploitation-of-critical-flaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;cve-2025-0282-cvss-90-ivanti-confirms-active-exploitation-of-critical-flaw&#34;&gt;CVE-2025-0282 (CVSS 9.0): Ivanti Confirms Active Exploitation of Critical Flaw&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23048/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ivanti has issued a security advisory addressing two vulnerabilities in its Connect Secure, Policy Secure, and Neurons for ZTA Gateways. The vulnerabilities—CVE-2025-0282 and CVE-2025-0283—pose signif &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (3 hours, 3 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Things First | SentinelOne Is A Fortune Best Workplace for Parents</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents, ranking among the top 70 companies worldwide for working parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wellbeing comes first at SentinelOne – for our customers, our communities, and our colleagues. We are proud to foster a culture of diversity, equality, and understanding for all. Supporting our working parents and the notion of a family’s evolving needs is a key part of that philosophy, and that is why we are extremely proud to be included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting AI Infrastructures | Introducing SentinelOne’s AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne’s new AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution helps organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of AI introduces unique security considerations. Misconfigurations in AI infrastructure and unsecured APIs can create weaknesses that cybercriminals will exploit. In this blog post, we dive deep into how SentinelOne’s agentless AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution addresses these challenges by offering AI inventory automation, misconfiguration detection, and attack path analysis to help organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing AWS Lambda | How Misconfigurations Can Lead to Lateral Movement</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how several misconfigurations and user-defined code issues in AWS Lambda could lead to potential credential theft and lateral movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As serverless computing continues to revolutionize the cloud landscape, AWS Lambda has emerged as a pivotal service, offering a Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) model that allows developers to focus solely on code while AWS manages the underlying infrastructure. This shift towards serverless architectures brings new security challenges and considerations that security researchers and professionals must understand and address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Safe and Secure K-12 Schools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-safe-and-secure-k-12-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-safe-and-secure-k-12-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Cyber Trust Mark logo for smart devices is coming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White House announced the launch of the US Cyber Trust Mark which aims to help buyers make an informed choice about the purchase of wireless internet-connected devices, such as baby monitors, doorbells, thermostats, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity labeling program for wireless consumer Internet of Things (IoT) products is voluntary but the participants include several major manufacturers, retailers, and trade associations for popular electronics, appliances, and consumer products. The companies and groups said they are committed to increase cybersecurity for the products they sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is phishing?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During phishing, a target or targets are approached by email, telephone, or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution. This is done to lure individuals into providing sensitive data such as passwords, banking and credit card details, and personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information is then used to access sensitive accounts, resulting in identity theft and financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of phishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; spear phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;search engine phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;email phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Features of Phishing:-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
