<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ux on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/ux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ux on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Midori Browser 11.5 Added Headless Mode &amp; New App Icon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ubuntuhandbook.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/midora-newicon-250x250.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori web browser announced new 11.5 release recently with some exciting new features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori was a popular lightweight web browser that was default in elementary OS and Bodhi Linux. It’s now a free open-source Firefox derived browser developed by Astian Foundation, and licensed under the Mozilla Public License (MPL).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The browser released new 11.5 recently, changed its app icon from a green lizard to &lt;strong&gt;new flat design logo&lt;/strong&gt; that IMO feels better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 essential Linux commands for every user</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From new user to power user, here are 20 Linux commands that will make your life easier.Typing commands into a darkened terminal window might seem puzzling, but for many computer users, it&amp;rsquo;s the most efficient, most accessible and clearest way to accomplish nearly any task on a computer. These days, thanks to all the projects that bring open source commands to non-open platforms like macOS and Windows, and with containers running everywhere, terminal commands are relevant to everybody. Try Red Hat Enterprise Linux before you buy, with a free 60-day evaluation.Here are the top 20 commands a mod&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-52869 - Teradata SUSE Enterprise Linux Server Elevated Privilege Group Misassignment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-52869&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Certain Teradata account-handling code through 2024-11-04, used with SUSE Enterprise Linux Server, mismanages groups. Specifically, when there is an operating system move from SUSE Enterprise Linux Server (SLES) 12 Service Pack (SP) 2 or 3 to SLES 15 SP2 on Teradata Database systems, some service/system user accounts, and possibly systems administrator created user accounts, are incorrectly assigned to groups that allow higher system-level privileges than intended for those user accounts. Depending on the usage of these accounts, this may lead to full system compromise.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
