<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quantumcomputing on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/quantumcomputing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quantumcomputing on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/quantumcomputing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Cybersecurity Priorities for The Trump Administration</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024: A year when AI, quantum computing, and cybersecurity converged to redefine our digital landscape. For those navigating these complex technological frontiers, clarity became the most critical currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inside Cyber, Key moments that resonated with our community:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Cybersecurity Trends for 2025 Diving deep into the evolving threat landscape and strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• AI, 5G, and Quantum: Innovation and Cybersecurity Risks Exploring the intersection of emerging technologies and security challenges &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&#34;&gt;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s a weird, weird quantum world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1994, as Professor Peter Shor PhD ’85 tells it, internal seminars at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs were lively affairs. The audience of physicists was an active and inquisitive bunch, often pelting speakers with questions throughout their talks. Shor, who worked at Bell Labs at the time, remembers several occasions when a speaker couldn’t get past their third slide, as they attempted to address a rapid line of questioning before their time was up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerry Emanuel,  David Sabatini, and Peter Shor receive BBVA Frontiers of Knowledge awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBVA Foundation awarded three MIT professors Frontiers of Knowledge Awards for their work in climate change, biology and biomedicine, and quantum computation. Department of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences Professor Kerry A. Emanuel, Department of Biology Professor David Sabatini, and Department of Mathematics Professor Peter Shor were recognized in the 12th edition of this annual award.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kerry Emanuel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emanuel, the Cecil and Ida Green Professor of Atmospheric Science, earned the BBVA’s Climate Change award “for his fundamental contributions to the understanding of tropical cyclones and how they are affected by climate change,” according to the committee’s citation. “By understanding the essential physics of atmospheric convection … he has unraveled the behavior of tropical cyclones — hurricanes and typhoons — as our climate changes.” He was also lauded for “extraordinary effectiveness in communicating the science of climate change to the public and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Is Adding New Cryptography Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is updating SymCrypt, its core cryptographic library, with new quantum-secure algorithms. Microsoft’s details are here. From a news article:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first new algorithm Microsoft added to SymCrypt is called ML-KEM. Previously known as CRYSTALS-Kyber, ML-KEM is one of three post-quantum standards formalized last month by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). The KEM in the new name is short for key encapsulation. KEMs can be used by two parties to negotiate a shared secret over a public channel. Shared secrets generated by a KEM can then be used with symmetric-key cryptographic operations, which aren’t vulnerable to Shor’s algorithm when the keys are of a sufficient size&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor receives 2022-2023 Killian Award</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Renowned mathematician and quantum computing pioneer Peter W. Shor PhD ’85 has been named the recipient of MIT’s 2022-2023 James R. Killian Jr. Faculty Achievement Award, the highest honor the Institute faculty can bestow upon one of its members each academic year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Killian Award citation credits Shor, who is the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics, with having made “seminal contributions that have forever shaped the foundations of quantum computing. Indeed, quantum computing exists today, in practice, because of Peter Shor.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor wins Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Shor, the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics at MIT, has been named a recipient of the 2023 Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics. He shares the $3 million prize with three others for “foundational work in the field of quantum information”: David Deutsch at the University of Oxford, Charles Bennett at IBM Research, and Gilles Brassard of the University of Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In announcing the award, the Breakthrough Prize Foundation highlighted Shor’s contributions to the quantum information field, including the eponymous Shor’s algorithm for factoring extremely large numbers, and for an algorithm to correct errors in quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Advice for PQC Migration for TLS 1.3</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/practical-advice-for-pqc-migration-for-tls-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/practical-advice-for-pqc-migration-for-tls-1-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Numerous blogs and articles are urging security professionals to start migrating to quantum-resistant algorithms immediately. This urgency was heightened on August 13, 2024, when NIST finalized the FIPS 203 (ML-KEM), FIPS 204 (ML-DSA), and FIPS 205 (SLH-DSA) standards. In this article, I present a simplified example of a client establishing a TLS 1.3 connection to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Practical Advice for PQC Migration for TLS 1.3 appeared first on Security Boulevard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a code-breaking quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most recent email you sent was likely encrypted using a tried-and-true method that relies on the idea that even the fastest computer would be unable to efficiently break a gigantic number into factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers, on the other hand, promise to rapidly crack complex cryptographic systems that a classical computer might never be able to unravel. This promise is based on a quantum factoring algorithm proposed in 1994 by Peter Shor, who is now a professor at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
