<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyberattack on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyberattack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyberattack on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyberattack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Black Swan’ Event That Could Upend Life in 2025: The World’s Largest Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 futurists, foreign policy analysts and other prognosticators provide Politico readers some explosive potential scenarios for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gary Marcus, author of the book “Taming Silicon Valley”, one of The New Yorker’s recommended books in 2024, warns 2025 could easily see the largest cyberattack in history, taking down, at least for a little while, some sizeable piece of the world’s infrastructure, whether for deliberate ransom or to manipulate people to make money off a short on global markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;US Treasury Department Sanctions Chinese Company Over Cyberattacks&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-treasury-department-sanctions-chinese-company-over-cyberattacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-treasury-department-sanctions-chinese-company-over-cyberattacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sanctions target Beijing Integrity Technology Group, which U.S. officials say employed workers responsible for the Flax Typhoon attacks which compromised devices including routers and internet-enabled cameras to infiltrate government and industrial targets in the United States, Taiwan, Europe and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sanctions target Beijing Integrity Technology Group, which U.S. officials say employed workers responsible for the Flax Typhoon attacks which compromised devices including routers and internet-enabled cameras to infiltrate government and industrial targets in the United States, Taiwan, Europe and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity 2025 | Preparing for Tomorrow’s Threats, Challenges and Strategic Shifts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore SentinelLabs&amp;rsquo; take on what 2025 may bring for cybersecurity, including emerging trends and actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crystal balls are notoriously fragile, and those who look into them are wise not to become fixated with the shadows cast by their refracted light, yet no business can function without some meaningful sense of what the future might hold. Reading the tea leaves of the past can offer no insight into novel and unexpected events to come, but it can help us prepare for that which is already forming in the shadows. Ultimately, the entire point of intelligence is to enable forward-looking decisions, and this means we’ll hit the mark with some and miss with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGERBEE Malware Detection: New Backdoor Variant Targets Internet Service Providers and State Bodies in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Eagerbee-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the re-emergence of a more advanced NonEuclid RAT variant in the cyber threat arena, a novel malware iteration known as the Eagerbee backdoor poses an increasing threat to organizations in the Middle East, primarily targeting Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and state agencies. The enhanced EAGERBEE backdoor variant can deploy payloads, scan file systems, and execute command shells, displaying significant evolution of its offensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Web-Based Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally published on Security Boulevard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-people-web-browsers-and-security&#34;&gt;Connecting People, Web Browsers and Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web browser has transformed significantly in recent years, becoming one of the most used tools for work today. However, as organizations adopt hybrid work models and cloud-based operations, securing this work tool has proved a challenge. Security infrastructures haven’t evolved as fast as the browser, making them prone to cyberattacks. With browsers being the primary gateway to the internet, any security lapse can lead to broad opportunities for significant data breaches and operational disruptions. Understanding the risks and implementing robust security measures is crucial for safeguarding the work we do today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why security teams rely on Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR for managed detection and response</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The expanding attack surface is creating more opportunities for exploitation and adding to the pressure on security leaders and teams. Increasingly, organizations are investing in managed detection and response services (MDR) to bolster their security operations center (SOC) and meet the challenge. Demand is growing rapidly: according to Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan, the market for MDR is expanding at a rate of 35.2% annually.1   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are new vendors launching MDR services regularly, many security teams are turning to Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR, a recognized leader, to deliver comprehensive coverage.1 Employed worldwide by organizations across industries, Microsoft’s team of dedicated experts proactively hunts for cyberthreats and triages, investigates, and responds to incidents on a customer’s behalf around the clock across their most critical assets. Our proven service brings together in-house security professionals and industry-leading protection with Microsoft Defender XDR to help security teams rapidly stop cyberthreats and keep their environments secure.2 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
