<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Srg on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/srg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Srg on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/srg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-adaptive thresholds for AI-driven quality gating</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0146_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;auto-adaptive thresholds&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest release of the Site Reliability Guardian incorporates assistance from Dynatrace Davis® AI to automatically derive appropriate threshold targets and adjust them over time to protect your quality improvements. This process, known as auto-adaptive thresholding, eliminates the need to define a static threshold upfront. Instead, it derives the suitable thresholds from previous validation results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-an-umbrella-for-development-and-operations&#34;&gt;Build an umbrella for Development and Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, the discipline of platform engineering delivers DevSecOps practices to developers to bridge the gaps between development, security, and operations and enhance the developer experience. A key element in platform engineering is the establishment of fast feedback cycles regarding the quality and security measures of new software releases. To provide automated feedback for developers, the concept of quality gates for static code analysis in continuous integration is widely adopted throughout the industry. However, this perspective differs in the continuous deployment practices of various organizations, where the feedback is either delayed or not returned to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
