<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Messaging on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/messaging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Messaging on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/messaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dear Apple: add “Disappearing Messages” to iMessage right now</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a cryptography blog and I always feel the need to apologize for any post that isn’t “straight cryptography.” I’m actually getting a little tired of apologizing for it (though if you want some hard-core cryptography content, there’s plenty here and here.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have to remind my colleagues that out in the real world, our job is not to solve exciting mathematical problems: &lt;em&gt;it’s to help people communicate securely&lt;/em&gt;. And people, at this very moment, need a lot of help. Many of my friends are Federal employees or work for contractors, and they’re terrified that they’re going to lose their job based on speech they post online. Unfortunately, “online” to many people includes thoughts sent over private text messages — so even private conversations are becoming chilled. And while this is hardly the worst thing happening to people in this world, it’s something that’s happening to my friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
