<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intermediate200 on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/intermediate200/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intermediate200 on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/intermediate200/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enable post-quantum key exchange in QUIC with the s2n-quic library</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enable-post-quantum-key-exchange-in-quic-with-the-s2n-quic-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enable-post-quantum-key-exchange-in-quic-with-the-s2n-quic-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated to only support Kyber. BIKE or other KEMs may still be added as the standardization proceeds. At Amazon Web Services (AWS) we prioritize security, performance, and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 25, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated to only support Kyber. BIKE or other KEMs may still be added as the standardization proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encryption in transit over external networks: AWS guidance for NYDFS and beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction to its Cybersecurity Resource Center, the Department explains that the revisions are aimed at addressing the changes in the increasing sophistication of threat actors, the prevalence of and relative ease in running cyberattacks, and the availability of additional controls to manage cyber risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tune TLS for hybrid post-quantum cryptography with Kyber</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 30, 2024: The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info. January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
