<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/hacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hacking on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/hacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Microsoft Takes Legal Action Against AI “Hacking as a Service” Scheme&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-takes-legal-action-against-ai-hacking-as-a-service-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-takes-legal-action-against-ai-hacking-as-a-service-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure this will matter in the end, but it’s a positive move:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is accusing three individuals of running a “hacking-as-a-service” scheme that was designed to allow the creation of harmful and illicit content using the company’s platform for AI-generated content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The foreign-based defendants developed tools specifically designed to bypass safety guardrails Microsoft has erected to prevent the creation of harmful content through its generative AI services, said Steven Masada, the assistant general counsel for Microsoft’s Digital Crimes Unit. They then compromised the legitimate accounts of paying customers. They combined those two things to create a fee-based platform people could use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Apps That Are Spying on Your Location&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;404 Media is reporting on all the apps that are spying on your location, based on a hack of the location data company Gravy Analytics:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thousands of apps, included in hacked files from location data company Gravy Analytics, include everything from games like Candy Crush to dating apps like Tinder, to pregnancy tracking and religious prayer apps across both Android and iOS. Because much of the collection is occurring through the advertising ecosystem­—not code developed by the app creators themselves—­this data collection is likely happening both without users’ and even app developers’ knowledge&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote hacking is possible for Garrett walk-through metal detectors.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A network component in Garrett Metal Detectors contains a number of security flaws that could allow remote attackers to bypass authentication requirements, tamper with metal detector configurations, and even execute arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a disclosure released last week, Cisco Talos noted that an attacker could use this module to remotely monitor statistics on a metal detector, such as whether the alarm has been triggered or how many visitors passed through. “They could also alter device configurations, such as changing the sensitivity level, potentially posing a security risk to users of these metal detectors.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Salt Typhoon’s Reach Continues to Grow&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/salt-typhoons-reach-continues-to-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/salt-typhoons-reach-continues-to-grow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US government has identified a ninth telecom that was successfully hacked by Salt Typhoon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US government has identified a ninth telecom that was successfully hacked by Salt Typhoon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Spyware Maker NSO Group Found Liable for Hacking WhatsApp&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spyware-maker-nso-group-found-liable-for-hacking-whatsapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spyware-maker-nso-group-found-liable-for-hacking-whatsapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A judge has found that NSO Group, maker of the Pegasus spyware, has violated the US Computer Fraud and Abuse Act by hacking WhatsApp in order to spy on people using it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jon Penney and I wrote a legal paper on the case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A judge has found that NSO Group, maker of the Pegasus spyware, has violated the US Computer Fraud and Abuse Act by hacking WhatsApp in order to spy on people using it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
