<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technicalhow-To on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/technicalhow-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technicalhow-To on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/technicalhow-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Encryption in transit over external networks: AWS guidance for NYDFS and beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction to its Cybersecurity Resource Center, the Department explains that the revisions are aimed at addressing the changes in the increasing sophistication of threat actors, the prevalence of and relative ease in running cyberattacks, and the availability of additional controls to manage cyber risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to secure your SaaS tenant data in DynamoDB with ABAC and client-side encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that can help you protect your customers and earn their trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use tokenization to improve data security and reduce audit scope</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-tokenization-to-improve-data-security-and-reduce-audit-scope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-tokenization-to-improve-data-security-and-reduce-audit-scope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April 25, 2023: We’ve updated this blog post to include more security learning resources. Tokenization of sensitive data elements is a hot topic, but you may not know what to tokenize, or even how to determine if tokenization is right for your organization’s business needs. Industries subject to financial, data security, regulatory, or privacy compliance […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 25, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve updated this blog post to include more security learning resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
