<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions: Areg Danagoulian on a new arms control tool and the future of nuclear security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Areg Danagoulian, associate professor in the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering, has built a career around nuclear detection technology. His work has focused, among other things, on a system that could greatly improve the current process for verifying compliance of nuclear warheads.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this year, he published new work on physical cryptographic nuclear warhead verification and on active detection of shielded nuclear materials in journals including&lt;/em&gt; Nature Communications &lt;em&gt;and the&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of the National Academy of Science. &lt;em&gt;He has also received a pair of prestigious accolades: a radiation science and technology award from the American Nuclear Society and the honor of being named, along with his team, as the 2019 Arms Control Association (ACA) Arms Control Persons of the Year.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;“This innovation paves the way for more effective arms control agreements, inspections, and enforcement,&amp;quot; said Daryl Kimball, executive director of the ACA. &amp;ldquo;Professor Danagoulian’s MIT team has brought the best science to arms control and provided a creative solution that can reduce nuclear threats and enhance security.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions: Ron Rivest on trusting electronic voting systems</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-ron-rivest-on-trusting-electronic-voting-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-ron-rivest-on-trusting-electronic-voting-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ron Rivest is an MIT Institute Professor in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. He’s an authority on algorithms and an inventor of the RSA public-key cryptosystem, one of the most widely used algorithms to securely transmit data. Since the 1980s, he’s taught students how to use cryptography to help secure voting systems. Then, in 2000, an historic recount in Florida determined the outcome of the U.S. presidential election, and the Caltech / MIT Voting Technology Project was founded with the mission to secure future elections, pulling in Rivest, who has been involved since, as well as other MIT faculty from the Department of Political Science and the MIT Sloan School of Management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
