<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big-Data on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/big-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big-Data on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/big-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Colab vs Jupyter Notebook: Key Differences Explained</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-colab-vs-jupyter-notebook-key-differences-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-colab-vs-jupyter-notebook-key-differences-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Colab and Jupyter Notebook are powerful tools for coding and data analysis, each offering unique features and benefits. Compare them to choose the best fit for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Kit: MongoDB Administrator</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-mongodb-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-mongodb-administrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the growing importance of big data for businesses, the need for database programs that are adaptable and scalable has become a priority. Enter MongoDB, an open-source database program that can accommodate a variety of programming languages. This customizable hiring kit from TechRepublic Premium provides a framework you can use to find the best candidate &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some rough impressions of Worldcoin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a reader wrote in and asked if I would look at Sam Altman’s Worldcoin, presumably to give thoughts on it from a privacy perspective. This was honestly the last thing I wanted to do, since life is short and this seemed like an obvious waste of it. Of course a project &lt;em&gt;devoted to literally scanning your eyeballs&lt;/em&gt; was up to some bad things, duh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However: the request got me curious. Against my better judgement, I decided to spend a few hours poking around Worldcoin’s documentation and code — in the hope of rooting out the obvious technical red flags that would lead to the true Bond-villain explanation of the whole thing. Because surely there had to be one. I mean: eyeball scanners. Right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tech Trends at CES 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI was everywhere at the consumer electronics show, promising everything from self-driving cars to more Copilot+ laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
