<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Australia Divided on DeepSeek Response: Industry Groups Call for Action, Minister Urges Caution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australia-divided-on-deepseek-response-industry-groups-call-for-action-minister-urges-caution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australia-divided-on-deepseek-response-industry-groups-call-for-action-minister-urges-caution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australian authorities disagree over the response the country should take to the runaway success of the Chinese AI app DeepSeek.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare is the Latest Tech Company to Adopt Content Credentials for Image Authenticity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-is-the-latest-tech-company-to-adopt-content-credentials-for-image-authenticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-is-the-latest-tech-company-to-adopt-content-credentials-for-image-authenticity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare Images customers can now choose to preserve Content Credentials. Adobe and Cloudflare worked closely to enable it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner: Samsung Was the Top Semiconductor Vendor Globally in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung Electronics returned to number one partially on the strength of its memory device sales. Intel and NVIDIA followed in the rankings in spots two and three, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Will Remove the Free VPN That Comes With Windows Defender Soon</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-will-remove-the-free-vpn-that-comes-with-windows-defender-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-will-remove-the-free-vpn-that-comes-with-windows-defender-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The feature will no longer be available starting Feb. 28. Microsoft wants to focus on “new areas that will better align to customer needs.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Software Testing: Ensuring Reliability in the Next Computing Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;As &lt;strong&gt;quantum computing&lt;/strong&gt; continues to evolve, ensuring software reliability has become a critical challenge. Our latest article explores key aspects of quantum software testing, from bug patterns and testing methodologies to quantum software deployment and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Rajiv Chopra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-software-testing&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantum Software Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum software testing is the process of executing a quantum program to find the faults. This ensures that the quantum software is correct, reliable and performs well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Announces ‘World-First’ Cyber Code of Practice for Companies Developing AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-announces-world-first-cyber-code-of-practice-for-companies-developing-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-announces-world-first-cyber-code-of-practice-for-companies-developing-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cyber Code of Practice applies to developers, system operators, and organisations that create, deploy, or manage AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Personal Note-Taking Assistant Is Just $39.99 for Life</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record, transcribe, summarize, and keep all your notes organized with this powerful app for Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Cheat Sheet: A Complete Guide for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get up and running with ChatGPT with this comprehensive cheat sheet. Learn everything from how to sign up for free to enterprise use cases, and start using ChatGPT quickly and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Reveals New Surface Laptop 7 and Surface Pro 11 With Intel Chips</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-reveals-new-surface-laptop-7-and-surface-pro-11-with-intel-chips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-reveals-new-surface-laptop-7-and-surface-pro-11-with-intel-chips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Surface Laptop 7 and Surface Pro 11 PCs for business include Copilot+ AI features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Big Data</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-big-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New things are rapidly emerging in the big data landscape. To keep a competitive edge, you should learn the basic vocabulary. This list of 30 essential terms and concepts from TechRepublic Premium will help you stay on top of the current chatter about big data. Featured definition from the download: ETL (extract, transform, and load) &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Ireland Salary Guide reveals latest emerging employment trends</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generative AI adoption accelerates – nearly 70% of businesses encourage their staff to use AI for routine tasks and enhanced productivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High demand for skilled professionals – 27% of businesses plan to expand permanent roles, with another 68% maintaining headcount across professional services in 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rising salary expectations across generations – 68% of Gen Z professionals are becoming more insistent on higher pay, compared to just 22% of Gen X and 10% of Baby Boomers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Robert Half, the world’s first and largest specialised talent solutions and business consulting firm, has published its inaugural 2025 Ireland Salary Guide, offering essential insights into hiring and remuneration trends. The study analyses labour market dynamics, benefits and incentives, as well as starting salaries for a wide array of roles in diverse professional sectors throughout Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Security Strategies for the Gen AI Era</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;generative-ai-is-evolvingis-your-security-strategy-keeping-pace&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI is Evolving—Is Your Security Strategy Keeping Pace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; has quickly become a pivotal element in &lt;strong&gt;digital transformation&lt;/strong&gt; across industries, driving automation, enhancing customer interactions, and accelerating software development. But with these advancements come new and complex security challenges. Companies are rushing to adopt &lt;strong&gt;generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; to stay competitive, yet many haven’t adapted their cybersecurity practices to handle the emerging threats. When companies designed their cybersecurity policies and controls, few, if any, had generative AI on their bingo card. As a result, we’re seeing organisations unprepared for the unique vulnerabilities this technology introduces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI decreases human-generated content, limiting data for training AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of ChatGPT has led to a decrease in human-generated content with people asking and answering fewer questions online, according to new research from Corvinus University of Budapest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content and discussions online are used by people to learn new things and solve problems, and essential for training AI, particularly Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johannes Wachs, Associate Professor at Corvinus University, and colleagues from UCL and LMU Munich investigated the impact of ChatGPT on the generation of open data on Stack Overflow, an online Q&amp;amp;A platform for computer programmers and an essential source of training data for LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin will reach $100k before Trump takes office</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Donald Trump heads back to the White House, a University of Sussex professor who has been successfully predicting bitcoin (BTC) prices since 2021, is forecasting unprecedented highs which may breach $100k per token.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prof Carol Alexander of the University of Sussex Business School says bitcoin’s rapid rise in the immediate wake of the US election is likely to continue before Trump’s inauguration on 20th January 2025. She also believes the lesser-known currencies ether (ETH) and dogecoin (DOGE) will keep moving in the same direction, especially with the latter’s links to key Trump ally Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing organisational sustainability with carbon management dashboards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan. However, driving down energy consumption and rolling out energy projects is the responsibility of more than one department in an organisation. Many people – from engineers to investors and from management to staff – need to be brought together to make success happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How open-source is shaping the future of innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-source technology&lt;/strong&gt; has significantly shaped how industries approach complex technical challenges and foster innovation. It has expanded beyond software to impact hardware and systems design, opening up new pathways for researchers, engineers, and tech enthusiasts to develop advanced solutions. This collective approach fuels innovation and contributes to sustainable development by creating accessible, adaptable tools that solve real-world problems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-awards--summit-2025-enter-the-ai-awards-and-be-a-part-of-the-future&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;democratising-open-source-technology-and-science&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Democratising open-source technology and science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open-source technology fundamentally changes how we access and utilise high-tech tools. Traditionally, advanced instruments like oscilloscopes, signal generators, and spectrum analysers were accessible primarily to well-funded research labs. With open-source tools such as Red Pitaya’s “pocket lab,” engineers and students can now access powerful measurement and testing capabilities in a compact, cost-effective format. This allows universities, startups, and even independent researchers and enthusiasts to innovate without being restricted by cost or proprietary limitations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Leader’s Guide to Edge Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-edge-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-edge-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Edge computing allows companies to deliver data processing and analysis capabilities to remote sites like branch offices, retail stores, warehouses, and manufacturing plants. Reducing their reliance on centralized cloud or data center resources can significantly improve performance and operational efficiency at remote (a.k.a., edge) business sites while mitigating security risks and enabling real-time insights. Nicole &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The partnership that will prevent vape sales to minors</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johnston Retail Services has partnered with Privately SA to bring the AgeAI app to Ireland, helping to prevent vape sales to minors and avoid the risk of costly fines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20 November 2024 – Stores across Ireland can now benefit from a pioneering AI solution that can estimate someone’s age with almost 100% accuracy, thanks to a new partnership between Dublin’s Johnston Retail Services and SafetyTech company Privately SA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privately’s AgeAI app provides automated and highly accurate facial age estimation, removing the guesswork from age checks and mitigating the risk of fines for selling vapes to children. It is 100% anonymous, with no images transmitted or stored, GDPR certified, and helps protect staff by reducing the need for unnecessary ID checks for adults who are a source of major conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tricentis launches qTest Copilot to empower QA Organisations to Ship Quality Software Faster</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tricentis, a global leader in continuous testing and quality engineering, today announced the expansion of its test management and analytics platform, TricentisqTest, with the launch of Tricentis qTest Copilot. The latest addition to its suite of generative AI-powered Tricentis Copilot solutions, qTest Copilot harnesses the power of generative AI to simplify and accelerate test case generation, allowing for greater test coverage and higher-quality software releases.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;qTest Copilot is a generative AI assistant that automatically drafts test cases and test steps based on source documents and user requirements, offering considerable time-saving benefits when compared to manual approaches. Embedded into the newest version of the qTest platform, qTest Copilot combines Tricentis’ scalable and unified test management technology, with new AI-augmented features to allow QA and developer teams to greatly accelerate software delivery. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for The European Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, November 20, 2024&lt;/strong&gt; – The &lt;strong&gt;winners of the European Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking a remarkable evening of celebration for exceptional achievements in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, a leader in industry events for over 17 years, this prestigious awards ceremony took place on November 19, 2024, in London, where companies, teams, and individuals came together to honour excellence and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for the North American Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toronto, Canada&lt;/strong&gt; – The winners of the &lt;strong&gt;North American Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking an inspiring evening dedicated to recognising excellence in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, the awards ceremony took place on &lt;strong&gt;November 27, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, in Toronto, Canada, and gathered industry leaders and professionals to celebrate the outstanding achievements of companies, teams, and individuals across North America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The program, encompassing &lt;strong&gt;16 categories&lt;/strong&gt;, provided a platform for businesses of all sizes and sectors to showcase their innovation, technical skills, and commitment to quality. Participants embarked on a journey that culminated in an unforgettable awards evening, where achievements were recognised, and connections within the software testing community were strengthened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google, Apple Under Investigation to Determine Compliance with New UK Competition Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Google or Apple is deemed to have Strategic Market Status in the U.K., the government might force it to make the user data it collects available to competitors, or give publishers more control over how their data is used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operator: OpenAI’s Next Step Toward the ‘Agentic’ Future</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operator-openais-next-step-toward-the-agentic-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operator-openais-next-step-toward-the-agentic-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Operator and the Computer-Using Agent will be available through the OpenAI API at an undisclosed time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P2P File Sharing Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/p2p-file-sharing-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/p2p-file-sharing-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The use of email systems to send large files has become obsolete. P2P file-sharing networks make it easy for users to exchange data and information. However, they can also facilitate the spread of malware and security threats and expose the company to risk via the sharing of copyrighted material or confidential information. The purpose of &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Pledges Public Sector AI Overhaul, Legacy Tech Causes £45 Billion in Missed Annual Savings</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-pledges-public-sector-ai-overhaul-legacy-tech-causes-45-billion-in-missed-annual-savings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-pledges-public-sector-ai-overhaul-legacy-tech-causes-45-billion-in-missed-annual-savings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initiatives include AI tools for policymakers and a new team to identify where tech can boost the efficiency of public services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Grok AI? Is It Worth the Hype?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-grok-ai-is-it-worth-the-hype/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-grok-ai-is-it-worth-the-hype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore Grok AI, Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s chatbot. Is it living up to the hype? Dive into its features, potential, and what sets it apart from competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Buyer’s Journey: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-buyers-journey-a-comprehensive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-buyers-journey-a-comprehensive-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the stages of the buyer&amp;rsquo;s journey and how they influence purchasing decisions. Learn how to incorporate the buyer’s journey into your sales process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is CRM Automation? A Complete Guide for Sales Teams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-crm-automation-a-complete-guide-for-sales-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-crm-automation-a-complete-guide-for-sales-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how CRM automation can streamline your workflows and processes. Learn the benefits, features, and best practices to enhance customer relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Steps to Address Human Impact of AI Adoption in the Workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this TechRepublic exclusive, Gartner analyst Autumn Stanish provides proactive and compassionate steps IT leaders can take to support employees as they navigate transitions related to AI integration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Can Now Schedule Tasks in Advance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-can-now-schedule-tasks-in-advance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-can-now-schedule-tasks-in-advance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tasks feature, now in beta, can provide daily weather reports or send reminders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Colab vs Jupyter Notebook: Key Differences Explained</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-colab-vs-jupyter-notebook-key-differences-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-colab-vs-jupyter-notebook-key-differences-explained/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Colab and Jupyter Notebook are powerful tools for coding and data analysis, each offering unique features and benefits. Compare them to choose the best fit for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Workspace Plans See Price Hike as Gemini AI Expands to All Tiers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-workspace-plans-see-price-hike-as-gemini-ai-expands-to-all-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-workspace-plans-see-price-hike-as-gemini-ai-expands-to-all-tiers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of a $20 or $30 standalone plan, Google added a few dollars to its business tiers and applied the Gemini generative AI to all plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to thrive in an AI-powered workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-will-your-role-work-with-ai&#34;&gt;How Will Your Role Work with AI? &lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Hugo Farinha, co-founder of Virtuoso QA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Integrating AI sensitively into the workplace while acknowledging the perceptions, negative and positive, around the impact AI may have is going to be an essential skill for the C-suite over the next few years. The landscape will shift, putting greater emphasis on certain skills that will be needed to cover the requirements of working alongside AI, and others better suited for areas where human involvement is still essential… &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Omnichannel: A Comprehensive Guide for Business</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-omnichannel-a-comprehensive-guide-for-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-omnichannel-a-comprehensive-guide-for-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how omnichannel marketing supports seamless customer experiences. Learn omnichannel strategies to improve engagement and retention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence: Benefits and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/artificial-intelligence-benefits-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/artificial-intelligence-benefits-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From business to healthcare, cybersecurity, and the environment, artificial intelligence promises inclusive economic prosperity, innovation, and scientific support. AI is the foundation for the next generation of advancements that are expected to touch people’s lives across our world. However, AI also poses unique challenges and risks that individuals and companies must understand and mitigate by &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eight AI trends to prioritise in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author: Richard Farrell, CIO at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Netcall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2024 saw the adoption of &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI (GenAI)&lt;/strong&gt; accelerate, it also witnessed significant debates and challenges surrounding its use within business from security and data privacy perspectives, with questions surrounding its true value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As CIOs prepare to tackle AI in 2025, Richard Farrell, CIO of Netcall, shares the top trends that must be prioritised in the year ahead to ensure successful adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Generative AI for Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Neha Khandelwal, Software Design Assurance Engineering Manager, Zebra Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Root Cause Analysis (RCA) is a critical yet time-consuming process in the realm of software quality assurance (QA). It requires meticulous investigation to pinpoint the underlying cause of defects, often involving sifting through logs, analysing code, and correlating various system behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QA teams spend significant effort identifying the root cause, which can delay resolutions and increase downtime. As systems grow more complex, traditional RCA methods become less efficient, demanding advanced tools to assist in automating and streamlining the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Kit: MongoDB Administrator</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-mongodb-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-mongodb-administrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the growing importance of big data for businesses, the need for database programs that are adaptable and scalable has become a priority. Enter MongoDB, an open-source database program that can accommodate a variety of programming languages. This customizable hiring kit from TechRepublic Premium provides a framework you can use to find the best candidate &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Half of Businesses Weaken Sustainability Goals Due to Generative AI Demands, Capgemini Report Reveals</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has stated that its goal to reach net-zero emissions across all its operations and value chain by 2030 is now “extremely ambitious” thanks to its data centre usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK’s New AI Action Plan Aims to Position Country as a Global Powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recommendations in the 50-point plan include increasing public compute capacity twentyfold, creating a training data library, and building AI hubs in deindustrialised areas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: AMD Introduces Radeon RX 9070 Series GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next-generation GPUs will be available from a variety of manufacturers in the first quarter of 2025. Plus, AMD shows upcoming AI chips for mobile performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: NVIDIA Unveils GeForce RTX 50-Series Chips, AI Research Supercomputers, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jensen Huang, NVIDIA’s CEO, unveiled the company’s first flagship desktop GPU series in over two years during his keynote speech.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell Introduces New Product Line Names</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Named brands like XPS and Inspiron will now fall under performance categories. Plus, Dell expanded its partnership with AMD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Kit: Machine Learning Engineer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-machine-learning-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-machine-learning-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Successful businesses are relying on digitization and automation to make their operations more efficient and productive. The underlying technologies that make this automation possible include artificial intelligence and machine learning. Developing, programming, and implementing these sophisticated automation tools requires the considerable skills of a machine learning engineer. This customizable hiring kit, created by Mark W. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HR Leaders in APAC Are Adopting AI for Efficiency Gains</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and machine learning are seen as allies in the battle to streamline HR workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp Investigated by UK Competition Authority</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ibms-acquisition-of-hashicorp-investigated-by-uk-competition-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ibms-acquisition-of-hashicorp-investigated-by-uk-competition-authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HashiCorp provides hybrid and multi-cloud lifecycle management products that could assist IBM’s customers with their AI ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to Invest $80 Billion in AI Data Centers in Fiscal 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than half of the investment has been earmarked for infrastructure in the U.S. Microsoft President Brad Smith frames AI investment as key to economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: Cloud Spending is Perplexing CFOs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud spending confusion is rising among CFOs. An IBM executive explains how FinOps, automation, and AI-powered solutions can improve cost visibility and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Payroll Compliance Penalties Driving Tech Adoption in Australia, Says Yellow Canary</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new law criminalising some underpayments to Australian employees this month is causing organisations to keep a close watch on their payroll technology, according to Yellow Canary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Shifts Attention to Superintelligence in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Superintelligence refers to AI with greater-than-human capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resource and Data Recovery Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/resource-and-data-recovery-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/resource-and-data-recovery-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Employees, data, and resources are three of the biggest assets in any given organization. With concepts such as mobility and cloud access becoming nearly ubiquitous, the ability of company staff to protect and recover data and/or resources spread out across disparate environments is especially vital for continued success. This policy, written by Scott Matteson for &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report: The Security and AI Landscape in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats are getting smarter, and businesses can’t afford to fall behind. This TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report, sponsored by Check Point Software, explores the biggest security challenges of 2025—from the explosion of AI adoption to the critical importance of Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA). With breaches on the rise and ransomware payouts hitting record highs, organizations &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechRepublic Premium Editorial Calendar: Policies, Hiring Kits, and Glossaries for Download</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TechRepublic Premium content helps you solve your toughest IT issues and jump-start your career or next project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tech Trends at CES 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI was everywhere at the consumer electronics show, promising everything from self-driving cars to more Copilot+ laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Project Management Trends to Watch in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-6-project-management-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-6-project-management-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the top project management trends for 2025. Explore insights and strategies for increased productivity and better collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Open Source Software Security in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-open-source-software-security-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-open-source-software-security-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hidden dependencies, social engineering attacks, and the complexity of foundation models can all contribute tothe insecure use of open-source software in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 key AI Predictions for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-key-ai-predictions-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-key-ai-predictions-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the insurance industry navigates a rapidly evolving landscape, Fadata looks ahead to 2025 and highlights the key developments and trends in insurance and digital transformation. &lt;strong&gt;Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on the close collaborations between Fadata and its clients, the major trends that Fadata predicts will shape the future of insurance are Internalization, Prevention, Cloud Migration, Embedded Insurance, Ecosystem Development and Talent Transformation. These six trends are driving transformative changes across the sector, with insurers adopting innovative approaches to address customer needs, operational efficiency, security, risk, and market demands:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>66% of LinkedIn Users Believe AI Should Be Taught in High Schools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/strong&gt; should be introduced as a subject in high schools, given its growing importance in job postings. This is the opinion of LinkedIn’s community, surveyed by OPIT – Open Institute of Technology, an EU-accredited academic institution led by Professor Francesco Profumo, former Minister of Education, and Riccardo Ocleppo, Founder and Director. &lt;strong&gt;According to the survey, 66% of LinkedIn users think it is essential to teach AI in high schools. Additionally, 72% observed an increase in AI-related mentions in job postings, while 48% stated that AI proficiency is a key requirement for the companies they applied to. AI is primarily used for text generation (38%), research and analysis (38%), and translations (23%).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>66% of LinkedIn Users Believe AI Should Be Taught in High Schools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/strong&gt; should be introduced as a subject in high schools, given its growing importance in job postings. This is the opinion of LinkedIn’s community, surveyed by OPIT – Open Institute of Technology, an EU-accredited academic institution led by Professor Francesco Profumo, former Minister of Education, and Riccardo Ocleppo, Founder and Director. &lt;strong&gt;According to the survey, 66% of LinkedIn users think it is essential to teach AI in high schools. Additionally, 72% observed an increase in AI-related mentions in job postings, while 48% stated that AI proficiency is a key requirement for the companies they applied to. AI is primarily used for text generation (38%), research and analysis (38%), and translations (23%).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack surface management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-surface-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-surface-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the AI Awards here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;attack-surface-management-you-cant-protect-what-you-cant-see&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack surface management: you can’t protect what you can’t see&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Marios Kyriacou&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines the attack surface of a software environment as “the sum of the different points where an unauthorised user can try to enter data, extract data, control a device or critical software in an environment.” It goes on to say. “&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping the attack surface as small as possible is a basic security measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open For The 2025 AI Awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, UK –&lt;/strong&gt; The highly anticipated &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is set to take place on &lt;strong&gt;16th April 2025&lt;/strong&gt; in London, bringing together AI innovators from across the globe. This event promises a full day of immersive learning and networking, culminating in an evening dedicated to recognising the transformative contributions of AI professionals and organisations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AI Summit&lt;/strong&gt; offers a unique platform for industry professionals to engage in meaningful conversations, explore the latest advancements in AI, and expand their networks. With &lt;strong&gt;eight brilliant and trending topics&lt;/strong&gt;, the Summit covers the most pressing themes and opportunities within artificial intelligence, delivering valuable insights for attendees across industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open For The 2025 AI Awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, UK –&lt;/strong&gt; The highly anticipated &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is set to take place on &lt;strong&gt;16th April 2025&lt;/strong&gt; in London, bringing together AI innovators from across the globe. This event promises a full day of immersive learning and networking, culminating in an evening dedicated to recognising the transformative contributions of AI professionals and organisations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AI Summit&lt;/strong&gt; offers a unique platform for industry professionals to engage in meaningful conversations, explore the latest advancements in AI, and expand their networks. With &lt;strong&gt;eight brilliant and trending topics&lt;/strong&gt;, the Summit covers the most pressing themes and opportunities within artificial intelligence, delivering valuable insights for attendees across industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open for the Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangalore, India – &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is now accepting entries, offering an unparalleled opportunity to celebrate excellence in digital technologies. This prestigious awards program recognises the outstanding achievements of businesses, teams, and individuals across the Asia Pacific region and the UAE who have demonstrated exceptional innovation and commitment to enhancing business processes, customer experience, or cultural transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;15 diverse categories&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Agile Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open for the Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangalore, India – &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is now accepting entries, offering an unparalleled opportunity to celebrate excellence in digital technologies. This prestigious awards program recognises the outstanding achievements of businesses, teams, and individuals across the Asia Pacific region and the UAE who have demonstrated exceptional innovation and commitment to enhancing business processes, customer experience, or cultural transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;15 diverse categories&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Agile Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How 5G and AI are revolutionising industries for the next billion users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the insurance industry navigates a rapidly evolving landscape, Fadata looks ahead to 2025 and highlights the key developments and trends in insurance and digital transformation. &lt;strong&gt;Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-future-how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Future: How 5G and AI Are Revolutionising Industries for the Next Billion Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by: Prianca Ravichander, CMO and Head of Global B2B2X Monetisation at Tecnotree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Smart Cities are Bridging the Digital Divide With AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-cities-are-bridging-the-digital-divide-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-cities-are-bridging-the-digital-divide-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Urban populations are expected to account for 68% of the global population, putting unprecedented strain on cities’ infrastructure. This rapid urbanisation is exposing critical gaps that compromise residents’ quality of life, from inefficient essential services to grid and water-management deficiencies. The implications are particularly profound for underserved communities, where infrastructure and basic services may already be lacking. Municipal leaders, policymakers, and sustainability directors are now grappling with the challenge of ensuring their cities evolve in a way that is both technologically advanced and equitable and inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key AI Predictions within the growth and sustainability sector</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; continues to chip away at the environment, next year, data centres will face a pivotal moment. Facilities will start to realise that there isn’t enough energy. Companies that were influenced by competitive urgency and rushed into AI, now face decisions regarding cost and sustainability of the technology. For example, some AI in-house setups cost upwards of $300,000 in hardware alone.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the predictions below to learn about AI growth and sustainability. The predictions also cover data centre accountability, tech-savvy Gen Zs, the rise of AI agents, the role of digital twins in data centres and more. **Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.**rr&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key AI Predictions within the growth and sustainability sector</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; continues to chip away at the environment, next year, data centres will face a pivotal moment. Facilities will start to realise that there isn’t enough energy. Companies that were influenced by competitive urgency and rushed into AI, now face decisions regarding cost and sustainability of the technology. For example, some AI in-house setups cost upwards of $300,000 in hardware alone.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the predictions below to learn about AI growth and sustainability. The predictions also cover data centre accountability, tech-savvy Gen Zs, the rise of AI agents, the role of digital twins in data centres and more. **Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.**rr&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software standards at risk as QA teams face new levels of pressure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital quality is integral to the development and rollout of new services. Yet managers and development teams alike often underestimate the value of &lt;strong&gt;quality assurance (QA)&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, many of the checks and balances required to deliver high-quality digital experiences are overlooked, putting companies at risk of losing customers and harming their reputations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mason, the CTO of Applause, believes the situation could reach boiling point in 2025 as businesses race to release new apps and features, placing more pressure on under-resourced QA teams. His predictions below offer caution and advice to organisations that want to ensure digital quality across the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software standards at risk as QA teams face new levels of pressure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital quality is integral to the development and rollout of new services. Yet managers and development teams alike often underestimate the value of &lt;strong&gt;quality assurance (QA)&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, many of the checks and balances required to deliver high-quality digital experiences are overlooked, putting companies at risk of losing customers and harming their reputations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mason, the CTO of Applause, believes the situation could reach boiling point in 2025 as businesses race to release new apps and features, placing more pressure on under-resourced QA teams. His predictions below offer caution and advice to organisations that want to ensure digital quality across the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The growing challenge of secrets management in DevOps and how automation can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The age of agile software development and the cloud has caused an explosion in enterprise secrets. From passwords, encryption keys and APIs, to tokens and certificates, digital secrets are what control access when data is transferred between applications. They’re essential to maintaining the security of that data, and in turn, the successful operation of digital enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-top-emerging-security-challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A top emerging security challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise, then, that secrets are extremely valuable to threat actors. Businesses need a robust secrets management strategy in place in order to not only effectively manage the respective secrets across their lifecycle, but also protect them from compromise. This is becoming a significant challenge within DevOps specifically, with Thales’ Data Threat Report finding that secrets management was identified as the top emerging DevOps security challenge by respondents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The growing challenge of secrets management in DevOps and how automation can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The age of agile software development and the cloud has caused an explosion in enterprise secrets. From passwords, encryption keys and APIs, to tokens and certificates, digital secrets are what control access when data is transferred between applications. They’re essential to maintaining the security of that data, and in turn, the successful operation of digital enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-top-emerging-security-challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A top emerging security challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise, then, that secrets are extremely valuable to threat actors. Businesses need a robust secrets management strategy in place in order to not only effectively manage the respective secrets across their lifecycle, but also protect them from compromise. This is becoming a significant challenge within DevOps specifically, with Thales’ Data Threat Report finding that secrets management was identified as the top emerging DevOps security challenge by respondents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
