<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Security risks exposed following hack of Apple’s USB-C controller</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-risks-exposed-following-hack-of-apples-usb-c-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-risks-exposed-following-hack-of-apples-usb-c-controller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ACE3 controller, which is an integral component to the management of charging and data transfer tasks in Apple devices, was compromised using reverse-engineering techniques to exploit weaknesses in its firmware and communication protocols.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a rule, book reviews are not a thing I usually do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when I received an out-of-the-blue email from Cory Doctorow last week asking if I would review his latest book, Red Team Blues, it took a minute to overcome my initial skepticism. While I’m a fan of Cory’s work, this is a narrow/nerdy blog about cryptography, not a place where we spend much time on literature. Moreover, my only previous attempt to review a popular cryptography novel — a quick sketch of Dan Brown’s abysmal &lt;em&gt;Digital Fortress&lt;/em&gt; — did not go very well for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instant Password Removal for Quicken 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/instant-password-removal-for-quicken-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/instant-password-removal-for-quicken-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/AINPR-3.14_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Advanced Intuit Password Recovery received a major overhaul, adding support for Intuit QuickBooks 2024. For QuickBooks’ annual update, we are excited to provide the complete solution for safe, instant, unconditional password removal. This enhancement addresses a persistent issue in earlier versions, making user management more reliable and efficient for users, IT professionals, and digital forensic specialists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tool&#34;&gt;The Tool&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tool we’re talking about is Advanced Intuit Password Recovery, a lightweight computer forensic product designed to recover lost or forgotten passwords for Intuit Quicken and QuickBooks files. It supports a wide range of Quicken versions from 2006 through 2022 and QuickBooks versions from 2006 through 2023 (and now also 2024), including many international and localized variants. For breaking Quicken passwords, the software is equipped with advanced hardware acceleration, utilizing last-generation NVIDIA video cards to speed up the password recovery process, while QuickBook passwords are subject to instant removal. It can unlock password-protected Quicken .QDF and QuickBooks .QBW files, making it an essential tool for IT professionals managing financial data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS Forensics: tool validation based on a known dataset - Preamble</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-forensics-tool-validation-based-on-a-known-dataset-preamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-forensics-tool-validation-based-on-a-known-dataset-preamble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world, it’s been a while since my last series of blog posts! But now I am ready to share with you the results of my recent research.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I face many different challenges in my daily work as a digital forensics analyst, who deals mainly with mobile devices. &lt;strong&gt;All modern smartphones are encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; (usually with file-based encryption (FBE)), so obtaining or cracking the passcode is required to gain access to all the data stored on the device. And even if we know the passcode (or the user has not set the passcode, which is increasingly rare these days), we still need an exploit to gain “root” access to the device to read and copy all the data and get our “best acquisition”, usually a full file system (FFS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sysdiagnose in iOS 16: a first look from a Digital Forensics perspective</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sysdiagnose-in-ios-16-a-first-look-from-a-digital-forensics-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sysdiagnose-in-ios-16-a-first-look-from-a-digital-forensics-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in May 2019, along with my colleagues Heather Mahalik and Adrian Leong, we wrote the paper &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Using Apple “Bug Reporting” for forensic purposes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; and some scripts to parse data stored in Sysdiagnose logs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The paper is still available for download and, for the most part, is still accurate. But time goes on, and new iOS versions have come on the market in recent years. I took a first look at a sysdiagnose generated on a freshly wiped iPhone with iOS 16 natively installed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Schnorr and beyond (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post continues a long, wonky discussion of Schnorr signature schemes and the Dilithium post-quantum signature. You may want to start with Part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous post I discussed the intuition behind Schnorr signatures, beginning with a high-level design rationale and ending with a concrete instantiation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a reminder: our discussion began with this Tweet by Chris Peikert:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/schnorrpeikert.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which we eventually developed into an abstract version of the Schnorr protocol that uses Chris’s “magic boxes” to realize part of its functionality:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Chip Export Rule Proposes Limits to Thwart Chinese GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Biden administration states the rule will prevent U.S. chips from passing to China through countries loosely allied or not politically allied with the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: AMD Introduces Radeon RX 9070 Series GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next-generation GPUs will be available from a variety of manufacturers in the first quarter of 2025. Plus, AMD shows upcoming AI chips for mobile performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: NVIDIA Unveils GeForce RTX 50-Series Chips, AI Research Supercomputers, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jensen Huang, NVIDIA’s CEO, unveiled the company’s first flagship desktop GPU series in over two years during his keynote speech.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell Introduces New Product Line Names</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Named brands like XPS and Inspiron will now fall under performance categories. Plus, Dell expanded its partnership with AMD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to Invest $80 Billion in AI Data Centers in Fiscal 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than half of the investment has been earmarked for infrastructure in the U.S. Microsoft President Brad Smith frames AI investment as key to economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechRepublic Premium Editorial Calendar: Policies, Hiring Kits, and Glossaries for Download</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TechRepublic Premium content helps you solve your toughest IT issues and jump-start your career or next project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tech Trends at CES 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI was everywhere at the consumer electronics show, promising everything from self-driving cars to more Copilot+ laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
