<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Email-Security on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/email-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Email-Security on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/email-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Software Collaborates with AppDirect to Offer Streamlined Cyber Security Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shifting-Paradigms-Cloud-Security-in-the-Post-Pandemic-Era-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security in the Post-Pandemic Era&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point Software and AppDirect, a B2B subscription commerce platform, have unveiled a strategic collaboration, allowing businesses to effortlessly obtain Check Point’s AI-powered cyber security solutions through the AppDirect marketplace. This partnership offers a unified procurement experience, ensuring more customers have access to the highest level of security they deserve. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, worldwide cyber attacks on organizations surged considerably in 2024. On average, organizations faced 1,673 attacks each week, marking a substantial 44% increase from the year before. As cyber attacks continue to escalate annually, it is crucial for every business to utilize advanced […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HT-ML Guard to Automatically Analyze and Secure HTML Files</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/blog-template-2000x700_5-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Highlights: HTML files are being used in phishing attacks, mimicking trusted websites HT-ML Guard is designed to analyze HTML files and accurately determine whether they are malicious, enhancing cyber security defenses. Check Point Harmony Email and Collaboration customers remain protected against this type of attack. HTML files are commonly used in the initial stages of cyber attacks. Cyber criminals craft these files to look legitimate, tempting unsuspecting users into a false sense of security. The main goal of these malicious HTML files is to deceive users into either disclosing sensitive information, such as login credentials and personal details, or downloading […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phishing Emails Targeting Australian Firms Rise by 30% in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/phishing-emails-targeting-australian-firms-rise-by-30-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/phishing-emails-targeting-australian-firms-rise-by-30-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the APAC region as a whole, credential phishing attacks rose by 30.5% between 2023 and 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
