<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awswickr on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/awswickr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awswickr on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/awswickr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP High authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New eBook: 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-ebook-5-keys-to-secure-enterprise-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-ebook-5-keys-to-secure-enterprise-messaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce a new eBook, 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging. The new eBook includes best practices for addressing the security and compliance risks associated with messaging apps. An estimated 3.09 billion mobile phone users access messaging apps to communicate, and this figure is projected to grow to 3.51 billion users in […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce a new eBook, 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging. The new eBook includes best practices for addressing the security and compliance risks associated with messaging apps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three key security themes from AWS re:Invent 2022</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations. Now in its 11th year, the conference featured 5 keynotes, 22 leadership sessions, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
