<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Half of Businesses Weaken Sustainability Goals Due to Generative AI Demands, Capgemini Report Reveals</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has stated that its goal to reach net-zero emissions across all its operations and value chain by 2030 is now “extremely ambitious” thanks to its data centre usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK’s New AI Action Plan Aims to Position Country as a Global Powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recommendations in the 50-point plan include increasing public compute capacity twentyfold, creating a training data library, and building AI hubs in deindustrialised areas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating 10 Years of Kubernetes: A Journey Through Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-10-years-of-kubernetes-a-journey-through-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-10-years-of-kubernetes-a-journey-through-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.codemotion.com/magazine/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/DALL%C2%B7E-2024-06-03-11.06.16-A-minimal-and-simple-widescreen-image-celebrating-10-years-of-Kubernetes.-The-design-features-a-clean-white-background-with-a-stylized-modern-repres.webp&#34; alt=&#34;10 years of kubernetes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes, the brainchild of Google, has revolutionized container orchestration and cloud-native computing over the past decade. &lt;strong&gt;Its evolution from an internal tool to an industry-standard platform&lt;/strong&gt; is a testament to its robustness and the thriving community behind it. This article delves into the timeline of Kubernetes’ development, its remarkable success, key orchestration patterns, and essential tools that complement it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-timeline-of-major-milestones-10-years-of-kubernetes&#34;&gt;A Timeline of Major Milestones: 10 years of Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To appreciate these 10 years of Kubernetes, we need to understand its significant milestones. From its inception to its current status, each phase brought innovations and improvements that cemented its place in the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Scams Based on Fake Google Emails&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scams-based-on-fake-google-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scams-based-on-fake-google-emails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scammers are hacking Google Forms to send email to victims that come from google.com.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brian Krebs reports on the effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boing Boing post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scammers are hacking Google Forms to send email to victims that come from google.com.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brian Krebs reports on the effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boing Boing post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firebase CLI Installer Making Calls to Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/firebase-cli-installer-making-calls-to-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/firebase-cli-installer-making-calls-to-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Firebase is a mobile and web application development platform provided by Google. One of the tools available for the platform is the Firebase CLI tool (GitHub repo) which helps developers interact with the platform from command line. An automatic install script is offered among other options, which allows installation of the CLI tool via the “curl | bash” pattern as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -sL https://firebase.tools | bash&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of our ongoing research into supply chain attacks, we have been looking into bash installer scripts that make calls to external systems. First, there is no way to verify that the installer is legit, However, to our surprise, we also found that this script makes calls to Google Analytics as part of the installation process. There is no sensitive data being collected but Google may still be collecting IP addresses of users installing the CLI. The source code for the installer script can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insecure Bootstrap Process in Google’s Cloud SQL Proxy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/insecure-bootstrap-process-in-googles-cloud-sql-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/insecure-bootstrap-process-in-googles-cloud-sql-proxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bootstrap process for Google’s cloud SQL Proxy CLI uses the “curl | bash” pattern and didn’t document a way to verify authenticity of the downloaded binaries. The vendor updated documentation with information on how to use checksums to verify the downloaded binaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vulnerability-details&#34;&gt;Vulnerability Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of our ongoing research into supply chain attacks, we have been analyzing bash installer scripts using the “curl | bash” pattern. Google provides such script used to install the Cloud SQL proxy. However, the documentation doesn’t indicate how to verify downloaded files prior to execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
