<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybercrimeawareness on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cybercrimeawareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybercrimeawareness on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cybercrimeawareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is phishing?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During phishing, a target or targets are approached by email, telephone, or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution. This is done to lure individuals into providing sensitive data such as passwords, banking and credit card details, and personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information is then used to access sensitive accounts, resulting in identity theft and financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of phishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; spear phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;search engine phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;email phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Features of Phishing:-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
