<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet-Governance on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/internet-governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet-Governance on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/internet-governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Reflection Series on CCG’s Technology and National Security Law and Policy Seminar Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, CCG-NLUD will commence the latest edition of its Seminar Course on Technology and National Security Law and Policy (“the Seminar Course”). The Seminar Course is offered to interested 4th and 5th year students who are enrolled in the B.A. LL.B. (Hons.) programme at the National Law University, Delhi. The course is set […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week I of the Fifth Substantive Session.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction Last month from April 11-21, 2023, the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communications Technologies (ICTs) for Criminal Purpose held its Fifth Session in Vienna. As we reported earlier, the negotiating process has reached a pivotal stage, wherein the Member Countries […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
