<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/azure-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/azure-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Full web support for conditional access policies across Azure DevOps and partner web properties</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-web-support-for-conditional-access-policies-across-azure-devops-and-partner-web-properties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that we’ve made significant progress in updating our web authentication stack on Azure DevOps services and partner web properties to utilize Microsoft Entra tokens to handle web sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By replacing our previous cookies with Entra tokens, we’ve deepened the integration we have with Microsoft Entra ID on our web experience. This change allows us to continuously evaluate identity compliance with Entra policies on an hourly basis (the duration of an Entra token).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update to Azure DevOps Allowed IP addresses</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/update-to-azure-devops-allowed-ip-addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/update-to-azure-devops-allowed-ip-addresses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are excited to announce some important upgrades to our networking infrastructure that will enhance the performance and reliability of our service. As part of these infrastructure upgrades, we are introducing new IP addresses that you will need to allow list in your firewall configurations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-changing-and-why&#34;&gt;What’s Changing And Why?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are transitioning from the current set of network edge devices supporting Azure DevOps to new, better-performing network edge devices by May 2025. As part of this transition, we have added new IP addresses to the current published allow list – Allowed address lists and network connections – Azure DevOps | Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changes to provisioning Azure DevOps projects using the Azure DevOps Demo Generator</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/changes-to-provisioning-azure-devops-projects-using-the-azure-devops-demo-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/changes-to-provisioning-azure-devops-projects-using-the-azure-devops-demo-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Azure DevOps Demo Generator is a tool that allows you to create projects in your Azure DevOps organization, complete with pre-filled sample content. This includes source code, work items, iterations, service connections, and build and release pipelines, all based on a template you select.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting &lt;strong&gt;February 28, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, we are eliminating the need for us to authenticate on your behalf. This update will give you greater control over creating new projects and ensure a more secure process. Instead of the previous authentication process, you will run the ADOGenerator project as a console application or executable (.exe) file to create projects in your Azure DevOps organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
