<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Report on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Report on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A first look at iOS 18 forensics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-first-look-at-ios-18-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-first-look-at-ios-18-forensics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been a tough year for me: my mom passed away in June, and I&amp;rsquo;m still slowly recovering from the hard blow. It&amp;rsquo;s time to start again doing what I love: researching and sharing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s early September and like every year, that moment is approaching when everyone who deals with mobile forensics starts to tremble at the thought of the arrival of a new version of iOS!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First the good news: the basic and traditional techniques for logical acquisition (or Advanced Logical, if you want to call it that) still work on iOS 18!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSides København – Meaningful Metrics in Information Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next BSides København will take place on 9 November 2024. There is one presentation in the schedule about the use of metrics in information security. Computers allow us to create documents, charts, and statistical values easily from any data collection we like. Therefore, the World Wide Web is full of graphs, tables with numbers, predictions, and all kinds of results. The problem is that not everything you can count is a suitable metric tied to real-life observations. Finding a metric is a science on its own. This presentation will give you some examples of how to measure meaningful attributes of computer systems and networks. You will also get to know the term metric more closely. Using proper metrics and assessing customer-provided reports will help you immensely when dealing with information security decisions. The&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepINTEL 2024 – a full Day all about Security Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepintel-2024-a-full-day-all-about-security-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepintel-2024-a-full-day-all-about-security-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The DeepINTEL 2024 security intelligence has begun. The day holds a full day of presentation about current and future threats. It is difficult to describe a TLP:AMBER event, because we do not publish the schedule for DeepINTEL. The term security intelligence has a wide spectrum. Basically, it includes all informations that will help you improve your defence, understand your adversaries, and how attacking groups operate. The sources are probes, monitoring systems, reports from attacks and their analysis. We are looking forward to provide the next iteration of DeepINTEL as a unique forum where security experts can get crucial updates. Grab your coffee, listen, and contribute!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Half of Businesses Weaken Sustainability Goals Due to Generative AI Demands, Capgemini Report Reveals</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has stated that its goal to reach net-zero emissions across all its operations and value chain by 2030 is now “extremely ambitious” thanks to its data centre usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh no! I have a wiped iPhone, now what?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oh-no-i-have-a-wiped-iphone-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oh-no-i-have-a-wiped-iphone-now-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I got asked during presentations and conferences is: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;During a search and seizure we found a wiped iPhone, what can we do next?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi6xIfngOuvXrGpaenivhwwqQadArE3RoQ9MynGYodzJ1SjdkoYvo1KOqbz23sL8xmL9t7IAxSgrKELQZZ6NEBRYFJu3wWr1ZxBQOW3lBtjyCq5gtrLgBKemMqluauKuC5lvteSiMW7t1Y/w296-h640/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost: &lt;strong&gt;you cannot recover data stored on the device before wiping occurred&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The encryption keys you need to decrypt the data are gone forever.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Full stop :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are aware of any method, technique, tool or magic box that can do that, please let me know :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
