<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/devops-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/devops-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What is DevOps Automation? Best Practices &amp; Benefits&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-automation-best-practices-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-automation-best-practices-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about DevOps automation. Discover the steps you should take to automate DevOps workflows and processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Software Testing: Ensuring Reliability in the Next Computing Revolution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-software-testing-ensuring-reliability-in-the-next-computing-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;As &lt;strong&gt;quantum computing&lt;/strong&gt; continues to evolve, ensuring software reliability has become a critical challenge. Our latest article explores key aspects of quantum software testing, from bug patterns and testing methodologies to quantum software deployment and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Rajiv Chopra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;quantum-software-testing&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantum Software Testing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum software testing is the process of executing a quantum program to find the faults. This ensures that the quantum software is correct, reliable and performs well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform State Mv Command: How to Move Resources</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-state-mv-command-how-to-move-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-state-mv-command-how-to-move-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use the terraform state mv command to move Terraform resources within state files. See use case examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform Moved Block to Refactor Resources</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-terraform-moved-block-to-refactor-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-terraform-moved-block-to-refactor-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to use the Terraform moved block to move resources in your configuration files. See examples and limitations of this method.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise helps BuzzFeed optimize its mobile development to grow customer engagement - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-helps-buzzfeed-optimize-its-mobile-development-to-grow-customer-engagement-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-helps-buzzfeed-optimize-its-mobile-development-to-grow-customer-engagement-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In conversation with BuzzFeed: Principal Software Engineer Josh Walker shares insights into how Bitrise has freed up BuzzFeed to innovate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importing Resources With Terraform Import Block</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/importing-resources-with-terraform-import-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/importing-resources-with-terraform-import-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we explain the Terraform import block released in HashiCorp Terraform v1.5 and how to use it for different resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding new software on a deadline: Microsoft Visual Studio App Center shutdown - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/onboarding-new-software-on-a-deadline-microsoft-visual-studio-app-center-shutdown-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/onboarding-new-software-on-a-deadline-microsoft-visual-studio-app-center-shutdown-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With just two months to go until the deprecation of Microsoft Visual Studio App Center, here&amp;rsquo;s a resource pack to help you make migration happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform with AWS EventBridge [Step-by-Step Guide]</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-with-aws-eventbridge-step-by-step-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/terraform-with-aws-eventbridge-step-by-step-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guide, you’ll learn how to integrate Terraform with AWS EventBridge. See how to manage rules, event buses, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kubernetes Control Plane: What It Is &amp; How It Works&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-control-plane-what-it-is-how-it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-control-plane-what-it-is-how-it-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn what Kubernetes control plane is, its purpose, components, and how it works with nodes. Control vs. master vs data plane.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Ireland Salary Guide reveals latest emerging employment trends</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-ireland-salary-guide-reveals-latest-emerging-employment-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generative AI adoption accelerates – nearly 70% of businesses encourage their staff to use AI for routine tasks and enhanced productivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High demand for skilled professionals – 27% of businesses plan to expand permanent roles, with another 68% maintaining headcount across professional services in 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rising salary expectations across generations – 68% of Gen Z professionals are becoming more insistent on higher pay, compared to just 22% of Gen X and 10% of Baby Boomers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Robert Half, the world’s first and largest specialised talent solutions and business consulting firm, has published its inaugural 2025 Ireland Salary Guide, offering essential insights into hiring and remuneration trends. The study analyses labour market dynamics, benefits and incentives, as well as starting salaries for a wide array of roles in diverse professional sectors throughout Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adapting Security Strategies for the Gen AI Era</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/adapting-security-strategies-for-the-gen-ai-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;generative-ai-is-evolvingis-your-security-strategy-keeping-pace&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI is Evolving—Is Your Security Strategy Keeping Pace?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; has quickly become a pivotal element in &lt;strong&gt;digital transformation&lt;/strong&gt; across industries, driving automation, enhancing customer interactions, and accelerating software development. But with these advancements come new and complex security challenges. Companies are rushing to adopt &lt;strong&gt;generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; to stay competitive, yet many haven’t adapted their cybersecurity practices to handle the emerging threats. When companies designed their cybersecurity policies and controls, few, if any, had generative AI on their bingo card. As a result, we’re seeing organisations unprepared for the unique vulnerabilities this technology introduces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI decreases human-generated content, limiting data for training AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-decreases-human-generated-content-limiting-data-for-training-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of ChatGPT has led to a decrease in human-generated content with people asking and answering fewer questions online, according to new research from Corvinus University of Budapest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content and discussions online are used by people to learn new things and solve problems, and essential for training AI, particularly Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johannes Wachs, Associate Professor at Corvinus University, and colleagues from UCL and LMU Munich investigated the impact of ChatGPT on the generation of open data on Stack Overflow, an online Q&amp;amp;A platform for computer programmers and an essential source of training data for LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin will reach $100k before Trump takes office</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitcoin-will-reach-100k-before-trump-takes-office/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Donald Trump heads back to the White House, a University of Sussex professor who has been successfully predicting bitcoin (BTC) prices since 2021, is forecasting unprecedented highs which may breach $100k per token.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prof Carol Alexander of the University of Sussex Business School says bitcoin’s rapid rise in the immediate wake of the US election is likely to continue before Trump’s inauguration on 20th January 2025. She also believes the lesser-known currencies ether (ETH) and dogecoin (DOGE) will keep moving in the same direction, especially with the latter’s links to key Trump ally Elon Musk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing organisational sustainability with carbon management dashboards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-organisational-sustainability-with-carbon-management-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With net zero and carbon reduction increasingly becoming a focal point for organisations, support through energy efficiency and sustainable transformation projects are crucial to the success of a carbon reduction plan. However, driving down energy consumption and rolling out energy projects is the responsibility of more than one department in an organisation. Many people – from engineers to investors and from management to staff – need to be brought together to make success happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How open-source is shaping the future of innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-open-source-is-shaping-the-future-of-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-source technology&lt;/strong&gt; has significantly shaped how industries approach complex technical challenges and foster innovation. It has expanded beyond software to impact hardware and systems design, opening up new pathways for researchers, engineers, and tech enthusiasts to develop advanced solutions. This collective approach fuels innovation and contributes to sustainable development by creating accessible, adaptable tools that solve real-world problems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-awards--summit-2025-enter-the-ai-awards-and-be-a-part-of-the-future&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.softwaretestingnews.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025: Enter the AI Awards and be a part of the future.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;democratising-open-source-technology-and-science&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Democratising open-source technology and science&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open-source technology fundamentally changes how we access and utilise high-tech tools. Traditionally, advanced instruments like oscilloscopes, signal generators, and spectrum analysers were accessible primarily to well-funded research labs. With open-source tools such as Red Pitaya’s “pocket lab,” engineers and students can now access powerful measurement and testing capabilities in a compact, cost-effective format. This allows universities, startups, and even independent researchers and enthusiasts to innovate without being restricted by cost or proprietary limitations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Now available for Enterprise, too: Apple API authentications on Bitrise - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/now-available-for-enterprise-too-apple-api-authentications-on-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/now-available-for-enterprise-too-apple-api-authentications-on-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using an Apple Enterprise development account? It’s now possible in Bitrise to manage your authentication via API key.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The partnership that will prevent vape sales to minors</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-partnership-that-will-prevent-vape-sales-to-minors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Johnston Retail Services has partnered with Privately SA to bring the AgeAI app to Ireland, helping to prevent vape sales to minors and avoid the risk of costly fines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20 November 2024 – Stores across Ireland can now benefit from a pioneering AI solution that can estimate someone’s age with almost 100% accuracy, thanks to a new partnership between Dublin’s Johnston Retail Services and SafetyTech company Privately SA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privately’s AgeAI app provides automated and highly accurate facial age estimation, removing the guesswork from age checks and mitigating the risk of fines for selling vapes to children. It is 100% anonymous, with no images transmitted or stored, GDPR certified, and helps protect staff by reducing the need for unnecessary ID checks for adults who are a source of major conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tricentis launches qTest Copilot to empower QA Organisations to Ship Quality Software Faster</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tricentis-launches-qtest-copilot-to-empower-qa-organisations-to-ship-quality-software-faster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tricentis, a global leader in continuous testing and quality engineering, today announced the expansion of its test management and analytics platform, TricentisqTest, with the launch of Tricentis qTest Copilot. The latest addition to its suite of generative AI-powered Tricentis Copilot solutions, qTest Copilot harnesses the power of generative AI to simplify and accelerate test case generation, allowing for greater test coverage and higher-quality software releases.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;qTest Copilot is a generative AI assistant that automatically drafts test cases and test steps based on source documents and user requirements, offering considerable time-saving benefits when compared to manual approaches. Embedded into the newest version of the qTest platform, qTest Copilot combines Tricentis’ scalable and unified test management technology, with new AI-augmented features to allow QA and developer teams to greatly accelerate software delivery. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for The European Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-european-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, November 20, 2024&lt;/strong&gt; – The &lt;strong&gt;winners of the European Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking a remarkable evening of celebration for exceptional achievements in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, a leader in industry events for over 17 years, this prestigious awards ceremony took place on November 19, 2024, in London, where companies, teams, and individuals came together to honour excellence and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winners Announced for the North American Software Testing Awards 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/winners-announced-for-the-north-american-software-testing-awards-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toronto, Canada&lt;/strong&gt; – The winners of the &lt;strong&gt;North American Software Testing Awards 2024&lt;/strong&gt; have been officially announced, marking an inspiring evening dedicated to recognising excellence in the software testing and quality engineering industry. Organised by &lt;strong&gt;31 Media&lt;/strong&gt;, the awards ceremony took place on &lt;strong&gt;November 27, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, in Toronto, Canada, and gathered industry leaders and professionals to celebrate the outstanding achievements of companies, teams, and individuals across North America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The program, encompassing &lt;strong&gt;16 categories&lt;/strong&gt;, provided a platform for businesses of all sizes and sectors to showcase their innovation, technical skills, and commitment to quality. Participants embarked on a journey that culminated in an unforgettable awards evening, where achievements were recognised, and connections within the software testing community were strengthened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>50&#43; Ransomware Statistics for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/50-ransomware-statistics-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/50-ransomware-statistics-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the latest ransomware statistics and trends and what they mean for businesses across various industries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring GitHub-hosted runners with Dynatrace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-github-hosted-runners-with-dynatrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-github-hosted-runners-with-dynatrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/github-dark-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | GitHub&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As more organizations embrace DevOps and CI/CD pipelines, GitHub-hosted runners and GitHub Actions have emerged as powerful tools for automating workflows. But as with many other automation tools, it can be difficult to maintain the performance and visibility of these workflows. That’s where Dynatrace business events and automation workflows come into play to provide a comprehensive view of your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore some of the advantages of monitoring GitHub runners using Dynatrace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Developer Velocity: What It is, How to Measure &amp; Improve It&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/developer-velocity-what-it-is-how-to-measure-improve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/developer-velocity-what-it-is-how-to-measure-improve-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about developer velocity, its importance, key factors, measurement challenges, and strategies to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Top Kubernetes Alternatives for Containers in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/13-top-kubernetes-alternatives-for-containers-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/13-top-kubernetes-alternatives-for-containers-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See the list of 13 best Kubernetes alternatives for container orchestration and the features to consider when choosing an alternative to K8s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrowserStack and Bitrise partner to help mobile developers build, test and release apps faster with confidence - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/browserstack-and-bitrise-partner-to-help-mobile-developers-build-test-and-release-apps-faster-with-confidence-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/browserstack-and-bitrise-partner-to-help-mobile-developers-build-test-and-release-apps-faster-with-confidence-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitrise is partnering with BrowserStack to improve your mobile DevOps experience, giving access to best-in-class mobile-first CI/CD and automated mobile device testing, plus an incredible free product offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;16 DevOps Metrics You Should Be Tracking [DORA &amp; Other]&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/16-devops-metrics-you-should-be-tracking-dora-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/16-devops-metrics-you-should-be-tracking-dora-other/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the most important DevOps performance metrics and KPIs, including the 4 key DORA metrics and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to thrive in an AI-powered workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-thrive-in-an-ai-powered-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-will-your-role-work-with-ai&#34;&gt;How Will Your Role Work with AI? &lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Hugo Farinha, co-founder of Virtuoso QA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Integrating AI sensitively into the workplace while acknowledging the perceptions, negative and positive, around the impact AI may have is going to be an essential skill for the C-suite over the next few years. The landscape will shift, putting greater emphasis on certain skills that will be needed to cover the requirements of working alongside AI, and others better suited for areas where human involvement is still essential… &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerd vs. Docker: Container Runtimes Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerd-vs-docker-container-runtimes-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerd-vs-docker-container-runtimes-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the difference between popular container runtimes - containerd and Docker and see which is better for your project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eight AI trends to prioritise in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author: Richard Farrell, CIO at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Netcall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2024 saw the adoption of &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI (GenAI)&lt;/strong&gt; accelerate, it also witnessed significant debates and challenges surrounding its use within business from security and data privacy perspectives, with questions surrounding its true value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As CIOs prepare to tackle AI in 2025, Richard Farrell, CIO of Netcall, shares the top trends that must be prioritised in the year ahead to ensure successful adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Generative AI for Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Neha Khandelwal, Software Design Assurance Engineering Manager, Zebra Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Root Cause Analysis (RCA) is a critical yet time-consuming process in the realm of software quality assurance (QA). It requires meticulous investigation to pinpoint the underlying cause of defects, often involving sifting through logs, analysing code, and correlating various system behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QA teams spend significant effort identifying the root cause, which can delay resolutions and increase downtime. As systems grow more complex, traditional RCA methods become less efficient, demanding advanced tools to assist in automating and streamlining the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Kubectl Patch Command &amp; How to Use It With Examples&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubectl-patch-command-how-to-use-it-with-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubectl-patch-command-how-to-use-it-with-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An overview of the kubectl patch command, including its syntax, how it works, and examples. Kubectl patch vs apply vs edit explained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the 1 Year Anniversary of OpenTofu Releases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-the-1-year-anniversary-of-opentofu-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-the-1-year-anniversary-of-opentofu-releases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year has passed since OpenTofu’s first stable release! With the celebration of the first anniversary, we’re also marking a new milestone -  the release of version 1.9.0!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Expert Q&amp;A: Hybrid vs native development, which is best? - Bitrise Blog&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/expert-qa-hybrid-vs-native-development-which-is-best-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/expert-qa-hybrid-vs-native-development-which-is-best-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore the hybrid vs. native development debate with insights from top experts. In this Q&amp;amp;A, industry leaders discussed the pros and cons of each approach, covering performance, user experience, developer productivity, and key decision-making factors. Get the insights you need to choose the best path for your app development journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Guide to Kubernetes Scaling: Horizontal, Vertical &amp; Cluster&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-kubernetes-scaling-horizontal-vertical-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-kubernetes-scaling-horizontal-vertical-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to scale Kubernetes? In this guide, you’ll learn about different methods of Kubernetes pod auto-scaling. See examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How AI will change software engineering: Insights from Bitrise&#39;s VP Engineering - Bitrise Blog&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-will-change-software-engineering-insights-from-bitrises-vp-engineering-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-will-change-software-engineering-insights-from-bitrises-vp-engineering-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how AI is reshaping software engineering with insights from Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s VP of Engineering, Arpad Kun. Explore the evolving role of AI, the skills engineers will need in the future, and how AI will enhance rather than replace software development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to Manage Cloud Infrastructure Drift &amp; Best Practices&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-manage-cloud-infrastructure-drift-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-manage-cloud-infrastructure-drift-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Managing cloud drift can be challenging. In this guide, you’ll learn what drift management is and discover best practices for implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What is DevOps Security? Challenges &amp; Best Practices&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-security-challenges-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-devops-security-challenges-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the role of DevOps security and learn best practices that will help protect your workflows and keep your DevOps environment safe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100&#43; Cloud Security Statistics for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/100-cloud-security-statistics-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/100-cloud-security-statistics-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we present key statistics related to cloud security that really caught our attention in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 DevOps Trends for 2025 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-devops-trends-for-2025-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/devops-e1734453914491-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Experts provide insight into the rise of FinOps, how APIs will force a rise in DevSecOps, and how low-code, no-code is here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 key AI Predictions for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-key-ai-predictions-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-key-ai-predictions-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the insurance industry navigates a rapidly evolving landscape, Fadata looks ahead to 2025 and highlights the key developments and trends in insurance and digital transformation. &lt;strong&gt;Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on the close collaborations between Fadata and its clients, the major trends that Fadata predicts will shape the future of insurance are Internalization, Prevention, Cloud Migration, Embedded Insurance, Ecosystem Development and Talent Transformation. These six trends are driving transformative changes across the sector, with insurers adopting innovative approaches to address customer needs, operational efficiency, security, risk, and market demands:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 DevOps Mistakes that Can Crush ISV Startups</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-devops-mistakes-that-can-crush-isv-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-devops-mistakes-that-can-crush-isv-startups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Devops-300x170.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Industry experts will tell you the best way to evolve your startup ISV into an established ISV is with DevOps — and they’re probably right. DevOps, however, which has only been in the mainstream for a little less than a decade, can be a difficult concept to master, and many software developers—especially startups—are still navigating […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>66% of LinkedIn Users Believe AI Should Be Taught in High Schools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/strong&gt; should be introduced as a subject in high schools, given its growing importance in job postings. This is the opinion of LinkedIn’s community, surveyed by OPIT – Open Institute of Technology, an EU-accredited academic institution led by Professor Francesco Profumo, former Minister of Education, and Riccardo Ocleppo, Founder and Director. &lt;strong&gt;According to the survey, 66% of LinkedIn users think it is essential to teach AI in high schools. Additionally, 72% observed an increase in AI-related mentions in job postings, while 48% stated that AI proficiency is a key requirement for the companies they applied to. AI is primarily used for text generation (38%), research and analysis (38%), and translations (23%).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>66% of LinkedIn Users Believe AI Should Be Taught in High Schools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/66-of-linkedin-users-believe-ai-should-be-taught-in-high-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI)&lt;/strong&gt; should be introduced as a subject in high schools, given its growing importance in job postings. This is the opinion of LinkedIn’s community, surveyed by OPIT – Open Institute of Technology, an EU-accredited academic institution led by Professor Francesco Profumo, former Minister of Education, and Riccardo Ocleppo, Founder and Director. &lt;strong&gt;According to the survey, 66% of LinkedIn users think it is essential to teach AI in high schools. Additionally, 72% observed an increase in AI-related mentions in job postings, while 48% stated that AI proficiency is a key requirement for the companies they applied to. AI is primarily used for text generation (38%), research and analysis (38%), and translations (23%).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Build Cache Insights Beta - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-build-cache-insights-beta-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-build-cache-insights-beta-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce an open beta for Bitrise Build Cache Insights. This enhancement expands on our existing Build, Test, and Git Insights, enabling you to monitor and optimize your Bitrise Build Cache performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Intelligence is here. What does it mean for developers, consumers, and innovation? - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-intelligence-is-here-what-does-it-mean-for-developers-consumers-and-innovation-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-intelligence-is-here-what-does-it-mean-for-developers-consumers-and-innovation-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover how Apple is redefining generative AI with Apple Intelligence, seamlessly integrating it into iOS to enhance consumer experiences and empower developers. Explore its potential to connect apps, boost innovation, and transform the Apple ecosystem, while addressing challenges like app functionality, integration, and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack surface management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-surface-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-surface-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter the AI Awards here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;attack-surface-management-you-cant-protect-what-you-cant-see&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attack surface management: you can’t protect what you can’t see&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;By Marios Kyriacou&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines the attack surface of a software environment as “the sum of the different points where an unauthorised user can try to enter data, extract data, control a device or critical software in an environment.” It goes on to say. “&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping the attack surface as small as possible is a basic security measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-adaptive thresholds for AI-driven quality gating</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0146_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;auto-adaptive thresholds&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest release of the Site Reliability Guardian incorporates assistance from Dynatrace Davis® AI to automatically derive appropriate threshold targets and adjust them over time to protect your quality improvements. This process, known as auto-adaptive thresholding, eliminates the need to define a static threshold upfront. Instead, it derives the suitable thresholds from previous validation results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-an-umbrella-for-development-and-operations&#34;&gt;Build an umbrella for Development and Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, the discipline of platform engineering delivers DevSecOps practices to developers to bridge the gaps between development, security, and operations and enhance the developer experience. A key element in platform engineering is the establishment of fast feedback cycles regarding the quality and security measures of new software releases. To provide automated feedback for developers, the concept of quality gates for static code analysis in continuous integration is widely adopted throughout the industry. However, this perspective differs in the continuous deployment practices of various organizations, where the feedback is either delayed or not returned to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating AWS Well-Architected Framework validations with Dynatrace CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/aws-light-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | AWS&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace is proud to be the first AWS global tech partner to offer &lt;strong&gt;ready-to-use CloudFormation templates&lt;/strong&gt; for validating the Well-Architected pillars. The Dynatrace CloudFormation templates are now available in the &lt;strong&gt;AWS CloudFormation Public Extensions Registry&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes Well-Architected validation even more accessible for AWS users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace and the AWS Well-Architected Framework ensure continuous optimization of cloud architecture, aligning with the key pillars of operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability. Our previous blog post discussed the importance of integrating Dynatrace with the AWS Well-Architected Framework to enhance your software development lifecycle (SDLC). By leveraging Dynatrace Workflow Automation and the Site Reliability Guardian, organizations can ensure that their applications meet AWS’s best practices across all pillars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise on AWS: Benefits of using a cloud-native mobile CI/CD solution - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-on-aws-benefits-of-using-a-cloud-native-mobile-ci-cd-solution-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-on-aws-benefits-of-using-a-cloud-native-mobile-ci-cd-solution-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In mobile app development, a seamless and secure CI/CD process is crucial. Bitrise leads the way with its mobile-focused CI/CD platform, automating build, test, and deployment workflows. For organizations facing regional restrictions or compliance challenges, Bitrise on AWS offers the perfect solution—leveraging the power of AWS to meet your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise Release Management introduces CI Agnostic distribution for testing and releasing to stores - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-release-management-introduces-ci-agnostic-distribution-for-testing-and-releasing-to-stores-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-release-management-introduces-ci-agnostic-distribution-for-testing-and-releasing-to-stores-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Release Management&amp;rsquo;s new features streamline distribution for testing and store releases. Plus, you can integrate it with your choice of CI!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitrise support in December 2024: What to expect - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-support-in-december-2024-what-to-expect-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bitrise-support-in-december-2024-what-to-expect-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the holiday season nears and 2024 comes to a close, we want to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re fully informed about Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s operations during this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Infrastructure Management: Components, Tools, Benefits</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-infrastructure-management-components-tools-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-infrastructure-management-components-tools-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is cloud infrastructure management? Learn about the key components, types, benefits, challenges, tools, technologies, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike incident takeaways: Revisiting vendor quality control and release standards to minimize outage exposure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-incident-takeaways-revisiting-vendor-quality-control-and-release-standards-to-minimize-outage-exposure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key learning from the outage caused by the faulty CrowdStrike “Rapid Response” update is how critical it is to understand your vendors’ quality control and release processes. Vendors should not only offer advanced technology to fulfill a business requirement but also demonstrate a strong commitment to reliability, security, and customer support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A variety of events and circumstances can cause an outage. This blog will suggest five areas to consider and questions to ask when evaluating your existing vendors and their risk management strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CrowdStrike update outage: Managing continuous delivery and deployment risk with Dynatrace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-update-outage-managing-continuous-delivery-and-deployment-risk-with-dynatrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdstrike-update-outage-managing-continuous-delivery-and-deployment-risk-with-dynatrace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/b94c1fe7-371e-4894-a3b8-8a96f593307f-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Site Reliability Guardian, CrowdStrike outage&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After organizations struggled to recover from the CrowdStrike update outage on their Windows hosts in July, teams are now looking for ways to bolster the resiliency of their software update and continuous delivery practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread impact of the CrowdStrike issue demonstrated how critical it is to avoid outages and failures during software deployments to maintain user trust and satisfaction. Traditional deployment techniques that roll out updates or patches directly into full production can present significant risks and lead to potential downtime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delivering a first-class health app with Bitrise: An interview with Maven Clinic - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/delivering-a-first-class-health-app-with-bitrise-an-interview-with-maven-clinic-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/delivering-a-first-class-health-app-with-bitrise-an-interview-with-maven-clinic-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maven Clinic partnered with Bitrise to optimize its mobile development, improving efficiency, automation, and app performance. Learn how Bitrise&amp;rsquo;s mobile-first platform helped Maven streamline release processes and enhance collaboration across teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Evolved: What’s Next?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devops-evolved-whats-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devops-evolved-whats-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Developers and operations teams continue to refine this approach to enhance product quality and cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace completes 2024 FedRAMP Moderate reauthorization with Rev.5 transition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0162_1_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;FedRAMP&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-fedramp-moderate-and-transition-to-rev5&#34;&gt;Understanding FedRAMP Moderate and transition to Rev.5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP (Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program) is a government program that provides a standardized approach to security assessment, authorization, and continuous monitoring for cloud products and services for U.S. state and federal agencies. The FedRAMP Moderate baseline is designed to protect sensitive data that, if compromised, could seriously adversely affect operations, assets, or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP Revision 5 (Rev.5) prioritizes customizing security controls for specific risks. It aligns with Cloud Service Providers, providing a baseline while allowing tailored adjustments for individual federal agencies. FedRAMP adopts a threat-based approach to security controls. Rather than a one-size-fits-all model, this methodology tailors controls based on specific threats and risks. The result is a more effective security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace proud to receive the Ally Technology Velocity with Quality award</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-proud-to-receive-the-ally-technology-velocity-with-quality-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-proud-to-receive-the-ally-technology-velocity-with-quality-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Badge_-Technology-Velocity-with-Quality-1-300x159.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re proud to announce that Ally Financial has presented Dynatrace with its Ally Technology Velocity with Quality award. Ally Financial is the home of the nation’s largest all-digital bank and is an industry-leading auto financing business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the second time Ally Financial has presented its Ally Technology Partner Awards. Specifically, the company recognized five third-party suppliers for delivering outstanding service excellence across various criteria that align with Ally’s core values and performance standards. These criteria include operational excellence, security and data privacy, speed to market, and disruptive innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effortless internal and tester build distribution arrives in Bitrise - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effortless-internal-and-tester-build-distribution-arrives-in-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effortless-internal-and-tester-build-distribution-arrives-in-bitrise-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Build distribution for testing is here to streamline the process of distributing your mobile app builds into the hands of your internal and external testers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open For The 2025 AI Awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, UK –&lt;/strong&gt; The highly anticipated &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is set to take place on &lt;strong&gt;16th April 2025&lt;/strong&gt; in London, bringing together AI innovators from across the globe. This event promises a full day of immersive learning and networking, culminating in an evening dedicated to recognising the transformative contributions of AI professionals and organisations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AI Summit&lt;/strong&gt; offers a unique platform for industry professionals to engage in meaningful conversations, explore the latest advancements in AI, and expand their networks. With &lt;strong&gt;eight brilliant and trending topics&lt;/strong&gt;, the Summit covers the most pressing themes and opportunities within artificial intelligence, delivering valuable insights for attendees across industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open For The 2025 AI Awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-2025-ai-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London, UK –&lt;/strong&gt; The highly anticipated &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;AI Awards &amp;amp; Summit 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is set to take place on &lt;strong&gt;16th April 2025&lt;/strong&gt; in London, bringing together AI innovators from across the globe. This event promises a full day of immersive learning and networking, culminating in an evening dedicated to recognising the transformative contributions of AI professionals and organisations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The AI Summit&lt;/strong&gt; offers a unique platform for industry professionals to engage in meaningful conversations, explore the latest advancements in AI, and expand their networks. With &lt;strong&gt;eight brilliant and trending topics&lt;/strong&gt;, the Summit covers the most pressing themes and opportunities within artificial intelligence, delivering valuable insights for attendees across industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open for the Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangalore, India – &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is now accepting entries, offering an unparalleled opportunity to celebrate excellence in digital technologies. This prestigious awards program recognises the outstanding achievements of businesses, teams, and individuals across the Asia Pacific region and the UAE who have demonstrated exceptional innovation and commitment to enhancing business processes, customer experience, or cultural transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;15 diverse categories&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Agile Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entries Now Open for the Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/entries-now-open-for-the-asia-pacific-software-testing-awards-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangalore, India – &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Asia Pacific Software Testing Awards 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is now accepting entries, offering an unparalleled opportunity to celebrate excellence in digital technologies. This prestigious awards program recognises the outstanding achievements of businesses, teams, and individuals across the Asia Pacific region and the UAE who have demonstrated exceptional innovation and commitment to enhancing business processes, customer experience, or cultural transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;15 diverse categories&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Agile Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First DevOps, Now NoOps?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-devops-now-noops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-devops-now-noops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/devops-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Consider what could be possible if you’d fully automate the “Ops” aspect of DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Challenges Threatening the Success of Global DevOps Teams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-challenges-threatening-the-success-of-global-devops-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-challenges-threatening-the-success-of-global-devops-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/devops-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;DevOps promises faster development and easier maintenance, but there are some real-world challenges DevOps teams must contend with daily.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From syslog to AWS Firehose: Dynatrace log management innovations that enhance observability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-syslog-to-aws-firehose-dynatrace-log-management-innovations-that-enhance-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/BAE14229_RC_logs-consumption-blog_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;log management innovations&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding that the first mile of getting data in can often be the hardest, Dynatrace continues to invest in log ingest, offering a range of out-of-the-box solutions within the Dynatrace Platform and apps. We’re excited to announce several log management innovations, including native support for Syslog messages, seamless integration with AWS Firehose, an agentless approach using Kubernetes Platform Monitoring solution with Fluent Bit, a new out-of-the-box ingest dashboard, and OpenPipeline ingest improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gain clarity and control with custom git commit status reports - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gain-clarity-and-control-with-custom-git-commit-status-reports-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gain-clarity-and-control-with-custom-git-commit-status-reports-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bring clarity to your CI/CD pipeline with custom Git commit statuses. Define dynamic, target-specific status updates using YAML to track every workflow or pipeline effortlessly. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s feature testing, deployment, or a build cycle, gain clear, actionable insights directly in your Git provider interface—keeping your team informed and your workflows efficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting your iOS apps ready for Apple Intelligence - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-your-ios-apps-ready-for-apple-intelligence-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-your-ios-apps-ready-for-apple-intelligence-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, you will learn about the changes Apple Intelligence will bring to Apple’s virtual assistant, Siri, and how you can prepare your iOS app to take advantage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How 5G and AI are revolutionising industries for the next billion users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the insurance industry navigates a rapidly evolving landscape, Fadata looks ahead to 2025 and highlights the key developments and trends in insurance and digital transformation. &lt;strong&gt;Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-future-how-5g-and-ai-are-revolutionising-industries-for-the-next-billion-users&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Future: How 5G and AI Are Revolutionising Industries for the Next Billion Users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by: Prianca Ravichander, CMO and Head of Global B2B2X Monetisation at Tecnotree&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How observability, application security, and AI enhance DevOps and platform engineering maturity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps and platform engineering are essential disciplines that provide immense value in the realm of cloud-native technology and software delivery. However, these practices cannot stand alone. Rather, they must be bolstered by additional technological investments to ensure reliability, security, and efficiency. One of these key investments includes observability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Observability of applications and infrastructure serves as a critical foundation for DevOps and platform engineering, offering a comprehensive view into system performance and behavior. It goes beyond traditional monitoring—metrics, logs, and traces—to encompass topology mapping, code-level details, and user experience metrics that provide real-time insights. This real-time awareness enables teams to rapidly detect and resolve issues: both indispensable capabilities for maintaining the agility and reliability that are central to DevOps and platform engineering processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Red Hat and Dynatrace intelligently automate your production environment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Blog_-OTP-0100_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Red Hat and Dynatrace integration&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Red Hat and Dynatrace are joining forces to revolutionize day-one and day-two operations. A tight integration between Red Hat Ansible Automation Platform, Dynatrace Davis® AI, and the Dynatrace observability and security platform enables closed-loop remediation to automate the process from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detecting a problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Managing incidents in corresponding tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the root cause and proper countermeasures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Executing corrective actions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keeping relevant stakeholders in the loop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This way, disruptions are minimized, MTTR is significantly decreased, and DevSecOps and SREs collaborate efficiently to boost productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Smart Cities are Bridging the Digital Divide With AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-cities-are-bridging-the-digital-divide-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-cities-are-bridging-the-digital-divide-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Urban populations are expected to account for 68% of the global population, putting unprecedented strain on cities’ infrastructure. This rapid urbanisation is exposing critical gaps that compromise residents’ quality of life, from inefficient essential services to grid and water-management deficiencies. The implications are particularly profound for underserved communities, where infrastructure and basic services may already be lacking. Municipal leaders, policymakers, and sustainability directors are now grappling with the challenge of ensuring their cities evolve in a way that is both technologically advanced and equitable and inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Comments in Terraform Code</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-comments-in-terraform-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-add-comments-in-terraform-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to effectively comment on Terraform files with single-line and multiline comments. See examples and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Directory in Ansible Step-by-Step</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-directory-in-ansible-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-create-a-directory-in-ansible-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to create, manage, and remove directories in Ansible. Step-by-step guide with best practices, permissions, and error handling tips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important updates: Changes to App secrets API - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-updates-changes-to-app-secrets-api-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-updates-changes-to-app-secrets-api-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To manage your secrets more effectively, we&amp;rsquo;ve made a few updates to our API endpoints. Here’s what you need to know to keep your apps running smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In 2024, Prepare to Shift Down, Not Left</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/in-2024-prepare-to-shift-down-not-left/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/in-2024-prepare-to-shift-down-not-left/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/DevSecOps-security-kubernetes-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevSecOps-security-kubernetes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Sustainable innovation requires balancing developer capabilities with support from advanced tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inspiring action: Bitrise and Blood Agents join forces to mobilize blood donations in Ukraine - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inspiring-action-bitrise-and-blood-agents-join-forces-to-mobilize-blood-donations-in-ukraine-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inspiring-action-bitrise-and-blood-agents-join-forces-to-mobilize-blood-donations-in-ukraine-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building a life-saving app: learn how Bitrise and Blood Agents partnered to transform blood donation in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Graph Pipelines: build faster, build smarter - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-graph-pipelines-build-faster-build-smarter-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-graph-pipelines-build-faster-build-smarter-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you struggling to keep reducing build times as your project grows in complexity? Got particular workflows that take a long time to complete which needlessly hold up other parts of your build whilst you wait for the next stage? The waiting ends now with Graph Pipelines, a new feature which enables you to reduce overall build time by running CI tasks in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karpenter vs. Cluster Autoscaler – Kubernetes Scaling Tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/karpenter-vs-cluster-autoscaler-kubernetes-scaling-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/karpenter-vs-cluster-autoscaler-kubernetes-scaling-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;See the comparison between Karpenter and Cluster Autoscaling and choose the right solution for your Kubernetes scaling strategy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key AI Predictions within the growth and sustainability sector</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; continues to chip away at the environment, next year, data centres will face a pivotal moment. Facilities will start to realise that there isn’t enough energy. Companies that were influenced by competitive urgency and rushed into AI, now face decisions regarding cost and sustainability of the technology. For example, some AI in-house setups cost upwards of $300,000 in hardware alone.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the predictions below to learn about AI growth and sustainability. The predictions also cover data centre accountability, tech-savvy Gen Zs, the rise of AI agents, the role of digital twins in data centres and more. **Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.**rr&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key AI Predictions within the growth and sustainability sector</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/key-ai-predictions-within-the-growth-and-sustainability-sector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; continues to chip away at the environment, next year, data centres will face a pivotal moment. Facilities will start to realise that there isn’t enough energy. Companies that were influenced by competitive urgency and rushed into AI, now face decisions regarding cost and sustainability of the technology. For example, some AI in-house setups cost upwards of $300,000 in hardware alone.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the predictions below to learn about AI growth and sustainability. The predictions also cover data centre accountability, tech-savvy Gen Zs, the rise of AI agents, the role of digital twins in data centres and more. **Entries are now open for the 2025 AI Awards. Check out all the award categories here.**rr&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes with GitHub Actions: CI/CD for Containers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-with-github-actions-ci-cd-for-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kubernetes-with-github-actions-ci-cd-for-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this step-by-step guide, you’ll learn how to create a GitHub Actions workflow to automate Kubernetes deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observability throughout the software development lifecycle increases delivery performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0207_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, development teams suffer from a lack of automation for time-consuming tasks, the absence of standardization due to an overabundance of tool options, and insufficiently mature DevSecOps processes. This leads to frustrating bottlenecks for developers attempting to build and deliver software. For multinational enterprises, the cost of all that toil, complexity, and frustration multiplies exponentially due to the size of those organizations. In such contexts, platform engineering offers a compelling solution to enable business competitiveness in a manner that significantly enhances the developer experience. A central element of platform engineering teams is a robust Internal Developer Platform (IDP), which encompasses a set of tools, services, and infrastructure that enables developers to build, test, and deploy software applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliability indicators that matter to your business: SLOs for all data types</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0195_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-at-a-glance-view-of-your-systems-health-and-performance&#34;&gt;An at-a-glance view of your system’s health and performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace guides you in quickly getting the most valuable service level objectives (SLOs) set up in just a few clicks. To provide maximum freedom in selecting the service-level indicators that matter most to your business, Dynatrace combines SLOs with the power of Dynatrace Grail™ data lakehouse, the central data platform with heterogeneous and contextually linked data. Service-level objectives now utilize highly flexible Dynatrace Query Language (DQL) for all Grail data sources. This lets you build your SLOs around the indicators that matter to you and your customers—critical metrics related to availability, failure rates, request response times, or select logs and business events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Build Caching: The key to fast, efficient builds - Bitrise Blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-build-caching-the-key-to-fast-efficient-builds-bitrise-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-build-caching-the-key-to-fast-efficient-builds-bitrise-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slow build times are a developer’s biggest frustration and a major barrier to innovation. Tamás Bazsonyi, Solutions Engineer at Bitrise, explores how remote caching—the transformative &amp;ldquo;fly&amp;rdquo; step in build optimization—can cut build times by up to 90% and revolutionize your CI/CD pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RSA guide 2024: AI and security are top concerns for organizations in every industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rsa-guide-2024-ai-and-security-are-top-concerns-for-organizations-in-every-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/17619_RC_BlogImage_RSA-Guide_800x450_FINAL-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RSA guide, DevSecOps transformation and vulnerability management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is top of mind for security teams across every industry. As more organizations adopt generative AI and cloud-native technologies, IT teams confront more challenges with securing their high-performing cloud applications in the face of expanding attack surfaces. According to McKinsey’s State of AI in 2023 report, 40% of respondents said their organizations plan to increase their overall AI investment because of advancements in generative AI. But only 21% said their organizations have established policies governing employees’ use of generative AI technologies. Moreover, in addition to managing cloud spend and resource utilization, organizations must also now consider the cost and carbon impact of developing and using generative AI models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six causes of major software outages–And how to avoid them</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/six-causes-of-major-software-outages-and-how-to-avoid-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3d-abstract-beautiful-ba-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;software outages&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recent events have demonstrated, major software outages are an ever-present threat in our increasingly digital world. From business operations to personal communication, the reliance on software and cloud infrastructure is only increasing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outages can disrupt services, cause financial losses, and damage brand reputations. Understanding the causes of these outages is crucial for preventing them and ensuring smoother, more reliable tech operations. It’s also critical to have a strategy in place to address these outages, including both documented remediation processes and an observability platform to help you proactively identify and resolve issues to minimize customer and business impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmartBear Delivers Full-Stack Observability Insights for Developers with Back-end Performance Monitoring and Distributed Tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smartbear-delivers-full-stack-observability-insights-for-developers-with-back-end-performance-monitoring-and-distributed-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smartbear-delivers-full-stack-observability-insights-for-developers-with-back-end-performance-monitoring-and-distributed-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/automated-software-testing-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;automated-software-testing&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;BugSnag, a SmartBear solution, unveiled with back-end performance monitoring and OpenTelemetry-native distributed tracing for full end-to-end visibility into app experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software standards at risk as QA teams face new levels of pressure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital quality is integral to the development and rollout of new services. Yet managers and development teams alike often underestimate the value of &lt;strong&gt;quality assurance (QA)&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, many of the checks and balances required to deliver high-quality digital experiences are overlooked, putting companies at risk of losing customers and harming their reputations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mason, the CTO of Applause, believes the situation could reach boiling point in 2025 as businesses race to release new apps and features, placing more pressure on under-resourced QA teams. His predictions below offer caution and advice to organisations that want to ensure digital quality across the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software standards at risk as QA teams face new levels of pressure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/software-standards-at-risk-as-qa-teams-face-new-levels-of-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digital quality is integral to the development and rollout of new services. Yet managers and development teams alike often underestimate the value of &lt;strong&gt;quality assurance (QA)&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, many of the checks and balances required to deliver high-quality digital experiences are overlooked, putting companies at risk of losing customers and harming their reputations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rob Mason, the CTO of Applause, believes the situation could reach boiling point in 2025 as businesses race to release new apps and features, placing more pressure on under-resourced QA teams. His predictions below offer caution and advice to organisations that want to ensure digital quality across the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spacelift Wins 2024 Digital Innovator Award from Intellyx</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spacelift-wins-2024-digital-innovator-award-from-intellyx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/spacelift-wins-2024-digital-innovator-award-from-intellyx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intellyx has just revealed we’ve won the Winter 2024 Intellyx Digital Innovator Award, crowning a year of achievement for Spacelift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of DevOps is AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-devops-is-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-devops-is-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/DevOps-AI-AIOps-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DevOps-AI-AIOps&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Uncover how AI-driven code generation reshapes testing, agile planning, and the future of enterprise DevOps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The growing challenge of secrets management in DevOps and how automation can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The age of agile software development and the cloud has caused an explosion in enterprise secrets. From passwords, encryption keys and APIs, to tokens and certificates, digital secrets are what control access when data is transferred between applications. They’re essential to maintaining the security of that data, and in turn, the successful operation of digital enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-top-emerging-security-challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A top emerging security challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise, then, that secrets are extremely valuable to threat actors. Businesses need a robust secrets management strategy in place in order to not only effectively manage the respective secrets across their lifecycle, but also protect them from compromise. This is becoming a significant challenge within DevOps specifically, with Thales’ Data Threat Report finding that secrets management was identified as the top emerging DevOps security challenge by respondents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The growing challenge of secrets management in DevOps and how automation can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-growing-challenge-of-secrets-management-in-devops-and-how-automation-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The age of agile software development and the cloud has caused an explosion in enterprise secrets. From passwords, encryption keys and APIs, to tokens and certificates, digital secrets are what control access when data is transferred between applications. They’re essential to maintaining the security of that data, and in turn, the successful operation of digital enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-top-emerging-security-challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A top emerging security challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise, then, that secrets are extremely valuable to threat actors. Businesses need a robust secrets management strategy in place in order to not only effectively manage the respective secrets across their lifecycle, but also protect them from compromise. This is becoming a significant challenge within DevOps specifically, with Thales’ Data Threat Report finding that secrets management was identified as the top emerging DevOps security challenge by respondents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of DevOps Automation assessment: How automated are you?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-devops-automation-assessment-how-automated-are-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-devops-automation-assessment-how-automated-are-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/devops-concept-with-infi-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The benefits of unified observability and security for BizDevSecOps use cases&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to the scale and complexity of modern cloud-native technology, organizations are increasingly reliant on automation to properly manage their infrastructure and workflows. DevOps automation eliminates extraneous manual processes, enabling DevOps teams to develop, test, deliver, deploy, and execute other key processes at scale. Automation thus contributes to accelerated productivity and innovation across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automation can be particularly powerful when applied to DevOps workflows. According to the Dynatrace 2023 DevOps Automation Pulse report, an average of 56% of end-to-end DevOps processes are automated across organizations of all kinds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of Salesforce DevOps 2024: Key Insights from Gearset’s Annual Survey</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-salesforce-devops-2024-key-insights-from-gearsets-annual-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-salesforce-devops-2024-key-insights-from-gearsets-annual-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Survey findings underscore the critical role of unified processes, more training, and continuous improvement in achieving DevOps excellence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Infrastructure as Code (IaC) Scanning Tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-10-infrastructure-as-code-iac-scanning-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-10-infrastructure-as-code-iac-scanning-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the top Infrastructure as Code (IaC) security scanning tools you should use in 2025 to improve your deployments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is OpenTelemetry? An open source standard for logs, metrics, and traces</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/NAM-2379-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is OpenTelemetry? The range of open source observability technologies can be daunting, and it’s easy to get overwhelmed. When it comes to managing complex multicloud environments and the services that run on them, however, it’s important to standardize, which is where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemtery was born from the combination of OpenCensus and OpenTracing and has emerged as the open source telemetry standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Are You on Your DevOps Journey?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-are-you-on-your-devops-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-are-you-on-your-devops-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devprojournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/devops-ISV-software-development-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devops-ISV-software-development&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Can ISVs achieve the benefits of DevOps without increasing developer stress and burnout?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
