<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/microsoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/microsoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zloader Banking a new Malware attack can be bypass Microsoft Signature Verification.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ZLoader malware campaign is exploiting a nine-year-old flaw in Microsoft’s digital signature verification to steal credentials and sensitive information using remote monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Check Point Research, which has been tracking the sophisticated infection chain since November 2021, it has been attributed to a cybercriminal group dubbed MalSmoke, citing similarities with previous attacks. “The infection chain incorporates legitimate remote management software (RMM) to gain access to the target machine.” After injecting its payload into a signed DLL, the malware further evades the system’s defenses by exploiting Microsoft’s digital signature verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Is Adding New Cryptography Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-is-adding-new-cryptography-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is updating SymCrypt, its core cryptographic library, with new quantum-secure algorithms. Microsoft’s details are here. From a news article:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first new algorithm Microsoft added to SymCrypt is called ML-KEM. Previously known as CRYSTALS-Kyber, ML-KEM is one of three post-quantum standards formalized last month by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). The KEM in the new name is short for key encapsulation. KEMs can be used by two parties to negotiate a shared secret over a public channel. Shared secrets generated by a KEM can then be used with symmetric-key cryptographic operations, which aren’t vulnerable to Shor’s algorithm when the keys are of a sufficient size&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
