<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sideloading Low-Level Extraction Agent with Regular Apple IDs from Windows and Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/EIFT-8.60_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Low-level extraction enables access to all the data stored in the iOS device. Previously, sideloading the extraction agent for imaging the file system and decrypting keychain required enrolling one’s Apple ID into Apple’s paid Developer Program if one used a Windows or Linux PC. Mac users could utilize a regular, non-developer Apple ID. Today, we are bringing this feature to Windows and Linux editions of iOS Forensic Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are several different methods achieving essentially the same goal, modern devices (starting with those based on the chip found in the iPhone Xr/Xs) require the use of a special app called extraction agent. On the device, the extraction agent attempts to acquire the required level of privileges by utilizing a chain of exploits, which is an absolute requirement for accessing the root of the file system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Midori Browser 11.5 Added Headless Mode &amp; New App Icon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ubuntuhandbook.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/midora-newicon-250x250.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori web browser announced new 11.5 release recently with some exciting new features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori was a popular lightweight web browser that was default in elementary OS and Bodhi Linux. It’s now a free open-source Firefox derived browser developed by Astian Foundation, and licensed under the Mozilla Public License (MPL).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The browser released new 11.5 recently, changed its app icon from a green lizard to &lt;strong&gt;new flat design logo&lt;/strong&gt; that IMO feels better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 essential Linux commands for every user</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From new user to power user, here are 20 Linux commands that will make your life easier.Typing commands into a darkened terminal window might seem puzzling, but for many computer users, it&amp;rsquo;s the most efficient, most accessible and clearest way to accomplish nearly any task on a computer. These days, thanks to all the projects that bring open source commands to non-open platforms like macOS and Windows, and with containers running everywhere, terminal commands are relevant to everybody. Try Red Hat Enterprise Linux before you buy, with a free 60-day evaluation.Here are the top 20 commands a mod&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running AI Locally Without Spending All Day on Setup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/LargeLanguageModel.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many AI models out there that you can play with from companies like OpenAI, Google, and a host of others. But when you use them, you get the experience they want, and you run it on their computer. There are a variety of reasons you might not like this. You may not want your data or ideas sent through someone else’s computer. Maybe you want to tune and tweak in ways they aren’t going to let you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a public or private network in Windows, and why does it matter?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-public-or-private-network-in-windows-and-why-does-it-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-public-or-private-network-in-windows-and-why-does-it-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You might have seen Windows 11 labeling networks as public or private, but what do these options mean? It&amp;rsquo;s all about security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At one point or another, you may have noticed that Windows labels your Wi-Fi networks as either private or public networks in the Wi-Fi settings. In fact, by default, they&amp;rsquo;re all public networks, even if you&amp;rsquo;re using it at home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
