<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awssecurity on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/awssecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awssecurity on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/awssecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP High authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP Moderate authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
