<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Botnet on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/botnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Botnet on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/botnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new botnet Orchard Generates DGA Domains with Bitcoin Transaction Information</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-new-botnet-orchard-generates-dga-domains-with-bitcoin-transaction-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-new-botnet-orchard-generates-dga-domains-with-bitcoin-transaction-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DGA is one of the classic techniques for botnets to hide their C2s, attacker only needs to selectively register a very small number of C2 domains, while for the defenders, it is difficult to determine in advance which domain names will be generated and registered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;360 netlab has long focused on the research of botnet attack and defense technology, we maintain a free DGA feed and share the research results with the industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fodcha Is Coming Back, Raising A Wave of Ransom  DDoS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fodcha-is-coming-back-raising-a-wave-of-ransom-ddos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fodcha-is-coming-back-raising-a-wave-of-ransom-ddos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On April 13, 2022, 360Netlab first disclosed the &lt;code&gt;Fodcha&lt;/code&gt; botnet. After our article was published, Fodcha suffered a crackdown from the relevant authorities, and its authors quickly responded by leaving &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Netlab pls leave me alone I surrender&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; in an updated sample.No surprise, Fodcha&amp;rsquo;s authors didn&amp;rsquo;t really stop updating after the fraudulent surrender, and soon a new version was released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the new version, the authors of Fodcha redesigned the communication protocol and started to use &lt;code&gt;xxtea&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;chacha20&lt;/code&gt; algorithms to encrypt sensitive resources and network communications to avoid detection at the file &amp;amp; traffic level; at the same time, a dual-C2 scheme with &lt;code&gt;OpenNIC domain&lt;/code&gt; as the primary C2 and &lt;code&gt;ICANN domain&lt;/code&gt; as the backup C2 was adopted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fodcha, a new DDos botnet</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fodcha-a-new-ddos-botnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fodcha-a-new-ddos-botnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, CNCERT and 360netlab worked together and discovered a rapidly spreading DDoS botnet on the Internet. The global infection looks fairly big as just in China there are more than 10,000 daily active bots (IPs) and alsomore than 100 DDoS victims beingtargeted on a daily basis. We named the botnet Fodcha because of its initial use of the C2 domain name folded.in and its use of the chacha algorithm to encrypt network traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heads up! Xdr33, A Variant Of CIA’s HIVE  Attack Kit Emerges</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heads-up-xdr33-a-variant-of-cias-hive-attack-kit-emerges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heads-up-xdr33-a-variant-of-cias-hive-attack-kit-emerges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Oct 21, 2022, 360Netlab&amp;rsquo;s honeypot system captured a suspicious ELF file &lt;code&gt;ee07a74d12c0bb3594965b51d0e45b6f&lt;/code&gt;, which propagated via F5 vulnerability with zero VT detection, our system observces that it communicates with IP &lt;code&gt;45.9.150.144&lt;/code&gt; using SSL with &lt;strong&gt;forged Kaspersky certificates&lt;/strong&gt;, this caught our attention. After further lookup, we confirmed that this sample was adapted from the leaked Hive project server source code from CIA. &lt;strong&gt;This is the first time we caught a variant of the CIA HIVE attack kit in the wild&lt;/strong&gt;, and we named it &lt;code&gt;xdr33&lt;/code&gt; based on its embedded Bot-side certificate &lt;code&gt;CN=xdr33&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PureCrypter is busy pumping out various malicious malware families</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/purecrypter-is-busy-pumping-out-various-malicious-malware-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/purecrypter-is-busy-pumping-out-various-malicious-malware-families/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our daily botnet analysis work, it is common to encounter various loaders.Compared to other types of malware, loaders are unique in that they are mainly used to &amp;ldquo;promote&amp;rdquo;, i.e., download and run other malware on the infected machine. According to our observations, most loaders are proprietary and have a binding relationship with the family they are promoting. A few loader families make themselves into promotion platforms that can spread any other malware family, achieving the so-called malware-as-a-service (MaaS). Compared with proprietary loaders, MaaS types are obviously more dangerous and should be our primary target of concern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
