<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Un on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/un/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Un on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/un/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>• 🚀 Frontend Developer Ready for New Adventures | #OpenToWork</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/-frontend-developer-ready-for-new-adventures-opentowork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/-frontend-developer-ready-for-new-adventures-opentowork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year begins full of possibilities, new professional chapter: Open to Work!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;After a journey of learning, challenges, and experiences, I am seeking new opportunities as a Front-end Developer to apply my knowledge and experiences in ways that allow me to expand my horizons even further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personal projects:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🪴Breath Natural - NestJS Chronicles Part 1 &amp;lt;- NestJS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Food Hut - Angular Chronicles - Part 1 &amp;lt;- AngularJs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🌿Github &amp;lt;- Github&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;💻 My core skills:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;CVE-2024-12854 - &#34;WordPress Garden Gnome Package Plugin Remote Code Execution File Upload Vulnerability&#34;&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12854&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Garden Gnome Package plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the functionality that automatically extracts &amp;lsquo;ggpkg&amp;rsquo; files that have been uploaded in all versions up to, and including, 2.3.0. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Midori Browser 11.5 Added Headless Mode &amp; New App Icon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ubuntuhandbook.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/midora-newicon-250x250.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori web browser announced new 11.5 release recently with some exciting new features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori was a popular lightweight web browser that was default in elementary OS and Bodhi Linux. It’s now a free open-source Firefox derived browser developed by Astian Foundation, and licensed under the Mozilla Public License (MPL).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The browser released new 11.5 recently, changed its app icon from a green lizard to &lt;strong&gt;new flat design logo&lt;/strong&gt; that IMO feels better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Samsung&#39;s new Odyssey gaming monitors require a monster PC build&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/samsungs-new-odyssey-gaming-monitors-require-a-monster-pc-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/samsungs-new-odyssey-gaming-monitors-require-a-monster-pc-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung unveiled some ultra powerful gaming monitors at CES 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas is where some of the largest names in tech gather to announce the technologies and products that will define next year&amp;rsquo;s product cycles. Against that backdrop, CES is also well-known for outrageous product releases not exactly aimed at the average consumer, and Samsung&amp;rsquo;s new Odyssey gaming monitors announced at CES 2025 are the perfect example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 essential Linux commands for every user</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From new user to power user, here are 20 Linux commands that will make your life easier.Typing commands into a darkened terminal window might seem puzzling, but for many computer users, it&amp;rsquo;s the most efficient, most accessible and clearest way to accomplish nearly any task on a computer. These days, thanks to all the projects that bring open source commands to non-open platforms like macOS and Windows, and with containers running everywhere, terminal commands are relevant to everybody. Try Red Hat Enterprise Linux before you buy, with a free 60-day evaluation.Here are the top 20 commands a mod&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 NIST rules on minimum password length: Aim for 16 characters or more!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta our focus is to keep our users&amp;rsquo; data secure with quantum-safe encryption. To achieve maximum security, the importance of strong, secure passwords that are long enough cannot be overstated. Passwords and the password length are the first line of defense to make sure that no unauthorized access can bring harm to your data or yourself. While factors like complexity and unpredictability matter, experts emphasize that length is a critical element in ensuring password security. But given new threats of quantum computers, what is the optimal minimum password length recommended by NIST and CISA?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38C3: It’s TOSLINK, Over Long Distance Fibre</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/fibre-toslink-featured.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve owned a CD player or other piece of consumer digital audio gear manufactured since the 1980s, the chances are it has a TOSLINK port on the back. This is a fairly simple interface that sends I2S digital audio data down a short length of optical fibre, and it’s designed to run between something like a CD player and an external DAC. It’s ancient technology in optical fibre terms, with a lowish data rate and plastic fibre, but consider for a minute whether it could be adapted for modern ultra-high-speed conenctions. It’s what [Ben Cartwright-Cox] has done, and he delivered a talk about it at the recent 38C3 event in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 reasons you should you use 2FA apps over SMS-based authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2FA over SMS isn&amp;rsquo;t just unreliable, it&amp;rsquo;s also a security risk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MFA, or Multi-Factor Authentication, has proliferated throughout our computing lives over the last decade. It largely began with SMS-based authentication in addition to a password, allowing users to add an extra layer of authentication by forcing users to enter a code sent to their phone upon an attempted login. The truth is, SMS-based authentication was never secure. Due to the inherent technology and the infrastructure around SIM cards, 2FA with SMS is not only inadequate; it also actively compromises your security, and here are 4 reasons why you should use a dedicated 2FA app instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 features to look for when buying a new mouse</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-features-to-look-for-when-buying-a-new-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-features-to-look-for-when-buying-a-new-mouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Buying a new mouse? Here are a few things you should be on the lookout for to make sure you get the right one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upgrading any part of your computer setup is always a fun time. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not a gamer, getting that little bit of extra comfort or quality can go a long way toward making your experience better. It could make it easier to win games, but it could also help you get work done faster, and that&amp;rsquo;s no different with computer mice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add Onvite to Rails 8 Authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/add-onvite-to-rails-8-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/add-onvite-to-rails-8-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published on Rails Designer Build a SaaS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the third article on Building a SaaS with Ruby on Rails. This article continues where the previous one, adding sign up to Rails 8&amp;rsquo; authentication, stops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most SaaS products are used by multiple people from the same team or company. Although I would, when you start building your SaaS, urge you to keep it simple and just support one user on launch. I would álso urge you to build the blocks needed for teams in your app from the get-go. Having to deal with workspaces, teams and roles when you already have users is a bigger pain than you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check out this post on one of the non-functional requirements for your applications - Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-this-post-on-one-of-the-non-functional-requirements-for-your-applications-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-this-post-on-one-of-the-non-functional-requirements-for-your-applications-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Forganization%2Fprofile_image%2F2794%2F88da75b6-aadd-4ea1-8083-ae2dfca8be94.png&#34; alt=&#34;AWS Community Builders &#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F1037830%2F5768f8f1-81ca-4d33-bcd1-0d9312b2451c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-functional-application-requirements-security&#34;&gt;Non-functional Application Requirements: Security&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oluwasegun-adedigba-for-aws-community-builders--jan-7&#34;&gt;Oluwasegun Adedigba for AWS Community Builders ・ Jan 7&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#aws #security #discuss #softwaredevelopment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud economics vs. Cloud FinOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-economics-vs-cloud-finops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-economics-vs-cloud-finops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La gestión de costos en los últimos años, se ha priorizado para que la migración o implementación de los servicios nube mantengan un enfoque de optimización, que favorezca el valor de negocio de las compañías, es decir, una operación computacional guiada por principios de optimización financiera&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cloud economics se encarga de estudiar el costo-beneficio del uso de los recursos en las plataformas de nube.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sus principios fundamentales, son dos, el primero respecta la implicación de las economías de escala, que representan un ahorro para las empresas al adquirir recursos de nube en grandes cantidades sin la inversión de una propia infraestructura física, como centros de datos de gran capacidad, lo que representa una disminución en las cifras de CAPEX de las empresas -es decir la inversión de capital- (ORACLE, 2024)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Y el segundo; alcance global, que es una característica clave de la computación en la nube, pues es posible acceder a recursos desde cualquier parte del mundo, gracias a las regiones de centros de datos de los diferentes proveedores de nube, que existen actualmente. Esto implica un ahorro para las compañías, pues no es necesario incurrir en costos de mano de obra en cada zona para desplegar infraestructura, y ofertar servicios.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Por su lado, Cloud FinOps, es una disciplina de gestión financiera que permite una mayor comprensión de los gastos en la nube, para la mejor toma de decisiones de optimización de costos y recursos, su objetivo fundamental no es el ahorro económico, por sí sólo, sino la optimización, logrando que todos los recursos se aprovechen conforme a los cambios en la demanda, y el ahorro pueda reinvertirse en otros proyectos o recursos, como la innovación y la mejora tecnológica continua (TIVIT, 2023)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Para este punto, podría parecer que ambas disciplinas se dedican a lo mismo, sin embargo, quisiera ahondar en la comprensión de la diferencia mientras evaluamos dos conceptualizaciones clave que tiene un caso similar, es decir, Dev y DevOps.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dev se centra en la creación de software con tareas como escribir código, diseñar arquitecturas, probar nuevas funcionalidades y corregir errores. Su objetivo fundamental es la creación de software funcional, eficiente y acorde con las necesidades del usuario (IBM, 2024). Mientras que DevOps es una metodología enfocada en la integración y la colaboración entre los equipos de desarrollo y operaciones de IT con el objetivo de mejorar la eficiencia en la entrega del software -Una gran diferencia si me lo preguntan a mí-, sin embargo, para lograr estos objetivos Dev y DevOps trabajan juntos ya que la colaboración entre ambos es fundamental para lograr un ciclo de vida de desarrollo de software más eficiente, rápido y de calidad.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Algo muy similar ocurre con Cloud Economics y Finops&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Esta última mantiene un enfoque operativo. Se centra en las mejores prácticas para gestionar y optimizar los costos en la nube, para lograrlo, los equipos de FinOps desarrollan una cultura con las áreas de desarrollo, operaciones y finanzas para equilibrar costos&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Por su lado Cloud Economics, tiene una perspectiva más estratégica y de largo plazo. Analiza la economía detrás de la adopción de la nube, incluyendo el análisis de costo-beneficio, y el cálculo del retorno de inversión conocido como -ROI-, así como los cambios en el gasto en nube a lo largo del tiempo (BBVA, 2024).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Haciendo un simil con los dos primeros conceptos presentados, cloud economics es muy similar a Dev, su objetivo es medir la economía detrás de la nube, mientras que FinOps es una cultura o conjunto de buenas prácticas como devops que busca alcanzar la optimización de costos&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ComfyUI tips for improved workflow</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/comfyui-tips-for-improved-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/comfyui-tips-for-improved-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ComfyUI tips to improve workflow and productivity, even for the beginner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even if you’ve been using ComfyUI for a while, you’re bound to discover something that seems simple in hindsight, but you just never noticed. I’ve been using ComfyUI for almost two years now, and I still remember how overwhelming it was to open someone else’s workflow — dozens of nodes, hundreds of parameters, and all that spaghetti everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the scope of IAM Access Analyzer unused access analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management Access Analyzer simplifies inspecting unused access to guide you towards least privilege. You can use unused access findings to identify over-permissive access granted to AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles and users in your accounts or organization. From a delegated administrator account for IAM Access Analyzer, you can use the dashboard to review unused access findings across your organization and prioritize the accounts to inspect based on the volume and type of findings. The findings highlight unused roles, unused access keys for IAM users, and unused passwords for IAM users. For active IAM users and roles, the findings provide visibility into unused services and actions. Recently, IAM Access Analyzer launched new configuration capabilities that you can use to customize the analysis. You can select accounts, roles, and users to exclude, and focus on the areas that matter the most to you. You can use identifiers such as account ID or scale configuration using tags. By scoping the IAM Access Analyzer to monitor a subset of accounts and roles, you can reduce noise from unwanted findings. You can update the configuration when needed to change the scope of analysis. With this new offering, IAM Access Analyzer provides enhanced controls to help you tailor the analysis more closely to your organization’s security needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12431 - GitLab Unauthorized Issue Status Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12431-gitlab-unauthorized-issue-status-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12431-gitlab-unauthorized-issue-status-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12431&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; An issue was discovered in GitLab CE/EE affecting all versions starting from 15.5 before 17.5.5, 17.6 before 17.6.3, and 17.7 before 17.7.1, in which unauthorized users could manipulate the status of issues in public projects.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.3 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12853 - WordPress Modula Image Gallery Remote File Upload Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12853&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Modula Image Gallery plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the zip upload functionality in all versions up to, and including, 2.11.10. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13189 - ZeroWdd MyBlog Remote File Permission Bypass Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13189&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical has been found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This affects an unknown part of the file src/main/java/com/wdd/myblog/config/MyBlogMvcConfig.java. The manipulation leads to permission issues. It is possible to initiate the attack remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13190 - ZeroWdd Myblog Xml Injection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13190&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical was found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This vulnerability affects unknown code of the file src/main/resources/mapper/BlogMapper.xml. The manipulation of the argument findBlogList/getTotalBlogs leads to xml injection. The attack can be initiated remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.3 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-52869 - Teradata SUSE Enterprise Linux Server Elevated Privilege Group Misassignment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-52869&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Certain Teradata account-handling code through 2024-11-04, used with SUSE Enterprise Linux Server, mismanages groups. Specifically, when there is an operating system move from SUSE Enterprise Linux Server (SLES) 12 Service Pack (SP) 2 or 3 to SLES 15 SP2 on Teradata Database systems, some service/system user accounts, and possibly systems administrator created user accounts, are incorrectly assigned to groups that allow higher system-level privileges than intended for those user accounts. Depending on the usage of these accounts, this may lead to full system compromise.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54010 - Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches ICMP and UDP Packet Forwarding Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54010&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability in the firewall component of HPE Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches exists. It could allow an unauthenticated adjacent attacker to conduct a packet forwarding attack against the ICMP and UDP protocol. For this attack to be successful an attacker requires a switch configuration that allows packets routing (at layer 3). Configurations that do not allow network traffic routing are not impacted. Successful exploitation could allow an attacker to bypass security policies, potentially leading to unauthorized data exposure.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.4 | LOW&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54818 - SourceCodester Computer Laboratory Management System Unauthenticated Remote OS Command Injection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54818-sourcecodester-computer-laboratory-management-system-unauthenticated-remote-os-command-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54818-sourcecodester-computer-laboratory-management-system-unauthenticated-remote-os-command-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54818&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; SourceCodester Computer Laboratory Management System 1.0 is vulnerable to Incorrect Access Control. via /php-lms/admin/?page=user/list.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-55656 - Redis RedisBloom Probabilistic Data Structures Integer Overflow Information Leak Out-of-Bounds Write</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-55656&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 4:15 p.m. | 5 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; RedisBloom adds a set of probabilistic data structures to Redis. There is an integer overflow vulnerability in RedisBloom, which is a module used in Redis. The integer overflow vulnerability allows an attacker (a redis client which knows the password) to allocate memory in the heap lesser than the required memory due to wraparound. Then read and write can be performed beyond this allocated memory, leading to info leak and OOB write. The integer overflow is in CMS.INITBYDIM command, which initialize a Count-Min Sketch to dimensions specified by user. It accepts two values (width and depth) and uses them to allocate memory in NewCMSketch(). This vulnerability is fixed in 2.2.19, 2.4.12, 2.6.14, and 2.8.2.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0194 - GitLab Information Disclosure</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0194-gitlab-information-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0194-gitlab-information-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-0194&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; An issue was discovered in GitLab CE/EE affecting all versions starting from 17.4 prior to 17.5.1, starting from 17.6 prior to 17.6.1, and starting from 17.7 prior to 17.7.1. Under certain conditions, access tokens may have been logged when API requests were made in a specific manner.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.5 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22137 - Pingvin Share File Traversal</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22137-pingvin-share-file-traversal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22137-pingvin-share-file-traversal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22137&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 4:15 p.m. | 5 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Pingvin Share is a self-hosted file sharing platform and an alternative for WeTransfer. This vulnerability allows an authenticated or unauthenticated (if anonymous shares are allowed) user to overwrite arbitrary files on the server, including sensitive system files, via HTTP POST requests. The issue has been patched in version 1.4.0.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 9.8 | CRITICAL&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22140 - WeGIA SQL Injection Vulnerability (Authenticated)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22140&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A SQL Injection vulnerability was identified in the /html/funcionario/dependente_listar_um.php endpoint, specifically in the id_dependente parameter. This vulnerability allows attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands, compromising the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the database. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22145 - Carbon PHP DateTime Remote File Include Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22145&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Carbon is an international PHP extension for DateTime. Application passing unsanitized user input to Carbon::setLocale are at risk of arbitrary file include, if the application allows users to upload files with .php extension in an folder that allows include or require to read it, then they are at risk of arbitrary code ran on their servers. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.8.4 and 2.72.6.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term &lt;em&gt;real-world&lt;/em&gt; data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to learn quickly without needing to venture into the world of data cleaning, but real-world data has problems and is messy. Real-world data needs cleaning before it can give us useful insights, and that’s the subject of this blog post. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data of more than 8,500 customers breached on Green Bay Packers shopping website</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-of-more-than-8500-customers-breached-on-green-bay-packers-shopping-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-of-more-than-8500-customers-breached-on-green-bay-packers-shopping-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Green Bay Packers Pro Shop website was exposed to malicious code that stole data about more than 8,500 shoppers, the NFL team says.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with internet addiction</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dealing-with-internet-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guten Morgen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Farticles%2Fwsjqfjhcbr5p8ysj2pdw.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Kitty stretchs&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wish I could know who drew the cover image. It&amp;rsquo;s very well done. Would suggest you to check out their work, but sadly not even I know.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I wanted to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m going through. This is by no means an exhaustive research made alongside a mental health professional, and I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for anything that will be written here to be of any utility to anybody. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t pretend to be that. It&amp;rsquo;s merely a blog post of someone who wishes to start 2025 in good spirits, avoiding the pitfalls, so that it becomes the professional it seeks to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading the same file 102&#43; times</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have YOU ever tried downloading the same file 102+ times in your favorite browser? Do you know what happens on the 102nd time? 🙃&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do. The answer is &amp;hellip; it depends 😋 It varies between browsers and it’s a bit of a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I show you the screenshots, let me first tell you a short story about how I ended up in the &lt;em&gt;“lets-download-this-file-102-times”&lt;/em&gt; rabbit hole so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education software firm’s hack exposes personal data for students, teachers nationwide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/education-software-firms-hack-exposes-personal-data-for-students-teachers-nationwide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/education-software-firms-hack-exposes-personal-data-for-students-teachers-nationwide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An education software company which stores data belonging to more than 60 million K-12 students and teachers on Tuesday said it had been hacked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Things First | SentinelOne Is A Fortune Best Workplace for Parents</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents, ranking among the top 70 companies worldwide for working parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wellbeing comes first at SentinelOne – for our customers, our communities, and our colleagues. We are proud to foster a culture of diversity, equality, and understanding for all. Supporting our working parents and the notion of a family’s evolving needs is a key part of that philosophy, and that is why we are extremely proud to be included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLOSS Weekly Episode 815: You Win Some, You Lose Some</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/floss-weekly-episode-815-you-win-some-you-lose-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/floss-weekly-episode-815-you-win-some-you-lose-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pipewire.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, Jonathan Bennett and Randal chat with Matija Šuklje about Open Source and the Law! How do Open Source projects handle liability, what should a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) look like, and where can an individual or project turn for legal help?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matija.suklje.name/&#34;&gt;https://matija.suklje.name/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openchainproject.org&#34;&gt;https://openchainproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matija.suklje.name/fiduciary-license-agreement-20&#34;&gt;https://matija.suklje.name/fiduciary-license-agreement-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can watch the live recording of the show Right on our YouTube Channel? Have someone you’d like us to interview? Let us know, or contact the guest and have them contact us! Take a look at the schedule here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google AI Developers Community Spotlight Contest</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-ai-developers-community-spotlight-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-ai-developers-community-spotlight-contest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Google AI Developers Community Spotlight Contest is seeking innovative, diverse projects using Google&amp;rsquo;s AI tools like Gemini and Gemma to create code repositories, videos, documentation, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s why Julia is THE language in scientific programming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working in quantum computing is being exposed to a whole new set of skills and tools. For those of us coming from the software engineering side, discovering the things our academic peers are using is an interesting experience. One of the best for me personally was coming across the Julia programming language, and learning why it has become the go-to language for serious scientific programming in some circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different hacking techniques to be aware of. At the time of publication, the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework identified some 236 hacking techniques across 14 different categories. Luckily, you don’t need to understand all these tactics to stay safe. Many are close variations of the same basic approach. The best cybersecurity tools […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks appeared first on Heimdal Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to recall an email in Outlook</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-recall-an-email-in-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-recall-an-email-in-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you made a mistake in an email and need to recall it, see how to unsend an email in Outlook.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why someone may want to recall an email, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a simple mistake, the wrong recipient, or something more serious, like leaking confidential data. Fortunately, Microsoft Outlook users need not fret on such an occasion as Outlook has a built-in and easy-to-use recall feature to help unsend emails. However, there are caveats to the process, so it is important to consider a few factors before taking advantage of this feature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laravel IQ - Level 1 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ১&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Laravel কীভাবে MVC আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Laravel &lt;strong&gt;MVC&lt;/strong&gt; (Model-View-Controller) আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model:&lt;/strong&gt; ডাটাবেসের সঙ্গে কাজ করার জন্য ব্যবহৃত হয়। এটি ডাটাবেস কোয়েরি ও ডাটাবেস সম্পর্কিত লজিক পরিচালনা করে।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View:&lt;/strong&gt; ব্যবহারকারীর জন্য UI বা প্রেজেন্টেশন লেয়ার তৈরি করে। Blade টেমপ্লেট ইঞ্জিন ব্যবহার করে HTML পেজ তৈরি করা হয়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; এটি Model এবং View এর মধ্যে যোগাযোগ করায়। Controller ডাটাবেস থেকে ডেটা নিয়ে View-তে পাঠায়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ২&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Routing কী? Laravel-এ Route এবং Controller এর মধ্যে সম্পর্ক ব্যাখ্যা কর।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Routing ব্যবহার করে Laravel অ্যাপ্লিকেশনে &lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt; এবং এর সাথে সংযুক্ত ক্রিয়াকলাপ সংজ্ঞায়িত করা হয়।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source all the way down: Upgrading our developer documentation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Cloudflare, we treat developer content like a product, where we take the user and their feedback into consideration. We are constantly iterating, testing, analyzing, and refining content. Inspired by agile practices, treating developer content like an open source product means we approach our documentation the same way an open source software project is created and maintained.  Open source documentation empowers the developer community because it allows anyone, anywhere, to contribute content. By making both the content and the framework of the documentation site publicly accessible, we provide developers with the opportunity to not only improve the material itself but also understand and engage with the processes that govern how the documentation is built, approved, and maintained. This transparency fosters collaboration, learning, and innovation, enabling developers to contribute their expertise and learn from others in a shared, open environment. We also provide feedback to other open source products and plugins, giving back to the same community that supports us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pall Mall Process to tackle commercial hacking proliferation raises more concerns than solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An initiative spearheaded by France and the U.K. last year to tackle commercial spyware has experienced setbacks and significant gaps, according to participants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remotely Controlled Vehicles Over Starlink</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/starboat_feat.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern remote control (RC) radios are capable of incredible range, but they’re still only made for line-of-sight use. What if you want to control a vehicle that’s 100s of kilometers away, or even on the other side of the planet? Cellular is an option, but is obviously limited by available infrastructure — good luck getting a cell signal in the middle of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what if you could beam your commands down from space? That’s what [Thingify] was looking to test when they put together an experimental RC boat using a Starlink Mini for communications. Physically, there was no question it would work on the boat. After all, it was small, light, and power-efficient enough. But would the network connection be up to the task of controlling the vehicle in real-time?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During early ground testing, the Mini version of the Starlink receiver worked very well. Despite being roughly 1/4 the size of its predecessor, the smaller unit met or exceeded its performance during benchmarks on bandwidth, latency, and signal strength. As expected, it also drew far less power: the Mini’s power consumption peaked at around 33 watts, compared to the monstrous 180 W for the larger receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the water, there was even more good news. The bandwidth was more than enough to run a high-resolution video feedback to the command center. Most of the time the boat was moving autonomously between waypoints, but when [Thingify] switched over to manual control, the latency was low enough that maneuvering wasn’t a problem. We wouldn’t recommend manually piloting a high-speed aircraft over Starlink, but for a boat that’s cruising along at 4 km/h, the lag didn’t even come into play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside? Starlink is a fairly expensive proposition; you’d need to have a pretty specific mission in mind to justify the cost. The Mini receiver currently costs $599 USD (though it occasionally goes on sale), and you’ll need at least a $50 per month plan to go with it. While this puts it out of the price range for recreational RC, [Thingify] notes that it’s not a bad deal if you’re looking to explore uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running AI Locally Without Spending All Day on Setup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/LargeLanguageModel.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many AI models out there that you can play with from companies like OpenAI, Google, and a host of others. But when you use them, you get the experience they want, and you run it on their computer. There are a variety of reasons you might not like this. You may not want your data or ideas sent through someone else’s computer. Maybe you want to tune and tweak in ways they aren’t going to let you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satechi rounds off its CES 2025 announcements with this sleek mechanical keyboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/satechi-rounds-off-its-ces-2025-announcements-with-this-sleek-mechanical-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/satechi-rounds-off-its-ces-2025-announcements-with-this-sleek-mechanical-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great-looking keyboard for work and play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Satechi has been giving us a sprinkle of exciting CES 2025 announcements over the past few days, including a must-have accessory for Mac Mini M4 fans and a the perfect charging companions for tech lovers on the go. Now, the company is rounding off its CES spree with this fancy full-sized keyboard that definitely looks the part.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serializing an enum in a Spring Boot web application</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/serializing-an-enum-in-a-spring-boot-web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/serializing-an-enum-in-a-spring-boot-web-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Enum is a good structure to define a set of limited and well defined values inside the domain of our application. They could help to prevent impossible states in our codebase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-scenario&#34;&gt;The scenario&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s use a note taking web application as an example to show the possible ways to serialize and deserialize an eum value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are going to implement it using Spring Boot 3.3.x and MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We define a &lt;code&gt;Type&lt;/code&gt; enum class to represent the permitted types of todos inside the application: events and activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Dual Compilation (SSR &#43; CSR) in ViteJS with vite-plugin-builder</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/setting-up-dual-compilation-ssr-csr-in-vitejs-with-vite-plugin-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/setting-up-dual-compilation-ssr-csr-in-vitejs-with-vite-plugin-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;using&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt; to Set Up an SSR and CSR Project in Vite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I will show you how to create a project from scratch with &lt;strong&gt;Vite&lt;/strong&gt;, configure it to build both &lt;strong&gt;Server-Side Rendering (SSR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Client-Side Rendering (CSR)&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; plugin, which simplifies the whole process with a single command.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a plugin for &lt;strong&gt;Vite&lt;/strong&gt; that simplifies the setup and compilation of applications requiring both &lt;strong&gt;SSR&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CSR&lt;/strong&gt; in a single project (dual build). With it, you can easily manage both server and client entry points, which is ideal for modern applications that need to process content both on the server and on the client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech In Plain Sight: Security Envelopes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/letterlocking-mary-queen-of-scots-last-letter-a-spiral-lock-england-1587-uh0135-dzpe1mcgxxo-mkv-shot0002_featured.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You probably get a few of these things each week in the mail. And some of them actually do a good job of obscuring the contents inside, even if you hold the envelope up to the light. But have you ever taken the time to appreciate the beauty of security envelope patterns? Yeah, I didn’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The really interesting thing is just how many different patterns are out there when a dozen or so would probably cover it. But there are so, so many patterns in the world. In my experience, many utilities and higher-end companies create their own security patterns for mailing out statements and the like, so that right there adds up to some unknown abundance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nintendo Switch 2 could be launching in April, according to an accessory maker</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-nintendo-switch-2-could-be-launching-in-april-according-to-an-accessory-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-nintendo-switch-2-could-be-launching-in-april-according-to-an-accessory-maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nintendo Switch 2 will reportedly arrive in April 2025, according to an accessory manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CES 2025 is buzzing with the latest hardware from NVIDIA, AMD, Lenovo, and plenty of other tech giants — all of which were expected, but unexpectedly, it&amp;rsquo;s also buzzing with news about the new Nintendo Switch that&amp;rsquo;s slated to arrive this year. The latest being a report from Numerama (thanks, VGC) where accessory maker Genki has potentially spilled the beans that Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s next generation of hardware will arrive sometime in April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from First Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Earlier this month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the proceedings of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, which has been tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Anatomy of Cyber Enabled Crimes and their Governance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Digital systems and Information Communication Technology (ICT) play an increasingly central role in our lives. Technological advancement has created new opportunities for cybercriminals to exploit vulnerabilities in digital systems and networks. The resulting cybercrimes can affect everyone, from government and multinational corporations to individuals. As technology continues to make deeper inroads into our lives, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Engineering: Hack Week 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Canonical, the work of our teams is strongly embedded in the open source principles and philosophy. We believe open source software will become the most prevalent method of software development and delivery in the future. Being open source is more than making the source of your software available, it’s also about contributing to other open source projects and helping to build communities. With this in mind, the web engineering team recently had the privilege of dedicating a week solely to contribute to external open source projects. We do this every year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xbox Game Pass can reportedly cut away as much as 80% of a games premium sales on Xbox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/xbox-game-pass-can-reportedly-cut-away-as-much-as-80-of-a-games-premium-sales-on-xbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/xbox-game-pass-can-reportedly-cut-away-as-much-as-80-of-a-games-premium-sales-on-xbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Games business journalist Chris Dring offers insight into how Xbox Game Pass impacts game sales on Xbox.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Xbox unveiled its new generation of subscription services with Xbox Game Pass in 2017, the appeal for players was immediately apparent. Pay a monthly fee and get an ever-growing library of games right at your fingertips. Even brand-new releases from Xbox&amp;rsquo;s first-party studios, at no extra cost. Like Netflix, but for games, and with limited-time promotions that made the cost of a Game Pass subscription as low as $1, Game Pass colloquially earned the title, &amp;rsquo;the best deal in gaming.&#39;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
