<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hack on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/hack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hack on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/hack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Black Swan’ Event That Could Upend Life in 2025: The World’s Largest Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 futurists, foreign policy analysts and other prognosticators provide Politico readers some explosive potential scenarios for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gary Marcus, author of the book “Taming Silicon Valley”, one of The New Yorker’s recommended books in 2024, warns 2025 could easily see the largest cyberattack in history, taking down, at least for a little while, some sizeable piece of the world’s infrastructure, whether for deliberate ransom or to manipulate people to make money off a short on global markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Influence Ops | Twisting Tales of Volt Typhoon at Home and Abroad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s CVERC attempts to attribute Volt Typhoon activities to the U.S., but the fact-free claims reveal much about the PRC&amp;rsquo;s real agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The latest CVERC report reflects China’s ongoing efforts to undermine support for U.S. surveillance activities by attempting to fuel debate over Section 702.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The CVERC report also draws Microsoft into its crosshairs as part of an ongoing push to remove foreign technology from PRC government systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The report highlights previous intelligence from France and Germany regarding U.S spying in an attempt to deflect attention away from recent incidents of Chinese espionage in Europe, likely as a means to shape narratives amid ongoing political debates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China’s Computer Virus Emergency Response Center has released part three of a running series claiming that the U.S. government is actually behind Volt Typhoon activity, rather than China. The latest CVERC report, whose front page includes an oddly edited photo with the text “Lie to Me,” provides no new evidence of these claims and rehashes old leaked U.S. intelligence documents. However, this CVERC report is not useless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGERBEE Malware Detection: New Backdoor Variant Targets Internet Service Providers and State Bodies in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Eagerbee-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the re-emergence of a more advanced NonEuclid RAT variant in the cyber threat arena, a novel malware iteration known as the Eagerbee backdoor poses an increasing threat to organizations in the Middle East, primarily targeting Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and state agencies. The enhanced EAGERBEE backdoor variant can deploy payloads, scan file systems, and execute command shells, displaying significant evolution of its offensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Education software firm’s hack exposes personal data for students, teachers nationwide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/education-software-firms-hack-exposes-personal-data-for-students-teachers-nationwide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/education-software-firms-hack-exposes-personal-data-for-students-teachers-nationwide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An education software company which stores data belonging to more than 60 million K-12 students and teachers on Tuesday said it had been hacked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens&#34;&gt;Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23037/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hackers are trying to exploit CVE-2024-52875, a critical CRLF injection vulnerability that leads to 1-click remote code execution (RCE) attacks in GFI KerioControl firewall product. KerioControl is a &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (2 hours, 48 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different hacking techniques to be aware of. At the time of publication, the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework identified some 236 hacking techniques across 14 different categories. Luckily, you don’t need to understand all these tactics to stay safe. Many are close variations of the same basic approach. The best cybersecurity tools […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks appeared first on Heimdal Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti warns hackers are exploiting new vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The company released an advisory and a corresponding blog about two bugs — CVE-2025-0282 and CVE-2025-0283 — and warned that some customers have already seen CVE-2025-0282 exploited in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pall Mall Process to tackle commercial hacking proliferation raises more concerns than solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An initiative spearheaded by France and the U.K. last year to tackle commercial spyware has experienced setbacks and significant gaps, according to participants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running AI Locally Without Spending All Day on Setup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/LargeLanguageModel.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many AI models out there that you can play with from companies like OpenAI, Google, and a host of others. But when you use them, you get the experience they want, and you run it on their computer. There are a variety of reasons you might not like this. You may not want your data or ideas sent through someone else’s computer. Maybe you want to tune and tweak in ways they aren’t going to let you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian internet provider confirms its network was ‘destroyed’ following attack claimed by Ukrainian hackers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a statement on the Russian social media platform VKontakte, the St. Petersburg-based company said the “planned” attack “destroyed” its infrastructure overnight. Nodex added that it was working to restore systems from backups but could not provide a timeline for when operations would fully resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Engineering: Hack Week 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Canonical, the work of our teams is strongly embedded in the open source principles and philosophy. We believe open source software will become the most prevalent method of software development and delivery in the future. Being open source is more than making the source of your software available, it’s also about contributing to other open source projects and helping to build communities. With this in mind, the web engineering team recently had the privilege of dedicating a week solely to contribute to external open source projects. We do this every year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
