<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>It-Resources on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/it-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in It-Resources on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/it-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Topics Every Cybersecurity Awareness Training Program Should Cover</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-topics-every-cybersecurity-awareness-training-program-should-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-topics-every-cybersecurity-awareness-training-program-should-cover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Employee training starts with cybersecurity awareness programs, which teach employees how to recognize cyberattacks and prevent or mitigate cyber incidents. Boost Cybersecurity — The 10 logical topics are easy to implement. Enhance Knowledge — This 11-page PDF guide will minimize human errors. Expertly-Curated — Written by Kara Sherrer through 22 hours of research, writing, editing, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checklist: Network and Systems Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/checklist-network-and-systems-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/checklist-network-and-systems-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This checklist can assist information security professionals in identifying and managing cyberthreats. Customizable Document — Ready to use now or suitable for editing. Enhance Your Cybersecurity — This six-page checklist will boost your organization’s cyber defenses. Expert Guidance — Written by Erik Eckel through 12 hours of research, writing, and editing. This resource is available &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity for Small Businesses: Challenges and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-for-small-businesses-challenges-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-for-small-businesses-challenges-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strengthen cybersecurity and ensure success for your small business with this comprehensive guide. Constantly Updated — The download contains the latest and most accurate details. Enhance Your Knowledge — This 11-page PDF explains the threat landscape, the challenges, and best practices. Expert Guidance — Written by Franklin Okeke through 22 hours of research, writing, editing, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Handling Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-handling-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-handling-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every organization collects and processes data as part of normal operations, and all data has the potential to contain sensitive information. This may include personally identifiable information, such as names, addresses, social security numbers, and banking account numbers, which could be used by a malicious third-party to identify consumers or employees.  The privacy of this &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Data Disposal Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/electronic-data-disposal-policy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/electronic-data-disposal-policy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speed up the disposal of information and the destruction of electronic media with this in-depth IT policy. Customizable Document — Ready to use as-is or customize as you see fit. Boost Your Security — This nine-page document will ensure confidential information is properly removed before disposal or reassignment. Expert Guidance — Written by Scott Matteson &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Data Disposal Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/electronic-data-disposal-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/electronic-data-disposal-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speed up the disposal of information and the destruction of electronic media with this in-depth IT policy. Customizable Document — Ready to use as-is or customize as you see fit. Boost Your Security — This nine-page document will ensure confidential information is properly removed before disposal or reassignment. Expert Guidance — Written by Scott Matteson &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Email/Instant Message/Voicemail Retention Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/email-instant-message-voicemail-retention-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/email-instant-message-voicemail-retention-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maintaining electronic communications in business involves walking a fine line. Employees want relevant information to be kept available for future reference so that they can do their jobs, but keeping these items long-term can pose security and resource risks. The purpose of this customizable policy, written by Scott Matteson for TechRepublic Premium, is to establish &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Kit: Big Data Modeler</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-big-data-modeler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-big-data-modeler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Successful big data modelers are the architects of data-driven decisions within an organization. They possess a unique combination of sharp analytical thinking and a comprehensive understanding of data structures, statistical modeling techniques, and the intricate business processes specific to your industry. This blend of abilities allows them to transform raw, complex data sets into well-organized, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Can Data Centers Stay Cool to Keep AI Racks from Overheating?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-can-data-centers-stay-cool-to-keep-ai-racks-from-overheating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-can-data-centers-stay-cool-to-keep-ai-racks-from-overheating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keep your data centers cool and your business on track with this detailed guide. Constantly Updated — The guide contains the latest and most accurate details. Improve Your Knowledge — This nine-page PDF outlines the growth of data centers, cooling technologies, drawbacks, hybrid cooling, and more. Expert Guidance — Created by Drew Robb through 18 &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Leader’s Guide to Data Loss Prevention</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-data-loss-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-leaders-guide-to-data-loss-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide looks at different data loss prevention strategies and their importance in an organization’s cloud security posture management. Constantly Updated — The guide contains the latest and most accurate details. Boost Data Security — This 10-page PDF will enhance your organization’s security. Expert Guidance — Written by Franklin Okeke through 20 hours of research, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT Staff Systems and Data Access Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-staff-systems-and-data-access-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/it-staff-systems-and-data-access-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT professionals, such as system and network administrators, help desk staff, management personnel, and sometimes external vendor representatives, are routinely provided full access to company servers, network devices and data so that they can effectively perform their jobs. This customizable policy, written by Scott Matteson for TechRepublic Premium, provides guidelines for a company and its &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Business Intelligence and Analytics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-business-intelligence-and-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-business-intelligence-and-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Business intelligence and data analytics give tech decision makers a clearer idea of how well their companies are running and whether they’re meeting goals. Because BI incorporates data from across the enterprise — revenue operations, sales, supply chain, and logistics — its insight is beneficial in areas such as customer profiling, customer support, and market &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter whether your organization is a huge multinational business enterprise or a one-person operation. At some point, your computer networks and systems will be attacked by someone with criminal intent. Cybersecurity attacks, in all their various forms, are inevitable and relentless. This quick glossary, written by Mark W. Kaelin for TechRepublic Premium, explains &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build an Effective Security Operations Center</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-an-effective-security-operations-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-an-effective-security-operations-center/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a coordinated security approach is one way to leave no loopholes. By this, we are referring to a cybersecurity architecture that comprises a team and security components working together in sync to provide more effective security operations as opposed to the usual fragmented approach, which often leaves businesses without a coordinated response to threats. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Big Data</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-big-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New things are rapidly emerging in the big data landscape. To keep a competitive edge, you should learn the basic vocabulary. This list of 30 essential terms and concepts from TechRepublic Premium will help you stay on top of the current chatter about big data. Featured definition from the download: ETL (extract, transform, and load) &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
