<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Microsoft Takes Legal Action Against AI “Hacking as a Service” Scheme&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-takes-legal-action-against-ai-hacking-as-a-service-scheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-takes-legal-action-against-ai-hacking-as-a-service-scheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure this will matter in the end, but it’s a positive move:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is accusing three individuals of running a “hacking-as-a-service” scheme that was designed to allow the creation of harmful and illicit content using the company’s platform for AI-generated content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The foreign-based defendants developed tools specifically designed to bypass safety guardrails Microsoft has erected to prevent the creation of harmful content through its generative AI services, said Steven Masada, the assistant general counsel for Microsoft’s Digital Crimes Unit. They then compromised the legitimate accounts of paying customers. They combined those two things to create a fee-based platform people could use&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The First Password on the Internet&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-first-password-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-first-password-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was created in 1973 by Peter Kirstein:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So from the beginning I put password protection on my gateway. This had been done in such a way that even if UK users telephoned directly into the communications computer provided by Darpa in UCL, they would require a password.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In fact this was the first password on Arpanet. It proved invaluable in satisfying authorities on both sides of the Atlantic for the 15 years I ran the service ­ during which no security breach occurred over my link. I also put in place a system of governance that any UK users had to be approved by a committee which I chaired but which also had UK government and British Post Office representation&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Upcoming Speaking Engagements&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upcoming-speaking-engagements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upcoming-speaking-engagements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a current list of where and when I am scheduled to speak:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’m speaking on “AI: Trust &amp;amp; Power” at Capricon 45 in Chicago, Illinois, USA, at 11:30 AM on February 7, 2025. I’m also signing books there on Saturday, February 8, starting at 1:45 PM.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’m speaking at Boskone 62 in Boston, Massachusetts, USA, which runs from February 14-16, 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’m speaking at the Rossfest Symposium in Cambridge, UK, on March 25, 2025.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The list is maintained on this page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Apps That Are Spying on Your Location&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;404 Media is reporting on all the apps that are spying on your location, based on a hack of the location data company Gravy Analytics:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thousands of apps, included in hacked files from location data company Gravy Analytics, include everything from games like Candy Crush to dating apps like Tinder, to pregnancy tracking and religious prayer apps across both Android and iOS. Because much of the collection is occurring through the advertising ecosystem­—not code developed by the app creators themselves—­this data collection is likely happening both without users’ and even app developers’ knowledge&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Friday Squid Blogging: Cotton-and-Squid-Bone Sponge&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/friday-squid-blogging-cotton-and-squid-bone-sponge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/friday-squid-blogging-cotton-and-squid-bone-sponge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;News:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sponge made of cotton and squid bone that has absorbed about 99.9% of microplastics in water samples in China could provide an elusive answer to ubiquitous microplastic pollution in water across the globe, a new report suggests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[…]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study tested the material in an irrigation ditch, a lake, seawater and a pond, where it removed up to 99.9% of plastic. It addressed 95%-98% of plastic after five cycles, which the authors say is remarkable reusability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Zero-Day Vulnerability in Ivanti VPN&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zero-day-vulnerability-in-ivanti-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zero-day-vulnerability-in-ivanti-vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s being actively exploited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s being actively exploited.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;US Treasury Department Sanctions Chinese Company Over Cyberattacks&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-treasury-department-sanctions-chinese-company-over-cyberattacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-treasury-department-sanctions-chinese-company-over-cyberattacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sanctions target Beijing Integrity Technology Group, which U.S. officials say employed workers responsible for the Flax Typhoon attacks which compromised devices including routers and internet-enabled cameras to infiltrate government and industrial targets in the United States, Taiwan, Europe and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sanctions target Beijing Integrity Technology Group, which U.S. officials say employed workers responsible for the Flax Typhoon attacks which compromised devices including routers and internet-enabled cameras to infiltrate government and industrial targets in the United States, Taiwan, Europe and elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
