<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial-Intelligence on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial-Intelligence on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Security Management for the Hyperconnected World</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-04-at-11.17.57-AM.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Check Point CPO Nataly Kremer announcing new AI capabilities at CPX 2025&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s security approach is siloed. Each deployed security tool is designed to provide a specific type of protection across different areas like the network, endpoints, email, and cloud environments. This hybrid methodology, often requiring dozens of systems, leads to several security and operational challenges for security operations center (SOC) and network operations center (NOC) teams. Adopting a hybrid environment is unavoidable, and Gartner[1] anticipates that “By 2025, over 50% of network firewall deployments will involve more than two deployment factors from the same vendor — up from less than 10% in 2023.” [1]  While the benefits of this new ecosystem are […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia Divided on DeepSeek Response: Industry Groups Call for Action, Minister Urges Caution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australia-divided-on-deepseek-response-industry-groups-call-for-action-minister-urges-caution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/australia-divided-on-deepseek-response-industry-groups-call-for-action-minister-urges-caution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australian authorities disagree over the response the country should take to the runaway success of the Chinese AI app DeepSeek.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Software Collaborates with AppDirect to Offer Streamlined Cyber Security Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shifting-Paradigms-Cloud-Security-in-the-Post-Pandemic-Era-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security in the Post-Pandemic Era&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point Software and AppDirect, a B2B subscription commerce platform, have unveiled a strategic collaboration, allowing businesses to effortlessly obtain Check Point’s AI-powered cyber security solutions through the AppDirect marketplace. This partnership offers a unified procurement experience, ensuring more customers have access to the highest level of security they deserve. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, worldwide cyber attacks on organizations surged considerably in 2024. On average, organizations faced 1,673 attacks each week, marking a substantial 44% increase from the year before. As cyber attacks continue to escalate annually, it is crucial for every business to utilize advanced […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare is the Latest Tech Company to Adopt Content Credentials for Image Authenticity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-is-the-latest-tech-company-to-adopt-content-credentials-for-image-authenticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloudflare-is-the-latest-tech-company-to-adopt-content-credentials-for-image-authenticity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare Images customers can now choose to preserve Content Credentials. Adobe and Cloudflare worked closely to enable it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPR Finds Threat Actors Already Leveraging DeepSeek and Qwen to Develop Malicious Content</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cpr-finds-threat-actors-already-leveraging-deepseek-and-qwen-to-develop-malicious-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cpr-finds-threat-actors-already-leveraging-deepseek-and-qwen-to-develop-malicious-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/blog-CPR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Check Point Research&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soon after the launch of AI models DeepSeek and Qwen, Check Point Research witnessed cyber criminals quickly shifting from ChatGPT to these new platforms to develop malicious content. Threat actors are sharing how to manipulate the models and show uncensored content, ultimately allowing hackers and criminals to use AI to create malicious content. Called jailbreaking, there are many methods to remove censors from AI models. However, we now see in-depth guides to jailbreaking methods, bypassing anti-fraud protections, and developing malware itself. This blog delves into how threat actors leverage these advanced models to develop harmful content, manipulate AI functionalities through […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gartner: Samsung Was the Top Semiconductor Vendor Globally in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gartner-samsung-was-the-top-semiconductor-vendor-globally-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung Electronics returned to number one partially on the strength of its memory device sales. Intel and NVIDIA followed in the rankings in spots two and three, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Will Remove the Free VPN That Comes With Windows Defender Soon</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-will-remove-the-free-vpn-that-comes-with-windows-defender-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-will-remove-the-free-vpn-that-comes-with-windows-defender-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The feature will no longer be available starting Feb. 28. Microsoft wants to focus on “new areas that will better align to customer needs.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Organization from GenAI Risks with Harmony SASE</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-organization-from-genai-risks-with-harmony-sase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/eliza1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love it or hate it, large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and other AI tools are reshaping the modern workplace. As AI becomes a critical part of daily work, establishing guardrails and deploying monitoring tools for these tools is critical. That’s where Check Point’s Harmony SASE comes in. We’ve already talked about Browser Security and the clipboard control feature to help define what types of information can’t be shared with LLMs. For monitoring these services, our GenAI Security service shows exactly which AI tools your team is using, who is using them, what kind of information they’re sharing with the […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Announces ‘World-First’ Cyber Code of Practice for Companies Developing AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-announces-world-first-cyber-code-of-practice-for-companies-developing-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-announces-world-first-cyber-code-of-practice-for-companies-developing-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cyber Code of Practice applies to developers, system operators, and organisations that create, deploy, or manage AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Personal Note-Taking Assistant Is Just $39.99 for Life</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record, transcribe, summarize, and keep all your notes organized with this powerful app for Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Cheat Sheet: A Complete Guide for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-cheat-sheet-a-complete-guide-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get up and running with ChatGPT with this comprehensive cheat sheet. Learn everything from how to sign up for free to enterprise use cases, and start using ChatGPT quickly and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Locked Down Public Database Access That Exposed Chat History</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-locked-down-public-database-access-that-exposed-chat-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-locked-down-public-database-access-that-exposed-chat-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research Firm Wiz Research began investigating DeepSeek soon after its generative AI took the tech world by storm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Reveals New Surface Laptop 7 and Surface Pro 11 With Intel Chips</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-reveals-new-surface-laptop-7-and-surface-pro-11-with-intel-chips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-reveals-new-surface-laptop-7-and-surface-pro-11-with-intel-chips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Surface Laptop 7 and Surface Pro 11 PCs for business include Copilot+ AI features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Autonomous Cyber Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Dan-v.1-e1737134156825.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of cyber security is no longer just about reacting to threats; it is about staying perpetually ahead in a world defined by complexity and speed. Autonomous cyber security represents a bold, transformative leap into the future—where intelligent, AI-driven systems operate at the edge of innovation, detecting, preventing, and responding to threats with unparalleled precision. This journey is more than technological advancement—it is a paradigm shift. By creating systems that think, reason, and act autonomously, organizations are poised to outpace adversaries and redefine what it means to be secure in an increasingly digitized world. The further along this journey […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WAF Security Test Results – How Does Your Vendor Rate?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/waf-security-test-results-how-does-your-vendor-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/waf-security-test-results-how-does-your-vendor-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/23167_blog_banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With cyber threats on the rise, organizations are increasingly concerned about their security posture. One area of prime concern is web applications and APIs that power key business processes. To protect mission-critical applications, efficient web application firewalls (WAFs) are required to block malicious traffic. A well-configured WAF acts as the first line of defense against external threats maintaining trust, achieving compliance, and ensuring uninterrupted operations. Periodic testing of security solutions ensures they are behaving as expected and are resilient enough to withstand complex and ever-evolving cyber threats. Often, resource-constrained security teams do not have the time to proactively test their […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What DeepSeek’s R1 Model Means For AI Innovation and Enterprise Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-deepseeks-r1-model-means-for-ai-innovation-and-enterprise-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-deepseeks-r1-model-means-for-ai-innovation-and-enterprise-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shutterstock_2403416063-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeepSeek’s R1 model launch marks a significant milestone in AI accessibility, combining advanced reasoning capabilities with free, unlimited access. The platform’s explosive growth is evident—its mobile app topped the iOS App Store charts within 48 hours of release, indicating unprecedented user adoption rates. While DeepSeek’s open-source model represents a breakthrough in cost-effective AI deployment, the DeepSeek consumer-facing app introduces substantial privacy and security challenges for enterprises. Most critically, the platform’s data collection practices extend far beyond typical usage data: according to DeepSeek’s privacy policy, all user interactions—including prompts, uploaded files, chat histories, voice inputs, images, and even keystroke patterns—are transmitted […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Eye Opener] Is DeepSeek The Next Threat in Social Engineering?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eye-opener-is-deepseek-the-next-threat-in-social-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eye-opener-is-deepseek-the-next-threat-in-social-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.knowbe4.com/hubfs/deepseek.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Eye Opener] Is DeepSeek The Next Threat in Social Engineering?&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is advancing at lightning speed, but it’s also raising some big questions, especially when it comes to security. The latest AI making headlines is DeepSeek, a Chinese startup that’s shaking up the game with its cost-efficient, high-performing models. But it’s also raising red flags for cybersecurity pros.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeepSeek overnight became a top contender, mostly driven by curiosity. It’s being praised for its efficiency, with models like DeepSeek-V3 and DeepSeek-R1 performing at a fraction of the cost and energy usage compared to competitors, being trained on Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s lower-power H800 chips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways AI Can Help Organizations Tackle Cyberattacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-ways-ai-can-help-organizations-tackle-cyberattacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Legacy security measures, while offering a baseline level of protection, heavily rely on predefined signatures and a narrow definition of the “abnormal.” They often follow a reactive approach, can be siloed, limiting information sharing, and lack the scalability to handle the terabytes of data generated by today’s complex IT systems. This is where artificial intelligence &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Best UCaaS Providers of 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-best-ucaas-providers-of-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-best-ucaas-providers-of-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the best UCaaS providers for new or small businesses, remote teams, traditional offices, global enterprises, and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Protect and Secure Your Data in 10 Ways</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use this comprehensive list of strategies to help you safeguard your company&amp;rsquo;s data from threats and data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing HT-ML Guard to Automatically Analyze and Secure HTML Files</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-ht-ml-guard-to-automatically-analyze-and-secure-html-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/blog-template-2000x700_5-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Highlights: HTML files are being used in phishing attacks, mimicking trusted websites HT-ML Guard is designed to analyze HTML files and accurately determine whether they are malicious, enhancing cyber security defenses. Check Point Harmony Email and Collaboration customers remain protected against this type of attack. HTML files are commonly used in the initial stages of cyber attacks. Cyber criminals craft these files to look legitimate, tempting unsuspecting users into a false sense of security. The main goal of these malicious HTML files is to deceive users into either disclosing sensitive information, such as login credentials and personal details, or downloading […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nextiva Review (2025): Is it Right for My Business?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nextiva-review-2025-is-it-right-for-my-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nextiva-review-2025-is-it-right-for-my-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wondering if Nextiva is the best choice for your team? Check out the full review to learn about its standout features, pros, cons and closest competitors in the business communications space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nextiva vs RingCentral (2025): Which One Is Best for Your Business?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nextiva-vs-ringcentral-2025-which-one-is-best-for-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nextiva-vs-ringcentral-2025-which-one-is-best-for-your-business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover which VoIP phone system is best for your business needs in this Nextiva vs. RingCentral comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 6 Best Call Center Software of 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-6-best-call-center-software-of-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-6-best-call-center-software-of-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Struggling to choose the best call center software for your business? Compare top options to find the solution that fits both your team and budget.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating our 2024 open-source contributions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-our-2024-open-source-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-our-2024-open-source-contributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Trail of Bits is known for developing security tools like Slither, Medusa, and Fickling, our engineering efforts extend far beyond our own projects. Throughout 2024, our team has been deeply engaged with the broader security ecosystem, tackling challenges in open-source tools and infrastructure that security engineers rely on every day. This year, our engineers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Celebrating our 2024 open-source contributions appeared first on Security Boulevard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operator: OpenAI’s Next Step Toward the ‘Agentic’ Future</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operator-openais-next-step-toward-the-agentic-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operator-openais-next-step-toward-the-agentic-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Operator and the Computer-Using Agent will be available through the OpenAI API at an undisclosed time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GhostGPT: Uncensored Chatbot Used by Cyber Criminals for Malware Creation, Scams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ghostgpt-uncensored-chatbot-used-by-cyber-criminals-for-malware-creation-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ghostgpt-uncensored-chatbot-used-by-cyber-criminals-for-malware-creation-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers from Abnormal Security discovered an advert for the chatbot on a cybercrime forum and tested its capabilities by asking it to create a DocuSign phishing email.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Predictions for 2025: A Cyber Security Expert’s Perspective</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-predictions-for-2025-a-cyber-security-experts-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-predictions-for-2025-a-cyber-security-experts-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Dan-v.1-e1737134156825.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we approach 2025, the rapid evolution of artificial intelligence (AI) is set to dramatically reshape the cyber security landscape. As an AI and cyber security expert, I foresee several key developments that will significantly impact our digital world. The surge in AI usage will have far-reaching implications for areas such as energy consumption, software development, and ethical and legal frameworks. Of course, AI technologies will also be weaponized by cyber criminals and nation state actors, creating new and formidable threats to cyber security. The AI Explosion The adoption of AI technologies is accelerating at an unprecedented rate. ChatGPT, for […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK Pledges Public Sector AI Overhaul, Legacy Tech Causes £45 Billion in Missed Annual Savings</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-pledges-public-sector-ai-overhaul-legacy-tech-causes-45-billion-in-missed-annual-savings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-pledges-public-sector-ai-overhaul-legacy-tech-causes-45-billion-in-missed-annual-savings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Initiatives include AI tools for policymakers and a new team to identify where tech can boost the efficiency of public services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Grok AI? Is It Worth the Hype?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-grok-ai-is-it-worth-the-hype/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-grok-ai-is-it-worth-the-hype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore Grok AI, Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s chatbot. Is it living up to the hype? Dive into its features, potential, and what sets it apart from competitors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Steps to Address Human Impact of AI Adoption in the Workplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-steps-to-address-human-impact-of-ai-adoption-in-the-workplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this TechRepublic exclusive, Gartner analyst Autumn Stanish provides proactive and compassionate steps IT leaders can take to support employees as they navigate transitions related to AI integration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT Can Now Schedule Tasks in Advance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-can-now-schedule-tasks-in-advance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chatgpt-can-now-schedule-tasks-in-advance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tasks feature, now in beta, can provide daily weather reports or send reminders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Health Care Cybersecurity: Bridging HIPAA Gaps with Innovation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-health-care-cybersecurity-bridging-hipaa-gaps-with-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-health-care-cybersecurity-bridging-hipaa-gaps-with-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The proposed HIPAA Security Rule introduces mandatory measures to prevent malicious cyberattacks in health care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Workspace Plans See Price Hike as Gemini AI Expands to All Tiers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-workspace-plans-see-price-hike-as-gemini-ai-expands-to-all-tiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-workspace-plans-see-price-hike-as-gemini-ai-expands-to-all-tiers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of a $20 or $30 standalone plan, Google added a few dollars to its business tiers and applied the Gemini generative AI to all plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence: Benefits and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/artificial-intelligence-benefits-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/artificial-intelligence-benefits-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From business to healthcare, cybersecurity, and the environment, artificial intelligence promises inclusive economic prosperity, innovation, and scientific support. AI is the foundation for the next generation of advancements that are expected to touch people’s lives across our world. However, AI also poses unique challenges and risks that individuals and companies must understand and mitigate by &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Half of Businesses Weaken Sustainability Goals Due to Generative AI Demands, Capgemini Report Reveals</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has stated that its goal to reach net-zero emissions across all its operations and value chain by 2030 is now “extremely ambitious” thanks to its data centre usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK’s New AI Action Plan Aims to Position Country as a Global Powerhouse</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uks-new-ai-action-plan-aims-to-position-country-as-a-global-powerhouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recommendations in the 50-point plan include increasing public compute capacity twentyfold, creating a training data library, and building AI hubs in deindustrialised areas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Chip Export Rule Proposes Limits to Thwart Chinese GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-chip-export-rule-proposes-limits-to-thwart-chinese-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Biden administration states the rule will prevent U.S. chips from passing to China through countries loosely allied or not politically allied with the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: AMD Introduces Radeon RX 9070 Series GPUs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-amd-introduces-radeon-rx-9070-series-gpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next-generation GPUs will be available from a variety of manufacturers in the first quarter of 2025. Plus, AMD shows upcoming AI chips for mobile performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2025: NVIDIA Unveils GeForce RTX 50-Series Chips, AI Research Supercomputers, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ces-2025-nvidia-unveils-geforce-rtx-50-series-chips-ai-research-supercomputers-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jensen Huang, NVIDIA’s CEO, unveiled the company’s first flagship desktop GPU series in over two years during his keynote speech.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dell Introduces New Product Line Names</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Named brands like XPS and Inspiron will now fall under performance categories. Plus, Dell expanded its partnership with AMD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Wants You to Code in a Browser With Project IDX</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-wants-you-to-code-in-a-browser-with-project-idx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-wants-you-to-code-in-a-browser-with-project-idx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developers can sign up for a waitlist for the Google Cloud-supported project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hiring Kit: Machine Learning Engineer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-machine-learning-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hiring-kit-machine-learning-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Successful businesses are relying on digitization and automation to make their operations more efficient and productive. The underlying technologies that make this automation possible include artificial intelligence and machine learning. Developing, programming, and implementing these sophisticated automation tools requires the considerable skills of a machine learning engineer. This customizable hiring kit, created by Mark W. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HR Leaders in APAC Are Adopting AI for Efficiency Gains</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and machine learning are seen as allies in the battle to streamline HR workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IBM’s Acquisition of HashiCorp Investigated by UK Competition Authority</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ibms-acquisition-of-hashicorp-investigated-by-uk-competition-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ibms-acquisition-of-hashicorp-investigated-by-uk-competition-authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HashiCorp provides hybrid and multi-cloud lifecycle management products that could assist IBM’s customers with their AI ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Azure AI Adds GPT-4 and New Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-azure-ai-adds-gpt-4-and-new-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-azure-ai-adds-gpt-4-and-new-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is working on creating guidelines for red teams making sure generative AI is secure and responsible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to Invest $80 Billion in AI Data Centers in Fiscal 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than half of the investment has been earmarked for infrastructure in the U.S. Microsoft President Brad Smith frames AI investment as key to economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: Cloud Spending is Perplexing CFOs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud spending confusion is rising among CFOs. An IBM executive explains how FinOps, automation, and AI-powered solutions can improve cost visibility and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Payroll Compliance Penalties Driving Tech Adoption in Australia, Says Yellow Canary</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new law criminalising some underpayments to Australian employees this month is causing organisations to keep a close watch on their payroll technology, according to Yellow Canary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Shifts Attention to Superintelligence in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Superintelligence refers to AI with greater-than-human capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report: The Security and AI Landscape in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats are getting smarter, and businesses can’t afford to fall behind. This TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report, sponsored by Check Point Software, explores the biggest security challenges of 2025—from the explosion of AI adoption to the critical importance of Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA). With breaches on the rise and ransomware payouts hitting record highs, organizations &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechRepublic Premium Editorial Calendar: Policies, Hiring Kits, and Glossaries for Download</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/techrepublic-premium-editorial-calendar-policies-hiring-kits-and-glossaries-for-download/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TechRepublic Premium content helps you solve your toughest IT issues and jump-start your career or next project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Tech Trends at CES 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-tech-trends-at-ces-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI was everywhere at the consumer electronics show, promising everything from self-driving cars to more Copilot+ laptops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 6 Project Management Trends to Watch in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-6-project-management-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-6-project-management-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the top project management trends for 2025. Explore insights and strategies for increased productivity and better collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for Open Source Software Security in 2025?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-open-source-software-security-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-open-source-software-security-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hidden dependencies, social engineering attacks, and the complexity of foundation models can all contribute tothe insecure use of open-source software in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
