<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Loss-Prevention on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-loss-prevention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Loss-Prevention on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-loss-prevention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Indicators of Compromise (IOC) Examples To Look Out For</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-indicators-of-compromise-ioc-examples-to-look-out-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-indicators-of-compromise-ioc-examples-to-look-out-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As information security professionals, you play a crucial role in using the term “indicators of compromise” (IOC) to describe any malicious activity that may suggest a computer system has been compromised. Your expertise in identifying IoCs can help quickly determine when an attack has occurred and identify the perpetrators. Your insights can also help determine the extent and severity of an attack and aid in an incident’s forensic analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide is not just a theoretical exploration of the top 10 indicators of compromise. It’s a practical tool that can empower your security team to develop effective incident response plans and safeguard your valuable data and assets. By understanding and monitoring these warning signs, you can stay one step ahead of potential threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Causes of Data Loss Threatening Businesses in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-causes-of-data-loss-threatening-businesses-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-causes-of-data-loss-threatening-businesses-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data is not just a strategic asset. It’s the lifeblood of your organization. Losing access to any strategic asset can threaten an organization’s viability; without plants and equipment, manufacturers would find it difficult to succeed, and service providers can’t operate without brand recognition. Similarly, without data, your organization could be left in a state of complete and utter paralysis, unable to function or recover. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like the security of other strategic assets, data loss prevention is not a reactive measure but a critical function that organizations must proactively address. By taking the initiative and implementing effective data loss prevention strategies, you can assert control over your data’s security and ensure the continuity of your operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Strategies for Cutting the Costs of Insider Threats</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-strategies-for-cutting-the-costs-of-insider-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-strategies-for-cutting-the-costs-of-insider-threats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The costs associated with insider threats continued to rise in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is bad news for organizations that are already under financial pressure from the uncertainty of the economy. As interest rates continue to climb and customers become more conservative about how they spend, the last thing that any organization needs is to be putting out fires from security incidents coming from arsonists inside their own house.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And yet, a variety of factors, not the least of which are sizable layoffs hitting companies and the fluidity of access to data, make the possibility of an insider threat increasingly likely. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Breach Versus Data Leak: What’s The Difference?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-breach-versus-data-leak-whats-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-breach-versus-data-leak-whats-the-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some terminology in the cybersecurity world can be slightly confusing. One example is the difference between two similar terms: data leak and data breach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People sometimes use these terms interchangeably to describe situations where sensitive data is exposed. However, the difference between a data leak and a data breach is concrete in some ways. Knowing the difference between them helps organizations defend against either type of loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-difference-between-a-data-leak-and-data-breach&#34;&gt;What is the Difference Between a Data Leak and Data Breach?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A data breach refers to unauthorized access or acquisition by an external party, often resulting from a cyberattack or security breach. A data leak is the accidental release or exposure of sensitive information due to internal errors or negligence. While a data breach is intentional, a data leak is typically accidental and can arise from various sources, such as misconfigured databases or human error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Handling Internal Security Threats: A Balanced Approach</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/handling-internal-security-threats-a-balanced-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/handling-internal-security-threats-a-balanced-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While external cyberattacks often make the headlines, internal security risks (aka insider risks) present a significant danger that is sometimes underestimated. These risks can arise from disgruntled employees, negligent insiders, or malicious actors with privileged access. The repercussions of such breaches can be severe, resulting in data loss, financial harm, legal fines, and harm to reputation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Effectively managing internal security threats requires a careful and balanced approach. Implementing overly strict measures can hinder creativity and dampen current employee morale, yet having weak security protocols can leave organizations open to exploitation. This article delves into the various facets of internal threats, exploring the potential outcomes and examining the essential elements of a strong internal security plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from 7 Real Insider Threat Examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-learned-from-7-real-insider-threat-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-learned-from-7-real-insider-threat-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Organizations must navigate myriad security threats. While many cyber threats come from malicious actors outside the organization, insider threats can be even more devastating to a business. Insider threat prevention should be a top priority for security teams. But what are these cyber attacks, and what do they teach us about how to protect critical assets?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here, we examine several real-world examples of insider threats at major organizations and what those organizations did to remediate the threat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What To Know About Endpoint Monitoring in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-to-know-about-endpoint-monitoring-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-to-know-about-endpoint-monitoring-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s workforce is more distributed than ever. Globally, 16% of companies are fully remote, while 40% have a hybrid arrangement. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As workforces become increasingly distributed, security leaders face many challenges. They must monitor potential malicious activity across a wide array of devices scattered throughout the entire network. With the rise of endpoint monitoring tools, it has become easier to monitor devices. But challenges remain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll go over everything you need to know about endpoint monitoring to improve your organization’s security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where Insider Threats Hide Out in a Segmented Network</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-insider-threats-hide-out-in-a-segmented-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/where-insider-threats-hide-out-in-a-segmented-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to insider threats and cybersecurity in general, experts often discuss how to practice policies of containment, and use these to mitigate threats. One fundamental way to do this is through the process of network segmentation. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-network-segmentation&#34;&gt;What is network segmentation?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Network segmentation means that you essentially create smaller subnetworks linked to each other, so that you structure your network better, for a few key benefits. First, it’s easier to see network activity and monitor it within these smaller systems. Second, it can enhance performance across the network. Third, it promotes the use of a zero trust strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
