<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backdoors on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/backdoors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backdoors on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/backdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Ashton Kutcher and Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in March I was fortunate to spend several days visiting Brussels, where I had a chance to attend a panel on “chat control“: the new content scanning regime being considered by the EU Commission. Among various requirements, this proposed legislation would mandate that &lt;em&gt;client-side scanning&lt;/em&gt; technology be incorporated into encrypted text messaging applications like Signal, WhatsApp and Apple’s iMessage. The scanning tech would examine private messages for certain types of illicit content, including child sexual abuse media (known as CSAM), along with a broad category of textual conversations that constitute “grooming behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks on “Chat Control”</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remarks-on-chat-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remarks-on-chat-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On March 23 I was invited to participate in a panel discussion at the European Internet Services Providers Association (EuroISPA). The focus of this discussion was on recent legislative proposals, especially the EU Commission’s new “chat control” content scanning proposal, as well as the future of encryption and fundamental rights. These are the introductory remarks I prepared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for inviting me today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should start by making brief introduction. I am a professor of computer science and a researcher in the field of applied cryptography. On a day-to-day basis this means that I work on the design of encryption systems. Most of what I do involves building things: I design new encryption systems and try to make existing encryption technologies more useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
