<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Fast Pace Health: Zero Phishing Incidents Since Harmony Email &amp; Collaboration Implementation&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fast-pace-health-zero-phishing-incidents-since-harmony-email-collaboration-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fast-pace-health-zero-phishing-incidents-since-harmony-email-collaboration-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Blog_HealthcareCloudMigration_260x260.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Healthcare entities have a 51% probability of falling victim to phishing attacks. Successful incidents not only lead to control over systems, but can also expose patient health information, financial and insurance data. Healthcare providers are seeing an 81% uptick in threats, especially as cyber criminals weaponize increasingly advanced methods, and some organizations are struggling to keep pace. With over 265 clinic locations across the United States and a mission to deliver high-quality, accessible and compassionate care to under-served communities, Fast Pace Health recently found itself ill-equipped to fend off high volumes of relentless cyber threats. On account of overseeing large […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How devops use cases in healthcare?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-use-cases-in-healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-use-cases-in-healthcare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/DevOps-in-healthcare-1024x401.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving healthcare industry, the integration of &lt;strong&gt;DevOps&lt;/strong&gt;—a collaborative approach that unifies software development (Dev) and IT operations (Ops)—is transforming the delivery of medical services. By fostering a culture of collaboration and continuous improvement, DevOps addresses the unique challenges of healthcare, including stringent regulatory requirements, the need for rapid innovation, and the imperative for high-quality patient care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits of DevOps in Healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementing DevOps in healthcare offers several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
