<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber-Crime-News on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-crime-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyber-Crime-News on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-crime-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug in macOS, Gatekeeper’s security can be bypassed by malware.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The macOS operating system was recently patched for a security vulnerability that could be exploited by a threat actor to bypass “myriad foundational macOS security mechanisms” and run arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Wardle described the discovery in a series of tweets on Thursday. According to CVE-2021-30853 (CVSS 5.5), the issue involves a scenario where a rogue macOS app can circumvent Gatekeeper checks, ensuring that only trusted apps can be run and have been notarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese government suspends the Alibaba deal because it did not share the 0-day of Log4j with the government.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) of China temporarily suspended a partnership with Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing subsidiary of the world’s largest e-commerce company, for six months after the company failed to promptly notify the government about a critical security vulnerability affecting the widely used Log4j logging library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reports from 21st Century Business Herald, a Chinese daily business newspaper, revealed the development to Reuters and South China Morning Post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Signing Certificates are being used by new BLISTER malware to avoid detection.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/code-signing-certificates-are-being-used-by-new-blister-malware-to-avoid-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to researchers, evasive malware exploits valid code-signing certificates to evade security measures and deploy Cobalt Strike and BitRAT payloads through compromised systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elastic Security experts have dubbed the binary “Blister,” with malware samples that have zero to negligible detections on VirusTotal. At the time of writing, the infection vector, as well as the ultimate objectives of the intrusion, are unknown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; One remarkable aspect of the attacks is that they rely on a valid code signing certificate issued by Sectigo. The malware has been observed to be signed by the certificate in question dating back to September 15, 2021. The company said that Elastic reached out to it to ensure that abused certificates were revoked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka Police arrests Turkish ATM hacker six months after escaping from Agartala</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Counter-Terrorism and Transnational Crime Unit apprehended Turkish national Hakan Zanburkan in Bangladesh on Tuesday. Agartala’s Govind Ballabh Pant (GBP) Hospital and Agartala Government Medical College (AGMC) were able to eject Hakan’s captive with the aid of the local folks from Tripura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several other members of an international ATM card cloning syndicate were also arrested in Bangladesh alongside him on Thursday, according to a police officer at Agartala. Agartala’s AGMC and GBP Hospitals had allowed the under-trial Hakan to escape through a window during a health check-up while security lapses existed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ON Log4j Vulnerability CISA, FBI, and NSA publish a joint advisory.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian, Canadian, New Zealand, U.S., and U.K. cyber security agencies released a joint advisory on Wednesday in response to the widespread exploitation of multiple vulnerabilities in Apache’s Log4j software library by malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“These vulnerabilities, especially Log4Shell, are severe,” the intelligence agencies stated in the new guidance. Cyber threat actors are actively scanning networks for vulnerabilities such as Log4Shell, CVE-2021-45046, and CVE-2021-45105. These vulnerabilities will likely be exploited over an extended period. Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) can be exploited by sending a specially crafted request to a vulnerable system that causes that system to execute arbitrary code. CVE-2021-45046, on the other hand, allows remote code execution in certain non-default configurations, while CVE-2021-45105 could be used by a remote attacker to cause a denial-of-service (DoS) condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote hacking is possible for Garrett walk-through metal detectors.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A network component in Garrett Metal Detectors contains a number of security flaws that could allow remote attackers to bypass authentication requirements, tamper with metal detector configurations, and even execute arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a disclosure released last week, Cisco Talos noted that an attacker could use this module to remotely monitor statistics on a metal detector, such as whether the alarm has been triggered or how many visitors passed through. “They could also alter device configurations, such as changing the sensitivity level, potentially posing a security risk to users of these metal detectors.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is phishing?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During phishing, a target or targets are approached by email, telephone, or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution. This is done to lure individuals into providing sensitive data such as passwords, banking and credit card details, and personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information is then used to access sensitive accounts, resulting in identity theft and financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of phishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; spear phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;search engine phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;email phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Features of Phishing:-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zloader Banking a new Malware attack can be bypass Microsoft Signature Verification.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ZLoader malware campaign is exploiting a nine-year-old flaw in Microsoft’s digital signature verification to steal credentials and sensitive information using remote monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Check Point Research, which has been tracking the sophisticated infection chain since November 2021, it has been attributed to a cybercriminal group dubbed MalSmoke, citing similarities with previous attacks. “The infection chain incorporates legitimate remote management software (RMM) to gain access to the target machine.” After injecting its payload into a signed DLL, the malware further evades the system’s defenses by exploiting Microsoft’s digital signature verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
