<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macos on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macos on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sideloading Low-Level Extraction Agent with Regular Apple IDs from Windows and Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sideloading-low-level-extraction-agent-with-regular-apple-ids-from-windows-and-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/EIFT-8.60_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Low-level extraction enables access to all the data stored in the iOS device. Previously, sideloading the extraction agent for imaging the file system and decrypting keychain required enrolling one’s Apple ID into Apple’s paid Developer Program if one used a Windows or Linux PC. Mac users could utilize a regular, non-developer Apple ID. Today, we are bringing this feature to Windows and Linux editions of iOS Forensic Toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are several different methods achieving essentially the same goal, modern devices (starting with those based on the chip found in the iPhone Xr/Xs) require the use of a special app called extraction agent. On the device, the extraction agent attempts to acquire the required level of privileges by utilizing a chain of exploits, which is an absolute requirement for accessing the root of the file system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;SentinelOne Continues to Set the Standard in MITRE ATT&amp;CK® Evaluations | 100% Detection, Zero Delays and 88% Less Noise&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne achieves 100% detection and zero detection delays in the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK® Evaluations: Enterprise 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In cybersecurity, speed and accuracy are necessities. Every second counts, and every detection could be the difference between resilience and breach. That’s why SentinelOne takes immense pride in protecting our customers, monitoring trillions of signals annually across organizations from SMBs to Fortune 10 enterprises to top government entities and critical infrastructure. With visibility into the most sophisticated threats, we’ve detected and disrupted countless ransomware attacks, thwarted advanced eCrime and nation state adversaries, and ensured operations remain protected against evolving risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 essential Linux commands for every user</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-essential-linux-commands-for-every-user/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From new user to power user, here are 20 Linux commands that will make your life easier.Typing commands into a darkened terminal window might seem puzzling, but for many computer users, it&amp;rsquo;s the most efficient, most accessible and clearest way to accomplish nearly any task on a computer. These days, thanks to all the projects that bring open source commands to non-open platforms like macOS and Windows, and with containers running everywhere, terminal commands are relevant to everybody. Try Red Hat Enterprise Linux before you buy, with a free 60-day evaluation.Here are the top 20 commands a mod&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug in macOS, Gatekeeper’s security can be bypassed by malware.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The macOS operating system was recently patched for a security vulnerability that could be exploited by a threat actor to bypass “myriad foundational macOS security mechanisms” and run arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Wardle described the discovery in a series of tweets on Thursday. According to CVE-2021-30853 (CVSS 5.5), the issue involves a scenario where a rogue macOS app can circumvent Gatekeeper checks, ensuring that only trusted apps can be run and have been notarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
