<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Black Swan’ Event That Could Upend Life in 2025: The World’s Largest Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 futurists, foreign policy analysts and other prognosticators provide Politico readers some explosive potential scenarios for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gary Marcus, author of the book “Taming Silicon Valley”, one of The New Yorker’s recommended books in 2024, warns 2025 could easily see the largest cyberattack in history, taking down, at least for a little while, some sizeable piece of the world’s infrastructure, whether for deliberate ransom or to manipulate people to make money off a short on global markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“WWI Fighter Plane Hack” Inspires Breakthrough in Cancer Treatment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Massachusetts Amherst have developed an innovative technology inspired by the synchronization mechanism of WWI fighter aircraft, which coordinated machine gun fire with propeller movement. This breakthrough allows precise, real-time control of the pH in a cell’s environment to influence its behavior. Detailed in &lt;strong&gt;Nano Letters&lt;/strong&gt;, the study opens exciting possibilities for developing new cancer and heart disease therapies and advancing the field of tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title># Why Low-Code Development is the Future of Software Engineering 🚀</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-low-code-development-is-the-future-of-software-engineering-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-low-code-development-is-the-future-of-software-engineering-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced digital world, businesses need to adapt quickly to changing market demands. This has led to the rise of &lt;strong&gt;low-code development platforms&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;strong&gt;OutSystems&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Appian&lt;/strong&gt;, which are revolutionizing the way software is developed. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into why low-code development is the future of software engineering and how these platforms are shaping this transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-low-code-development&#34;&gt;What is Low-Code Development?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Low-code development platforms allow developers to create applications through graphical user interfaces and configuration rather than traditional hand-coded programming. This approach drastically reduces the time and effort required to develop applications, making it accessible to both professional developers and business users with minimal coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;12 Months of Fighting Cybercrime &amp; Defending Enterprises | SentinelLABS 2024 Review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From ransomware repurposed for espionage to increased exploitation of cloud platforms, learn about the key trends from SentinelLABS research in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the convergence of cybercrime and nation-state espionage to the strategic misuse of trusted platforms like Microsoft Azure and SaaS APIs, the cybersecurity landscape has grown more complex than ever in 2024. SentinelLABS has been at the forefront of these challenges, analyzing trends, uncovering campaigns, and equipping organizations with actionable intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights | Empowering Customers Through Innovations &amp; Security in Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the latest technologies and innovations for cloud, container, and data security revealed at AWS re:Invent 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week marked another action-packed year at AWS re:Invent for the SentinelOne Team. Year after year, a consistent highlight from the event is the strong sense of community it builds with people from different backgrounds, geographies, and business types – all unified by their interest in innovating and doing business on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Samsung&#39;s new Odyssey gaming monitors require a monster PC build&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/samsungs-new-odyssey-gaming-monitors-require-a-monster-pc-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/samsungs-new-odyssey-gaming-monitors-require-a-monster-pc-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Samsung unveiled some ultra powerful gaming monitors at CES 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas is where some of the largest names in tech gather to announce the technologies and products that will define next year&amp;rsquo;s product cycles. Against that backdrop, CES is also well-known for outrageous product releases not exactly aimed at the average consumer, and Samsung&amp;rsquo;s new Odyssey gaming monitors announced at CES 2025 are the perfect example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;SentinelOne Continues to Set the Standard in MITRE ATT&amp;CK® Evaluations | 100% Detection, Zero Delays and 88% Less Noise&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne achieves 100% detection and zero detection delays in the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK® Evaluations: Enterprise 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In cybersecurity, speed and accuracy are necessities. Every second counts, and every detection could be the difference between resilience and breach. That’s why SentinelOne takes immense pride in protecting our customers, monitoring trillions of signals annually across organizations from SMBs to Fortune 10 enterprises to top government entities and critical infrastructure. With visibility into the most sophisticated threats, we’ve detected and disrupted countless ransomware attacks, thwarted advanced eCrime and nation state adversaries, and ensured operations remain protected against evolving risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Technology &amp; National Security Reflection Series Paper 10: International Responsibility for Hacker-for-Hire Operations: The BellTrox Problem&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anmol Dhawan* About the Author: The author is a 2021 graduate of National Law University, Delhi. Editor’s Note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author’s contribution serves as an adapted reflection to the following […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tripwire Enterprise Integration Framework (TEIF) Is Thriving. Here&#39;s How You Can Benefit&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tripwire-enterprise-integration-framework-teif-is-thriving-heres-how-you-can-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tripwire-enterprise-integration-framework-teif-is-thriving-heres-how-you-can-benefit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a team environment, it’s all about playing nice with others. The same could be said of your technology team (or stack), and its various components. The problem of disparate, complex systems – each coming from disparate, complex places – all being thrown together in an enterprise has been one the industry has been mulling over for some time. Any change to an individual service could have repercussions across the whole suite, and interconnected issues like these continue to perplex and overwhelm practitioners. With Tripwire Enterprise Integration Framework (TEIF), Fortra’s Tripwire offers&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ZDI Threat Hunting 2024: Highlights, Trends, &amp; Challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on 2024, it has been an eventful year for the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team. Throughout the year, we identified numerous threat actor campaigns exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities, uncovered additional variants of these vulnerabilities, and discovered even more vulnerabilities through our in-the-wild research. In this blog, we will highlight some of the key achievements of the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team, as well as discuss important in-the-wild vulnerability trends and industry challenges we encountered in 2024 which will continue into 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Best Cybercrime Blogs and Websites in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-best-cybercrime-blogs-and-websites-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-best-cybercrime-blogs-and-websites-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Feedspot Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FeedSpot named Cybercrime Magazine no. 1 on it’s list of 20 Best Cybercrime Blogs you should follow in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best Cybercrime blogs from thousands of blogs on the web are ranked by Feedspot for relevancy, authority, social media followers &amp;amp; freshness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“For news on the industry and worldwide cybersecurity research, turn to Cybersecurity Ventures,” says the editors at Feedspot. “They offer industry research, threat information, and cybersecurity trends on their website. With issues like data breaches, cybercrime, and developing technology covered, it’s a great tool for consumers, companies, and professionals that want to stay up to date on cybersecurity developments.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 Guide: Purchasing Cybersecurity Tools and Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-guide-purchasing-cybersecurity-tools-and-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2025-guide-purchasing-cybersecurity-tools-and-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Guide In American City &amp;amp; County&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 18, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Global cybercrime costs are rising rapidly, with estimates reaching $10.5 trillion by 2025, according to Cybersecurity Ventures. These financial hits stem from issues like damaged or stolen data, productivity losses, business disruptions, fraud, and the costly aftermath of recovery. The good news? Investing in the right cybersecurity solutions can empower your organization to defend against and recover from cybercrime and other IT-related incidents prevalent in our evolving digital landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38C3: It’s TOSLINK, Over Long Distance Fibre</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/fibre-toslink-featured.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve owned a CD player or other piece of consumer digital audio gear manufactured since the 1980s, the chances are it has a TOSLINK port on the back. This is a fairly simple interface that sends I2S digital audio data down a short length of optical fibre, and it’s designed to run between something like a CD player and an external DAC. It’s ancient technology in optical fibre terms, with a lowish data rate and plastic fibre, but consider for a minute whether it could be adapted for modern ultra-high-speed conenctions. It’s what [Ben Cartwright-Cox] has done, and he delivered a talk about it at the recent 38C3 event in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 reasons you should you use 2FA apps over SMS-based authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-reasons-you-should-you-use-2fa-apps-over-sms-based-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2FA over SMS isn&amp;rsquo;t just unreliable, it&amp;rsquo;s also a security risk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MFA, or Multi-Factor Authentication, has proliferated throughout our computing lives over the last decade. It largely began with SMS-based authentication in addition to a password, allowing users to add an extra layer of authentication by forcing users to enter a code sent to their phone upon an attempted login. The truth is, SMS-based authentication was never secure. Due to the inherent technology and the infrastructure around SIM cards, 2FA with SMS is not only inadequate; it also actively compromises your security, and here are 4 reasons why you should use a dedicated 2FA app instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Cybersecurity Priorities for The Trump Administration</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024: A year when AI, quantum computing, and cybersecurity converged to redefine our digital landscape. For those navigating these complex technological frontiers, clarity became the most critical currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inside Cyber, Key moments that resonated with our community:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Cybersecurity Trends for 2025 Diving deep into the evolving threat landscape and strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• AI, 5G, and Quantum: Innovation and Cybersecurity Risks Exploring the intersection of emerging technologies and security challenges &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&#34;&gt;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An overview of virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) in Linux</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-overview-of-virtual-routing-and-forwarding-vrf-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-overview-of-virtual-routing-and-forwarding-vrf-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) is a network virtualization technique allowing traffic isolation at the layer 3 (L3) of the OSI model by creating independent routing and forwarding domains. It is essentially the combination of a separate routing table and associated network interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other networking techniques exist but are operating at a different levels—such as VLAN and network namespaces, respectively at the layer 2 and at the device level. Those techniques can be combined, e.g., a VRF can be part of a network namespace and/or VLANs can be attached to a VRF. Note that a network namespace might look like a way to emulate a VRF but they differ in how traffic is handled, notably VRF does not impact layer 2 (L2) traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Bypass Vulnerability Found in Dell OpenManage Server Administrator</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/authentication-bypass-vulnerability-found-in-dell-openmanage-server-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/authentication-bypass-vulnerability-found-in-dell-openmanage-server-administrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;authentication-bypass-vulnerability-found-in-dell-openmanage-server-administrator&#34;&gt;Authentication Bypass Vulnerability Found in Dell OpenManage Server Administrator&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/22825/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dell Technologies has issued a critical security advisory for its OpenManage Server Administrator (OMSA) software. The advisory addresses a high-severity vulnerability (CVE-2024-52316) in Apache Tomca &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (8 hours, 17 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CVE-2025-21613 CVE-2024-52316 CVE-2024-39584&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIOS flaws expose iSeq DNA sequencers to bootkit attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bios-flaws-expose-iseq-dna-sequencers-to-bootkit-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bios-flaws-expose-iseq-dna-sequencers-to-bootkit-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;bios-flaws-expose-iseq-dna-sequencers-to-bootkit-attacks&#34;&gt;BIOS flaws expose iSeq DNA sequencers to bootkit attacks&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/22778/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BIOS/UEFI vulnerabilities in the iSeq 100 DNA sequencer from U.S. biotechnology company Illumina could let attackers disable devices used for detecting illnesses and developing vaccines. The Illumina &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 07, 2025 (14 hours, 47 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CVE-2023-1968 CVE-2023-1966&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Hat MEA 2024 In Guinness World Records – Crypto.com CISO</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-hat-mea-2024-in-guinness-world-records-crypto-com-ciso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-hat-mea-2024-in-guinness-world-records-crypto-com-ciso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Listen To the Podcast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 20, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jason Lau, CISO at Singapore-based Crypto.com, one of the world’s biggest crypto trading platforms with 100 million users across 90 countries, told Cybercrime Magazine Podcast host David Braue that there were around 40,000 people at the recent Black Hat Middle East &amp;amp; Africa Conference held in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia Nov. 24-26.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk | Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file &lt;code&gt;zshenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, researchers detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s discovery in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also reported on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to connect the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bug in macOS, Gatekeeper’s security can be bypassed by malware.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bug-in-macos-gatekeepers-security-can-be-bypassed-by-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The macOS operating system was recently patched for a security vulnerability that could be exploited by a threat actor to bypass “myriad foundational macOS security mechanisms” and run arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patrick Wardle described the discovery in a series of tweets on Thursday. According to CVE-2021-30853 (CVSS 5.5), the issue involves a scenario where a rogue macOS app can circumvent Gatekeeper checks, ensuring that only trusted apps can be run and have been notarized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bugs in Active Directory could allow hackers to take over Windows domain controllers.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bugs-in-active-directory-could-allow-hackers-to-take-over-windows-domain-controllers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the availability of a proof-of-concept (POC) tool on December 12, Microsoft is urging customers to patch two security vulnerabilities in Active Directory domain controllers that it addressed in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two vulnerabilities are identified as CVE-2021-42278 and CVE-2021-42287. They both affect Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) and have a severity rating of 7.5. Both bugs were discovered and reported by Andrew Bartlett of Catalyst IT.   Microsoft’s Active Directory is an identity and access management service that runs on Windows Server. While the tech giant rated the shortcomings as “exploitation less likely” in its assessment, the public disclosure of the PoC has prompted renewed calls for applying the fixes to mitigate any potential exploitation. ( CVE-2021-42278) allows an attacker to manipulate the SAM-Account-Name attribute, which is used to log a user into systems in the Active Directory domain; CVE-2021-42287 allows the attacker to impersonate the domain controller. In other words, a bad actor with domain user credentials can gain access as a domain admin user.  “An attacker may establish a clear path to a Domain Admin user in an Active Directory environment that hasn’t implemented these new patches by combining these two vulnerabilities,” Microsoft’s senior product manager Daniel Naim explained. “After compromising an ordinary user in the domain, attackers can simply raise their privilege to that of a Domain Admin using this escalation technique.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building for the Future: How Scalable Web Architecture Can Help Your Business Grow Without Limits</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-for-the-future-how-scalable-web-architecture-can-help-your-business-grow-without-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-for-the-future-how-scalable-web-architecture-can-help-your-business-grow-without-limits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Farticles%2Fc398838k59aehr52ucvg.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image description&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced digital world, businesses must be ready for anything. Imagine launching your product or service online, and everything&amp;rsquo;s going great-until a traffic spike occurs. Suddenly, your website crashes, and your customers can&amp;rsquo;t access your offerings. What happened? The culprit is most probably poor web architecture that wasn&amp;rsquo;t built for scalability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You understand the frustration firsthand if you have ever been caught in the chaos of website crashes or poor performance during peak traffic times. What if I told you, however, that by using the right approach to scalable web architecture, you can prevent these issues and build a website that will grow with your business? Your customers&amp;rsquo; experience will always be smooth, no matter how big you get.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Influence Ops | Twisting Tales of Volt Typhoon at Home and Abroad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s CVERC attempts to attribute Volt Typhoon activities to the U.S., but the fact-free claims reveal much about the PRC&amp;rsquo;s real agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The latest CVERC report reflects China’s ongoing efforts to undermine support for U.S. surveillance activities by attempting to fuel debate over Section 702.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The CVERC report also draws Microsoft into its crosshairs as part of an ongoing push to remove foreign technology from PRC government systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The report highlights previous intelligence from France and Germany regarding U.S spying in an attempt to deflect attention away from recent incidents of Chinese espionage in Europe, likely as a means to shape narratives amid ongoing political debates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China’s Computer Virus Emergency Response Center has released part three of a running series claiming that the U.S. government is actually behind Volt Typhoon activity, rather than China. The latest CVERC report, whose front page includes an oddly edited photo with the text “Lie to Me,” provides no new evidence of these claims and rehashes old leaked U.S. intelligence documents. However, this CVERC report is not useless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese government suspends the Alibaba deal because it did not share the 0-day of Log4j with the government.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinese-government-suspends-the-alibaba-deal-because-it-did-not-share-the-0-day-of-log4j-with-the-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) of China temporarily suspended a partnership with Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing subsidiary of the world’s largest e-commerce company, for six months after the company failed to promptly notify the government about a critical security vulnerability affecting the widely used Log4j logging library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reports from 21st Century Business Herald, a Chinese daily business newspaper, revealed the development to Reuters and South China Morning Post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIS Control 07: Continuous Vulnerability Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cis-control-07-continuous-vulnerability-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cis-control-07-continuous-vulnerability-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to cybersecurity, vulnerability management is one of the older technologies that still play a critical role in securing our assets. It is often overlooked, disregarded, or considered only for checkbox compliance needs, but a proper vulnerability management program can play a critical role in avoiding a series of data breaches. CIS Control 07 provides the minimum requirements and table stakes, if you will, for establishing a successful vulnerability management program. Key Takeaways for Control 7 At the core of CIS Control 7 is a reliance on known standards, terms from&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Malware | A Threat Hunter’s Guide to Analysis, Techniques and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about cloud threats, how to hunt for them and how to analyze them in this post based on Alex Delamotte&amp;rsquo;s recent LABScon workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many researchers have noticed, malware in the cloud is different. Perhaps more strikingly different than Windows versus Linux threats, cloud services are targeted through entirely different methods altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At LABScon 2024, I gave a workshop Taxonomy in the Troposphere that outlines categories of cloud threats and how to approach analyzing and hunting them. The workshop structure highlighted three general sections to approach this problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the scope of IAM Access Analyzer unused access analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management Access Analyzer simplifies inspecting unused access to guide you towards least privilege. You can use unused access findings to identify over-permissive access granted to AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles and users in your accounts or organization. From a delegated administrator account for IAM Access Analyzer, you can use the dashboard to review unused access findings across your organization and prioritize the accounts to inspect based on the volume and type of findings. The findings highlight unused roles, unused access keys for IAM users, and unused passwords for IAM users. For active IAM users and roles, the findings provide visibility into unused services and actions. Recently, IAM Access Analyzer launched new configuration capabilities that you can use to customize the analysis. You can select accounts, roles, and users to exclude, and focus on the areas that matter the most to you. You can use identifiers such as account ID or scale configuration using tags. By scoping the IAM Access Analyzer to monitor a subset of accounts and roles, you can reduce noise from unwanted findings. You can update the configuration when needed to change the scope of analysis. With this new offering, IAM Access Analyzer provides enhanced controls to help you tailor the analysis more closely to your organization’s security needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals Are Targeting AI Agents and Conversational Platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;emerging-risks-for-businesses-and-consumers&#34;&gt;Emerging risks for businesses and consumers&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– Shawn Loveland, Chief Operating Officer, Resecurity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;San Jose, Calif. – Dec. 11, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resecurity has identified a spike in malicious campaigns targeting &lt;strong&gt;AI agents&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Conversational AI platforms&lt;/strong&gt; that leverage chatbots to provide automated, human-like interactions for consumers. Conversational AI platforms are designed to facilitate natural interactions between humans and machines using technologies like &lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning (ML)&lt;/strong&gt;. These platforms enable applications such as chatbots and virtual agents to engage in meaningful conversations, making them valuable tools across various industries. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity 2025 | Preparing for Tomorrow’s Threats, Challenges and Strategic Shifts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore SentinelLabs&amp;rsquo; take on what 2025 may bring for cybersecurity, including emerging trends and actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crystal balls are notoriously fragile, and those who look into them are wise not to become fixated with the shadows cast by their refracted light, yet no business can function without some meaningful sense of what the future might hold. Reading the tea leaves of the past can offer no insight into novel and unexpected events to come, but it can help us prepare for that which is already forming in the shadows. Ultimately, the entire point of intelligence is to enable forward-looking decisions, and this means we’ll hit the mark with some and miss with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Is One Of The Top 5 Skills For Job Seekers To Learn In 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-is-one-of-the-top-5-skills-for-job-seekers-to-learn-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-is-one-of-the-top-5-skills-for-job-seekers-to-learn-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Forbes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 6, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Forbes story reports that cybersecurity skills are highly coveted, as the digital landscape faces unprecedented threats and skyrocketing costs associated with cybercrimes. By 2025, global cybercrime costs are projected to reach a staggering $10.5 trillion annually, according to a report by Cybercrime Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This surge in cybercrime is accompanied by a severe shortage of qualified professionals in the field. The cybersecurity job market is expected to grow by 33 percent between 2023 and 2033, with an estimated 3.5 million unfilled cybersecurity positions worldwide by the end of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Sheet: Nvidia’s $700 million open source surprise</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-sheet-nvidias-700-million-open-source-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-sheet-nvidias-700-million-open-source-surprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/data-sheet-nvidias-700-million-open-source-surprise.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plus: Bytedance’s $7 billion loophole, AI-enabled robo-surgeons, the U.S. Treasury hack, and an IBM antitrust probe—in the latest edition of Fortune’s flagship tech newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read more&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPRK IT Workers | A Network of Active Front Companies and Their Links to China</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has identified multiple deceptive websites linked to businesses in China fronting for North Korea&amp;rsquo;s fake IT workers scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has identified unique characteristics of multiple websites, now seized by the US Government, associated with the DPRK IT Worker front companies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that DPRK actors seek to impersonate US based software and technology consulting businesses by copying the online brands of legitimate organizations, seeking to use these for financial objectives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has linked the activity to several active front companies and links these with high confidence to a larger set of organizations being created in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our findings link additional companies, which remain active today, to the DPRK IT Workers scheme.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North Korea operates a global network of IT workers, both as individuals and under front companies, to evade sanctions and generate revenue for the regime. These workers are highly skilled in areas like software development, mobile applications, blockchain, and cryptocurrency technologies. By posing as professionals from other countries using fake identities and forged credentials, they secure remote jobs and freelance contracts with businesses worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EAGERBEE Malware Detection: New Backdoor Variant Targets Internet Service Providers and State Bodies in the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eagerbee-malware-detection-new-backdoor-variant-targets-internet-service-providers-and-state-bodies-in-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://socprime.com/wp-content/uploads/Eagerbee-2-400x234.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of the re-emergence of a more advanced NonEuclid RAT variant in the cyber threat arena, a novel malware iteration known as the Eagerbee backdoor poses an increasing threat to organizations in the Middle East, primarily targeting Internet Service Providers (ISPs) and state agencies. The enhanced EAGERBEE backdoor variant can deploy payloads, scan file systems, and execute command shells, displaying significant evolution of its offensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring GenAI in Cybersecurity: Gemini for Malware Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-genai-in-cybersecurity-gemini-for-malware-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-genai-in-cybersecurity-gemini-for-malware-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How useful are Generative AI technologies when it comes to being used in a security context? We have taken the plunge and gave it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/905791541/0/gdatasecurityblog-en&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gdatasoftware.com/fileadmin/_processed_/6/1/G_DATA_Blog_GenAI_Malware_Analysis_Preview_b0418967dc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/x.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing ‘Anom” – Inside The FBI’s Secret Encrypted Phone Company</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exposing-anom-inside-the-fbis-secret-encrypted-phone-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exposing-anom-inside-the-fbis-secret-encrypted-phone-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Listen To the Podcast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 19, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joseph Cox, author of the 2024 book “Dark Wire: The Incredible True Story of the Largest Sting Operation Ever“, came on the Cybercrime Magazine Podcast to share the inside story of the largest law-enforcement sting operation ever, in which the FBI made its own tech start-up to wiretap the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FLOSS Weekly Episode 815: You Win Some, You Lose Some</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/floss-weekly-episode-815-you-win-some-you-lose-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/floss-weekly-episode-815-you-win-some-you-lose-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pipewire.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week, Jonathan Bennett and Randal chat with Matija Šuklje about Open Source and the Law! How do Open Source projects handle liability, what should a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) look like, and where can an individual or project turn for legal help?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matija.suklje.name/&#34;&gt;https://matija.suklje.name/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openchainproject.org&#34;&gt;https://openchainproject.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matija.suklje.name/fiduciary-license-agreement-20&#34;&gt;https://matija.suklje.name/fiduciary-license-agreement-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can watch the live recording of the show Right on our YouTube Channel? Have someone you’d like us to interview? Let us know, or contact the guest and have them contact us! Take a look at the schedule here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaze Upon This Omni-directional Treadmill’s Clever LEGO Construction</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gaze-upon-this-omni-directional-treadmills-clever-lego-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gaze-upon-this-omni-directional-treadmills-clever-lego-construction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/How-I-Built-A-LEGO-Treadmill-That-Moves-In-EVERY-Direction-16-24-screenshot.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to see some wildly skillful LEGO construction? Check out [Banana Gear Studios]’ omni-directional treadmill which showcases not only how such a thing works, but demonstrates some pretty impressive problem solving in the process. Construction was far from straightforward!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/How-I-Built-A-LEGO-Treadmill-That-Moves-In-EVERY-Direction-15-54-screenshot.png?w=400&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 9×9 grid of LEGO shafts all turning in unison is just one of the non-trivial design challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In principle the treadmill works by placing an object on a bed of identical, rotating discs. By tilting the discs, one controls which edge is in contact with the object, which in turn controls the direction the object moves. While the concept is straightforward, the implementation is a wee bit more complex. LEGO pieces offer a rich variety of mechanical functions, but even so, making a 9×9 array of discs all rotate in unison turns out to be a nontrivial problem to solve. Gears alone are not the answer, because the shafts in such a dense array are a bit too close for LEGO gears to play nicely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Wanted: Data Scientists In The Cybersecurity Field</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/help-wanted-data-scientists-in-the-cybersecurity-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/help-wanted-data-scientists-in-the-cybersecurity-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Medium Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 7, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data science technology is about to revolutionize even the most traditional industries as it uses AI, Machine Learning, and Big Data, according to a story in Medium.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Total global data storage is projected to exceed 200 zettabytes by 2025, according to Cybersecurity Ventures. This includes data stored on private and public IT infrastructures, on utility infrastructures, on private and public cloud data centers, and personal computing devices; PCs, laptops, tablets, smartphones, and IoT devices&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s why Julia is THE language in scientific programming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working in quantum computing is being exposed to a whole new set of skills and tools. For those of us coming from the software engineering side, discovering the things our academic peers are using is an interesting experience. One of the best for me personally was coming across the Julia programming language, and learning why it has become the go-to language for serious scientific programming in some circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How business, government and kids united to fight cybercrime in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-business-government-and-kids-united-to-fight-cybercrime-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-business-government-and-kids-united-to-fight-cybercrime-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story In Mastercard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 23, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks are as old as the internet, but over the past several years they have become more insidious and destructive, in part by harnessing social engineering at scale and deploying increasingly sophisticated technology like generative AI. This year, cybercrime is projected to cost an estimated $9.5 trillion across the globe, according to Cybersecurity Ventures — approximately 9 percent of the world’s GDP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-defend-against-the-three-most-dangerous-cybersecurity-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different hacking techniques to be aware of. At the time of publication, the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework identified some 236 hacking techniques across 14 different categories. Luckily, you don’t need to understand all these tactics to stay safe. Many are close variations of the same basic approach. The best cybersecurity tools […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Defend Against the Three Most Dangerous Cybersecurity Attacks appeared first on Heimdal Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Steal an AI Model Without Actually Hacking Anything</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-steal-an-ai-model-without-actually-hacking-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-steal-an-ai-model-without-actually-hacking-anything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/how-to-steal-an-ai-model-without-actually-hacking-anything2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers developed a technique that senses a model’s electromagnetic ‘signature’ and compares it to other models run on the same kind of chip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read more&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IHAK: Capture Sector Growth In Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ihak-capture-sector-growth-in-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ihak-capture-sector-growth-in-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Seeking Alpha Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 3, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cybercrime costs are rising. According to Cybersecurity Ventures, it is expected to reach $10.5 trillion annually by 2025, making cybersecurity a crucial investment sector.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;iShares Cybersecurity and Tech ETF (IHAK) offers a diversified portfolio of top-performing cybersecurity stocks, reducing idiosyncratic risk while capturing sector growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite market volatility, the long-term outlook for cybersecurity remains strong, driven by increasing cyber threats and the need for robust defense mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Reflection Series on CCG’s Technology and National Security Law and Policy Seminar Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, CCG-NLUD will commence the latest edition of its Seminar Course on Technology and National Security Law and Policy (“the Seminar Course”). The Seminar Course is offered to interested 4th and 5th year students who are enrolled in the B.A. LL.B. (Hons.) programme at the National Law University, Delhi. The course is set […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti warns hackers are exploiting new vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The company released an advisory and a corresponding blog about two bugs — CVE-2025-0282 and CVE-2025-0283 — and warned that some customers have already seen CVE-2025-0282 exploited in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive healthcare breaches prompt US cybersecurity rules overhaul</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/massive-healthcare-breaches-prompt-us-cybersecurity-rules-overhaul2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) has proposed updates to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) to secure patients’ health data following a surge in massive healthcare data leaks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These stricter cybersecurity rules, proposed by the HHS’ Office for Civil Rights (OCR) and expected to be published as a final rule within 60 days, would require healthcare organizations to encrypt protected health information (PHI), implement multifactor authentication, and segment their networks to make it harder for attackers to move laterally through them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McAfee Deepfake Detector: Fighting Misinformation with AMD AI-Powered Precision</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafee-deepfake-detector-fighting-misinformation-with-amd-ai-powered-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafee-deepfake-detector-fighting-misinformation-with-amd-ai-powered-precision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/300x200_Blog_AMD-2x-300x200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a world where deepfake scams and misinformation are increasingly pervasive, McAfee is taking a bold step forward with major enhancements to its AI-powered deepfake detection technology. By partnering with AMD and harnessing the Neural Processing Unit (NPU) within the latest AMD Ryzen&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/2122.png&#34; alt=&#34;™&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; AI 300 Series processors announced at CES, McAfee Deepfake Detector is designed to empower users to discern truth from fiction like never before. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;deepfakes-a-growing-global-concern&#34;&gt;Deepfakes: A Growing Global Concern &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As deepfake technology becomes more sophisticated, so too does the challenge of identifying manipulated content. Nearly two-thirds of people globally report rising concerns over deepfakes, emphasizing the need for tools that can accurately detect falsified content. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ON Log4j Vulnerability CISA, FBI, and NSA publish a joint advisory.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-log4j-vulnerability-cisa-fbi-and-nsa-publish-a-joint-advisory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Australian, Canadian, New Zealand, U.S., and U.K. cyber security agencies released a joint advisory on Wednesday in response to the widespread exploitation of multiple vulnerabilities in Apache’s Log4j software library by malicious actors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“These vulnerabilities, especially Log4Shell, are severe,” the intelligence agencies stated in the new guidance. Cyber threat actors are actively scanning networks for vulnerabilities such as Log4Shell, CVE-2021-45046, and CVE-2021-45105. These vulnerabilities will likely be exploited over an extended period. Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) can be exploited by sending a specially crafted request to a vulnerable system that causes that system to execute arbitrary code. CVE-2021-45046, on the other hand, allows remote code execution in certain non-default configurations, while CVE-2021-45105 could be used by a remote attacker to cause a denial-of-service (DoS) condition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source all the way down: Upgrading our developer documentation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Cloudflare, we treat developer content like a product, where we take the user and their feedback into consideration. We are constantly iterating, testing, analyzing, and refining content. Inspired by agile practices, treating developer content like an open source product means we approach our documentation the same way an open source software project is created and maintained.  Open source documentation empowers the developer community because it allows anyone, anywhere, to contribute content. By making both the content and the framework of the documentation site publicly accessible, we provide developers with the opportunity to not only improve the material itself but also understand and engage with the processes that govern how the documentation is built, approved, and maintained. This transparency fosters collaboration, learning, and innovation, enabling developers to contribute their expertise and learn from others in a shared, open environment. We also provide feedback to other open source products and plugins, giving back to the same community that supports us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Digital Eye | Chinese APT Compromises Critical Digital Infrastructure via Visual Studio Code Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure to target large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From late June to mid-July 2024, a suspected China-nexus threat actor targeted large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe, an activity cluster that we dubbed ‘Operation Digital Eye’.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The intrusions could have enabled the adversaries to establish strategic footholds and compromise downstream entities. SentinelLabs and Tinexta Cyber detected and interrupted the activities in their initial phases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors used a lateral movement capability indicative of the presence of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster maintaining and provisioning tooling within the Chinese APT ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure for C2 purposes, attempting to evade detection by making malicious activities appear legitimate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our visibility suggests that the abuse of Visual Studio Code for C2 purposes had been relatively rare in the wild prior to this campaign. Operation Digital Eye marks the first instance of a suspected Chinese APT group using this technique that we have directly observed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tinexta Cyber and SentinelLabs have been tracking threat activities targeting business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe. Based on the malware, infrastructure, techniques used, victimology, and the timing of the activities, we assess that it is highly likely these attacks were conducted by a China-nexus threat actor with cyberespionage motivations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pall Mall Process to tackle commercial hacking proliferation raises more concerns than solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An initiative spearheaded by France and the U.K. last year to tackle commercial spyware has experienced setbacks and significant gaps, according to participants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLAYFULGHOST Delivered via Phishing and SEO Poisoning in Trojanized VPN Apps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/playfulghost-delivered-via-phishing-and-seo-poisoning-in-trojanized-vpn-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/playfulghost-delivered-via-phishing-and-seo-poisoning-in-trojanized-vpn-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/playfulghost-delivered-via-phishing-and-seo-poisoning-in-trojanized-vpn-apps.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PLAYFULGHOST malware mimics Gh0st RAT with advanced spyware features, targeting users via phishing and SEO poisoning techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read more&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting AI Infrastructures | Introducing SentinelOne’s AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne’s new AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution helps organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of AI introduces unique security considerations. Misconfigurations in AI infrastructure and unsecured APIs can create weaknesses that cybercriminals will exploit. In this blog post, we dive deep into how SentinelOne’s agentless AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution addresses these challenges by offering AI inventory automation, misconfiguration detection, and attack path analysis to help organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Leap: D-Wave’s Bold New Move! Discover the Future of Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking development poised to reshape the landscape of quantum computing, D-Wave Systems has announced their latest innovation: the Advantage2 quantum processor. As the industry grapples with an ever-increasing demand for computational power, this announcement signals a pivotal moment in the quest to harness the full potential of quantum technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game-Changing Technology&lt;/strong&gt; The Advantage2 processor boasts a staggering 7,000 qubits, significantly surpassing its predecessors and setting a new benchmark for quantum performance. This advancement is expected to enhance quantum annealing processes, thereby accelerating solutions for complex optimization problems that classical computers struggle to handle efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware Turns 35. How It All Started In 1989.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-turns-35-how-it-all-started-in-1989/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ransomware-turns-35-how-it-all-started-in-1989/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full CNBC Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 30, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first event considered to be a ransomware attack happened in 1989, according to CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A hacker physically mailed floppy disks claiming to contain software that could help determine whether someone was at risk of developing AIDs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, when installed, the software would hide directories and encrypt file names on people’s computers after they’d rebooted 90 times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian internet provider confirms its network was ‘destroyed’ following attack claimed by Ukrainian hackers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a statement on the Russian social media platform VKontakte, the St. Petersburg-based company said the “planned” attack “destroyed” its infrastructure overnight. Nodex added that it was working to restore systems from backups but could not provide a timeline for when operations would fully resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Ventures Invests in poolside, Next Generation AI for Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S Ventures invests in poolside, one of the most watched and highest valued startups in generative AI for software engineering today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October 2024, SentinelOne’s venture arm, S Ventures, made a strategic investment in poolside as part of the AI assistive coding startup’s $500 million Series B round. It was one of S Ventures notable recent investments in generative AI (GenAI) start-ups following similar investments in leading foundational and enterprise LLM platforms such as Anthropic and Cohere, as well as Scale, a startup focused on the development and tooling layer of AI, and Galileo, a leading evaluation intelligence platform for AI teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Satechi rounds off its CES 2025 announcements with this sleek mechanical keyboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/satechi-rounds-off-its-ces-2025-announcements-with-this-sleek-mechanical-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/satechi-rounds-off-its-ces-2025-announcements-with-this-sleek-mechanical-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great-looking keyboard for work and play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Satechi has been giving us a sprinkle of exciting CES 2025 announcements over the past few days, including a must-have accessory for Mac Mini M4 fans and a the perfect charging companions for tech lovers on the go. Now, the company is rounding off its CES spree with this fancy full-sized keyboard that definitely looks the part.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech In Plain Sight: Security Envelopes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/letterlocking-mary-queen-of-scots-last-letter-a-spiral-lock-england-1587-uh0135-dzpe1mcgxxo-mkv-shot0002_featured.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You probably get a few of these things each week in the mail. And some of them actually do a good job of obscuring the contents inside, even if you hold the envelope up to the light. But have you ever taken the time to appreciate the beauty of security envelope patterns? Yeah, I didn’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The really interesting thing is just how many different patterns are out there when a dozen or so would probably cover it. But there are so, so many patterns in the world. In my experience, many utilities and higher-end companies create their own security patterns for mailing out statements and the like, so that right there adds up to some unknown abundance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology and National Security Law Reflection Series Paper 5: Legality of Cyber Weapons Under International Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Siddharth Gautam* About the Author: The author is a 2020 graduate of National Law University, Delhi.  Editor’s note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author reflects upon the following question:  What are cyber weapons? […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas awards $170 million contract for cybersecurity assistance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of a year when Texas employees were among those targeted by hackers, the state has awarded a multi-million-dollar contract to a company that works with entities to increase technological efficiency and offer cybersecurity protection. Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC) announced Dec. 18 that it was awarded a $170.9 million contract from the Texas Department of Information Resources (DIR) to provide cybersecurity services in protection of state networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best, the Worst and the Ugliest in Cybersecurity | 2024 Edition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we ring in the New Year, SentinelOne reviews and reflects on some of the most formative cyber news stories that occurred in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s almost time to wave goodbye to the year that was 2024, and as we look ahead to 2025 and the challenges that might bring, now is a good time to reflect on the best, the worst and the ugliest cybersecurity news stories over the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nintendo Switch 2 could be launching in April, according to an accessory maker</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-nintendo-switch-2-could-be-launching-in-april-according-to-an-accessory-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-nintendo-switch-2-could-be-launching-in-april-according-to-an-accessory-maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nintendo Switch 2 will reportedly arrive in April 2025, according to an accessory manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CES 2025 is buzzing with the latest hardware from NVIDIA, AMD, Lenovo, and plenty of other tech giants — all of which were expected, but unexpectedly, it&amp;rsquo;s also buzzing with news about the new Nintendo Switch that&amp;rsquo;s slated to arrive this year. The latest being a report from Numerama (thanks, VGC) where accessory maker Genki has potentially spilled the beans that Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s next generation of hardware will arrive sometime in April 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from First Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Earlier this month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the proceedings of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, which has been tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Fourth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Last month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the Fourth Session of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week I of the Fifth Substantive Session.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction Last month from April 11-21, 2023, the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communications Technologies (ICTs) for Criminal Purpose held its Fifth Session in Vienna. As we reported earlier, the negotiating process has reached a pivotal stage, wherein the Member Countries […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week II of the Fifth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal In Part I of the two-part blog series, we briefed our readers on the developments that took place in the first week of the Fifth Session of the Ad-Hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we aim to capture the key discussion on provisions on (i) technical assistance, (ii) preventative measures, (iii) […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Sanctions Chinese Cybersecurity Firm for State-Backed Hacking Campaigns</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-s-sanctions-chinese-cybersecurity-firm-for-state-backed-hacking-campaigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-s-sanctions-chinese-cybersecurity-firm-for-state-backed-hacking-campaigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/u-s-sanctions-chinese-cybersecurity-firm-for-state-backed-hacking-campaigns.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;U.S. sanctions Integrity Technology Group for aiding Flax Typhoon’s state-sponsored hacks, targeting U.S. systems since 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read more&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Anatomy of Cyber Enabled Crimes and their Governance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Digital systems and Information Communication Technology (ICT) play an increasingly central role in our lives. Technological advancement has created new opportunities for cybercriminals to exploit vulnerabilities in digital systems and networks. The resulting cybercrimes can affect everyone, from government and multinational corporations to individuals. As technology continues to make deeper inroads into our lives, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Cyber Trust Mark logo for smart devices is coming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White House announced the launch of the US Cyber Trust Mark which aims to help buyers make an informed choice about the purchase of wireless internet-connected devices, such as baby monitors, doorbells, thermostats, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity labeling program for wireless consumer Internet of Things (IoT) products is voluntary but the participants include several major manufacturers, retailers, and trade associations for popular electronics, appliances, and consumer products. The companies and groups said they are committed to increase cybersecurity for the products they sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US sanctions prominent Chinese cyber company for role in Flax Typhoon attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-sanctions-prominent-chinese-cyber-company-for-role-in-flax-typhoon-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-sanctions-prominent-chinese-cyber-company-for-role-in-flax-typhoon-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Treasury Department said Integrity Technology provided Flax Typhoon actors with infrastructure between the summer of 2022 and fall of 2023 — with the state-backed groups sharing and receiving information from the company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wakaruyo - Browser Extension</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wakaruyo-browser-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wakaruyo-browser-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who know me are aware of how much I love the Japanese language and how dedicated I am to self-studying it. They also know that I can never sit still. For this reason, I developed &lt;strong&gt;Wakaruyo&lt;/strong&gt;, a browser extension that is currently in the experimental phase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This extension allows you to translate selected text on a webpage from Japanese to the language set in your browser, which is automatically detected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why security teams rely on Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR for managed detection and response</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The expanding attack surface is creating more opportunities for exploitation and adding to the pressure on security leaders and teams. Increasingly, organizations are investing in managed detection and response services (MDR) to bolster their security operations center (SOC) and meet the challenge. Demand is growing rapidly: according to Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan, the market for MDR is expanding at a rate of 35.2% annually.1   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are new vendors launching MDR services regularly, many security teams are turning to Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR, a recognized leader, to deliver comprehensive coverage.1 Employed worldwide by organizations across industries, Microsoft’s team of dedicated experts proactively hunts for cyberthreats and triages, investigates, and responds to incidents on a customer’s behalf around the clock across their most critical assets. Our proven service brings together in-house security professionals and industry-leading protection with Microsoft Defender XDR to help security teams rapidly stop cyberthreats and keep their environments secure.2 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
