<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Russia&#39;s largest platform for state procurement hit by cyberattack from pro-Ukraine group&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russias-largest-platform-for-state-procurement-hit-by-cyberattack-from-pro-ukraine-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russias-largest-platform-for-state-procurement-hit-by-cyberattack-from-pro-ukraine-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent Telegram statement, Roseltorg disclosed that it had been targeted by &amp;ldquo;an external attempt to destroy data and the entire infrastructure of electronic trading.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quick post on Chen’s algorithm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(April 19):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yilei Chen announced the discovery of a bug in the algorithm, which he does not know how to fix. This was independently discovered by Hongxun Wu and Thomas Vidick. At present, the paper does not provide a polynomial-time algorithm for solving LWE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a normal person — that is, a person who doesn’t obsessively follow the latest cryptography news — you probably missed last week’s cryptography bombshell. That news comes in the form of a new e-print authored by Yilei Chen, “Quantum Algorithms for Lattice Problems“, which has roiled the cryptography research community. The result is now being evaluated by experts in lattices and quantum algorithm design (&lt;em&gt;and to be clear, I am not one!&lt;/em&gt;) but if it holds up, it’s going to be quite a bad day/week/month/year for the applied cryptography community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABLE: Optimizing Mixed Arithmetic and Boolean Garbled Circuit</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/able-optimizing-mixed-arithmetic-and-boolean-garbled-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/able-optimizing-mixed-arithmetic-and-boolean-garbled-circuit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ePrint Report: &lt;strong&gt;ABLE: Optimizing Mixed Arithmetic and Boolean Garbled Circuit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Jianqiao Cambridge Mo, Brandon Reagen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy and security have become critical priorities in many scenarios. Privacy-preserving computation (PPC) is a powerful solution that allows functions to be computed directly on encrypted data. Garbled circuit (GC) is a key PPC technology that enables secure, confidential computing. GC comes in two forms: Boolean GC supports all operations by expressing functions as logic circuits; arithmetic GC is a newer technique to efficiently compute a set of arithmetic operations like addition and multiplication. Mixed GC combines both Boolean and arithmetic GC, in an attempt to optimize performance by computing each function in its most natural form. However, this introduces additional costly conversions between the two forms. It remains unclear if and when the efficiency gains of arithmetic GC outweigh these conversion costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atlassian Named a Leader in the 2024 Gartner® Magic Quadrant™ for DevOps Platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/atlassian-named-a-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-devops-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/atlassian-named-a-leader-in-the-2024-gartner-magic-quadrant-for-devops-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Naturalist John Muir once said, “The mountains are calling, and I must go…” I could not agree more, John.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is something about the joy of tackling tough challenges. For me, that call has taken me from Kilimanjaro in Tanzania to Machu Picchu in Peru to Everest Base Camp in Nepal (I thought about Taylor Swift Eras tour tickets but alas was not brave enough). In my personal journeys, there is no greater joy than realizing the payoff from all your hard work by reaching the summit – except perhaps in being able to share your joy with others who are on the journey with you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a rule, book reviews are not a thing I usually do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when I received an out-of-the-blue email from Cory Doctorow last week asking if I would review his latest book, Red Team Blues, it took a minute to overcome my initial skepticism. While I’m a fan of Cory’s work, this is a narrow/nerdy blog about cryptography, not a place where we spend much time on literature. Moreover, my only previous attempt to review a popular cryptography novel — a quick sketch of Dan Brown’s abysmal &lt;em&gt;Digital Fortress&lt;/em&gt; — did not go very well for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BSides København – Meaningful Metrics in Information Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next BSides København will take place on 9 November 2024. There is one presentation in the schedule about the use of metrics in information security. Computers allow us to create documents, charts, and statistical values easily from any data collection we like. Therefore, the World Wide Web is full of graphs, tables with numbers, predictions, and all kinds of results. The problem is that not everything you can count is a suitable metric tied to real-life observations. Finding a metric is a science on its own. This presentation will give you some examples of how to measure meaningful attributes of computer systems and networks. You will also get to know the term metric more closely. Using proper metrics and assessing customer-provided reports will help you immensely when dealing with information security decisions. The&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Containerizing workloads on image mode for RHEL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/containerizing-workloads-on-image-mode-for-rhel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous articles, we introduced bootable containers, discussed how to debug image mode for Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), which is built upon this new technology, and explained how to create CI/CD pipelines to automate the experience. In this article, we provide a comprehensive view of how you can manage workloads on image mode systems and set up a build pipeline to automate the experience of building, deploying, and managing Linux systems at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demonstrating reduction of vulnerability classes: a key step in CISA’s “Secure by Design” pledge</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/demonstrating-reduction-of-vulnerability-classes-a-key-step-in-cisas-secure-by-design-pledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving digital landscape, securing software systems has never been more critical. Cyber threats continue to exploit systemic vulnerabilities in widely used technologies, leading to widespread damage and disruption. That said, the United States Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency (CISA) helped shape best practices for the technology industry with their Secure-by-Design pledge. Cloudflare signed this pledge on May 8, 2024, reinforcing our commitment to creating resilient systems where security is not just a feature, but a foundational principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOJ deletes China-linked PlugX malware off more than 4,200 US computers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/doj-deletes-china-linked-plugx-malware-off-more-than-4200-us-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/doj-deletes-china-linked-plugx-malware-off-more-than-4200-us-computers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;U.S law enforcement accused the People’s Republic of China of paying hackers that are part of a well-known group called Mustang Panda to deploy the PlugX malware — which allows them to “infect, control, and steal information from victim computers.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eight AI trends to prioritise in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author: Richard Farrell, CIO at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Netcall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2024 saw the adoption of &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI (GenAI)&lt;/strong&gt; accelerate, it also witnessed significant debates and challenges surrounding its use within business from security and data privacy perspectives, with questions surrounding its true value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As CIOs prepare to tackle AI in 2025, Richard Farrell, CIO of Netcall, shares the top trends that must be prioritised in the year ahead to ensure successful adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Generative AI for Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Neha Khandelwal, Software Design Assurance Engineering Manager, Zebra Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Root Cause Analysis (RCA) is a critical yet time-consuming process in the realm of software quality assurance (QA). It requires meticulous investigation to pinpoint the underlying cause of defects, often involving sifting through logs, analysing code, and correlating various system behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QA teams spend significant effort identifying the root cause, which can delay resolutions and increase downtime. As systems grow more complex, traditional RCA methods become less efficient, demanding advanced tools to assist in automating and streamlining the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historical Patterns in Enterprise Ways of Working: Key Lessons from Industrial Revolutions Past</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/historical-patterns-in-enterprise-ways-of-working-key-lessons-from-industrial-revolutions-past/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a compelling keynote address at the 2024 Enterprise Technology Leadership Summit, Jon Smart, former head of ways of working at Barclays and author of &lt;em&gt;Sooner, Safer, Happier&lt;/em&gt;, revealed surprising parallels between historical management innovations and modern enterprise challenges. Drawing from extensive research spanning nearly two centuries of industrial evolution, Smart unveiled three critical patterns that continue to shape—and challenge—organizational effectiveness today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart’s presentation, based on his analysis of over 60 historical publications dating from 1776 to 1950, highlighted how modern organizations repeatedly struggle with lessons that were first learned during previous technological revolutions. His research, part of an upcoming book on the centuries-long evolution of working methods, demonstrates that despite technological advancement, core management principles remain remarkably consistent across eras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to build your first model using DSS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-your-first-model-using-dss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-your-first-model-using-dss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GenAI is everywhere, and it’s changing how we approach technology. If you’ve ever wanted to dive into the world of large language models (LLMs) but felt intimidated, there’s good news! Hugging Face recently launched a self-paced course that’s perfect for beginners and more experienced enthusiasts alike. It’s hands-on, approachable, and designed to work on standard hardware thanks to the small footprint of the models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As soon as I heard the news, I decided to give it a go using Canonical’s Data Science Stack (DSS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to monitor, optimize, and secure Amazon Cognito machine-to-machine authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-monitor-optimize-and-secure-amazon-cognito-machine-to-machine-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-monitor-optimize-and-secure-amazon-cognito-machine-to-machine-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Cognito is a developer-centric and security-focused customer identity and access management (CIAM) service that simplifies the process of adding user sign-up, sign-in, and access control to your mobile and web applications. Cognito is a highly available service that supports a range of use cases, from managing user authentication and authorization to enabling secure access to your APIs and workloads. It’s a managed service that can act as an identity provider (IdP) for your applications, can scale to millions of users, provides advanced security features, and can support identity federation with third-party IdPs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation, Automation, And The Cybersecurity Challenges Ahead</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/innovation-automation-and-the-cybersecurity-challenges-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/innovation-automation-and-the-cybersecurity-challenges-ahead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/innovation-automation-and-the-cybersecurity-challenges-ahead.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapid evolution of artificial intelligence is transforming cybersecurity, offering unprecedented opportunities to defend against increasingly complex and automated threats. AI is no longer a support tool—it’s emerging as a central pillar of modern security strategies. From detecting anomalies and automating threat responses to augmenting security teams, AI is enabling defenders to act faster, scale their operations, and outpace attackers. However, as the technology advances, significant challenges remain, from adversarial AI to the cultural inertia of legacy systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Disk Imaging Speeds</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximizing-disk-imaging-speeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximizing-disk-imaging-speeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/sata-blocker.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the field of digital forensics, properly handling the task of disk imaging is crucial for preserving data integrity. Using write blockers ensures that no data is altered during the imaging process, a key requirement for maintaining the chain of custody. While there are many factors influencing the efficiency and speed of this process, this article offers advanced tips and considerations that can help achieve optimal performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-overview-of-write-blockers&#34;&gt;A Brief Overview of Write Blockers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To recap, write blockers are software or hardware tools designed to prevent accidental modifications to the original evidence stored on disks being imaged. In this article, we will focus solely on SATA-based hardware write blockers. This type of write blockers act as intermediaries between the forensic expert’s computer and the storage device being imaged. We’ll focus on the latest generation of write blockers features a modern 10 Gbps chip that supports USB 3.2 Gen2 connectivity, while maintaining backward compatibility with older USB versions down to USB 2.0. We will test disk imaging performance for SATA storage devices in 2.5″/3.5″ and m.2 form factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McAFuse - open source McAfee FDE decryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafuse-open-source-mcafee-fde-decryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafuse-open-source-mcafee-fde-decryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a &lt;em&gt;guest&lt;/em&gt; post, where &lt;strong&gt;Andrea Canepa&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;recently&lt;/em&gt; graduated at University of Genoa, Computer Science) will explain his &lt;strong&gt;Master Thesis&lt;/strong&gt;. The topic is &lt;em&gt;how to handle McAfee FDE acquisitions&lt;/em&gt; when doing a DFIR investigations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suppose that you&amp;rsquo;re asked to perform a forensic investigation on a laptop where McAfee FDE is used: the company will provide you the xml file (McAfee ePO) with the decrypting key. How would you proceed?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Ashton Kutcher and Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in March I was fortunate to spend several days visiting Brussels, where I had a chance to attend a panel on “chat control“: the new content scanning regime being considered by the EU Commission. Among various requirements, this proposed legislation would mandate that &lt;em&gt;client-side scanning&lt;/em&gt; technology be incorporated into encrypted text messaging applications like Signal, WhatsApp and Apple’s iMessage. The scanning tech would examine private messages for certain types of illicit content, including child sexual abuse media (known as CSAM), along with a broad category of textual conversations that constitute “grooming behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks on “Chat Control”</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remarks-on-chat-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remarks-on-chat-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On March 23 I was invited to participate in a panel discussion at the European Internet Services Providers Association (EuroISPA). The focus of this discussion was on recent legislative proposals, especially the EU Commission’s new “chat control” content scanning proposal, as well as the future of encryption and fundamental rights. These are the introductory remarks I prepared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for inviting me today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should start by making brief introduction. I am a professor of computer science and a researcher in the field of applied cryptography. On a day-to-day basis this means that I work on the design of encryption systems. Most of what I do involves building things: I design new encryption systems and try to make existing encryption technologies more useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Repairing a Real (and Broken) Apollo-era DSKY</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/repairing-a-real-and-broken-apollo-era-dsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/repairing-a-real-and-broken-apollo-era-dsky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/apollo_dsky_unit_on_desk_curiousmarc_youtube.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/apollo_dsky_unit_in_MIT_simulator.jpg?w=400&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presumably the same DSKY unit installed in the simulator at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Display/Keyboard unit – DSKY for short – is the primary way that Apollo-era astronauts communicated with the onboard computers. Not all DSKYs ended up in space, however, with the MIT hosting a simulator that features one of these units. Unfortunately the unit that ended up at [CuriousMarc]’s lab had seen better days, with the assumption being that it was the same DSKY that was installed in a photo of the old simulator. In addition to the busted EL display and two (improper) replacement keys, the insides show signs of damaged modules and possibly worse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scammers Exploit California Wildfires: How to Stay Safe</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scammers-exploit-california-wildfires-how-to-stay-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/scammers-exploit-california-wildfires-how-to-stay-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/300x200_Blog_081424-B.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The devastating wildfires sweeping through Southern California have left countless neighborhoods in ruins, forcing thousands to evacuate and destroying homes in their path. While many people across the nation are moved to support those affected, this goodwill often becomes a target for opportunistic cybercriminals. McAfee researchers have discovered that social media networks have been flooded with deceptive images, showing how cryptocurrencies can be used to make donations for fire relief efforts. We believe these to be scams trying to dupe consumers. McAfee CTO, Steve Grobman says, “It’s really unfortunate because it’s such a tragic event, and we’re seeing cybercriminals and scammers take advantage of the situation in a whole host of ways, from fake GoFundMe sites to fraudulent campaign donation pages.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some rough impressions of Worldcoin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a reader wrote in and asked if I would look at Sam Altman’s Worldcoin, presumably to give thoughts on it from a privacy perspective. This was honestly the last thing I wanted to do, since life is short and this seemed like an obvious waste of it. Of course a project &lt;em&gt;devoted to literally scanning your eyeballs&lt;/em&gt; was up to some bad things, duh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However: the request got me curious. Against my better judgement, I decided to spend a few hours poking around Worldcoin’s documentation and code — in the hope of rooting out the obvious technical red flags that would lead to the true Bond-villain explanation of the whole thing. Because surely there had to be one. I mean: eyeball scanners. Right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ripple Effect of API Breaches: Analyzing Business Consequences and Mitigation Strategies</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ripple-effect-of-api-breaches-analyzing-business-consequences-and-mitigation-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ripple-effect-of-api-breaches-analyzing-business-consequences-and-mitigation-strategies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses rely heavily on Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) for seamless communication and data exchange, the stakes have never been higher. API breaches can lead to significant vulnerabilities, affecting not only the targeted organization but also their customers and partners. Understanding the causes and consequences of these breaches is essential for any business operating in a connected world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://stateofsecurity.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Nodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nodes&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nodes.jpg&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;High-profile incidents, such as the T-Mobile and Dropbox API breaches, have demonstrated the ripple effect these security lapses can have across various industries, from financial services to healthcare and e-commerce. The repercussions can be devastating, ranging from substantial financial losses to lasting damage to an organization’s reputation. As companies navigate this complex landscape, they must recognize that an API breach is much more than just a technical issue—it can alter the course of a business’s future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trusted-relationship cyberattacks and their prevention</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trusted-relationship-cyberattacks-and-their-prevention/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to work with suppliers to reduce the risk of incidents related to supply-chain cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old saying, “A chain is only as strong as its weakest link”, directly applies to enterprise cybersecurity. Businesses these days often rely on dozens or even hundreds of suppliers and contractors, who, in turn, use the services and products of yet more contractors and suppliers. And when these chains involve not raw materials but complex IT products, ensuring their security becomes significantly more challenging. This fact is exploited by attackers, who compromise a link in the chain to reach its end — their main target. Accordingly, it’s essential for business leaders and the heads of IT and information security to understand the risks of supply-chain attacks in order to manage them effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trustless Bridges via Random Sampling Light Clients</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trustless-bridges-via-random-sampling-light-clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trustless-bridges-via-random-sampling-light-clients/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ePrint Report: &lt;strong&gt;Trustless Bridges via Random Sampling Light Clients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Bhargav Nagaraja Bhatt, Fatemeh Shirazi, Alistair Stewart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The increasing number of blockchain projects introduced annually has led to a pressing need for secure and efficient interoperability solutions. Currently, the lack of such solutions forces end-users to rely on centralized intermediaries, contradicting the core principle of decentralization and trust minimization in blockchain technology. In this paper, we propose a decentralized and efficient interoperability solution (aka Bridge Protocol) that operates without additional trust assumptions, relying solely on the Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) of the two chains being connected. In particular, relayers (actors that exchange messages between networks) are permissionless and decentralized, hence eliminating any single point of failure. We introduce Random Sampling, a novel technique for on-chain light clients to efficiently follow the history of PoS blockchains by reducing the signature verifications required. Here, the randomness is drawn on-chain, for example, using Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s RANDAO. We analyze the security of the bridge from a crypto- economic perspective and provide a framework to derive the security parameters. This includes handling subtle concurrency issues and randomness bias in strawman designs. While the protocol is applicable to various PoS chains, we demonstrate its feasibility by instantiating a bridge between Polkadot and Ethereum (currently deployed), and discuss some practical security challenges. We also evaluate the efficiency (gas costs) of an on-chain light-client verifier implemented as a smart contract on ethereum against SNARK-based approaches. Even for large validator set sizes (up to $10^6$), the signature verification gas costs of our light-client verifier are a magnitude lower.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US issues final rule barring Chinese, Russian connected car tech</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-issues-final-rule-barring-chinese-russian-connected-car-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-issues-final-rule-barring-chinese-russian-connected-car-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Commerce Department on Tuesday announced a new rule barring certain Chinese and Russian connected car technology from being imported to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why developer experience is more important than productivity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-developer-experience-is-more-important-than-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-developer-experience-is-more-important-than-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;featured in TechCrunch&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;on January 29, 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-unhealthy-obsession-with-measuring-developer-productivity&#34;&gt;The unhealthy obsession with measuring developer productivity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s an unhealthy obsession with companies looking for a way to measure developer productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The desire to measure productivity is understandable; senior leaders have been under pressure to deliver results while capitalizing on their investments in teams and technology. There are no sinister intentions behind measuring developer productivity; leaders genuinely want their teams to be as productive as possible. The problem is that developer productivity is incredibly difficult to measure, resulting in organizations allocating disproportionate effort and resources while trying to find the magic measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why MSPs must offer 24/7 cybersecurity protection and response — and how OpenText MDR can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-must-offer-24-7-cybersecurity-protection-and-response-and-how-opentext-mdr-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-must-offer-24-7-cybersecurity-protection-and-response-and-how-opentext-mdr-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s cyber threat landscape, good enough is no longer good enough. Cyberattacks don’t clock out at 5 PM, and neither can your security strategy. For Managed Service Providers (MSPs), offering customers 24/7 cybersecurity protection and response isn’t just a competitive advantage—it’s an essential service for business continuity, customer trust, and staying ahead of attackers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But delivering round-the-clock security coverage is easier said than done. It requires the right tools, expertise, and scale. This is why partnering with OpenText for offering managed detection and response (MDR) can help MSPs deliver on this critical need without overburdening their resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Your Network Traffic Analysis Spot Today’s Threats?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/will-your-network-traffic-analysis-spot-todays-threats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/will-your-network-traffic-analysis-spot-todays-threats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s network traffic analysis tools leave you vulnerable to new security threats. Is it time for an upgrade? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 New Technology Trends for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/25-new-technology-trends-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/25-new-technology-trends-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Predicting 2025.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technology today is evolving at a rapid pace, enabling faster change and progress, causing an acceleration of the rate of change. However, it is not only technology trends and emerging technologies that are evolving, a lot more has changed, making IT professionals realize that their role will not stay the same in the contactless world tomorrow. And an IT professional in 2025 will constantly be learning, unlearning, and relearning, out of necessity, if not desire!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Signs You Need a Virtual Firewall to Secure Your Cloud</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-signs-you-need-a-virtual-firewall-to-secure-your-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-signs-you-need-a-virtual-firewall-to-secure-your-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover when a virtual firewall excels plus its advantages over traditional options so you can determine if it&amp;rsquo;s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BadRAM: attack using malicious RAM module | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/badram-attack-using-malicious-ram-module-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/badram-attack-using-malicious-ram-module-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Theoretical BadRAM attack on virtualization systems exploits a vulnerability in AMD EPYC processors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers from three European universities recently demonstrated the so-called BadRAM attack. This attack is made possible because of a vulnerability in AMD EPYC processors, and primarily threatens cloud-solution providers and virtualization systems. In the worst-case scenario, the vulnerability could be used to compromise data from highly secure virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, implementing this scenario in practice would be quite difficult. The attack requires physical access to the server, plus the highest level of access to the software. Before discussing the BadRAM attack in detail, we should first understand the concept of a trusted execution environment (TEE).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Smart IVR Unlocks a Better Caller Journey</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-ivr-unlocks-a-better-caller-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-smart-ivr-unlocks-a-better-caller-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Smart IVR represents the next generation of interactive voice response systems. Learn what it can do for your customers and your bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Know if a Natural Language IVR Is Worth the Cost</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-know-if-a-natural-language-ivr-is-worth-the-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-know-if-a-natural-language-ivr-is-worth-the-cost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Natural language IVR can boost the agent and customer experience, but it comes at a cost. Here’s how to know if it&amp;rsquo;s right for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HR Leaders in APAC Are Adopting AI for Efficiency Gains</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hr-leaders-in-apac-are-adopting-ai-for-efficiency-gains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence and machine learning are seen as allies in the battle to streamline HR workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Packets: Understanding How the Internet Works (Easy)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/network-packets-understanding-how-the-internet-works-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/network-packets-understanding-how-the-internet-works-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everything you stream and share is broken into network packets. Learn how this enables the seamless flow of data that powers the internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Traffic Types (With Examples)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/network-traffic-types-with-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/network-traffic-types-with-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the key types of network traffic and their role in optimizing performance plus real-world examples to see how they impact data flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Payroll Compliance Penalties Driving Tech Adoption in Australia, Says Yellow Canary</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-payroll-compliance-penalties-driving-tech-adoption-in-australia-says-yellow-canary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new law criminalising some underpayments to Australian employees this month is causing organisations to keep a close watch on their payroll technology, according to Yellow Canary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick Glossary: Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quick-glossary-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps no innovation in information technology history has saved more money for more enterprises than virtualization, yet the technology goes mostly unheralded and underappreciated. By reducing the need for purchasing additional and ever more expensive hardware — and at the same time, maximizing the capacity of whatever hardware is available — virtualization has truly changed &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrotechtacular: The 1951 Telephone Selector</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retrotechtacular-the-1951-telephone-selector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retrotechtacular-the-1951-telephone-selector/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/bell.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Telephone systems predate the use of cheap computers and electronic switches. Yesterday’s phone system used lots of stepping relays in a box known as a “selector.” If you worked for the phone company around 1951, you might have seen the Bell System training film shown below that covers 197 selectors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The relays are not all the normal ones we think of today. There are slow release relays and vertical shafts that are held by a “dog.” The shaft moves to match the customer’s rotary dial input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding the Backbone of the Global Economy: OT/ICS Security in the Oil and Gas Industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oil and gas industry is an essential pillar of the global economy, enabling energy production, transportation, and storage that fuel every aspect of modern life. At the core of these operations lie Operational Technology (OT) and Industrial Control Systems (ICS), critical systems responsible for monitoring and controlling key industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the industry embraces digitization to improve efficiency and productivity, the reliance on OT/ICS has grown. However, this digital transformation comes at a cost—these systems have become prime targets for cyberattacks, with increasingly severe consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report: The Security and AI Landscape in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technologyadvice-industry-trend-report-the-security-and-ai-landscape-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats are getting smarter, and businesses can’t afford to fall behind. This TechnologyAdvice Industry Trend Report, sponsored by Check Point Software, explores the biggest security challenges of 2025—from the explosion of AI adoption to the critical importance of Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA). With breaches on the rise and ransomware payouts hitting record highs, organizations &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly in Cybersecurity – Week 2</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-in-cybersecurity-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-in-cybersecurity-week-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US govt launches cyber trust program, spammers use neglected domains to evade detection, and Japan accuses MirrorFace of cyber espionage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good--feds-launch-cyber-trust-program--ofac-sanctions-flax-typhoon-linked-company&#34;&gt;The Good | Feds Launch Cyber Trust Program &amp;amp; OFAC Sanctions Flax Typhoon-Linked Company&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. government took both defensive and offensive actions this week, starting with the launch of the Cyber Trust Mark and followed by sanctions on the company behind Flax Typhoon threat actors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The White House first introduced the Cyber Trust Mark as a cybersecurity label for internet-connected devices. The label allows consumers to identify safe ‘smart’ products such as TVs, appliances, baby monitors, and fitness trackers. Devices that meet NIST’s criteria, including strong default passwords, regular software updates, and data protection measures, can display the mark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hollywood Sign is Not on Fire: Deepfakes Spread During L.A. Wildfires</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-hollywood-sign-is-not-on-fire-deepfakes-spread-during-l-a-wildfires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-hollywood-sign-is-not-on-fire-deepfakes-spread-during-l-a-wildfires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/300x200_Blog_Hollywoodd-300x200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amid the devastation of the Los Angeles County wildfires – scorching an area twice the size of Manhattan – McAfee threat researchers have identified and verified a rise in AI-generated deepfakes and misinformation, including startling but false images of the Hollywood sign engulfed in flames.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;debunking-the-myth-hollywood-sign-safe-amid-wildfire-rumors-on-social-media&#34;&gt;Debunking the Myth: Hollywood Sign Safe Amid Wildfire Rumors on Social Media&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Social media and local broadcast news have been flooded with deceptive images claiming the Hollywood sign is engulfed in flames, with many people alleging that the iconic landmark is “surrounded by fire.” &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Desktop Infrastructure: Benefits and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virtual-desktop-infrastructure-benefits-and-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virtual-desktop-infrastructure-benefits-and-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the umbrella of this digital transformation and acceleration trend, one virtualization technology is becoming increasingly popular, virtual desktop infrastructure. VDI is used by enterprises to provide workers, customers and users with access to its central system and the necessary tools and resources they need. As a powerful tool, VDI can help organizations improve their &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When to Use a Mesh VPN and Four Signs You Shouldn’t</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-to-use-a-mesh-vpn-and-four-signs-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-to-use-a-mesh-vpn-and-four-signs-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A mesh VPN enables direct, flexible communication if it&amp;rsquo;s a good fit. See whether or not it’s a viable solution for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worried About VoIP Security and Encryption? We Aren’t</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/worried-about-voip-security-and-encryption-we-arent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/worried-about-voip-security-and-encryption-we-arent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you choose a top provider, maintaining VoIP security and encryption is no harder than using a strong password. Here’s how to get set up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Casio warns employees, customers about data leak from October ransomware attack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/casio-warns-employees-customers-about-data-leak-from-october-ransomware-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/casio-warns-employees-customers-about-data-leak-from-october-ransomware-attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a notice on Wednesday, Casio provided a post-mortem on an October attack, explaining that 6,456 employees, 1,931 business partners and 91 customers were impacted by the ransomware incident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivanti warns hackers are exploiting new vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ivanti-warns-hackers-are-exploiting-new-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The company released an advisory and a corresponding blog about two bugs — CVE-2025-0282 and CVE-2025-0283 — and warned that some customers have already seen CVE-2025-0282 exploited in their environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pall Mall Process to tackle commercial hacking proliferation raises more concerns than solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pall-mall-process-to-tackle-commercial-hacking-proliferation-raises-more-concerns-than-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An initiative spearheaded by France and the U.K. last year to tackle commercial spyware has experienced setbacks and significant gaps, according to participants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian internet provider confirms its network was ‘destroyed’ following attack claimed by Ukrainian hackers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/russian-internet-provider-confirms-its-network-was-destroyed-following-attack-claimed-by-ukrainian-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a statement on the Russian social media platform VKontakte, the St. Petersburg-based company said the “planned” attack “destroyed” its infrastructure overnight. Nodex added that it was working to restore systems from backups but could not provide a timeline for when operations would fully resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
