<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/azure-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/azure-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the General Availability of Managed DevOps Pools (MDP) for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-the-general-availability-of-managed-devops-pools-mdp-for-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-the-general-availability-of-managed-devops-pools-mdp-for-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Managed DevOps Pools for Azure DevOps is now generally available! This milestone marks a significant advancement in our mission to improve developer productivity in the CI/CD loop, reduce your cloud bill for ES infra and to reduce the toil associated with creating and maintaining custom CI/CD infrastructure for your pipelines. If you are new to Managed DevOps Pools, you can read about it in the Managed DevOps Pools documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the most out of Azure DevOps and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-the-most-out-of-azure-devops-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-the-most-out-of-azure-devops-and-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has two very successful DevSecOps products in the market – GitHub and Azure DevOps. Azure DevOps has a large enterprise customer base that loves the highly customizable enterprise-focused planning and tracking capabilities in Azure Boards, the robust continuous delivery capabilities in Azure Pipelines, the manual and exploratory testing capabilities in Azure Test Plans, and the deep integrations across the suite. GitHub is the world’s largest developer community, with over 100M developers. It also serves over 4M organizations, including 90% of the Fortune 100. It’s beloved by developers and at the forefront of innovation with features like GitHub Copilot, which is transforming every aspect of the software development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important: Switching CDN providers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-switching-cdn-providers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-switching-cdn-providers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The current content delivery network (CDN) provider Edgio, used by Azure DevOps is retiring. We’re urgently transitioning to a solution served by Akamai and Azure Front Door CDNs to maintain the responsiveness of our services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What this means for you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For most of you, this transition will be seamless. To ensure that you can continue to access Azure DevOps without any interruptions, use the following &lt;strong&gt;Powershell commands&lt;/strong&gt; to validate that your current firewall settings allow connectivity to the new CDN providers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Pull Request Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning in GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-pull-request-annotation-for-codeql-and-dependency-scanning-in-github-advanced-security-for-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the world of software development, security is paramount. As developers, we strive to write clean, efficient, and most importantly, secure code. GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps has always been at the forefront of providing tools that make it easier to build and release high-quality software. Today, we’re excited to announce a new feature release that will take your code security to the next level: PR (Pull Request) Annotation for CodeQL and Dependency Scanning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft DevLabs Extensions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-devlabs-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-devlabs-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft DevLabs publisher was created as a hub for internal teams at Microsoft to channel their passion for Azure DevOps into experimental extensions. These extensions helped address product gaps and fostered innovation, ultimately benefiting Azure DevOps customers via the public marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/devops/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2024/12/marketplace.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image marketplace&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge&#34;&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over time, as the original creators of these extensions moved on to other things, many extensions became outdated. This led to several problems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unresolved Issues and Questions&lt;/strong&gt;: Customer feedback and bug reports were left unaddressed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outdated Dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;: Security and dependency updates were not maintained.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Frustration&lt;/strong&gt;: The resulting decline in extension quality negatively impacted the Azure DevOps experience as a whole.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To restore the value of the Microsoft DevLabs publisher, we conducted a review to identify which extensions should be actively maintained and which needed to be deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Boards Hub Rollout Expectations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-boards-hub-rollout-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the process may seem slow, we are steadily progressing toward rolling out the New Boards Hub to all customers. Our plan is to deprecate the old Boards experience for all Azure DevOps service users by the end Q1 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rollout is advancing on two fronts. First, we are setting the New Boards Hub as the default experience. Second, for customers who already have the New Boards Hub enabled as the default, we are transitioning groups to exclusively use the New Boards Hub. Removing the option to revert to the old Boards experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No new Azure DevOps OAuth apps beginning March 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-new-azure-devops-oauth-apps-beginning-march-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-new-azure-devops-oauth-apps-beginning-march-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting March 3, 2025, we will no longer accept new registrations of Azure DevOps OAuth apps. This is the first step we’ll be taking towards our longer-term vision of sunsetting the Azure DevOps OAuth platform. Moving forward, we’ll be publicly advocating all developers that are building applications on top of Azure DevOps REST APIs to explore the Microsoft Identity platform and registering a new Entra application instead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All existing Azure DevOps OAuth apps will continue working until the official end-of-life date, which we will announce in 2025. In the interim, we offer continued support to all current Azure DevOps OAuth app developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering restrictive policies and more secure alternatives. PATs can be an enticing vector for unauthorized access, especially when insecurely stored, over-scoped, or set for long durations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-entra-profile-information-in-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-entra-profile-information-in-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the ability to use Entra profile information in Azure DevOps. This has been a long-standing feature request from the community (ex. profile, picture, email, and name). Beyond the convenience of configuring profile information in one place and ensuring the accuracy of personal information, using Entra profile information in Azure DevOps provides important security and compliance benefits for Enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today we encourage users in Entra backed organizations to turn on &lt;strong&gt;Entra Profile information&lt;/strong&gt; in Preview Features. When you do, your Azure DevOps profile will become read-only, and information will be populated from Entra instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
