<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eight AI trends to prioritise in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-ai-trends-to-prioritise-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author: Richard Farrell, CIO at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Netcall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst 2024 saw the adoption of &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI (GenAI)&lt;/strong&gt; accelerate, it also witnessed significant debates and challenges surrounding its use within business from security and data privacy perspectives, with questions surrounding its true value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As CIOs prepare to tackle AI in 2025, Richard Farrell, CIO of Netcall, shares the top trends that must be prioritised in the year ahead to ensure successful adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraction Agent and Firewall: Software vs. Hardware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/firewall_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a firewall is essential to secure the installation of the extraction agent when performing low-level extraction from a variety of iOS devices. We developed two solutions: a software-based firewall for macOS and a hardware-based firewall using a Raspberry Pi (or similar microcomputer) with our own custom firmware. This guide will help you choose the best option for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let us clarify that the solutions described in this article are neither traditional nor fully-featured firewalls. Instead, they are designed to restrict internet access to specific endpoints during a critical phase of the sideloading process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Generative AI for Root Cause Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/harnessing-generative-ai-for-root-cause-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Neha Khandelwal, Software Design Assurance Engineering Manager, Zebra Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Root Cause Analysis (RCA) is a critical yet time-consuming process in the realm of software quality assurance (QA). It requires meticulous investigation to pinpoint the underlying cause of defects, often involving sifting through logs, analysing code, and correlating various system behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QA teams spend significant effort identifying the root cause, which can delay resolutions and increase downtime. As systems grow more complex, traditional RCA methods become less efficient, demanding advanced tools to assist in automating and streamlining the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
