<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ui on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/ui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ui on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/ui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>38C3: It’s TOSLINK, Over Long Distance Fibre</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/fibre-toslink-featured.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve owned a CD player or other piece of consumer digital audio gear manufactured since the 1980s, the chances are it has a TOSLINK port on the back. This is a fairly simple interface that sends I2S digital audio data down a short length of optical fibre, and it’s designed to run between something like a CD player and an external DAC. It’s ancient technology in optical fibre terms, with a lowish data rate and plastic fibre, but consider for a minute whether it could be adapted for modern ultra-high-speed conenctions. It’s what [Ben Cartwright-Cox] has done, and he delivered a talk about it at the recent 38C3 event in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add Onvite to Rails 8 Authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/add-onvite-to-rails-8-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/add-onvite-to-rails-8-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article was originally published on Rails Designer Build a SaaS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the third article on Building a SaaS with Ruby on Rails. This article continues where the previous one, adding sign up to Rails 8&amp;rsquo; authentication, stops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most SaaS products are used by multiple people from the same team or company. Although I would, when you start building your SaaS, urge you to keep it simple and just support one user on launch. I would álso urge you to build the blocks needed for teams in your app from the get-go. Having to deal with workspaces, teams and roles when you already have users is a bigger pain than you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check out this post on one of the non-functional requirements for your applications - Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-this-post-on-one-of-the-non-functional-requirements-for-your-applications-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-this-post-on-one-of-the-non-functional-requirements-for-your-applications-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Forganization%2Fprofile_image%2F2794%2F88da75b6-aadd-4ea1-8083-ae2dfca8be94.png&#34; alt=&#34;AWS Community Builders &#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F1037830%2F5768f8f1-81ca-4d33-bcd1-0d9312b2451c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-functional-application-requirements-security&#34;&gt;Non-functional Application Requirements: Security&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oluwasegun-adedigba-for-aws-community-builders--jan-7&#34;&gt;Oluwasegun Adedigba for AWS Community Builders ・ Jan 7&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#aws #security #discuss #softwaredevelopment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud economics vs. Cloud FinOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-economics-vs-cloud-finops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-economics-vs-cloud-finops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La gestión de costos en los últimos años, se ha priorizado para que la migración o implementación de los servicios nube mantengan un enfoque de optimización, que favorezca el valor de negocio de las compañías, es decir, una operación computacional guiada por principios de optimización financiera&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cloud economics se encarga de estudiar el costo-beneficio del uso de los recursos en las plataformas de nube.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sus principios fundamentales, son dos, el primero respecta la implicación de las economías de escala, que representan un ahorro para las empresas al adquirir recursos de nube en grandes cantidades sin la inversión de una propia infraestructura física, como centros de datos de gran capacidad, lo que representa una disminución en las cifras de CAPEX de las empresas -es decir la inversión de capital- (ORACLE, 2024)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Y el segundo; alcance global, que es una característica clave de la computación en la nube, pues es posible acceder a recursos desde cualquier parte del mundo, gracias a las regiones de centros de datos de los diferentes proveedores de nube, que existen actualmente. Esto implica un ahorro para las compañías, pues no es necesario incurrir en costos de mano de obra en cada zona para desplegar infraestructura, y ofertar servicios.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Por su lado, Cloud FinOps, es una disciplina de gestión financiera que permite una mayor comprensión de los gastos en la nube, para la mejor toma de decisiones de optimización de costos y recursos, su objetivo fundamental no es el ahorro económico, por sí sólo, sino la optimización, logrando que todos los recursos se aprovechen conforme a los cambios en la demanda, y el ahorro pueda reinvertirse en otros proyectos o recursos, como la innovación y la mejora tecnológica continua (TIVIT, 2023)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Para este punto, podría parecer que ambas disciplinas se dedican a lo mismo, sin embargo, quisiera ahondar en la comprensión de la diferencia mientras evaluamos dos conceptualizaciones clave que tiene un caso similar, es decir, Dev y DevOps.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Dev se centra en la creación de software con tareas como escribir código, diseñar arquitecturas, probar nuevas funcionalidades y corregir errores. Su objetivo fundamental es la creación de software funcional, eficiente y acorde con las necesidades del usuario (IBM, 2024). Mientras que DevOps es una metodología enfocada en la integración y la colaboración entre los equipos de desarrollo y operaciones de IT con el objetivo de mejorar la eficiencia en la entrega del software -Una gran diferencia si me lo preguntan a mí-, sin embargo, para lograr estos objetivos Dev y DevOps trabajan juntos ya que la colaboración entre ambos es fundamental para lograr un ciclo de vida de desarrollo de software más eficiente, rápido y de calidad.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Algo muy similar ocurre con Cloud Economics y Finops&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Esta última mantiene un enfoque operativo. Se centra en las mejores prácticas para gestionar y optimizar los costos en la nube, para lograrlo, los equipos de FinOps desarrollan una cultura con las áreas de desarrollo, operaciones y finanzas para equilibrar costos&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Por su lado Cloud Economics, tiene una perspectiva más estratégica y de largo plazo. Analiza la economía detrás de la adopción de la nube, incluyendo el análisis de costo-beneficio, y el cálculo del retorno de inversión conocido como -ROI-, así como los cambios en el gasto en nube a lo largo del tiempo (BBVA, 2024).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Haciendo un simil con los dos primeros conceptos presentados, cloud economics es muy similar a Dev, su objetivo es medir la economía detrás de la nube, mientras que FinOps es una cultura o conjunto de buenas prácticas como devops que busca alcanzar la optimización de costos&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the scope of IAM Access Analyzer unused access analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management Access Analyzer simplifies inspecting unused access to guide you towards least privilege. You can use unused access findings to identify over-permissive access granted to AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles and users in your accounts or organization. From a delegated administrator account for IAM Access Analyzer, you can use the dashboard to review unused access findings across your organization and prioritize the accounts to inspect based on the volume and type of findings. The findings highlight unused roles, unused access keys for IAM users, and unused passwords for IAM users. For active IAM users and roles, the findings provide visibility into unused services and actions. Recently, IAM Access Analyzer launched new configuration capabilities that you can use to customize the analysis. You can select accounts, roles, and users to exclude, and focus on the areas that matter the most to you. You can use identifiers such as account ID or scale configuration using tags. By scoping the IAM Access Analyzer to monitor a subset of accounts and roles, you can reduce noise from unwanted findings. You can update the configuration when needed to change the scope of analysis. With this new offering, IAM Access Analyzer provides enhanced controls to help you tailor the analysis more closely to your organization’s security needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-55656 - Redis RedisBloom Probabilistic Data Structures Integer Overflow Information Leak Out-of-Bounds Write</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-55656&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 4:15 p.m. | 5 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; RedisBloom adds a set of probabilistic data structures to Redis. There is an integer overflow vulnerability in RedisBloom, which is a module used in Redis. The integer overflow vulnerability allows an attacker (a redis client which knows the password) to allocate memory in the heap lesser than the required memory due to wraparound. Then read and write can be performed beyond this allocated memory, leading to info leak and OOB write. The integer overflow is in CMS.INITBYDIM command, which initialize a Count-Min Sketch to dimensions specified by user. It accepts two values (width and depth) and uses them to allocate memory in NewCMSketch(). This vulnerability is fixed in 2.2.19, 2.4.12, 2.6.14, and 2.8.2.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22145 - Carbon PHP DateTime Remote File Include Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22145&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Carbon is an international PHP extension for DateTime. Application passing unsanitized user input to Carbon::setLocale are at risk of arbitrary file include, if the application allows users to upload files with .php extension in an folder that allows include or require to read it, then they are at risk of arbitrary code ran on their servers. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.8.4 and 2.72.6.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading the same file 102&#43; times</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have YOU ever tried downloading the same file 102+ times in your favorite browser? Do you know what happens on the 102nd time? 🙃&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do. The answer is &amp;hellip; it depends 😋 It varies between browsers and it’s a bit of a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I show you the screenshots, let me first tell you a short story about how I ended up in the &lt;em&gt;“lets-download-this-file-102-times”&lt;/em&gt; rabbit hole so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Things First | SentinelOne Is A Fortune Best Workplace for Parents</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents, ranking among the top 70 companies worldwide for working parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wellbeing comes first at SentinelOne – for our customers, our communities, and our colleagues. We are proud to foster a culture of diversity, equality, and understanding for all. Supporting our working parents and the notion of a family’s evolving needs is a key part of that philosophy, and that is why we are extremely proud to be included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is your organization ready for the future? Why skills matter</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-your-organization-ready-for-the-future-why-skills-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-your-organization-ready-for-the-future-why-skills-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The drive toward AI-enabled transformation is causing organizations to focus on upskilling, reskilling and reconnecting their IT teams. Recent data from IDC1 shows that 58% of CEOs are concerned about whether their organization’s skill sets can meet the demands of AI initiatives. This IDC report reinforces the need to invest in building an organization with the skills that will support productivity, efficiency and competitiveness.Organizations across all industries and regions are facing a growing shortage of IT skills, whether in security, cloud, IT service management or AI. Fast-changing t&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remotely Controlled Vehicles Over Starlink</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/starboat_feat.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern remote control (RC) radios are capable of incredible range, but they’re still only made for line-of-sight use. What if you want to control a vehicle that’s 100s of kilometers away, or even on the other side of the planet? Cellular is an option, but is obviously limited by available infrastructure — good luck getting a cell signal in the middle of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what if you could beam your commands down from space? That’s what [Thingify] was looking to test when they put together an experimental RC boat using a Starlink Mini for communications. Physically, there was no question it would work on the boat. After all, it was small, light, and power-efficient enough. But would the network connection be up to the task of controlling the vehicle in real-time?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During early ground testing, the Mini version of the Starlink receiver worked very well. Despite being roughly 1/4 the size of its predecessor, the smaller unit met or exceeded its performance during benchmarks on bandwidth, latency, and signal strength. As expected, it also drew far less power: the Mini’s power consumption peaked at around 33 watts, compared to the monstrous 180 W for the larger receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the water, there was even more good news. The bandwidth was more than enough to run a high-resolution video feedback to the command center. Most of the time the boat was moving autonomously between waypoints, but when [Thingify] switched over to manual control, the latency was low enough that maneuvering wasn’t a problem. We wouldn’t recommend manually piloting a high-speed aircraft over Starlink, but for a boat that’s cruising along at 4 km/h, the lag didn’t even come into play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside? Starlink is a fairly expensive proposition; you’d need to have a pretty specific mission in mind to justify the cost. The Mini receiver currently costs $599 USD (though it occasionally goes on sale), and you’ll need at least a $50 per month plan to go with it. While this puts it out of the price range for recreational RC, [Thingify] notes that it’s not a bad deal if you’re looking to explore uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Dual Compilation (SSR &#43; CSR) in ViteJS with vite-plugin-builder</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/setting-up-dual-compilation-ssr-csr-in-vitejs-with-vite-plugin-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/setting-up-dual-compilation-ssr-csr-in-vitejs-with-vite-plugin-builder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;using&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using &lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt; to Set Up an SSR and CSR Project in Vite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I will show you how to create a project from scratch with &lt;strong&gt;Vite&lt;/strong&gt;, configure it to build both &lt;strong&gt;Server-Side Rendering (SSR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Client-Side Rendering (CSR)&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; plugin, which simplifies the whole process with a single command.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;vite-plugin-builder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a plugin for &lt;strong&gt;Vite&lt;/strong&gt; that simplifies the setup and compilation of applications requiring both &lt;strong&gt;SSR&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CSR&lt;/strong&gt; in a single project (dual build). With it, you can easily manage both server and client entry points, which is ideal for modern applications that need to process content both on the server and on the client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech In Plain Sight: Security Envelopes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tech-in-plain-sight-security-envelopes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/letterlocking-mary-queen-of-scots-last-letter-a-spiral-lock-england-1587-uh0135-dzpe1mcgxxo-mkv-shot0002_featured.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You probably get a few of these things each week in the mail. And some of them actually do a good job of obscuring the contents inside, even if you hold the envelope up to the light. But have you ever taken the time to appreciate the beauty of security envelope patterns? Yeah, I didn’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The really interesting thing is just how many different patterns are out there when a dozen or so would probably cover it. But there are so, so many patterns in the world. In my experience, many utilities and higher-end companies create their own security patterns for mailing out statements and the like, so that right there adds up to some unknown abundance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Engineering: Hack Week 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Canonical, the work of our teams is strongly embedded in the open source principles and philosophy. We believe open source software will become the most prevalent method of software development and delivery in the future. Being open source is more than making the source of your software available, it’s also about contributing to other open source projects and helping to build communities. With this in mind, the web engineering team recently had the privilege of dedicating a week solely to contribute to external open source projects. We do this every year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
