<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Costa Rica refinery cyberattack was first deployment for new US response program, ambassador says</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/costa-rica-refinery-cyberattack-was-first-deployment-for-new-us-response-program-ambassador-says/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/costa-rica-refinery-cyberattack-was-first-deployment-for-new-us-response-program-ambassador-says/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent ransomware attack on RECOPE, Costa Rica&amp;rsquo;s state-run energy company, was the first real-world test for FALCON, a new State Department program for foreign incident response, a top diplomat tells Recorded Future News.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace completes 2024 FedRAMP Moderate reauthorization with Rev.5 transition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0162_1_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;FedRAMP&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-fedramp-moderate-and-transition-to-rev5&#34;&gt;Understanding FedRAMP Moderate and transition to Rev.5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP (Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program) is a government program that provides a standardized approach to security assessment, authorization, and continuous monitoring for cloud products and services for U.S. state and federal agencies. The FedRAMP Moderate baseline is designed to protect sensitive data that, if compromised, could seriously adversely affect operations, assets, or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP Revision 5 (Rev.5) prioritizes customizing security controls for specific risks. It aligns with Cloud Service Providers, providing a baseline while allowing tailored adjustments for individual federal agencies. FedRAMP adopts a threat-based approach to security controls. Rather than a one-size-fits-all model, this methodology tailors controls based on specific threats and risks. The result is a more effective security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT launches new data privacy-focused initiative</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategic use of data is vital for progress in science, commerce, and even politics, but at the same time, citizens are demanding more responsible, respectful use of personal data. Internet users have never felt more helpless about how their data are being used: Surveys show that the vast majority of U.S. adults feel that they have little to no control over the data that the government and private companies collect about them. In response to these concerns, new privacy laws are being enacted in Europe, California, Virginia, and elsewhere around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The “last mile” from credentials to employment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-last-mile-from-credentials-to-employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academic digital credentials — the cryptographically verifiable assertion that an individual holds a degree, certificate, or other credential — have been available for the better part of a decade. Yet despite the potential value of these data-rich, transportable credentials to graduates, employers, and academic institutions, digital credentials have by no means become the standard in presenting or verifying skills and qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new report from the Digital Credentials Consortium (DCC), housed at MIT Open Learning, explores this gap between the promise of digital credentials and their widespread adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP High authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP Moderate authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
