<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Securitystudiesandmilitary on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/securitystudiesandmilitary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Securitystudiesandmilitary on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/securitystudiesandmilitary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3 Questions: Areg Danagoulian on a new arms control tool and the future of nuclear security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-questions-areg-danagoulian-on-a-new-arms-control-tool-and-the-future-of-nuclear-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Areg Danagoulian, associate professor in the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering, has built a career around nuclear detection technology. His work has focused, among other things, on a system that could greatly improve the current process for verifying compliance of nuclear warheads.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlier this year, he published new work on physical cryptographic nuclear warhead verification and on active detection of shielded nuclear materials in journals including&lt;/em&gt; Nature Communications &lt;em&gt;and the&lt;/em&gt; Proceedings of the National Academy of Science. &lt;em&gt;He has also received a pair of prestigious accolades: a radiation science and technology award from the American Nuclear Society and the honor of being named, along with his team, as the 2019 Arms Control Association (ACA) Arms Control Persons of the Year.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;“This innovation paves the way for more effective arms control agreements, inspections, and enforcement,&amp;quot; said Daryl Kimball, executive director of the ACA. &amp;ldquo;Professor Danagoulian’s MIT team has brought the best science to arms control and provided a creative solution that can reduce nuclear threats and enhance security.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portable technology offers boost for nuclear security, arms control</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/portable-technology-offers-boost-for-nuclear-security-arms-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/portable-technology-offers-boost-for-nuclear-security-arms-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About five years ago, Areg Danagoulian, associate professor in the MIT Department of Nuclear Science and Engineering (NSE), became intrigued by a technique developed by researchers at Los Alamos National Laboratory that uses a neutron beam to identify unknown materials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“They could look into a black box containing uranium and say what kind and how much,” says Danagoulian, who directs MIT’s Laboratory of Applied Nuclear Physics (LANPh). “I was thinking about the problem of verifying nuclear material in warheads, and it just dawned on me, this amazing technology could be applied to what we’re working on.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working toward a more secure world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/working-toward-a-more-secure-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/working-toward-a-more-secure-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well before arriving on campus, Peninah (Nina) Levine knew what she wanted from her undergraduate education:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I came to MIT to be in an environment that would push me beyond my comfortable limits,” says Levine, a senior majoring in nuclear science and engineering (NSE). “I had to find where my passions lay and forge my own path.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, Levine is well along that path, engaged in a five-year combined undergraduate and master’s program and helping develop technologies for characterizing nuclear material — tools to aid in nuclear weapons verification or to prevent illicit trafficking of nuclear material. Her research is based in the Laboratory for Applied Nuclear Physics, directed by Associate Professor Areg Danagoulian.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
