<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial-Intelligence on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial-Intelligence on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Eight Lincoln Laboratory technologies named 2020 R&amp;D 100 Award winners&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight technologies developed by MIT Lincoln Laboratory researchers, either wholly or in collaboration with researchers from other organizations, were among the winners of the 2020 R&amp;amp;D 100 Awards. Annually since 1963, these international R&amp;amp;D awards recognize 100 technologies that a panel of expert judges selects as the most revolutionary of the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six of the laboratory’s winning technologies are software systems, a number of which take advantage of artificial intelligence techniques. The software technologies are solutions to difficulties inherent in analyzing large volumes of data and to problems in maintaining cybersecurity. Another technology is a process designed to assure secure fabrication of integrated circuits, and the eighth winner is an optical communications technology that may enable future space missions to transmit error-free data to Earth at significantly higher rates than currently possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT launches new data privacy-focused initiative</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategic use of data is vital for progress in science, commerce, and even politics, but at the same time, citizens are demanding more responsible, respectful use of personal data. Internet users have never felt more helpless about how their data are being used: Surveys show that the vast majority of U.S. adults feel that they have little to no control over the data that the government and private companies collect about them. In response to these concerns, new privacy laws are being enacted in Europe, California, Virginia, and elsewhere around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School of Engineering welcomes new faculty</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The School of Engineering welcomes 15 new faculty members across six of its academic departments. This new cohort of faculty members, who have either recently started their roles at MIT or will start within the next year, conduct research across a diverse range of disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of these new faculty specialize in research that intersects with multiple fields. In addition to positions in the School of Engineering, a number of these faculty have positions at other units across MIT. Faculty with appointments in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) report into both the School of Engineering and the MIT Stephen A. Schwarzman College of Computing. This year, new faculty also have joint appointments between the School of Engineering and the School of Humanities, Arts, and Social Sciences and the School of Science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Noonification: We’ve Been Here Before: The Impacts of Today’s Age of AI (4/26/2024)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-noonification-weve-been-here-before-the-impacts-of-todays-age-of-ai-4-26-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-noonification-weve-been-here-before-the-impacts-of-todays-age-of-ai-4-26-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;4/26/2024: Top 5 stories on the HackerNoon homepage!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read All&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4/26/2024: Top 5 stories on the HackerNoon homepage!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read All&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
