<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browser on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/browser/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browser on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/browser/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Check out my latest post, especially if you&#39;re a fan of Japanese culture or if you&#39;re studying it!&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-my-latest-post-especially-if-youre-a-fan-of-japanese-culture-or-if-youre-studying-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-my-latest-post-especially-if-youre-a-fan-of-japanese-culture-or-if-youre-studying-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F1253234%2F39957cd3-32a4-4a71-9837-724db3e804bc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;matteosant_dev&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wakaruyo---browser-extension&#34;&gt;Wakaruyo - Browser Extension&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;matteo-santoro-dev--jan-8&#34;&gt;Matteo Santoro Dev ・ Jan 8&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#webdev #javascript #browser #programming&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Midori Browser 11.5 Added Headless Mode &amp; New App Icon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/midori-browser-11-5-added-headless-mode-new-app-icon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://ubuntuhandbook.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/midora-newicon-250x250.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori web browser announced new 11.5 release recently with some exciting new features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Midori was a popular lightweight web browser that was default in elementary OS and Bodhi Linux. It’s now a free open-source Firefox derived browser developed by Astian Foundation, and licensed under the Mozilla Public License (MPL).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The browser released new 11.5 recently, changed its app icon from a green lizard to &lt;strong&gt;new flat design logo&lt;/strong&gt; that IMO feels better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ZDI Threat Hunting 2024: Highlights, Trends, &amp; Challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on 2024, it has been an eventful year for the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team. Throughout the year, we identified numerous threat actor campaigns exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities, uncovered additional variants of these vulnerabilities, and discovered even more vulnerabilities through our in-the-wild research. In this blog, we will highlight some of the key achievements of the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team, as well as discuss important in-the-wild vulnerability trends and industry challenges we encountered in 2024 which will continue into 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk | Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file &lt;code&gt;zshenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, researchers detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s discovery in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also reported on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to connect the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chrome Update Addresses High-Severity Vulnerability: CVE-2025-0291</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chrome-update-addresses-high-severity-vulnerability-cve-2025-0291/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chrome-update-addresses-high-severity-vulnerability-cve-2025-0291/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;chrome-update-addresses-high-severity-vulnerability-cve-2025-0291&#34;&gt;Chrome Update Addresses High-Severity Vulnerability: CVE-2025-0291&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/22826/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google has just released a critical security update for its Chrome web browser, addressing a high-severity vulnerability that could leave users open to attack. The update, rolling out to Windows, Mac, &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (8 hours, 12 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22132 - WeGIA Charitable Institutions XSS File Upload Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22132-wegia-charitable-institutions-xss-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22132-wegia-charitable-institutions-xss-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22132&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 7, 2025, 10:15 p.m. | 11 hours, 35 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) vulnerability was identified in the file upload functionality of the WeGIA/html/socio/sistema/controller/controla_xlsx.php endpoint. By uploading a file containing malicious JavaScript code, an attacker can execute arbitrary scripts in the context of a victim&amp;rsquo;s browser. This can lead to information theft, session hijacking, and other forms of client-side exploitation. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.7.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberVolk | A Deep Dive into the Hacktivists, Tools and Ransomware Fueling Pro-Russian Cyber Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A loose collective of mostly low-skilled actors, CyberVolk absorbs and adapts a wide array of destructive malware for use against political targets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CyberVolk/GLORIAMIST is a hacktivist collective originating in India with pro-Russia leanings. Between June and October 2024, CyberVolk claimed responsibility for multiple ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The main objective of CyberVolk and related groups is to leverage geopolitical issues to launch and justify attacks on public and government entities, primarily in the service of Russian government interests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a shared codebase used by CyberVolk, AzzaSec and DoubleFace’s ransomware. Additionally, CyberVolk has promoted other ransomware families like HexaLocker and Parano. These groups and the tools they leverage are all closely intertwined.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These hacktivist groups are extremely dynamic and volatile. In-fighting, threats, and inflated political-posturing are common, leading to fragmentation and the rapid re-shaping of the hacktivist threat landscape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CyberVolk is a politically motivated hacktivist collective which launched its own RaaS in June 2024. The group uses both DDoS and ransomware attacks in its efforts to undermine and disrupt the operations of those opposed to Russian interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downloading the same file 102&#43; times</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/downloading-the-same-file-102-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have YOU ever tried downloading the same file 102+ times in your favorite browser? Do you know what happens on the 102nd time? 🙃&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do. The answer is &amp;hellip; it depends 😋 It varies between browsers and it’s a bit of a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I show you the screenshots, let me first tell you a short story about how I ended up in the &lt;em&gt;“lets-download-this-file-102-times”&lt;/em&gt; rabbit hole so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laravel IQ - Level 1 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ১&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Laravel কীভাবে MVC আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Laravel &lt;strong&gt;MVC&lt;/strong&gt; (Model-View-Controller) আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model:&lt;/strong&gt; ডাটাবেসের সঙ্গে কাজ করার জন্য ব্যবহৃত হয়। এটি ডাটাবেস কোয়েরি ও ডাটাবেস সম্পর্কিত লজিক পরিচালনা করে।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View:&lt;/strong&gt; ব্যবহারকারীর জন্য UI বা প্রেজেন্টেশন লেয়ার তৈরি করে। Blade টেমপ্লেট ইঞ্জিন ব্যবহার করে HTML পেজ তৈরি করা হয়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; এটি Model এবং View এর মধ্যে যোগাযোগ করায়। Controller ডাটাবেস থেকে ডেটা নিয়ে View-তে পাঠায়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ২&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Routing কী? Laravel-এ Route এবং Controller এর মধ্যে সম্পর্ক ব্যাখ্যা কর।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Routing ব্যবহার করে Laravel অ্যাপ্লিকেশনে &lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt; এবং এর সাথে সংযুক্ত ক্রিয়াকলাপ সংজ্ঞায়িত করা হয়।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Digital Eye | Chinese APT Compromises Critical Digital Infrastructure via Visual Studio Code Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure to target large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From late June to mid-July 2024, a suspected China-nexus threat actor targeted large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe, an activity cluster that we dubbed ‘Operation Digital Eye’.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The intrusions could have enabled the adversaries to establish strategic footholds and compromise downstream entities. SentinelLabs and Tinexta Cyber detected and interrupted the activities in their initial phases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors used a lateral movement capability indicative of the presence of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster maintaining and provisioning tooling within the Chinese APT ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure for C2 purposes, attempting to evade detection by making malicious activities appear legitimate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our visibility suggests that the abuse of Visual Studio Code for C2 purposes had been relatively rare in the wild prior to this campaign. Operation Digital Eye marks the first instance of a suspected Chinese APT group using this technique that we have directly observed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tinexta Cyber and SentinelLabs have been tracking threat activities targeting business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe. Based on the malware, infrastructure, techniques used, victimology, and the timing of the activities, we assess that it is highly likely these attacks were conducted by a China-nexus threat actor with cyberespionage motivations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Web-Based Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally published on Security Boulevard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-people-web-browsers-and-security&#34;&gt;Connecting People, Web Browsers and Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web browser has transformed significantly in recent years, becoming one of the most used tools for work today. However, as organizations adopt hybrid work models and cloud-based operations, securing this work tool has proved a challenge. Security infrastructures haven’t evolved as fast as the browser, making them prone to cyberattacks. With browsers being the primary gateway to the internet, any security lapse can lead to broad opportunities for significant data breaches and operational disruptions. Understanding the risks and implementing robust security measures is crucial for safeguarding the work we do today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SocGholish: Fake update puts visitors at risk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/socgholish-fake-update-puts-visitors-at-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/socgholish-fake-update-puts-visitors-at-risk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The SocGholish downloader has been a favourite of several cybercrime groups since 2017. It delivers a payload that poses as a browser update. As any piece of malware, it undergoes an evolutionary process. We have taken a look at the latest developments, which targets Wordpress based websites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://feeds.feedblitz.com/~/i/901680059/0/gdatasecurityblog-en&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.gdatasoftware.com/fileadmin/_processed_/4/2/G_DATA_Blog_SocGholish_Preview_0819d13e00.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fbshare20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/fblike20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/x.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/email20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://assets.feedblitz.com/i/rss20.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Cyber Trust Mark logo for smart devices is coming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White House announced the launch of the US Cyber Trust Mark which aims to help buyers make an informed choice about the purchase of wireless internet-connected devices, such as baby monitors, doorbells, thermostats, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity labeling program for wireless consumer Internet of Things (IoT) products is voluntary but the participants include several major manufacturers, retailers, and trade associations for popular electronics, appliances, and consumer products. The companies and groups said they are committed to increase cybersecurity for the products they sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
