<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Breach on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-breach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Breach on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-breach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 steps to safeguarding your privacy online</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more devices, digital apps and online accounts you use, the more efficient and convenient your life becomes. But all that ease of use comes with a price. Your devices are constantly collecting your personal data to fine-tune your user experience. At the same time, hackers, and other cyber criminals are working round the clock to steal this sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of your digital identity as a confidential file full of high-value information – passwords, credit card numbers, bank account details, social security numbers and more. If you’re not taking the proper steps to guard your online privacy, you could end up handing over the files to a vast army of cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Breach Versus Data Leak: What’s The Difference?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-breach-versus-data-leak-whats-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-breach-versus-data-leak-whats-the-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some terminology in the cybersecurity world can be slightly confusing. One example is the difference between two similar terms: data leak and data breach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People sometimes use these terms interchangeably to describe situations where sensitive data is exposed. However, the difference between a data leak and a data breach is concrete in some ways. Knowing the difference between them helps organizations defend against either type of loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-difference-between-a-data-leak-and-data-breach&#34;&gt;What is the Difference Between a Data Leak and Data Breach?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A data breach refers to unauthorized access or acquisition by an external party, often resulting from a cyberattack or security breach. A data leak is the accidental release or exposure of sensitive information due to internal errors or negligence. While a data breach is intentional, a data leak is typically accidental and can arise from various sources, such as misconfigured databases or human error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
