<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edge on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/edge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edge on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/edge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A first look at iOS 18 forensics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-first-look-at-ios-18-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-first-look-at-ios-18-forensics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This has been a tough year for me: my mom passed away in June, and I&amp;rsquo;m still slowly recovering from the hard blow. It&amp;rsquo;s time to start again doing what I love: researching and sharing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s early September and like every year, that moment is approaching when everyone who deals with mobile forensics starts to tremble at the thought of the arrival of a new version of iOS!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First the good news: the basic and traditional techniques for logical acquisition (or Advanced Logical, if you want to call it that) still work on iOS 18!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a rule, book reviews are not a thing I usually do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when I received an out-of-the-blue email from Cory Doctorow last week asking if I would review his latest book, Red Team Blues, it took a minute to overcome my initial skepticism. While I’m a fan of Cory’s work, this is a narrow/nerdy blog about cryptography, not a place where we spend much time on literature. Moreover, my only previous attempt to review a popular cryptography novel — a quick sketch of Dan Brown’s abysmal &lt;em&gt;Digital Fortress&lt;/em&gt; — did not go very well for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSec 2024 Keynote – The Mind Bomb</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepsec-2024-keynote-the-mind-bomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepsec-2024-keynote-the-mind-bomb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DeepSec 2024 ended on 22 November 2024. We took a week off to post-process the event in terms of video material and dialogues. Usually only participants get first access to the video recordings, but because of the threat of disinformation from nation states, we published the keynote early and freely. Randahl Fink explained his take on manipulation of elections and entire societies. Russia, among others, is very proficient in creating election results that keep on surprising politicians and analysts alike. The Mind Bomb is real, and it is about to explode in Western democracies. You can watch the video online on Randahl’s YouTube channel, his Patreon site, or on our Vimeo account. Presenters at conferences are storytellers. They make topics come alive, create links between seemingly unrelated aspects, teach new knowledge, and hopefully make&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraction Agent and Firewall: Software vs. Hardware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/extraction-agent-and-firewall-software-vs-hardware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/firewall_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a firewall is essential to secure the installation of the extraction agent when performing low-level extraction from a variety of iOS devices. We developed two solutions: a software-based firewall for macOS and a hardware-based firewall using a Raspberry Pi (or similar microcomputer) with our own custom firmware. This guide will help you choose the best option for your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we go any further, let us clarify that the solutions described in this article are neither traditional nor fully-featured firewalls. Instead, they are designed to restrict internet access to specific endpoints during a critical phase of the sideloading process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS Forensics: tool validation based on a known dataset - Preamble</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-forensics-tool-validation-based-on-a-known-dataset-preamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-forensics-tool-validation-based-on-a-known-dataset-preamble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello world, it’s been a while since my last series of blog posts! But now I am ready to share with you the results of my recent research.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I face many different challenges in my daily work as a digital forensics analyst, who deals mainly with mobile devices. &lt;strong&gt;All modern smartphones are encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; (usually with file-based encryption (FBE)), so obtaining or cracking the passcode is required to gain access to all the data stored on the device. And even if we know the passcode (or the user has not set the passcode, which is increasingly rare these days), we still need an exploit to gain “root” access to the device to read and copy all the data and get our “best acquisition”, usually a full file system (FFS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Ashton Kutcher and Secure Multi-Party Computation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/on-ashton-kutcher-and-secure-multi-party-computation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in March I was fortunate to spend several days visiting Brussels, where I had a chance to attend a panel on “chat control“: the new content scanning regime being considered by the EU Commission. Among various requirements, this proposed legislation would mandate that &lt;em&gt;client-side scanning&lt;/em&gt; technology be incorporated into encrypted text messaging applications like Signal, WhatsApp and Apple’s iMessage. The scanning tech would examine private messages for certain types of illicit content, including child sexual abuse media (known as CSAM), along with a broad category of textual conversations that constitute “grooming behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRFs, PRPs and other fantastic things</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/prfs-prps-and-other-fantastic-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/prfs-prps-and-other-fantastic-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I ran into a conversation on Twitter about the weaknesses of applied cryptography textbooks, and how they tend to spend way too much time lecturing people about Feistel networks and the boring details of AES. Some of the folks in this conversation suggested that instead of these things, we should be digging into more fundamental topics like “what is a pseudorandom function.” (I’d link to the thread itself, but today’s Twitter is basically a forgetting machine.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sysdiagnose in iOS 16: a first look from a Digital Forensics perspective</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sysdiagnose-in-ios-16-a-first-look-from-a-digital-forensics-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sysdiagnose-in-ios-16-a-first-look-from-a-digital-forensics-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in May 2019, along with my colleagues Heather Mahalik and Adrian Leong, we wrote the paper &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Using Apple “Bug Reporting” for forensic purposes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; and some scripts to parse data stored in Sysdiagnose logs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The paper is still available for download and, for the most part, is still accurate. But time goes on, and new iOS versions have come on the market in recent years. I took a first look at a sysdiagnose generated on a freshly wiped iPhone with iOS 16 natively installed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Schnorr and beyond (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post continues a long, wonky discussion of Schnorr signature schemes and the Dilithium post-quantum signature. You may want to start with Part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous post I discussed the intuition behind Schnorr signatures, beginning with a high-level design rationale and ending with a concrete instantiation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a reminder: our discussion began with this Tweet by Chris Peikert:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/schnorrpeikert.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which we eventually developed into an abstract version of the Schnorr protocol that uses Chris’s “magic boxes” to realize part of its functionality:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Sockets: From Registered I/O to SYSTEM Privileges</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/windows-sockets-from-registered-i-o-to-system-privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/windows-sockets-from-registered-i-o-to-system-privileges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Luca Ginex&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post discusses CVE-2024-38193, a use-after-free vulnerability in the afd.sys Windows driver. Specifically, the vulnerability is in the Registered I/O extension for Windows sockets. The vulnerability was patched in the August 2024 Patch Tuesday. This post describes the exploitation process for the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we give a general overview of the registered I/O extension for Winsock, describing the driver’s internal structures. We then analyze the vulnerability and proceed to detailing the exploitation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;5 Best Linux CentOS Replacement Options &amp; Alternatives&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-linux-centos-replacement-options-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-best-linux-centos-replacement-options-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s decision to end CentOS is forcing most developers and companies to find an alternative OS. In this guide, learn about the top competitors&amp;rsquo; features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK government invests £40 million in 5G</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find out the possible benefits and challenges of the U.K. government’s 5G strategy and how it&amp;rsquo;s laying the foundations for 6G.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
