<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Check-Point-Research on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/check-point-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Check-Point-Research on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/check-point-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Q4 2024 Brand Phishing Trends: Microsoft Remains the Top Target as LinkedIn Makes a Comeback</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-q4-2024-brand-phishing-trends-microsoft-remains-the-top-target-as-linkedin-makes-a-comeback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-q4-2024-brand-phishing-trends-microsoft-remains-the-top-target-as-linkedin-makes-a-comeback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CPR_blog_article_Ebook_blog_300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyber criminals continue to refine their phishing tactics, targeting trusted global brands to deceive users and steal sensitive information. Check Point Research (CPR), the intelligence arm of Check Point® Software, has unveiled its latest findings for Q4 2024, revealing key trends in brand phishing attacks. Technology Sector Leads in Phishing Attempts Microsoft retained its dominance as the most imitated brand in phishing schemes, accounting for a staggering 32% of all attempts. Apple followed with 12%, while Google ranked third. Notably, LinkedIn reentered the list at fourth place, emphasizing the persistent targeting of technology and Social Network brands. The persistence of […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the Code: How Banshee Stealer Targets macOS Users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cracking-the-code-how-banshee-stealer-targets-macos-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cracking-the-code-how-banshee-stealer-targets-macos-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/tax-scam-blog-2000x700-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary: Since September, Check Point Research (CPR) has been monitoring a new version of the Banshee macOS Stealer, a malware that steals browser credentials, cryptocurrency wallets, and other sensitive data. Undetected for over two months, Banshee’s latest version introduced string encryption taken from Apple’s XProtect, likely causing antivirus detection systems to overlook the malware Threat actors distributed Banshee using phishing websites and fake GitHub repositories, often impersonating popular software like Chrome and Telegram. A key update in the new version removed a Russian language check, expanding the malware’s potential targets. The Banshee Stealer highlights the growing risks to macOS […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
