<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gpu on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/gpu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gpu on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/gpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Load Balancing: Optimizing Password Recovery Across Heterogeneous Units</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intelligent-load-balancing-optimizing-password-recovery-across-heterogeneous-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intelligent-load-balancing-optimizing-password-recovery-across-heterogeneous-units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/EDPR-4.70-2_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the latest update of Elcomsoft Distributed Password Recovery (EDPR), we’ve introduced a revamped load-balancing feature. The new feature aims to enhance resource utilization on local workstations across diverse hardware configurations. This update has drastically reduced the time required to break passwords in certain hardware configurations, thanks to a refined load distribution algorithm. In this article, we’ll share some technical details on how load balancing leverages a mix of GPUs and CPU cores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Password Breaking A to Z</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/password-breaking-a-to-z/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/passwords-az.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our blog features numerous articles on breaking passwords and accessing encrypted data, ranging from simple “how-to” guides to comprehensive manuals. However, many of the questions we are frequently asked are not about the technical stuff but rather the very basics of password recovery. Can you break that password? Is it legal? How much time do you think it will take to break this one? We do have the answers, but they require digging through the extensive content of our blog. To address this, we’ve created a comprehensive A to Z article that not only answers many common questions but also links to our previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
