<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lg on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/lg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lg on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/lg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A quick post on Chen’s algorithm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(April 19):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yilei Chen announced the discovery of a bug in the algorithm, which he does not know how to fix. This was independently discovered by Hongxun Wu and Thomas Vidick. At present, the paper does not provide a polynomial-time algorithm for solving LWE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a normal person — that is, a person who doesn’t obsessively follow the latest cryptography news — you probably missed last week’s cryptography bombshell. That news comes in the form of a new e-print authored by Yilei Chen, “Quantum Algorithms for Lattice Problems“, which has roiled the cryptography research community. The result is now being evaluated by experts in lattices and quantum algorithm design (&lt;em&gt;and to be clear, I am not one!&lt;/em&gt;) but if it holds up, it’s going to be quite a bad day/week/month/year for the applied cryptography community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the week: Airdrop tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wrote an “attack of the week” post, and the fault for this is entirely mine. I’ve been much too busy writing boring posts about Schnorr signatures! But this week’s news brings an exciting story with both technical &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; political dimensions: new reports claim that Chinese security agencies have developed a technique to trace the sender of AirDrop transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically my “attack of the week” posts are intended to highlight recent research. What’s unusual about this one is that the attack is not really &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;; it was discovered way back in 2019, when a set of TU Darmstadt researchers — Heinrich, Hollick, Schneider, Stute, and Weinert — reverse-engineered the Apple AirDrop protocol and disclosed several privacy flaws to Apple. (The resulting paper, which appeared in Usenix Security 2021 can be found here.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Schnorr and beyond (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: extremely wonky cryptography post. Also, possibly stupid and bound for nowhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest problems in applied cryptography (and perhaps all of computer science!) is explaining &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; our tools work the way they do. After all, we’ve been gifted an amazing basket of useful algorithms from those who came before us. Hence it’s perfectly understandable for practitioners to want to take those gifts and simply start to apply them. But sometimes this approach leaves us wondering &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we’re doing certain things: in these cases it’s helpful to take a step back and think about what’s actually going on, and perhaps what was in the inventors’ heads when the tools were first invented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft to Invest $80 Billion in AI Data Centers in Fiscal 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-to-invest-80-billion-in-ai-data-centers-in-fiscal-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than half of the investment has been earmarked for infrastructure in the U.S. Microsoft President Brad Smith frames AI investment as key to economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
