<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phishing on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/phishing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phishing on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/phishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smishing, Beyond Trust, CryptoReligion, Aviatrix, Azure, Josh Marpet, and more... - SWN #442</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smishing-beyond-trust-cryptoreligion-aviatrix-azure-josh-marpet-and-more-swn-442/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/smishing-beyond-trust-cryptoreligion-aviatrix-azure-josh-marpet-and-more-swn-442/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is phishing?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During phishing, a target or targets are approached by email, telephone, or text message by someone posing as a legitimate institution. This is done to lure individuals into providing sensitive data such as passwords, banking and credit card details, and personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information is then used to access sensitive accounts, resulting in identity theft and financial loss.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Types of phishing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; spear phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whaling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;search engine phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;email phishing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Common Features of Phishing:-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypto phishing losses surged in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crypto-phishing-losses-surged-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crypto-phishing-losses-surged-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wallet drainer attack activity was particularly elevated during the first three months of 2024, with the loss of $55.4 million worth of cryptocurrency in the year&amp;rsquo;s biggest heist bringing stolen proceeds to $187 million, according to a study from Scam Sniffer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress phishing plugin drives online shopping fraud</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wordpress-phishing-plugin-drives-online-shopping-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wordpress-phishing-plugin-drives-online-shopping-fraud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhishWP imitates trusted payment services and sends stolen information directly to Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 steps to safeguarding your privacy online</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more devices, digital apps and online accounts you use, the more efficient and convenient your life becomes. But all that ease of use comes with a price. Your devices are constantly collecting your personal data to fine-tune your user experience. At the same time, hackers, and other cyber criminals are working round the clock to steal this sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of your digital identity as a confidential file full of high-value information – passwords, credit card numbers, bank account details, social security numbers and more. If you’re not taking the proper steps to guard your online privacy, you could end up handing over the files to a vast army of cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft announces recipients of academic grants for AI research on combating phishing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day in the ever-changing technology landscape, we see boundaries shift as new ideas challenge the old status quo. This constant shift is observed in the increasingly sophisticated and connected tools, products, and services people and organizations use on a daily basis, but also in the security that needs to be built into these technologies to protect them against adversaries intent on abusing the same technologies for nefarious purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft, we are committed to harnessing the immense potential of AI to help solve many of our technology concerns today. We believe that working on the “bleeding edge” offers one of the best ways to serve our customers and the broader ecosystem, and AI is key to advancing our understanding and technical capabilities in many complex areas of cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
