<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quickly diagnose issues by viewing previous Pipeline runs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quickly-diagnose-issues-by-viewing-previous-pipeline-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the release of a new capability in Bitbucket Pipelines that will improve your experience diagnosing issues with your pipeline runs, by allowing you to view and access previous runs within the Pipelines UI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://atlassianblog.wpengine.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-1-600x491.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The previous pipeline &lt;strong&gt;Runs&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown will not show up if you re-run an entire pipeline, because re-running an entire pipeline creates an entirely separate pipeline record, rather than an additional run on an existing pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patch Tuesday: January 2025 Security Update Patches Exploited Elevation of Privilege Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-tuesday-january-2025-security-update-patches-exploited-elevation-of-privilege-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/patch-tuesday-january-2025-security-update-patches-exploited-elevation-of-privilege-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s monthly patches cover Hyper-V NT Kernel Integration VSPs, Git in Visual Studio, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing personal access token (PAT) usage across Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-personal-access-token-pat-usage-across-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the new year, we’ll be making moves towards strengthening Microsoft and our customers’ security posture in regards to the usage and creation of personal access tokens (PATs).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following this blog, you may have noticed we’ve been distancing away from PATs as the recommended authentication method for Azure DevOps APIs by offering restrictive policies and more secure alternatives. PATs can be an enticing vector for unauthorized access, especially when insecurely stored, over-scoped, or set for long durations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitBleed – Finding Secrets in Mirrored Git Repositories – CVE-2022-24975</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitbleed-finding-secrets-in-mirrored-git-repositories-cve-2022-24975/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitbleed-finding-secrets-in-mirrored-git-repositories-cve-2022-24975/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to a discrepancy in Git behavior, partial parts of a source code repository are visible when making copies via the “git clone” command. There are additional parts of the repository that only become visible when using the “–mirror” option. This can lead to secrets being exposed via git repositories when not removed properly, and a false sense of security when repositories are scanned for secrets against a cloned, non-mirrored copy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
