<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debugging 2024: Lessons learned, wins, and achievements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debugging-2024-lessons-learned-wins-and-achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debugging-2024-lessons-learned-wins-and-achievements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who love looking back on a year. Reflecting on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and what I want to achieve in the following year. This year—like many others—I jumped on Twitch to recap my year, review the stats, and talk about what I want to do moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the stats, things I learned, and goals I have for 2025. The main reason I like sharing these things is to inspire and motivate others. I hope you find it interesting ❤️.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;If you&#39;re trying to add collaborative features inside your app? Check this article!&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/if-youre-trying-to-add-collaborative-features-inside-your-app-check-this-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/if-youre-trying-to-add-collaborative-features-inside-your-app-check-this-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F647287%2Fb72ea6c2-a966-40c4-bce6-badefc1face6.png&#34; alt=&#34;astrodevil&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-real-time-presence-features-like-figma-and-google-docs-in-your-app-in-minutes&#34;&gt;Build Real-Time Presence Features Like Figma and Google Docs in Your App in Minutes🚀🔥🧑‍💻&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;astrodevil--dec-26-24&#34;&gt;Astrodevil ・ Dec 26 &amp;lsquo;24&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#webdev #javascript #beginners #programming&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Check out my latest post, especially if you&#39;re a fan of Japanese culture or if you&#39;re studying it!&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-my-latest-post-especially-if-youre-a-fan-of-japanese-culture-or-if-youre-studying-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-out-my-latest-post-especially-if-youre-a-fan-of-japanese-culture-or-if-youre-studying-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F1253234%2F39957cd3-32a4-4a71-9837-724db3e804bc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;matteosant_dev&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wakaruyo---browser-extension&#34;&gt;Wakaruyo - Browser Extension&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;matteo-santoro-dev--jan-8&#34;&gt;Matteo Santoro Dev ・ Jan 8&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#webdev #javascript #browser #programming&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Malware | A Threat Hunter’s Guide to Analysis, Techniques and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about cloud threats, how to hunt for them and how to analyze them in this post based on Alex Delamotte&amp;rsquo;s recent LABScon workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many researchers have noticed, malware in the cloud is different. Perhaps more strikingly different than Windows versus Linux threats, cloud services are targeted through entirely different methods altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At LABScon 2024, I gave a workshop Taxonomy in the Troposphere that outlines categories of cloud threats and how to approach analyzing and hunting them. The workshop structure highlighted three general sections to approach this problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s why Julia is THE language in scientific programming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working in quantum computing is being exposed to a whole new set of skills and tools. For those of us coming from the software engineering side, discovering the things our academic peers are using is an interesting experience. One of the best for me personally was coming across the Julia programming language, and learning why it has become the go-to language for serious scientific programming in some circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular (Expression) Chess</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/regular-expression-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/regular-expression-chess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/chess.png?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Nicholas Carlini] found some extra time on his hands over the holiday, so he decide to do something with “entirely no purpose.” The result: 84,688 regular expressions that can play chess using a 2-ply minmax strategy. No kidding. We think we can do some heavy-duty regular expressions, but this is a whole other level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you might expect, the code to play is extremely simple as it just runs the board through series of regular expressions that implement the game logic. Of course, that doesn’t count the thousands of strings containing the regular expressions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Ventures Invests in poolside, Next Generation AI for Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S Ventures invests in poolside, one of the most watched and highest valued startups in generative AI for software engineering today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October 2024, SentinelOne’s venture arm, S Ventures, made a strategic investment in poolside as part of the AI assistive coding startup’s $500 million Series B round. It was one of S Ventures notable recent investments in generative AI (GenAI) start-ups following similar investments in leading foundational and enterprise LLM platforms such as Anthropic and Cohere, as well as Scale, a startup focused on the development and tooling layer of AI, and Galileo, a leading evaluation intelligence platform for AI teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
