<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United-Nations on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/united-nations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United-Nations on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/united-nations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from First Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-first-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Earlier this month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the proceedings of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, which has been tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week I of the Fifth Substantive Session.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction Last month from April 11-21, 2023, the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communications Technologies (ICTs) for Criminal Purpose held its Fifth Session in Vienna. As we reported earlier, the negotiating process has reached a pivotal stage, wherein the Member Countries […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week II of the Fifth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal In Part I of the two-part blog series, we briefed our readers on the developments that took place in the first week of the Fifth Session of the Ad-Hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we aim to capture the key discussion on provisions on (i) technical assistance, (ii) preventative measures, (iii) […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
