<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;iPhone &amp; Android Users: A Major Privacy Upgrade is Coming Soon&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-android-users-a-major-privacy-upgrade-is-coming-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-android-users-a-major-privacy-upgrade-is-coming-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This breakthrough will finally allow secure, encrypted messaging between different mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Top Tech Conferences &amp; Events to Add to Your Calendar in 2025&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-tech-conferences-events-to-add-to-your-calendar-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-tech-conferences-events-to-add-to-your-calendar-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great way to stay current with the latest technology trends and innovations is by attending conferences. Read and bookmark our tech events guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Passwords App Vulnerability Exposed Users for Months</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-passwords-app-vulnerability-exposed-users-for-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-passwords-app-vulnerability-exposed-users-for-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Passwords app had a security flaw that exposed users to phishing attacks for months. Learn what happened and how to stay protected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear Apple: add “Disappearing Messages” to iMessage right now</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dear-apple-add-disappearing-messages-to-imessage-right-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a cryptography blog and I always feel the need to apologize for any post that isn’t “straight cryptography.” I’m actually getting a little tired of apologizing for it (though if you want some hard-core cryptography content, there’s plenty here and here.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have to remind my colleagues that out in the real world, our job is not to solve exciting mathematical problems: &lt;em&gt;it’s to help people communicate securely&lt;/em&gt;. And people, at this very moment, need a lot of help. Many of my friends are Federal employees or work for contractors, and they’re terrified that they’re going to lose their job based on speech they post online. Unfortunately, “online” to many people includes thoughts sent over private text messages — so even private conversations are becoming chilled. And while this is hardly the worst thing happening to people in this world, it’s something that’s happening to my friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 16e Review: An iPhone That’s Good Enough for Most People</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-16e-review-an-iphone-thats-good-enough-for-most-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-16e-review-an-iphone-thats-good-enough-for-most-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 16e is not the best iPhone, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty darn good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post iPhone 16e Review: An iPhone That’s Good Enough for Most People appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft officially supports running Windows 11 on M1 and M2 Macs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-officially-supports-running-windows-11-on-m1-and-m2-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-officially-supports-running-windows-11-on-m1-and-m2-macs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get related details about Parallels and VMware, as well as the limitations to what can run on Arm versions of Windows 11.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Guide to Apple Watch Bands in 2025: Sizing, Styles, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-complete-guide-to-apple-watch-bands-in-2025-sizing-styles-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-complete-guide-to-apple-watch-bands-in-2025-sizing-styles-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy to change Apple Watch bands to suit your style. Here is an overview of the different types of bands Apple sells.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post The Complete Guide to Apple Watch Bands in 2025: Sizing, Styles, and More appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three questions about Apple, encryption, and the U.K.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-questions-about-apple-encryption-and-the-u-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-questions-about-apple-encryption-and-the-u-k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, the Washington Post reported that the U.K. government had issued a secret order to Apple demanding that the company include a “backdoor” into the company’s end-to-end encrypted iCloud Backup feature. From the article:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The British government’s undisclosed order, issued last month, requires blanket capability to view fully encrypted material, not merely assistance in cracking a specific account, and has no known precedent in major democracies. Its application would mark a significant defeat for tech companies in their decades-long battle to avoid being wielded as government tools against their users, the people said, speaking under the condition of anonymity to discuss legally and politically sensitive issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.K. asks to backdoor iCloud Backup encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m supposed to be finishing a wonky series on proof systems (here and here) and I promise I will do that this week. In the midst of this I’ve been a bit distracted by world events.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week the Washington Post published a bombshell story announcing that the U.K. had filed “technical capability notices” demanding that Apple modify the encryption used in their Advanced Data Protection (ADP) system for iCloud. For those who don’t know about ADP, it’s a system that enables full “end-to-end” encryption for iCloud backups, including photos and other data. This means that your backup data should be encrypted under your phone’s passcode — and critically, neither Apple nor hackers can access it. The U.K. request would secretly weaken that feature for at least some users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which iPad is best for you in 2025? Comparison of iPad Pro, iPad Air, iPad mini, iPad 10th gen</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/which-ipad-is-best-for-you-in-2025-comparison-of-ipad-pro-ipad-air-ipad-mini-ipad-10th-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/which-ipad-is-best-for-you-in-2025-comparison-of-ipad-pro-ipad-air-ipad-mini-ipad-10th-gen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With so many options, it’s not easy to know which iPad is right for you. This guide looks at Apple’s current product line, and explains which iPad you should get based on how you plan to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Which iPad is best for you in 2025? Comparison of iPad Pro, iPad Air, iPad mini, iPad 10th gen appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Apple Taking Legal Action Against UK’s Government?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-is-apple-taking-legal-action-against-uks-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-is-apple-taking-legal-action-against-uks-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple told TechRepublic it is “gravely disappointed” to remove Advanced Data Protection in the U.K., as it fights government demands for an iCloud backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Lock Apps on iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set your iPad into kiosk mode and pass it around without worrying about someone opening other apps or accessing unwanted content through an accessibility feature called Guided Access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Personal Note-Taking Assistant Is Just $39.99 for Life</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record, transcribe, summarize, and keep all your notes organized with this powerful app for Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google, Apple Under Investigation to Determine Compliance with New UK Competition Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Google or Apple is deemed to have Strategic Market Status in the U.K., the government might force it to make the user data it collects available to competitors, or give publishers more control over how their data is used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People on social media who don&amp;rsquo;t understand how iPhones work have been spreading misinformation about some Siri settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Cheat Sheet: The Ultimate Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive guide covers essential PowerShell information, including features, system requirements, and how Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s framework extends to task automation and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the week: Airdrop tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wrote an “attack of the week” post, and the fault for this is entirely mine. I’ve been much too busy writing boring posts about Schnorr signatures! But this week’s news brings an exciting story with both technical &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; political dimensions: new reports claim that Chinese security agencies have developed a technique to trace the sender of AirDrop transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically my “attack of the week” posts are intended to highlight recent research. What’s unusual about this one is that the attack is not really &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;; it was discovered way back in 2019, when a set of TU Darmstadt researchers — Heinrich, Hollick, Schneider, Stute, and Weinert — reverse-engineered the Apple AirDrop protocol and disclosed several privacy flaws to Apple. (The resulting paper, which appeared in Usenix Security 2021 can be found here.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
