<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Lock Apps on iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set your iPad into kiosk mode and pass it around without worrying about someone opening other apps or accessing unwanted content through an accessibility feature called Guided Access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your Personal Note-Taking Assistant Is Just $39.99 for Life</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/your-personal-note-taking-assistant-is-just-39-99-for-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record, transcribe, summarize, and keep all your notes organized with this powerful app for Apple devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DeepSeek Chatbot Beats OpenAI on App Store Leaderboard</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deepseek-chatbot-beats-openai-on-app-store-leaderboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chinese firm said it cost just $5.6 million to train a model that can reason through complex answers and compete with OpenAI’s o1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google, Apple Under Investigation to Determine Compliance with New UK Competition Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-apple-under-investigation-to-determine-compliance-with-new-uk-competition-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Google or Apple is deemed to have Strategic Market Status in the U.K., the government might force it to make the user data it collects available to competitors, or give publishers more control over how their data is used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People on social media who don&amp;rsquo;t understand how iPhones work have been spreading misinformation about some Siri settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Complete Guide to Apple Watch Bands in 2025: Sizing, Styles, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-complete-guide-to-apple-watch-bands-in-2025-sizing-styles-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-complete-guide-to-apple-watch-bands-in-2025-sizing-styles-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy to change Apple Watch bands to suit your style. Here is an overview of the different types of bands Apple sells.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post The Complete Guide to Apple Watch Bands in 2025: Sizing, Styles, and More appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Cheat Sheet: The Ultimate Guide for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/powershell-cheat-sheet-the-ultimate-guide-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive guide covers essential PowerShell information, including features, system requirements, and how Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s framework extends to task automation and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the week: Airdrop tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wrote an “attack of the week” post, and the fault for this is entirely mine. I’ve been much too busy writing boring posts about Schnorr signatures! But this week’s news brings an exciting story with both technical &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; political dimensions: new reports claim that Chinese security agencies have developed a technique to trace the sender of AirDrop transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically my “attack of the week” posts are intended to highlight recent research. What’s unusual about this one is that the attack is not really &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;; it was discovered way back in 2019, when a set of TU Darmstadt researchers — Heinrich, Hollick, Schneider, Stute, and Weinert — reverse-engineered the Apple AirDrop protocol and disclosed several privacy flaws to Apple. (The resulting paper, which appeared in Usenix Security 2021 can be found here.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
