<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithms on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/algorithms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithms on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/algorithms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Eight Lincoln Laboratory technologies named 2020 R&amp;D 100 Award winners&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight technologies developed by MIT Lincoln Laboratory researchers, either wholly or in collaboration with researchers from other organizations, were among the winners of the 2020 R&amp;amp;D 100 Awards. Annually since 1963, these international R&amp;amp;D awards recognize 100 technologies that a panel of expert judges selects as the most revolutionary of the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six of the laboratory’s winning technologies are software systems, a number of which take advantage of artificial intelligence techniques. The software technologies are solutions to difficulties inherent in analyzing large volumes of data and to problems in maintaining cybersecurity. Another technology is a process designed to assure secure fabrication of integrated circuits, and the eighth winner is an optical communications technology that may enable future space missions to transmit error-free data to Earth at significantly higher rates than currently possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s a weird, weird quantum world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1994, as Professor Peter Shor PhD ’85 tells it, internal seminars at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs were lively affairs. The audience of physicists was an active and inquisitive bunch, often pelting speakers with questions throughout their talks. Shor, who worked at Bell Labs at the time, remembers several occasions when a speaker couldn’t get past their third slide, as they attempted to address a rapid line of questioning before their time was up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor receives 2022-2023 Killian Award</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-receives-2022-2023-killian-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Renowned mathematician and quantum computing pioneer Peter W. Shor PhD ’85 has been named the recipient of MIT’s 2022-2023 James R. Killian Jr. Faculty Achievement Award, the highest honor the Institute faculty can bestow upon one of its members each academic year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Killian Award citation credits Shor, who is the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics, with having made “seminal contributions that have forever shaped the foundations of quantum computing. Indeed, quantum computing exists today, in practice, because of Peter Shor.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor wins Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Shor, the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics at MIT, has been named a recipient of the 2023 Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics. He shares the $3 million prize with three others for “foundational work in the field of quantum information”: David Deutsch at the University of Oxford, Charles Bennett at IBM Research, and Gilles Brassard of the University of Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In announcing the award, the Breakthrough Prize Foundation highlighted Shor’s contributions to the quantum information field, including the eponymous Shor’s algorithm for factoring extremely large numbers, and for an algorithm to correct errors in quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a code-breaking quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most recent email you sent was likely encrypted using a tried-and-true method that relies on the idea that even the fastest computer would be unable to efficiently break a gigantic number into factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers, on the other hand, promise to rapidly crack complex cryptographic systems that a classical computer might never be able to unravel. This promise is based on a quantum factoring algorithm proposed in 1994 by Peter Shor, who is now a professor at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
