<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dell Introduces New Product Line Names</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dell-introduces-new-product-line-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Named brands like XPS and Inspiron will now fall under performance categories. Plus, Dell expanded its partnership with AMD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind the Gap: Cloud Spending is Perplexing CFOs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mind-the-gap-cloud-spending-is-perplexing-cfos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cloud spending confusion is rising among CFOs. An IBM executive explains how FinOps, automation, and AI-powered solutions can improve cost visibility and management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI Shifts Attention to Superintelligence in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-shifts-attention-to-superintelligence-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Superintelligence refers to AI with greater-than-human capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK government invests £40 million in 5G</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uk-government-invests-40-million-in-5g/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find out the possible benefits and challenges of the U.K. government’s 5G strategy and how it&amp;rsquo;s laying the foundations for 6G.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Desktop Infrastructure: Benefits and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virtual-desktop-infrastructure-benefits-and-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virtual-desktop-infrastructure-benefits-and-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the umbrella of this digital transformation and acceleration trend, one virtualization technology is becoming increasingly popular, virtual desktop infrastructure. VDI is used by enterprises to provide workers, customers and users with access to its central system and the necessary tools and resources they need. As a powerful tool, VDI can help organizations improve their &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Virtualization?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtualization lets organizations run multiple isolated workloads from the same hardware platform, saving money, and enabling more efficient scaling. It is also used by cloud providers to deliver on-demand computing resources for multiple customers using shared hardware. It’s what allows businesses to pay for only the cloud computing resources they need and quickly (or even &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title># Why Low-Code Development is the Future of Software Engineering 🚀</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-low-code-development-is-the-future-of-software-engineering-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-low-code-development-is-the-future-of-software-engineering-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced digital world, businesses need to adapt quickly to changing market demands. This has led to the rise of &lt;strong&gt;low-code development platforms&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;strong&gt;OutSystems&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Appian&lt;/strong&gt;, which are revolutionizing the way software is developed. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into why low-code development is the future of software engineering and how these platforms are shaping this transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-low-code-development&#34;&gt;What is Low-Code Development?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Low-code development platforms allow developers to create applications through graphical user interfaces and configuration rather than traditional hand-coded programming. This approach drastically reduces the time and effort required to develop applications, making it accessible to both professional developers and business users with minimal coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;12 Months of Fighting Cybercrime &amp; Defending Enterprises | SentinelLABS 2024 Review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From ransomware repurposed for espionage to increased exploitation of cloud platforms, learn about the key trends from SentinelLABS research in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the convergence of cybercrime and nation-state espionage to the strategic misuse of trusted platforms like Microsoft Azure and SaaS APIs, the cybersecurity landscape has grown more complex than ever in 2024. SentinelLABS has been at the forefront of these challenges, analyzing trends, uncovering campaigns, and equipping organizations with actionable intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights | Empowering Customers Through Innovations &amp; Security in Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the latest technologies and innovations for cloud, container, and data security revealed at AWS re:Invent 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week marked another action-packed year at AWS re:Invent for the SentinelOne Team. Year after year, a consistent highlight from the event is the strong sense of community it builds with people from different backgrounds, geographies, and business types – all unified by their interest in innovating and doing business on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;SentinelOne Continues to Set the Standard in MITRE ATT&amp;CK® Evaluations | 100% Detection, Zero Delays and 88% Less Noise&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sentinelone-continues-to-set-the-standard-in-mitre-attck-evaluations-100-detection-zero-delays-and-88-less-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne achieves 100% detection and zero detection delays in the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK® Evaluations: Enterprise 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In cybersecurity, speed and accuracy are necessities. Every second counts, and every detection could be the difference between resilience and breach. That’s why SentinelOne takes immense pride in protecting our customers, monitoring trillions of signals annually across organizations from SMBs to Fortune 10 enterprises to top government entities and critical infrastructure. With visibility into the most sophisticated threats, we’ve detected and disrupted countless ransomware attacks, thwarted advanced eCrime and nation state adversaries, and ensured operations remain protected against evolving risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;🤔Retro’ing and Debugging 2024: a year of data, books, APIs, BOTs &amp; AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/retroing-and-debugging-2024-a-year-of-data-books-apis-bots-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-about&#34;&gt;🤗 About&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was an incredible year filled with challenges, achievements, and an abundance of - sometimes unexpected - &lt;strong&gt;learning opportunities that came to me on my way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the year, here are &lt;strong&gt;some of the highlights&lt;/strong&gt; that shaped my growth as a professional and as a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I enjoyed the most this year is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;I could transform real life problems into nicely well packaged IT projects&lt;/strong&gt; that could satisfy my own curiosity and then be shared with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous SOC Is a Journey, Not a Destination | Introducing The Autonomous SOC Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about autonomous SOC and how SentinelOne uses a maturity model to frame the shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The autonomous SOC: A well-grounded vision for the future of machine speed, AI-driven cyber defense, or nothing more than a pipe dream? Few concepts in modern security have been as polarizing, with sides painted as distinct camps of “believers” versus “non-believers”, each accompanied by increasingly hyperbolic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SentinelOne, you will hear us and our customers talk about the autonomous SOC and the fundamental shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations. Today, we want to be clear about what we mean when we say that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals Are Targeting AI Agents and Conversational Platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;emerging-risks-for-businesses-and-consumers&#34;&gt;Emerging risks for businesses and consumers&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– Shawn Loveland, Chief Operating Officer, Resecurity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;San Jose, Calif. – Dec. 11, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resecurity has identified a spike in malicious campaigns targeting &lt;strong&gt;AI agents&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Conversational AI platforms&lt;/strong&gt; that leverage chatbots to provide automated, human-like interactions for consumers. Conversational AI platforms are designed to facilitate natural interactions between humans and machines using technologies like &lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning (ML)&lt;/strong&gt;. These platforms enable applications such as chatbots and virtual agents to engage in meaningful conversations, making them valuable tools across various industries. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Wanted: Data Scientists In The Cybersecurity Field</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/help-wanted-data-scientists-in-the-cybersecurity-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/help-wanted-data-scientists-in-the-cybersecurity-field/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Medium Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 7, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data science technology is about to revolutionize even the most traditional industries as it uses AI, Machine Learning, and Big Data, according to a story in Medium.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Total global data storage is projected to exceed 200 zettabytes by 2025, according to Cybersecurity Ventures. This includes data stored on private and public IT infrastructures, on utility infrastructures, on private and public cloud data centers, and personal computing devices; PCs, laptops, tablets, smartphones, and IoT devices&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McAfee Deepfake Detector: Fighting Misinformation with AMD AI-Powered Precision</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafee-deepfake-detector-fighting-misinformation-with-amd-ai-powered-precision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mcafee-deepfake-detector-fighting-misinformation-with-amd-ai-powered-precision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/300x200_Blog_AMD-2x-300x200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a world where deepfake scams and misinformation are increasingly pervasive, McAfee is taking a bold step forward with major enhancements to its AI-powered deepfake detection technology. By partnering with AMD and harnessing the Neural Processing Unit (NPU) within the latest AMD Ryzen&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/2122.png&#34; alt=&#34;™&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; AI 300 Series processors announced at CES, McAfee Deepfake Detector is designed to empower users to discern truth from fiction like never before. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;deepfakes-a-growing-global-concern&#34;&gt;Deepfakes: A Growing Global Concern &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As deepfake technology becomes more sophisticated, so too does the challenge of identifying manipulated content. Nearly two-thirds of people globally report rising concerns over deepfakes, emphasizing the need for tools that can accurately detect falsified content. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source all the way down: Upgrading our developer documentation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Cloudflare, we treat developer content like a product, where we take the user and their feedback into consideration. We are constantly iterating, testing, analyzing, and refining content. Inspired by agile practices, treating developer content like an open source product means we approach our documentation the same way an open source software project is created and maintained.  Open source documentation empowers the developer community because it allows anyone, anywhere, to contribute content. By making both the content and the framework of the documentation site publicly accessible, we provide developers with the opportunity to not only improve the material itself but also understand and engage with the processes that govern how the documentation is built, approved, and maintained. This transparency fosters collaboration, learning, and innovation, enabling developers to contribute their expertise and learn from others in a shared, open environment. We also provide feedback to other open source products and plugins, giving back to the same community that supports us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Leap: D-Wave’s Bold New Move! Discover the Future of Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/quantum-leap-d-waves-bold-new-move-discover-the-future-of-computing2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking development poised to reshape the landscape of quantum computing, D-Wave Systems has announced their latest innovation: the Advantage2 quantum processor. As the industry grapples with an ever-increasing demand for computational power, this announcement signals a pivotal moment in the quest to harness the full potential of quantum technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game-Changing Technology&lt;/strong&gt; The Advantage2 processor boasts a staggering 7,000 qubits, significantly surpassing its predecessors and setting a new benchmark for quantum performance. This advancement is expected to enhance quantum annealing processes, thereby accelerating solutions for complex optimization problems that classical computers struggle to handle efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S Ventures Invests in poolside, Next Generation AI for Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/s-ventures-invests-in-poolside-next-generation-ai-for-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S Ventures invests in poolside, one of the most watched and highest valued startups in generative AI for software engineering today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In October 2024, SentinelOne’s venture arm, S Ventures, made a strategic investment in poolside as part of the AI assistive coding startup’s $500 million Series B round. It was one of S Ventures notable recent investments in generative AI (GenAI) start-ups following similar investments in leading foundational and enterprise LLM platforms such as Anthropic and Cohere, as well as Scale, a startup focused on the development and tooling layer of AI, and Galileo, a leading evaluation intelligence platform for AI teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
