<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Investigation on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/investigation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Investigation on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/investigation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous SOC Is a Journey, Not a Destination | Introducing The Autonomous SOC Maturity Model</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/autonomous-soc-is-a-journey-not-a-destination-introducing-the-autonomous-soc-maturity-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about autonomous SOC and how SentinelOne uses a maturity model to frame the shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The autonomous SOC: A well-grounded vision for the future of machine speed, AI-driven cyber defense, or nothing more than a pipe dream? Few concepts in modern security have been as polarizing, with sides painted as distinct camps of “believers” versus “non-believers”, each accompanied by increasingly hyperbolic claims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At SentinelOne, you will hear us and our customers talk about the autonomous SOC and the fundamental shifts it will bring to day-to-day security operations. Today, we want to be clear about what we mean when we say that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Malware | A Threat Hunter’s Guide to Analysis, Techniques and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-malware-a-threat-hunters-guide-to-analysis-techniques-and-delivery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about cloud threats, how to hunt for them and how to analyze them in this post based on Alex Delamotte&amp;rsquo;s recent LABScon workshop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many researchers have noticed, malware in the cloud is different. Perhaps more strikingly different than Windows versus Linux threats, cloud services are targeted through entirely different methods altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At LABScon 2024, I gave a workshop Taxonomy in the Troposphere that outlines categories of cloud threats and how to approach analyzing and hunting them. The workshop structure highlighted three general sections to approach this problem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhaka Police arrests Turkish ATM hacker six months after escaping from Agartala</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dhaka-police-arrests-turkish-atm-hacker-six-months-after-escaping-from-agartala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dhaka Metropolitan Police’s Counter-Terrorism and Transnational Crime Unit apprehended Turkish national Hakan Zanburkan in Bangladesh on Tuesday. Agartala’s Govind Ballabh Pant (GBP) Hospital and Agartala Government Medical College (AGMC) were able to eject Hakan’s captive with the aid of the local folks from Tripura.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several other members of an international ATM card cloning syndicate were also arrested in Bangladesh alongside him on Thursday, according to a police officer at Agartala. Agartala’s AGMC and GBP Hospitals had allowed the under-trial Hakan to escape through a window during a health check-up while security lapses existed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DPRK IT Workers | A Network of Active Front Companies and Their Links to China</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dprk-it-workers-a-network-of-active-front-companies-and-their-links-to-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has identified multiple deceptive websites linked to businesses in China fronting for North Korea&amp;rsquo;s fake IT workers scheme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has identified unique characteristics of multiple websites, now seized by the US Government, associated with the DPRK IT Worker front companies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that DPRK actors seek to impersonate US based software and technology consulting businesses by copying the online brands of legitimate organizations, seeking to use these for financial objectives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has linked the activity to several active front companies and links these with high confidence to a larger set of organizations being created in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our findings link additional companies, which remain active today, to the DPRK IT Workers scheme.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;North Korea operates a global network of IT workers, both as individuals and under front companies, to evade sanctions and generate revenue for the regime. These workers are highly skilled in areas like software development, mobile applications, blockchain, and cryptocurrency technologies. By posing as professionals from other countries using fake identities and forged credentials, they secure remote jobs and freelance contracts with businesses worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source all the way down: Upgrading our developer documentation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-all-the-way-down-upgrading-our-developer-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Cloudflare, we treat developer content like a product, where we take the user and their feedback into consideration. We are constantly iterating, testing, analyzing, and refining content. Inspired by agile practices, treating developer content like an open source product means we approach our documentation the same way an open source software project is created and maintained.  Open source documentation empowers the developer community because it allows anyone, anywhere, to contribute content. By making both the content and the framework of the documentation site publicly accessible, we provide developers with the opportunity to not only improve the material itself but also understand and engage with the processes that govern how the documentation is built, approved, and maintained. This transparency fosters collaboration, learning, and innovation, enabling developers to contribute their expertise and learn from others in a shared, open environment. We also provide feedback to other open source products and plugins, giving back to the same community that supports us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
