<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Military on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/military/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Military on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“WWI Fighter Plane Hack” Inspires Breakthrough in Cancer Treatment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Massachusetts Amherst have developed an innovative technology inspired by the synchronization mechanism of WWI fighter aircraft, which coordinated machine gun fire with propeller movement. This breakthrough allows precise, real-time control of the pH in a cell’s environment to influence its behavior. Detailed in &lt;strong&gt;Nano Letters&lt;/strong&gt;, the study opens exciting possibilities for developing new cancer and heart disease therapies and advancing the field of tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises – providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data – if paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texas awards $170 million contract for cybersecurity assistance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/texas-awards-170-million-contract-for-cybersecurity-assistance2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of a year when Texas employees were among those targeted by hackers, the state has awarded a multi-million-dollar contract to a company that works with entities to increase technological efficiency and offer cybersecurity protection. Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC) announced Dec. 18 that it was awarded a $170.9 million contract from the Texas Department of Information Resources (DIR) to provide cybersecurity services in protection of state networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
