<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disasterresponse on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/disasterresponse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disasterresponse on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/disasterresponse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Eight Lincoln Laboratory technologies named 2020 R&amp;D 100 Award winners&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/eight-lincoln-laboratory-technologies-named-2020-rd-100-award-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight technologies developed by MIT Lincoln Laboratory researchers, either wholly or in collaboration with researchers from other organizations, were among the winners of the 2020 R&amp;amp;D 100 Awards. Annually since 1963, these international R&amp;amp;D awards recognize 100 technologies that a panel of expert judges selects as the most revolutionary of the past year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six of the laboratory’s winning technologies are software systems, a number of which take advantage of artificial intelligence techniques. The software technologies are solutions to difficulties inherent in analyzing large volumes of data and to problems in maintaining cybersecurity. Another technology is a process designed to assure secure fabrication of integrated circuits, and the eighth winner is an optical communications technology that may enable future space missions to transmit error-free data to Earth at significantly higher rates than currently possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS launches AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications. The Android Team Awareness Kit (ATAK)—also known as Android Tactical Assault Kit for military use—is a smartphone geospatial infrastructure and situational awareness application. It provides mapping, messaging, and geofencing capabilities to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
