<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eaps on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/eaps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eaps on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/eaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kerry Emanuel,  David Sabatini, and Peter Shor receive BBVA Frontiers of Knowledge awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBVA Foundation awarded three MIT professors Frontiers of Knowledge Awards for their work in climate change, biology and biomedicine, and quantum computation. Department of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences Professor Kerry A. Emanuel, Department of Biology Professor David Sabatini, and Department of Mathematics Professor Peter Shor were recognized in the 12th edition of this annual award.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kerry Emanuel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emanuel, the Cecil and Ida Green Professor of Atmospheric Science, earned the BBVA’s Climate Change award “for his fundamental contributions to the understanding of tropical cyclones and how they are affected by climate change,” according to the committee’s citation. “By understanding the essential physics of atmospheric convection … he has unraveled the behavior of tropical cyclones — hurricanes and typhoons — as our climate changes.” He was also lauded for “extraordinary effectiveness in communicating the science of climate change to the public and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
