<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bypass on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/bypass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bypass on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/bypass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TOCTOU Vulnerability in Log4J 2.15</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toctou-vulnerability-in-log4j-2-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toctou-vulnerability-in-log4j-2-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Log4J has been in the spotlight for the past two weeks for a new attack vector which relies on Java Naming and Directory Interface (JNDI). In this blog, we will detail the new mitigation introduced in 2.15 and the bypass we found using a Time of Check, Time of Use vulnerability (TOCTOU). This vector was also discovered independently by Alvaro Muñoz and Tony Torralba. It is likely that many other individuals have reported related bypass techniques because there were multiple weaknesses in the same Java class (&lt;code&gt;JndiManager&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;12 Months of Fighting Cybercrime &amp; Defending Enterprises | SentinelLABS 2024 Review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From ransomware repurposed for espionage to increased exploitation of cloud platforms, learn about the key trends from SentinelLABS research in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the convergence of cybercrime and nation-state espionage to the strategic misuse of trusted platforms like Microsoft Azure and SaaS APIs, the cybersecurity landscape has grown more complex than ever in 2024. SentinelLABS has been at the forefront of these challenges, analyzing trends, uncovering campaigns, and equipping organizations with actionable intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ZDI Threat Hunting 2024: Highlights, Trends, &amp; Challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zdi-threat-hunting-2024-highlights-trends-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on 2024, it has been an eventful year for the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team. Throughout the year, we identified numerous threat actor campaigns exploiting zero-day vulnerabilities, uncovered additional variants of these vulnerabilities, and discovered even more vulnerabilities through our in-the-wild research. In this blog, we will highlight some of the key achievements of the Zero Day Initiative Threat Hunting team, as well as discuss important in-the-wild vulnerability trends and industry challenges we encountered in 2024 which will continue into 2025&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk | Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file &lt;code&gt;zshenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, researchers detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s discovery in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also reported on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to connect the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13189 - ZeroWdd MyBlog Remote File Permission Bypass Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13189&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical has been found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This affects an unknown part of the file src/main/java/com/wdd/myblog/config/MyBlogMvcConfig.java. The manipulation leads to permission issues. It is possible to initiate the attack remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54010 - Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches ICMP and UDP Packet Forwarding Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54010&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability in the firewall component of HPE Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches exists. It could allow an unauthenticated adjacent attacker to conduct a packet forwarding attack against the ICMP and UDP protocol. For this attack to be successful an attacker requires a switch configuration that allows packets routing (at layer 3). Configurations that do not allow network traffic routing are not impacted. Successful exploitation could allow an attacker to bypass security policies, potentially leading to unauthorized data exposure.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.4 | LOW&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SonicWall urges admins to patch exploitable SSLVPN bug immediately</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;sonicwall-urges-admins-to-patch-exploitable-sslvpn-bug-immediately&#34;&gt;SonicWall urges admins to patch exploitable SSLVPN bug immediately&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23038/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SonicWall is emailing customers urging them to upgrade their firewall&amp;rsquo;s SonicOS firmware to patch an authentication bypass vulnerability in SSL VPN and SSH management that is &amp;ldquo;susceptible to actual ex &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (2 hours, 27 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zloader Banking a new Malware attack can be bypass Microsoft Signature Verification.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/zloader-banking-a-new-malware-attack-can-be-bypass-microsoft-signature-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ZLoader malware campaign is exploiting a nine-year-old flaw in Microsoft’s digital signature verification to steal credentials and sensitive information using remote monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Check Point Research, which has been tracking the sophisticated infection chain since November 2021, it has been attributed to a cybercriminal group dubbed MalSmoke, citing similarities with previous attacks. “The infection chain incorporates legitimate remote management software (RMM) to gain access to the target machine.” After injecting its payload into a signed DLL, the malware further evades the system’s defenses by exploiting Microsoft’s digital signature verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
