<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynatrace on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/dynatrace/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dynatrace on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/dynatrace/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-adaptive thresholds for AI-driven quality gating</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/auto-adaptive-thresholds-for-ai-driven-quality-gating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0146_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;auto-adaptive thresholds&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest release of the Site Reliability Guardian incorporates assistance from Dynatrace Davis® AI to automatically derive appropriate threshold targets and adjust them over time to protect your quality improvements. This process, known as auto-adaptive thresholding, eliminates the need to define a static threshold upfront. Instead, it derives the suitable thresholds from previous validation results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-an-umbrella-for-development-and-operations&#34;&gt;Build an umbrella for Development and Operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern software engineering, the discipline of platform engineering delivers DevSecOps practices to developers to bridge the gaps between development, security, and operations and enhance the developer experience. A key element in platform engineering is the establishment of fast feedback cycles regarding the quality and security measures of new software releases. To provide automated feedback for developers, the concept of quality gates for static code analysis in continuous integration is widely adopted throughout the industry. However, this perspective differs in the continuous deployment practices of various organizations, where the feedback is either delayed or not returned to the developer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace completes 2024 FedRAMP Moderate reauthorization with Rev.5 transition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0162_1_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;FedRAMP&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-fedramp-moderate-and-transition-to-rev5&#34;&gt;Understanding FedRAMP Moderate and transition to Rev.5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP (Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program) is a government program that provides a standardized approach to security assessment, authorization, and continuous monitoring for cloud products and services for U.S. state and federal agencies. The FedRAMP Moderate baseline is designed to protect sensitive data that, if compromised, could seriously adversely affect operations, assets, or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP Revision 5 (Rev.5) prioritizes customizing security controls for specific risks. It aligns with Cloud Service Providers, providing a baseline while allowing tailored adjustments for individual federal agencies. FedRAMP adopts a threat-based approach to security controls. Rather than a one-size-fits-all model, this methodology tailors controls based on specific threats and risks. The result is a more effective security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Red Hat and Dynatrace intelligently automate your production environment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-red-hat-and-dynatrace-intelligently-automate-your-production-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Blog_-OTP-0100_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Red Hat and Dynatrace integration&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Red Hat and Dynatrace are joining forces to revolutionize day-one and day-two operations. A tight integration between Red Hat Ansible Automation Platform, Dynatrace Davis® AI, and the Dynatrace observability and security platform enables closed-loop remediation to automate the process from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detecting a problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Managing incidents in corresponding tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the root cause and proper countermeasures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Executing corrective actions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keeping relevant stakeholders in the loop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This way, disruptions are minimized, MTTR is significantly decreased, and DevSecOps and SREs collaborate efficiently to boost productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observability throughout the software development lifecycle increases delivery performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0207_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, development teams suffer from a lack of automation for time-consuming tasks, the absence of standardization due to an overabundance of tool options, and insufficiently mature DevSecOps processes. This leads to frustrating bottlenecks for developers attempting to build and deliver software. For multinational enterprises, the cost of all that toil, complexity, and frustration multiplies exponentially due to the size of those organizations. In such contexts, platform engineering offers a compelling solution to enable business competitiveness in a manner that significantly enhances the developer experience. A central element of platform engineering teams is a robust Internal Developer Platform (IDP), which encompasses a set of tools, services, and infrastructure that enables developers to build, test, and deploy software applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reliability indicators that matter to your business: SLOs for all data types</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reliability-indicators-that-matter-to-your-business-slos-for-all-data-types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0195_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-at-a-glance-view-of-your-systems-health-and-performance&#34;&gt;An at-a-glance view of your system’s health and performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace guides you in quickly getting the most valuable service level objectives (SLOs) set up in just a few clicks. To provide maximum freedom in selecting the service-level indicators that matter most to your business, Dynatrace combines SLOs with the power of Dynatrace Grail™ data lakehouse, the central data platform with heterogeneous and contextually linked data. Service-level objectives now utilize highly flexible Dynatrace Query Language (DQL) for all Grail data sources. This lets you build your SLOs around the indicators that matter to you and your customers—critical metrics related to availability, failure rates, request response times, or select logs and business events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
