<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/jenkins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jenkins on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/jenkins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>300,000&#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/300000-prometheus-servers-and-exporters-exposed-to-dos-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/300000-prometheus-servers-and-exporters-exposed-to-dos-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Prometheus-blog-main-image-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;300,000&amp;#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this research, we uncovered several vulnerabilities and security flaws within the Prometheus ecosystem. These findings span across three major areas: information disclosure, denial-of-service (DoS), and code execution.  We found that exposed Prometheus servers or exporters, often lacking proper authentication, allowed attackers to easily gather sensitive information, such as credentials and API keys.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Prometheus-blog-main-image-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;300,000&amp;#43; Prometheus Servers and Exporters Exposed to DoS Attacks&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-must-see-sessions-at-kubecon-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-must-see-sessions-at-kubecon-north-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-KubeCon-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who’s getting excited? Next week, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation’s flagship conference, KubeCon + CloudNativeCon, will kick off in Salt Lake City, Utah. In its ninth year, the conference has grown into more than just a technical conference—it’s a vibrant community event that offers attendees the tools, relationships, and inspiration to drive innovation in the cloud native ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-KubeCon-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5 Must-See Sessions at KubeCon North America&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS CDK Risk: Exploiting a Missing S3 Bucket Allowed Account Takeover</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-cdk-risk-exploiting-a-missing-s3-bucket-allowed-account-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-cdk-risk-exploiting-a-missing-s3-bucket-allowed-account-takeover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/AWS-CDK-blog-main-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AWS CDK Risk: Exploiting a Missing S3 Bucket Allowed Account Takeover&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In June 2024, we uncovered a security issue related to the AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK), an open-source project. This discovery adds to the six other vulnerabilities we discovered within AWS services.  The impact of this issue could, in certain scenarios (outlined in the blog), &lt;strong&gt;allow an attacker to gain administrative access to a target AWS account&lt;/strong&gt;, resulting in a full account takeover. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Foreign aliases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-foreign-aliases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-foreign-aliases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In an organisation with many repositories and developers that are frequently shifting the maintenance of OWNERS and OWNERS_ALIASES files can be tedious. In the passing year a couple of functionalities has been added to help with this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreign-aliases&#34;&gt;Foreign aliases&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid maintaining the OWNERS_ALIASES file in many repositories you can now refer to the OWNERS_ALIASES file in another repository. In the Jenkins X project we have the main OWNERS_ALIASES file in the jx-community repository. So in the jx repository the OWNERS_ALIASES file only looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Google Summer of Code 2022 project proposal template ☀️</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-google-summer-of-code-2022-project-proposal-template-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-google-summer-of-code-2022-project-proposal-template-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposal-template&#34;&gt;Proposal template&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-contact-details&#34;&gt;1. Contact details&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full name:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Country:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time zone:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Email:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Github ID:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personal blog (optional):&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Twitter/LinkedIn/others:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-gsoc-information&#34;&gt;2. GSOC information&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you participated in the Google Summer of Code previously? Please describe your experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are you applying to any other organizations this year? If so, please list them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How many hours will you devote to your GSoC project each week? Do you have any other commitments during the summer?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you ever contributed code to Jenkins X? If you have, post the Pull Request (PR) links (It’s ok if they have not been merged/approved yet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you plan on contributing to the Jenkins X project after GSoC is finished?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Were you able to install Jenkins X locally on your laptop?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If no, please explain why (Unsupported architecture, missing documentation, time constraints etc)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If yes, how was the installation experience (missing documentation, complexity etc)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you used kubernetes in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible links to the work.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have you used golang in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible some code samples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(If you are interested in the UI project) Have you worked with a frontend framework/library in the past? Please provide a brief description and if possible some code samples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-project-idea&#34;&gt;3. Project idea&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Repeat this section for as many project ideas as you want (Go in the order most likely to least likely).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Community Bonding Period with Jenkins X</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-community-bonding-period-with-jenkins-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-community-bonding-period-with-jenkins-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, I am Rajat Gupta, pursuing my bachelor’s in Information Technology. In 2022, I have been selected as a student developer in Google Summer of Code under Jenkins X. We will be building a new UI for Jenkins X. I got this news on May 20th, as I received an email from google.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-started&#34;&gt;How I started&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The technologies needed were &lt;strong&gt;Golang&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;GitOps&lt;/strong&gt;. I used golang only once before, while linting Jenkins X codebase, I only used Kubernetes once before while setting up a k3s cluster to run Jenkins X pipelines. These tasks were necessary to do for all GSoC participants. Apart from that, I was a total beginner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Final Report: Building Jenkins X UI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-building-jenkins-x-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-building-jenkins-x-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jenkins-x-new-ui&#34;&gt;Jenkins X New UI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a web application built with Golang for the backend and Sveltekit for the frontend, both of which are built together and used in the same container. To function properly, it must be installed as a helm chart with Jenkins X CRDs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟 It has light and dark themes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/gsoc-work-report-22/homepage.png&#34; alt=&#34;homepage.png&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/gsoc-work-report-22/pipelinesPage.png&#34; alt=&#34;pipelinesPage.png&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-need-a-new-ui&#34;&gt;Why need a new UI?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good UI is essential for a CI/CD tool, as not everyone is familiar with the CLI. The current UI (jx-pipeline-visualizer) is a read-only UI, the user can view the logs of PipelineActivity but neither can start nor stop the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: GSoC 2022 Final Report: Improving Supply Chain Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-improving-supply-chain-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-gsoc-2022-final-report-improving-supply-chain-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supply chain security is a rising concern in the current software era. Securing the software supply chain encompasses vulnerability remediation and the implementation of controls throughout the software development process. Due to massive increase in attacks on software supply chain and the diversity of its types, Jenkins X has to make efforts to ensure that the build process is secure. As part of securing Jenkins X installation by default I worked on both securing our own components and enabling our users to use these features in their build and release steps..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-hacktoberfest-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-hacktoberfest-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that Jenkins X will be participating in Hacktoberfest again this year! Hacktoberfest is a month-long global celebration of open source software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All backgrounds and skill levels are encouraged to participate in Hacktoberfest and join a global community of open source contributors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more about Hacktoberfest and sign up here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;contribute-to-jenkins-x&#34;&gt;Contribute to Jenkins X&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome your contributions to the Jenkins X project!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues labelled “hacktoberfest” generally indicate good first issues. However, all pull requests will count towards your Hacktoberfest challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Improve your changelogs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-improve-your-changelogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-improve-your-changelogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standard part of the Jenkins X pipelines since a long time is the execution of &lt;code&gt;jx changelog create&lt;/code&gt; that takes the commit messages between the release currently being created and the previous one and creates a change log from these. The change log is then stored as a release note in GitHub or other git provider.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the last year some improvements have landed in various Jenkins X components to improve the changelogs and their usefulness. So I’ll take this opportunity to describe these improvements and also in general give hints to how to get useful changelogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Introduction to Software Bill Of Materials</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-introduction-to-software-bill-of-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-introduction-to-software-bill-of-materials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before going through Software Bill Of Materials (SBOMs), we need to set the ground for a rising concern in the software industry which is Software Supply Chain Security. Like traditional industries, deploying a piece of a software artifact goes through multiple stages composed of collecting source code components, libraries, tools, and processes used in those stages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkins-x.io/images/sbom-guide/supply-chain.png&#34; alt=&#34;comparing the different steps in a real world supply chain with software supply chain&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Kubernetes 1.22 - Breaking change!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-kubernetes-1-22-breaking-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-kubernetes-1-22-breaking-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To allow Jenkins X to support Kubernetes 1.22, we had to update our version of Tekton. This updated version of Tekton contains breaking changes that has consequences if you made your own custom Jenkins X pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make sure that your custom pipelines continue to work after this upgrade, you must edit the resource settings in your pipelines. Otherwise your pipelines will most likely not be able to start at all, or if they do, consume a lot of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Migrate to Google Artifact Registry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-migrate-to-google-artifact-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-migrate-to-google-artifact-registry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has announced that container registry will be shut down some time after March 18, 2025. For GKE clusters created with version 1.12.0 or later of terraform-google-jx it’s unlikely that anything needs to be done, but for older clusters you should upgrade your cluster while considering our advice regarding migration from container registry to artifact registry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using a Google Service Account to run terraform you need to add the role requirement roles/artifactregistry.admin. See our guide regarding Google Service Account for details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Project ideas for Google Summer of Code 2023 ☀️</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-ideas-for-google-summer-of-code-2023-%EF%B8%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-ideas-for-google-summer-of-code-2023-%EF%B8%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have put together some project ideas as part of our application to participate in the Google Summer of Code 2023 program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-cd-events-integration-with-jenkins-x&#34;&gt;1. CD events integration with Jenkins X&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cdEvents project standardises the way systems talk to each other, which enables Interoperability between systems so they speak a common language through the cdEvents spec in the event. Creating a capability in Jenkins X that can receive and sent a cdEvent would benefit the project and the DevOps ecosystem in general, by stopping glue code used to integrate systems and power innovation by letting end users swap out tools with no effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Project proposal for Google Season of Docs 2022 📄</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-proposal-for-google-season-of-docs-2022-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-project-proposal-for-google-season-of-docs-2022-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have put together a project proposal as part of our application to participate in the Google Season of Docs 2022 program.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-proposal&#34;&gt;Project proposal&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;better-documentation-for-real-world-use-cases---jenkins-x&#34;&gt;Better documentation for real world use cases - Jenkins X&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jenkins X provides automated CI/CD for Kubernetes with Preview Environments on Pull Requests using Cloud Native pipelines from Tekton.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;problem&#34;&gt;Problem&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;End users of Jenkins X are unable to find information on how to use Jenkins X for real world use cases which includes:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Production best practices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scanning images in Jenkins X pipelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How to make your app use different configuration/secrets for each environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Observability for your apps, logging, metrics, tracing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tests (Integration, e2e)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Artifact management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Multi cluster&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integration with other tools in the cloud native sector&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;project-scope&#34;&gt;Project scope&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Audit the current Jenkins X documentation and create a friction log&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the friction log as a guide for understanding the gaps in the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interact with the Jenkins X community to create a list of top use cases&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a survey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look at the github issues and slack messages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work with the volunteers to incorporate those changes into the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Establish a feedback loop (the target customers are the end users of Jenkins X) to improve the documentation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;measuring-project-success&#34;&gt;Measuring project success&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decrease in the number of github issues raised by end users on documentation related to common real world use cases&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Short 1-2 minute videos on common tasks that end users of Jenkins X would like to perform.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;recommended-skills&#34;&gt;Recommended skills&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Must have:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Experience with github&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Communication skills to work with the Jenkins X community&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Creating online surveys&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nice to have:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basic experience with docker compose (local development scripts use compose)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Good video editing skills.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some knowledge working with the documentation of other tools in the kubernetes ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;mentorsvolunteers&#34;&gt;Mentors/Volunteers&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ankit D Mohapatra&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christoffer Vig&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mårten Svantesson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tom Hobson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project will take roughly 6 months to complete. Once the technical writer is selected, we will do an orientation to bring him up to speed. This is the timeline we have in mind, but we are flexible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Reconcile with kpt live apply</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-reconcile-with-kpt-live-apply/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-reconcile-with-kpt-live-apply/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the dawn of Jenkins X 3 the default last step of reconciling the state of the files in your cluster repository to your cluster has been to execute &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt;. You can find more details about this here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some drawbacks with &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; though. The one that made me start looking for alternatives was that if you remove a resource from your cluster repository it may not be removed from your cluster. The way deletion works with &lt;code&gt;kubectl apply&lt;/code&gt; is that it is handed the option &lt;code&gt;--prune&lt;/code&gt; which will remove resources that are not in the manifests. Except that it doesn’t always work as expected. It will only remove certain kinds of resources defined in kubectl. In my case I removed an HorizontalPodAutoscaler from my cluster repository, but it wasn’t removed from my cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Software Bill Of Materials Formats</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-formats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t understand what is Software Bill of Materials (SBOM), please read this blog post first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-sbom-formats-comparison&#34;&gt;Different SBOM formats comparison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) in the U.S. defined minimum requirements for SBOM formats:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the supplier of the software component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identifying the details about the version of the component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including unique identifiers for the component like cryptographic hash functions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including the relationships between all dependencies inside the component.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Including a timestamp of when and by whom the SBOM report was created or last modified&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this section, we discuss different kinds and formats for SBOM standards and make a brief comparison between them. Three commonly used standards achieved the NTIA minimum requirements for SBOM generation and each one results in a different final SBOM document.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog: Software Bill Of Materials generation tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-generation-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/blog-software-bill-of-materials-generation-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before you read this, you have to understand what are SBOMs and what are different formats of SBOMs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;different-sbom-generation-tools-comparison&#34;&gt;Different SBOM generation tools comparison&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you got this far, you already realize the importance of SBOM generation, and also it should meet certain requirements to achieve its purpose. Due to various requirements depending on what standard you’re following, there has to be a way to automatically generate different output formats for different standards. Also, it has to be suited for ci/cd solutions to keep up with the increasing number of releases for each organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-trends-predictions-and-strategies-for-resilience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-trends-predictions-and-strategies-for-resilience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cloud-Security-trends-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2025, &lt;strong&gt;cloud native security&lt;/strong&gt; is set to undergo transformative progress. As Chief Information Security Officer at Aqua, I’ve seen how rapidly evolving threats and operational demands are driving organizations to redefine their approach to security. The focus is no longer just on adapting to challenges—it’s about deeply embedding security into every facet of development pipelines, runtime environments, and cloud ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cloud-Security-trends-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security Trends: Predictions and Strategies for Resilience&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-uk-cybersecurity-and-resilience-impact-of-the-new-national-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-uk-cybersecurity-and-resilience-impact-of-the-new-national-bill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cyber-Security-and-Resilience-Bill-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the digital landscape rapidly evolves, the need for a robust, adaptive security strategy becomes increasingly critical. Cyber threats are becoming more sophisticated and widespread, necessitating a proactive approach to cybersecurity. The UK&amp;rsquo;s Cyber Security and Resilience Bill represents a significant stride towards fortifying the nation’s defenses against these threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Cyber-Security-and-Resilience-Bill-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enhancing UK Cybersecurity and Resilience: Impact of the New National Bill&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Theory to Practice: How to Make DevSecOps Work in Your Organization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-theory-to-practice-how-to-make-devsecops-work-in-your-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-theory-to-practice-how-to-make-devsecops-work-in-your-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-DevSecOps-Buyers-Guide-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;From Theory to Practice: How to Make DevSecOps Work in Your Organization&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Houston, we have a problem: implementing DevSecOps isn’t as straightforward as it seems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevSecOps has redefined security in modern software development, becoming the benchmark for organizational success. By embedding security into every phase of the development lifecycle, organizations can deploy faster and collaborate more efficiently while ensuring security at every step. Yet, despite its advantages, according to IDC’s 2024 DevSecOps and Software Supply Chain Security Survey, only 66% of application development teams use DevSecOps methodologies on average. If it were easy to implement, that number would be much closer to 100%. So, what’s holding teams back? Let’s explore the most common challenges—and how to address them. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/matrix-unleashes-a-new-widespread-ddos-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/matrix-unleashes-a-new-widespread-ddos-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/matrix-blog-main-text-1200x628.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aqua Nautilus researchers uncovered a new and widespread Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) campaign orchestrated by a threat actor named Matrix. Triggered by activities detected on our honeypots, this investigation dives deep into Matrix’s methods, targets, tools, and overall goals.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/matrix-blog-main-text-1200x628.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix Unleashes A New Widespread DDoS Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aqua Nautilus researchers uncovered a new and widespread Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) campaign orchestrated by a threat actor named Matrix. Triggered by activities detected on our honeypots, this investigation dives deep into Matrix’s methods, targets, tools, and overall goals.   &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-aqua-user-experience-streamlined-vulnerability-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-aqua-user-experience-streamlined-vulnerability-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Aqua-Hub-1200x628-2024%20FINAL-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Aqua Hub update is designed to take the headache out of vulnerability management, addressing common challenges like alert overload and data consistency issues. With this update, teams get a clean, streamlined view of vulnerabilities that cuts through the noise, so they can focus on the critical issues without getting lost in irrelevant details. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-Aqua-Hub-1200x628-2024%20FINAL-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New Aqua User Experience: Streamlined Vulnerability Management&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new Aqua Hub update is designed to take the headache out of vulnerability management, addressing common challenges like alert overload and data consistency issues. With this update, teams get a clean, streamlined view of vulnerabilities that cuts through the noise, so they can focus on the critical issues without getting lost in irrelevant details. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Actors Hijack Misconfigured Servers for Live Sports Streaming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-actors-hijack-misconfigured-servers-for-live-sports-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-actors-hijack-misconfigured-servers-for-live-sports-streaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/Blog-Stream_Ripping-main-text.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Threat Actors Hijack Misconfigured Servers for Live Sports Streaming&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the ever-evolving world of cybersecurity, Aqua Nautilus researchers deploy honeypots that mimic real-world development environments. During a recent threat-hunting operation, they uncovered a surprising new attack vector: threat actors using misconfigured servers to hijack environments for streaming sports events. By exploiting misconfigured JupyterLab and Jupyter Notebook applications, attackers drop live streaming capture tools and duplicate the broadcast on their illegal server, thus conducting stream ripping. In this blog, we explain how our threat hunting operation helped us uncover this and how we analyzed this attack using Aqua Tracee and Traceeshark.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Alert: TeamTNT’s Docker Gatling Gun Campaign</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-alert-teamtnts-docker-gatling-gun-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-alert-teamtnts-docker-gatling-gun-campaign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.aquasec.com/hubfs/blog-main-TeamTNT-Docker-Gun-1200x628-2024%20final.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Threat Alert: TeamTNT’s Docker Gatling Gun Campaign&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long time no see, Aqua Nautilus researchers have identified a new campaign in the making by TeamTNT, a notorious hacking group. In this campaign, TeamTNT appears to be returning to its roots while preparing for a large-scale attack on cloud native environments. The group is currently targeting exposed Docker daemons to deploy Sliver malware, a cyber worm, and cryptominers, using compromised servers and Docker Hub as the infrastructure to spread their malware.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
