<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eu on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eu on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A quick post on Chen’s algorithm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-quick-post-on-chens-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(April 19):&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yilei Chen announced the discovery of a bug in the algorithm, which he does not know how to fix. This was independently discovered by Hongxun Wu and Thomas Vidick. At present, the paper does not provide a polynomial-time algorithm for solving LWE.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a normal person — that is, a person who doesn’t obsessively follow the latest cryptography news — you probably missed last week’s cryptography bombshell. That news comes in the form of a new e-print authored by Yilei Chen, “Quantum Algorithms for Lattice Problems“, which has roiled the cryptography research community. The result is now being evaluated by experts in lattices and quantum algorithm design (&lt;em&gt;and to be clear, I am not one!&lt;/em&gt;) but if it holds up, it’s going to be quite a bad day/week/month/year for the applied cryptography community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI can assess a study’s novelty and impact various industries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-ai-can-assess-a-studys-novelty-and-impact-various-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.devopsonline.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/AI-webpost-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovative-ai-tools-in-scientific-research&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative AI tools in scientific research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s rapidly evolving world, &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; is not just transforming industries but also unlocking new opportunities for innovation across almost all sectors, including research. One such opportunity in scientific research is to create an objective method for evaluating the originality of research: an AI-powered tool for novelty scores. By assessing the novelty of studies, i.e. how surprising and innovative yet sensible these studies are, these scores enable industries such as pharmaceutical research &amp;amp; development to quickly identify and gauge areas for innovation more efficiently. This helps significantly speed up the traditional peer review processes. Professor Philipp Koellinger, Co-Founder and CEO of the preprint start-up DeSci Labs, explores how embracing AI in scientific publishing can accelerate progress and drive meaningful advancements across multiple industries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearly Half of Businesses Weaken Sustainability Goals Due to Generative AI Demands, Capgemini Report Reveals</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nearly-half-of-businesses-weaken-sustainability-goals-due-to-generative-ai-demands-capgemini-report-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google has stated that its goal to reach net-zero emissions across all its operations and value chain by 2030 is now “extremely ambitious” thanks to its data centre usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRFs, PRPs and other fantastic things</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/prfs-prps-and-other-fantastic-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/prfs-prps-and-other-fantastic-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I ran into a conversation on Twitter about the weaknesses of applied cryptography textbooks, and how they tend to spend way too much time lecturing people about Feistel networks and the boring details of AES. Some of the folks in this conversation suggested that instead of these things, we should be digging into more fundamental topics like “what is a pseudorandom function.” (I’d link to the thread itself, but today’s Twitter is basically a forgetting machine.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Schnorr and beyond (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/to-schnorr-and-beyond-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post continues a long, wonky discussion of Schnorr signature schemes and the Dilithium post-quantum signature. You may want to start with Part 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous post I discussed the intuition behind Schnorr signatures, beginning with a high-level design rationale and ending with a concrete instantiation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a reminder: our discussion began with this Tweet by Chris Peikert:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/schnorrpeikert.png?w=1024&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which we eventually developed into an abstract version of the Schnorr protocol that uses Chris’s “magic boxes” to realize part of its functionality:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
