<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Observability on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/observability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observability on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/observability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Google Cloud is using devops in Monitoring and Observability?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-google-cloud-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-google-cloud-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-8-1024x589.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving world of cloud computing, the need for efficiency, speed, and reliability has never been greater. To address these needs, many companies have embraced &lt;strong&gt;DevOps&lt;/strong&gt;, a set of practices that combine development and operations teams to streamline the entire software delivery lifecycle. But while DevOps principles are critical to improving collaboration and accelerating development, they also demand effective tools for &lt;strong&gt;monitoring&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;observability&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure the health and performance of applications at all stages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Datadog is Using DevOps in Monitoringand Observability?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-datadog-is-using-devops-in-monitoringand-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-datadog-is-using-devops-in-monitoringand-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-4-1024x579.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced world of software development and IT operations, organizations need to continuously improve their ability to deploy applications quickly, reliably, and at scale. This is where DevOps practices come into play, blending development and operations for more efficient workflows. One of the cornerstones of a successful DevOps implementation is &lt;strong&gt;monitoring and observability&lt;/strong&gt;, as it ensures real-time visibility into application performance, system health, and infrastructure. Datadog, a leading platform in this field, is at the forefront of providing these capabilities, helping DevOps teams ensure better service delivery, faster problem resolution, and enhanced operational insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating AWS Well-Architected Framework validations with Dynatrace CloudFormation templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-aws-well-architected-framework-validations-with-dynatrace-cloudformation-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/aws-light-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dynatrace | AWS&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace is proud to be the first AWS global tech partner to offer &lt;strong&gt;ready-to-use CloudFormation templates&lt;/strong&gt; for validating the Well-Architected pillars. The Dynatrace CloudFormation templates are now available in the &lt;strong&gt;AWS CloudFormation Public Extensions Registry&lt;/strong&gt;, which makes Well-Architected validation even more accessible for AWS users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynatrace and the AWS Well-Architected Framework ensure continuous optimization of cloud architecture, aligning with the key pillars of operational excellence, security, reliability, performance efficiency, cost optimization, and sustainability. Our previous blog post discussed the importance of integrating Dynatrace with the AWS Well-Architected Framework to enhance your software development lifecycle (SDLC). By leveraging Dynatrace Workflow Automation and the Site Reliability Guardian, organizations can ensure that their applications meet AWS’s best practices across all pillars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynatrace completes 2024 FedRAMP Moderate reauthorization with Rev.5 transition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dynatrace-completes-2024-fedramp-moderate-reauthorization-with-rev-5-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/Blog_-OTP-0162_1_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;FedRAMP&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-fedramp-moderate-and-transition-to-rev5&#34;&gt;Understanding FedRAMP Moderate and transition to Rev.5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP (Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program) is a government program that provides a standardized approach to security assessment, authorization, and continuous monitoring for cloud products and services for U.S. state and federal agencies. The FedRAMP Moderate baseline is designed to protect sensitive data that, if compromised, could seriously adversely affect operations, assets, or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need-to-know&#34;&gt;What you need to know&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FedRAMP Revision 5 (Rev.5) prioritizes customizing security controls for specific risks. It aligns with Cloud Service Providers, providing a baseline while allowing tailored adjustments for individual federal agencies. FedRAMP adopts a threat-based approach to security controls. Rather than a one-size-fits-all model, this methodology tailors controls based on specific threats and risks. The result is a more effective security posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AppDynamics is Revolutionizing Monitoring and Observability with DevOps</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-appdynamics-is-revolutionizing-monitoring-and-observability-with-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-appdynamics-is-revolutionizing-monitoring-and-observability-with-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-2-1024x580.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s high-speed digital world, where applications are the backbone of businesses, ensuring seamless performance isn’t just an option—it’s a necessity. With increasing complexities in IT infrastructures and user expectations soaring, tools like &lt;strong&gt;AppDynamics&lt;/strong&gt; have emerged as a game-changer. Combining the power of &lt;strong&gt;DevOps principles&lt;/strong&gt; with cutting-edge monitoring and observability solutions, AppDynamics empowers organizations to stay ahead of performance issues, ensuring smooth user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-appdynamics-and-why-does-it-matter&#34;&gt;What is AppDynamics and Why Does it Matter?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AppDynamics&lt;/strong&gt; is a leading application performance management (APM) solution that provides visibility into your application stack, from the backend infrastructure to the end-user experience. But what sets it apart? AppDynamics doesn’t just monitor—it helps &lt;strong&gt;teams observe, analyze, and act&lt;/strong&gt; in real-time. When coupled with DevOps practices, AppDynamics ensures applications are not only functioning but thriving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AWS is Using DevOps in Monitoring and Observability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-aws-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-aws-is-using-devops-in-monitoring-and-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-1-1024x577.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the evolving world of cloud computing, &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;/strong&gt; has embraced &lt;strong&gt;DevOps practices&lt;/strong&gt; to revolutionize monitoring and observability. By integrating cutting-edge tools and methodologies, AWS provides comprehensive solutions that ensure system reliability, performance, and security. This blog explores how AWS leverages DevOps principles to enhance monitoring and observability, empowering organizations to optimize their applications and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-monitoring-and-observability-in-devops&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Monitoring and Observability in DevOps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Figure2-1024x469.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the distinction between monitoring and observability is crucial in the DevOps ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Elastic is using DevOps in Monitoringand Observability?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-elastic-is-using-devops-in-monitoringand-observability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-elastic-is-using-devops-in-monitoringand-observability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-7-1024x580.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced software development environment, DevOps plays a crucial role in bridging the gap between development and operations. To ensure smooth deployment cycles, optimal performance, and system reliability, monitoring, and observability are key components of the DevOps practice. Elastic, renowned for its Elastic Stack (previously known as the ELK Stack), is leveraging advanced observability tools to enhance DevOps workflows. In this blog, we will delve into how Elastic is incorporating DevOps in monitoring and observability, offering innovative solutions for enhanced visibility and performance tracking across systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observability throughout the software development lifecycle increases delivery performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/observability-throughout-the-software-development-lifecycle-increases-delivery-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Blog_-OTP-0207_-high-res-version-300x169.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, development teams suffer from a lack of automation for time-consuming tasks, the absence of standardization due to an overabundance of tool options, and insufficiently mature DevSecOps processes. This leads to frustrating bottlenecks for developers attempting to build and deliver software. For multinational enterprises, the cost of all that toil, complexity, and frustration multiplies exponentially due to the size of those organizations. In such contexts, platform engineering offers a compelling solution to enable business competitiveness in a manner that significantly enhances the developer experience. A central element of platform engineering teams is a robust Internal Developer Platform (IDP), which encompasses a set of tools, services, and infrastructure that enables developers to build, test, and deploy software applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is OpenTelemetry? An open source standard for logs, metrics, and traces</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-opentelemetry-an-open-source-standard-for-logs-metrics-and-traces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/NAM-2379-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;﻿&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is OpenTelemetry? The range of open source observability technologies can be daunting, and it’s easy to get overwhelmed. When it comes to managing complex multicloud environments and the services that run on them, however, it’s important to standardize, which is where OpenTelemetry comes in. OpenTelemtery was born from the combination of OpenCensus and OpenTracing and has emerged as the open source telemetry standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
