<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International-Law on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/international-law/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International-Law on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/international-law/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Technology &amp; National Security Reflection Series Paper 10: International Responsibility for Hacker-for-Hire Operations: The BellTrox Problem&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-national-security-reflection-series-paper-10-international-responsibility-for-hacker-for-hire-operations-the-belltrox-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anmol Dhawan* About the Author: The author is a 2021 graduate of National Law University, Delhi. Editor’s Note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author’s contribution serves as an adapted reflection to the following […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCG-NLUD’s Statement on International Cooperation to the Fifth Session of the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communication Technologies for Criminal Purposes</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ccg-nluds-statement-on-international-cooperation-to-the-fifth-session-of-the-ad-hoc-committee-to-elaborate-a-comprehensive-international-convention-on-countering-the-use-of-information-and-co/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal As an accredited stakeholder to the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc Committee”), CCG-NLUD recently participated in the Fifth Session of this key process setting the stage for first universal and legally […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Reflection Series on CCG’s Technology and National Security Law and Policy Seminar Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, CCG-NLUD will commence the latest edition of its Seminar Course on Technology and National Security Law and Policy (“the Seminar Course”). The Seminar Course is offered to interested 4th and 5th year students who are enrolled in the B.A. LL.B. (Hons.) programme at the National Law University, Delhi. The course is set […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technology and National Security Law Reflection Series Paper 5: Legality of Cyber Weapons Under International Law</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technology-and-national-security-law-reflection-series-paper-5-legality-of-cyber-weapons-under-international-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Siddharth Gautam* About the Author: The author is a 2020 graduate of National Law University, Delhi.  Editor’s note: This post is part of the Reflection Series showcasing exceptional student essays from CCG-NLUD’s Seminar Course on Technology &amp;amp; National Security Law. In the present essay, the author reflects upon the following question:  What are cyber weapons? […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Fourth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Last month, the Centre for Communication Governance at National Law University Delhi had the opportunity to participate as a stakeholder in the Fourth Session of the United Nations Ad-hoc Committee, tasked to elaborate a comprehensive international convention on countering the use of information and communications technologies (ICTs) for criminal purposes (“the Ad Hoc […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Fourth Substantive Session (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-fourth-substantive-session-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction  In Part I of this two-part blog series, we provided our readers a brief overview and observations from the discussions pertaining to the second reading of the provisions on criminalisation of offences under the proposed convention during the Fourth Session of the Ad-hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we will […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week I of the Fifth Substantive Session.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-i-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Sukanya Thapliyal Introduction Last month from April 11-21, 2023, the Ad Hoc Committee to Elaborate a Comprehensive International Convention on Countering the Use of Information and Communications Technologies (ICTs) for Criminal Purpose held its Fifth Session in Vienna. As we reported earlier, the negotiating process has reached a pivotal stage, wherein the Member Countries […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The United Nations Ad-hoc Committee for Development of an International Cybercrime Convention: Overview and Key Observations from Week II of the Fifth Substantive Session</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-united-nations-ad-hoc-committee-for-development-of-an-international-cybercrime-convention-overview-and-key-observations-from-week-ii-of-the-fifth-substantive-session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal In Part I of the two-part blog series, we briefed our readers on the developments that took place in the first week of the Fifth Session of the Ad-Hoc Committee. In Part II of the series, we aim to capture the key discussion on provisions on (i) technical assistance, (ii) preventative measures, (iii) […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Anatomy of Cyber Enabled Crimes and their Governance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-the-anatomy-of-cyber-enabled-crimes-and-their-governance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukanya Thapliyal Digital systems and Information Communication Technology (ICT) play an increasingly central role in our lives. Technological advancement has created new opportunities for cybercriminals to exploit vulnerabilities in digital systems and networks. The resulting cybercrimes can affect everyone, from government and multinational corporations to individuals. As technology continues to make deeper inroads into our lives, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
