<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Secure-Enclave on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/secure-enclave/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Secure-Enclave on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/secure-enclave/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Red Team Blues</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/book-review-red-team-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a rule, book reviews are not a thing I usually do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when I received an out-of-the-blue email from Cory Doctorow last week asking if I would review his latest book, Red Team Blues, it took a minute to overcome my initial skepticism. While I’m a fan of Cory’s work, this is a narrow/nerdy blog about cryptography, not a place where we spend much time on literature. Moreover, my only previous attempt to review a popular cryptography novel — a quick sketch of Dan Brown’s abysmal &lt;em&gt;Digital Fortress&lt;/em&gt; — did not go very well for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Weaknesses in Secure Elements and Enclaves</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hidden-weaknesses-in-secure-elements-and-enclaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hidden-weaknesses-in-secure-elements-and-enclaves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.cryptomathic.com/hubfs/blog%20%283%29.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hidden Weaknesses in Secure Elements and Enclaves&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secure elements (SE) on Android and secure enclaves on iOS have emerged as trusted hardware-backed solutions for storing and protecting sensitive information, such as cryptographic keys. They are often touted as &lt;em&gt;tamper-resistant&lt;/em&gt;, isolated, and secure environments with the highest certifications (e.g., AVA_VAN.5 under Common Criteria). However, while the hardware is robust, the &lt;strong&gt;software layers above it&lt;/strong&gt; introduce significant vulnerabilities. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog post highlights the risks of relying solely on SEs or secure enclaves, including potential &lt;strong&gt;hooking attacks&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;emulation&lt;/strong&gt;, and the implications of &lt;strong&gt;jailbroken/rooted devices&lt;/strong&gt;. We also explore how software-level weaknesses can undermine hardware-backed security. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
