<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facebook on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facebook on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Delete Your Social Media Accounts: Facebook, X, Instagram, TikTok, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-delete-your-social-media-accounts-facebook-x-instagram-tiktok-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-delete-your-social-media-accounts-facebook-x-instagram-tiktok-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to delete social media accounts, here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it on the most popular social media services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Delete Your Social Media Accounts: Facebook, X, Instagram, TikTok, and More appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp for Android Retains Deleted Contacts Locally</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whatsapp-for-android-retains-deleted-contacts-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whatsapp-for-android-retains-deleted-contacts-locally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WhatApp for Android retains contact info locally after contacts get deleted. This would allow an attacker with physical access to the device to check if the WhatsApp user had interactions with specific contacts, even though they have been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vulnerability-details&#34;&gt;Vulnerability Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a contact is deleted on WhatsApp, their information about security code changes is retained (while the chat content is not). The only way to get rid of that is to select “Clear Chat” for the contact before deleting it. Even deleting the chat itself doesn’t do it unless the “Clear Chat” operation is done first. The “security code change notifications” option must be enabled in order for this to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
