<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computerscienceandtechnology on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/computerscienceandtechnology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computerscienceandtechnology on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/computerscienceandtechnology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It’s a weird, weird quantum world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/its-a-weird-weird-quantum-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1994, as Professor Peter Shor PhD ’85 tells it, internal seminars at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Labs were lively affairs. The audience of physicists was an active and inquisitive bunch, often pelting speakers with questions throughout their talks. Shor, who worked at Bell Labs at the time, remembers several occasions when a speaker couldn’t get past their third slide, as they attempted to address a rapid line of questioning before their time was up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janabel Xia: Algorithms, dance rhythms, and the drive to succeed</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/janabel-xia-algorithms-dance-rhythms-and-the-drive-to-succeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/janabel-xia-algorithms-dance-rhythms-and-the-drive-to-succeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Senior math major Janabel Xia is a study of a person in constant motion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When she isn’t sorting algorithms and improving traffic control systems for driverless vehicles, she’s dancing as a member of at least four dance clubs. She’s joined several social justice organizations, worked on cryptography and web authentication technology, and created a polling app that allows users to vote anonymously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In her final semester, she’s putting the pedal to the metal, with a green light to lessen the carbon footprint of urban transportation by using sensors at traffic light intersections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerry Emanuel,  David Sabatini, and Peter Shor receive BBVA Frontiers of Knowledge awards</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kerry-emanuel-david-sabatini-and-peter-shor-receive-bbva-frontiers-of-knowledge-awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBVA Foundation awarded three MIT professors Frontiers of Knowledge Awards for their work in climate change, biology and biomedicine, and quantum computation. Department of Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Sciences Professor Kerry A. Emanuel, Department of Biology Professor David Sabatini, and Department of Mathematics Professor Peter Shor were recognized in the 12th edition of this annual award.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kerry Emanuel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emanuel, the Cecil and Ida Green Professor of Atmospheric Science, earned the BBVA’s Climate Change award “for his fundamental contributions to the understanding of tropical cyclones and how they are affected by climate change,” according to the committee’s citation. “By understanding the essential physics of atmospheric convection … he has unraveled the behavior of tropical cyclones — hurricanes and typhoons — as our climate changes.” He was also lauded for “extraordinary effectiveness in communicating the science of climate change to the public and policymakers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT launches new data privacy-focused initiative</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mit-launches-new-data-privacy-focused-initiative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategic use of data is vital for progress in science, commerce, and even politics, but at the same time, citizens are demanding more responsible, respectful use of personal data. Internet users have never felt more helpless about how their data are being used: Surveys show that the vast majority of U.S. adults feel that they have little to no control over the data that the government and private companies collect about them. In response to these concerns, new privacy laws are being enacted in Europe, California, Virginia, and elsewhere around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peter Shor wins Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/peter-shor-wins-breakthrough-prize-in-fundamental-physics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Peter Shor, the Morss Professor of Applied Mathematics at MIT, has been named a recipient of the 2023 Breakthrough Prize in Fundamental Physics. He shares the $3 million prize with three others for “foundational work in the field of quantum information”: David Deutsch at the University of Oxford, Charles Bennett at IBM Research, and Gilles Brassard of the University of Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In announcing the award, the Breakthrough Prize Foundation highlighted Shor’s contributions to the quantum information field, including the eponymous Shor’s algorithm for factoring extremely large numbers, and for an algorithm to correct errors in quantum computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School of Engineering welcomes new faculty</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/school-of-engineering-welcomes-new-faculty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The School of Engineering welcomes 15 new faculty members across six of its academic departments. This new cohort of faculty members, who have either recently started their roles at MIT or will start within the next year, conduct research across a diverse range of disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of these new faculty specialize in research that intersects with multiple fields. In addition to positions in the School of Engineering, a number of these faculty have positions at other units across MIT. Faculty with appointments in the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) report into both the School of Engineering and the MIT Stephen A. Schwarzman College of Computing. This year, new faculty also have joint appointments between the School of Engineering and the School of Humanities, Arts, and Social Sciences and the School of Science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward a code-breaking quantum computer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/toward-a-code-breaking-quantum-computer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most recent email you sent was likely encrypted using a tried-and-true method that relies on the idea that even the fastest computer would be unable to efficiently break a gigantic number into factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quantum computers, on the other hand, promise to rapidly crack complex cryptographic systems that a classical computer might never be able to unravel. This promise is based on a quantum factoring algorithm proposed in 1994 by Peter Shor, who is now a professor at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yael Tauman Kalai PhD ’06 awarded 2022 ACM Prize in Computing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yael-tauman-kalai-phd-06-awarded-2022-acm-prize-in-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yael-tauman-kalai-phd-06-awarded-2022-acm-prize-in-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yael Tauman Kalai PhD ’06, an MIT Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS) adjunct professor, member of the MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL), and senior principal researcher at Microsoft Research has been awarded the 2022 ACM Prize in Computing for “breakthroughs in verifiable delegation of computation and fundamental contributions to cryptography” by the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM). The $250,000 prize recognizes early-to-mid-career computer scientists who have made key research contributions to the field, such as Kalai’s influence on modern cryptographic practices. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
