<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-Beacon on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/the-beacon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-Beacon on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/the-beacon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is America Poised to Overreact to DeepSeek?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-america-poised-to-overreact-to-deepseek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-america-poised-to-overreact-to-deepseek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last several days have been dubbed a “Sputnik moment” for Americans, who are discovering that foreign software engineers are much further ahead than previously thought. On January 20th, the Chinese company DeepSeek announced the release of their newest large language model (LLM) “DeepSeek R1.” Reportedly trained for just $6 million, DeepSeek R1 achieves capabilities that more than rival the output of American AI giants like Anthropic, OpenAI, Meta and Google, whose models have required billions in investment. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Should Increase High-Skilled Immigration</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trump-should-increase-high-skilled-immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/trump-should-increase-high-skilled-immigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk’s and Vivek Ramaswamy’s support for increasing high-skilled immigration visas has stirred up a political storm within conservative circles. Although Trump has supported Musk’s and Ramaswamy’s comments, his words conflict with his first-term immigration policies. If his change in rhetoric is matched by a change in policy, it would help make America great.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Musk and Ramaswamy, whom Trump has tasked with improving government efficiency, both recently suggested that increasing the number of high-skill H-1B visas would improve the U.S. economy. Musk wrote on X that more H-1B visas are needed because “There is a permanent shortage of excellent engineering talent. It is the fundamental limiting factor in Silicon Valley.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congress Must Stop Trading Stocks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/congress-must-stop-trading-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/congress-must-stop-trading-stocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Legislators—Congressmen and Senators—routinely receive material non-public information that is crucial to crafting legislation for the US government to operate efficiently and meet the needs of the American people. Unfortunately, many legislators use this information to enrich themselves at the expense of the very people they are elected to represent. Using privileged information for personal gain is a tremendous abuse of power and tantamount to graft. Service in the Congress is an honor. Legislators, senior officials in the executive and judicial branches, and their families should be prohibited from trading in individual securities. Those officials who have profited from this abuse of power have revealed their lack of moral fiber and should no longer serve in government. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Of Budgets and Biases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/of-budgets-and-biases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/of-budgets-and-biases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Austrian economist Gene Callahan likes to remind us that fantasy is not an adult policy option.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are often reminded of his words in national debates and handwringing over potential budget cuts, whether by the Republican-led Congress, or President Trump’s new Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE)—or attempts to address the $36 trillion debt elephant in the room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Economist Bryan Caplan has pointed out a number of systematically biased beliefs American voters hold about the economy. Generally, Americans tend to hold four basic biases about the economy: an anti-market bias, leading to favor government intervention; an anti-foreign bias, which leads them to underestimate the contributions of foreigners and the benefits of trade; a make-work bias, which equates prosperity with the number of jobs (regardless of productivity or value added); and a pessimism bias, which leads them to think that economic conditions are far worse than they really are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Resurgence of Tariffs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resurgence-of-tariffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resurgence-of-tariffs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump imposed a 25% tariffs on Canadian and Mexican imports and a further 10% tariff on Chinese imports, to take effect on Feb. 1. In doing so Trump built on tariffs he put into effect during his first term—tariffs that President Joe Biden largely kept in place or added to. This resurgence of tariffs provide a good reason for revisiting economic history and what the science of economics tells us about international trade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bureaucrats Ordered to Go Back to Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bureaucrats-ordered-to-go-back-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bureaucrats-ordered-to-go-back-to-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The offices where Washington D.C.’s bureaucrats work were largely empty on Monday, January 20, 2025, as Donald Trump was inaugurated as U.S. President for the second time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But they weren’t empty for the inauguration. Because that Monday coincided with the Martin Luther King Jr. Day federal holiday, most U.S. government employees had a paid day off work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But then, many of the federal government’s buildings continued to sit empty on Tuesday, January 21, and again on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Republic of Georgia on Economic Freedom</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-republic-of-georgia-on-economic-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-republic-of-georgia-on-economic-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a child, I was told by many people that the United States was the only free country in the world, the land of the free, which implicitly suggested that every other country was somehow not free. I thought that other countries were tyrannical states, which subjugated their citizens and treated them like slaves. As I grew older, I realized that nothing was further from the truth. A myriad of free societies exist throughout the world, many of which are free in ways that are completely different from the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neoliberalism Never Happened</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/neoliberalism-never-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/neoliberalism-never-happened/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neoliberalism is a myth. The concept suggests that starting in the 1970s Western economies have been shaped by free-market principles, the state has retreated, and markets have reigned supreme. And yet, the last fifty years were not about liberalizing, but about strengthening the state. Neoliberalism never happened. Instead, what unfolded was neostatism—a strategy where governments restructured their role to protect and expand their power. From the late 1970s onward, policies branded as “neoliberal” were crafted not to relinquish state control but to reassert it. And today, as overt state intervention returns with a vengeance, it becomes clear that the “neoliberal era” was a carefully managed illusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Banking Surveillance Industrial Complex</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-banking-surveillance-industrial-complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-banking-surveillance-industrial-complex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bombshell report was released in December of 2024 by the House Judiciary Committee, revealing that a massive and constitutionally dubious surveillance operation has been underway by the federal government against countless Americans. Titled, &lt;em&gt;“How the Federal Government Weaponized the Bank Secrecy Act to Spy on Americans,”&lt;/em&gt; its key findings demonstrate that the FBI and the Treasury Department’s Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) have been working together to undermine the 4th Amendment and conduct widespread &lt;em&gt;warrantless surveillance&lt;/em&gt; on the financial transactions of innocent U.S. citizens engaging in constitutionally protected behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Governments Fail, Private Initiative Is the Solution</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-governments-fail-private-initiative-is-the-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-governments-fail-private-initiative-is-the-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a disturbing number of incidents in recent years, local governments have withheld critical services, resulting in destruction and death. Consider, for example, the mass shooting in Uvalde, Texas, on May 24, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement officers waited for 77 minutes inside Robb Elementary School before confronting and killing the active shooter who murdered 21 people—19 children and two teachers—and trapped 36 people in a room, many of whom were shot and dying. In the final incident review by the U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General Merrick Garland called the law enforcement response “a failure,” but “criminal” is likely more accurate. Two of the responding officers will go on trial in Texas in October 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Am I Racist? Stand the Test of Time?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/will-am-i-racist-stand-the-test-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/will-am-i-racist-stand-the-test-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am I Racist?&lt;/em&gt;, Matt Walsh’s searing attack on Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI) initiatives, dominated the documentary film box office in 2024. Screening in 1,600 theaters at its height, the film earned $12.3 million before streaming on the Daily Wire. Walsh’s film grossed more at the box office than any other documentary since 2019. That’s when Peter Jackson’s artistically boundary-pushing World War I film &lt;em&gt;They Shall Not Grow Old&lt;/em&gt; brought in $12.2 million. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
