<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virus on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/virus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virus on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/virus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-23114: Critical Vulnerability in Veeam Backup Products</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-23114-critical-vulnerability-in-veeam-backup-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-23114-critical-vulnerability-in-veeam-backup-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A critical security vulnerability identified as CVE-2025-23114 affects multiple Veeam backup products. This vulnerability resides within the Veeam Updater component and allows attackers to execute arbitrary code on the affected server through a Man-in-the-Middle (MitM) attack. The issue arises from a failure to properly validate TLS certificates during the update process. Understanding the Vulnerability CVE-2025-23114 […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post CVE-2025-23114: Critical Vulnerability in Veeam Backup Products appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazarus Group Targets Organizations with Sophisticated LinkedIn Recruiting Scam</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lazarus-group-targets-organizations-with-sophisticated-linkedin-recruiting-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lazarus-group-targets-organizations-with-sophisticated-linkedin-recruiting-scam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitdefender Labs warns of an active campaign by the North Korea-linked Lazarus Group, targeting organizations by capturing credentials and delivering malware through fake LinkedIn job offers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn may be a vital tool for job seekers and professionals, but it has also become a playground for cybercriminals exploiting its credibility. From fake job offers and elaborate phishing schemes to scams and even state-sponsored threat actors who prey on people’s career aspirations and trust in profess&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outsmart, Outpace, and Outlast Threats in Multicloud Environments</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/outsmart-outpace-and-outlast-threats-in-multicloud-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/outsmart-outpace-and-outlast-threats-in-multicloud-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a multicloud reality, coming up with a thoroughly satisfying answer to the question of security has created a host of problems for those IT pros who attempt to find the ideal solutions. Their attempts alone create a fragmented approach to cloud security which simply goes against the main objective of fortification. And when dealing […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Outsmart, Outpace, and Outlast Threats in Multicloud Environments appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Thorn in your Security: RCE Flaws discovered in Cacti</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-thorn-in-your-security-rce-flaws-discovered-in-cacti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/a-thorn-in-your-security-rce-flaws-discovered-in-cacti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cacti is an open-source network monitoring and graphing tool that helps visualize and track network performance, server health, and device availability. It leverages Round Robin Database Tool (RRD Tool) to store data and generate real-time graphs, making it popular for IT infrastructure monitoring. A critical vulnerability tracked as CVE-2025-22604, with a CVSS score of 9.1 […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post A Thorn in your Security: RCE Flaws discovered in Cacti appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Hygiene Checklist for 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-hygiene-checklist-for-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-hygiene-checklist-for-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The digital world has become an inseparable part of our lives and so have the threats that come with it. Cyberattacks are getting smarter, faster, and harder to detect. In 2025, businesses and individuals alike must treat cybersecurity like personal hygiene, a regular routine to stay safe. Cyber hygiene is the practice of maintaining systems, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cyber Hygiene Checklist for 2025 appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect Your Systems: VMware Avi Load Balancer Hit by High-Risk SQL Injection Flaw</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-systems-vmware-avi-load-balancer-hit-by-high-risk-sql-injection-flaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protect-your-systems-vmware-avi-load-balancer-hit-by-high-risk-sql-injection-flaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction Cybersecurity is a top priority for businesses worldwide, and vulnerabilities in critical software can have dire consequences. A recent high-severity flaw discovered in VMware Avi Load Balancer has raised alarms for IT teams and security professionals. This vulnerability tracked as CVE-2025-22217, could potentially allow cybercriminals to gain unauthorized access to sensitive database information, posing […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Protect Your Systems: VMware Avi Load Balancer Hit by High-Risk SQL Injection Flaw appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Vulnerability Management &amp; Cybersecurity Trends to Look For in 2025&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerability-management-cybersecurity-trends-to-look-for-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerability-management-cybersecurity-trends-to-look-for-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Phew. What a year 2024 was. High-profile attacks, rapid digital transformation, and the elephant in the room, AI, of course. These events have changed the cybersecurity world and will have longstanding ramifications! But what about cybersecurity trends in 2025? The year 2025 is set to redefine the cybersecurity landscape and could be a significant year […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Vulnerability Management &amp;amp; Cybersecurity Trends to Look For in 2025 appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Releases Critical Security Updates January 2025 – Patch Now!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-releases-critical-security-updates-january-2025-patch-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-releases-critical-security-updates-january-2025-patch-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oracle has released its Critical Patch Update (CPU) for January 2025, addressing 318 new security patches across various product families, including Oracle Database Server, Oracle MySQL, Oracle Communications, Oracle E-Business Suite, Oracle Fusion Middleware, and more. This update mitigates vulnerabilities in both Oracle code and third-party components. Oracle strongly recommends applying these patches immediately to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Oracle Releases Critical Security Updates January 2025 – Patch Now! appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urgent: Patch Now! Critical Zero-Day CVE-2025-23006 Targets SonicWall SMA Appliances</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/urgent-patch-now-critical-zero-day-cve-2025-23006-targets-sonicwall-sma-appliances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/urgent-patch-now-critical-zero-day-cve-2025-23006-targets-sonicwall-sma-appliances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CVE-2025-23006 is a critical zero-day vulnerability affecting SonicWall Secure Mobile Access (SMA) 1000 series appliances. This vulnerability, categorized as a deserialization of untrusted data flaws, resides within the Appliance Management Console (AMC) and Central Management Console (CMC). Exploited by remote attackers without requiring authentication, this vulnerability allows for executing arbitrary code on the affected devices, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Urgent: Patch Now! Critical Zero-Day CVE-2025-23006 Targets SonicWall SMA Appliances appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Reducing R&amp;D Costs and Speeding Up Time-to-Market – How Integrating SecPod Can Help Businesses&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-rd-costs-and-speeding-up-time-to-market-how-integrating-secpod-can-help-businesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reducing-rd-costs-and-speeding-up-time-to-market-how-integrating-secpod-can-help-businesses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to product development, Technology Vendors are under immense pressure to innovate rapidly, reduce costs, and maintain end-to-end security. This trifecta of challenges often strains resources, delays launches and impacts customer satisfaction. However, integrating SecPod’s advanced technology solutions into the product development lifecycle offers a strategic way to overcome these obstacles. In this […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Reducing R&amp;amp;D Costs and Speeding Up Time-to-Market – How Integrating SecPod Can Help Businesses appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Code Execution Vulnerability (CVE-2025-0411) Detected in 7-Zip</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-code-execution-vulnerability-cve-2025-0411-detected-in-7-zip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-code-execution-vulnerability-cve-2025-0411-detected-in-7-zip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A critical security vulnerability identified as CVE-2025-0411 has been detected in 7-Zip, a widely used file archiver. With a CVSS score of 7.0, this vulnerability allows attackers to bypass the Windows “Mark-of-the-Web” (MotW) security feature. If exploited, it could lead to the execution of malicious code on a victim’s system. Understanding the Vulnerability CVE-2025-0411 What […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Critical Code Execution Vulnerability (CVE-2025-0411) Detected in 7-Zip appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Accelerate Product Development with Integrated Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-accelerate-product-development-with-integrated-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-accelerate-product-development-with-integrated-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a hyper-competitive landscape today, OEMs must innovate quickly to stay ahead. However, the race to market often overlooks a critical factor: security. Neglecting security in product development can lead to costly breaches, compliance issues, and damage to customer trust. Integrated security offers a solution, allowing OEMs to build robust security measures into their products […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Accelerate Product Development with Integrated Security  appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Security Best Practices That Every User Should Implement</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-best-practices-that-every-user-should-implement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-best-practices-that-every-user-should-implement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cloud has become a foundational element of modern business operations due to its far-reaching scalability, adaptability, and cost-effectiveness. However, as more companies adopt cloud computing, the dangers of cyber threats and security violations increase. That’s why implementing preventive measures for cloud security is imperative to safeguard a business’s sensitive data, infrastructure, and vital applications. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cloud Security Best Practices That Every User Should Implement appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Path Traversal Vulnerabilities (CVE-2024-10811, CVE-2024-13161, CVE-2024-13160, and CVE-2024-13159) in Ivanti Endpoint Manager</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-path-traversal-vulnerabilities-cve-2024-10811-cve-2024-13161-cve-2024-13160-and-cve-2024-13159-in-ivanti-endpoint-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-path-traversal-vulnerabilities-cve-2024-10811-cve-2024-13161-cve-2024-13160-and-cve-2024-13159-in-ivanti-endpoint-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ivanti, an IT management solutions, has identified and addressed four critical vulnerabilities in its Endpoint Manager (EPM) software. These vulnerabilities, identified as CVE-2024-10811, CVE-2024-13161, CVE-2024-13160, and CVE-2024-13159, have been assigned a CVSS score of 9.8, indicating their high severity. Understanding the Vulnerabilities These vulnerabilities involve absolute path traversal flaws that allow remote, unauthenticated attackers to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Critical Path Traversal Vulnerabilities (CVE-2024-10811, CVE-2024-13161, CVE-2024-13160, and CVE-2024-13159) in Ivanti Endpoint Manager appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Patches 159 Flaws, 8 Zero Days in January 2025 Patch Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-patches-159-flaws-8-zero-days-in-january-2025-patch-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-patches-159-flaws-8-zero-days-in-january-2025-patch-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 is upon us! We’re ringing in the new year with – you guessed it – another Patch Tuesday. This year’s curtains open with 159 fixes, eight zero-days, and 12 critical flaws. 58 of the flaws found could result in Remote Code Execution. The following chart shows the number of vulnerabilities found in each category. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Microsoft Patches 159 Flaws, 8 Zero Days in January 2025 Patch Tuesday appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Vulnerability Uncovered: CVE-2025-0282 Puts Ivanti Systems at Risk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-vulnerability-uncovered-cve-2025-0282-puts-ivanti-systems-at-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-vulnerability-uncovered-cve-2025-0282-puts-ivanti-systems-at-risk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ivanti has disclosed a critical vulnerability identified as CVE-2025-0282, affecting several of its products, including Ivanti Connect Secure, Policy Secure, and Neurons for ZTA gateways. With a CVSS Score of 9.0, this stack-based buffer overflow vulnerability allows remote, unauthenticated attackers to execute arbitrary code on the target device, posing significant security risks to affected systems. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Critical Vulnerability Uncovered: CVE-2025-0282 Puts Ivanti Systems at Risk appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research that builds detections</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/research-that-builds-detections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/research-that-builds-detections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You can view the full content of the blog here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detection engineering is becoming increasingly important in surfacing new malicious activity. Threat actors might take advantage of previously unknown malware families - but a successful detection of certain methodologies or artifacts can help expose the entire infection chain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In previous blog posts, we announced the integration of Sigma rules for macOS and Linux into VirusTotal, as well as ways in which Sigma rules can be converted to YARA to take advantage of VirusTotal Livehunt capabilities. In this post, we will show different approaches to hunt for interesting samples and derive new Sigma detection opportunities based on their behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Tips to protect your devices from malware attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/8-tips-to-protect-your-devices-from-malware-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/8-tips-to-protect-your-devices-from-malware-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, when your devices are infected with a virus, it’s not as easy as a little bed rest for them to recover, and the damage can be long-lasting. A cyberattack can compromise your computers, phones and tablets, and open the door for cyber thieves to steal your sensitive personal information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to a study by the University of Maryland’s A. James Clark School of Engineering, there is a cyberattack approximately every 39 seconds. The most common form of cyberattack is malware, a type of software that’s used to break into your computer system. Last year alone, there were more than 6 billion malware attacks detected worldwide. Some of the many forms of malware include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>American Radio Relay League Paid $1 Million Ransom</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/american-radio-relay-league-paid-1-million-ransom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/american-radio-relay-league-paid-1-million-ransom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The American Radio Relay League (ARRL), a prominent national association for amateur radio enthusiasts, recently confirmed that it paid a staggering $1 million ransom to cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;arrl-hit-by-cyber-attack&#34;&gt;ARRL Hit by Cyber Attack&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARRL found itself at the mercy of a sophisticated ransomware attack. Upon realizing the severity of the attack, the ARRL was left with limited options. The decision to pay the $1 million ransom was not made lightly, but it was deemed necessary to regain access to critical data and ensure the organization’s continued operation. The move, while effective in recovering data, raises ethical and practical concerns about the long-term implications of complying with ransom demands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Rhadamanthys Malware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/analysis-of-rhadamanthys-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/analysis-of-rhadamanthys-malware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the final quarter of 2022, the infostealer malware, Rhadamanthys, was found. Given that it could target browser extensions and wallet clients installed on the victim’s computer, its capabilities demonstrated a particular interest in cryptocurrency wallets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary means of distribution for this threat that have been noticed are phishing emails and phony software websites that are advertised through Google Ads, regardless of the vertical or region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although its distribution and information theft methods have been observed previously, its downloader component makes it stand out. It analyzes by conventional security methods extremely difficult by combining sophisticated anti-analysis techniques with heavy obfuscation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cleo MFT Mass Exploitation Payload Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cleo-mft-mass-exploitation-payload-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cleo-mft-mass-exploitation-payload-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written by ARC Labs contributors, John Dwyer and Eric Gonzalez ARC Labs recently capture and analyzed the second and third stage payloads used during a Cleo MFT compromise. The compromise is a result of exploitation of CVE-2024-50623 which allows for unauthorized remote code execution. Additional reports suggest that exploitation of the vulnerability continues to be possible even after […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cleo MFT Mass Exploitation Payload Analysis appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Security Resolutions for a Threat-Free 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-resolutions-for-a-threat-free-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cloud-security-resolutions-for-a-threat-free-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the New Year begins, most people are busy crafting their resolutions; promises to hit the gym, learn a new skill, or break an old habit. Businesses navigating the complex digital landscape, on the other hand, face an evolving challenge of critical significance. Fortifying cloud security emerges as the ultimate strategic imperative for organizational resilience.  […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cloud Security Resolutions for a Threat-Free 2025  appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Dell SupportAssist Vulnerability          (CVE-2024-52535) Exploited</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-dell-supportassist-vulnerability-cve-2024-52535-exploited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/critical-dell-supportassist-vulnerability-cve-2024-52535-exploited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dell announced a critical security vulnerability affecting its SupportAssist software, widely used for system diagnostics and updates on Dell PCs. Identified as CVE-2024-52535, this flaw poses significant risks to cybersecurity experts and end-users. Understanding the Vulnerability Dell SupportAssist versions up to 4.6.1 for Home PCs and up to 4.5.0 for Business PCs contain a symbolic […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Critical Dell SupportAssist Vulnerability (CVE-2024-52535) Exploited appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Moneyball Part 1: Managed Deception for Easy Outs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-moneyball-part-1-managed-deception-for-easy-outs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-moneyball-part-1-managed-deception-for-easy-outs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When your enemies are making mistakes, don&amp;rsquo;t interrupt them. They’re just giving you an out, man. They’re just giving it to you. Take it and say thank you.&amp;rdquo; (Moneyball [Motion Picture], Columbia Pictures)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cybersecurity Moneyball Part 1: Managed Deception for Easy Outs  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity Moneyball Part 2: Binary Defense’s New Paradigm in Malware Detection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-moneyball-part-2-binary-defenses-new-paradigm-in-malware-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-moneyball-part-2-binary-defenses-new-paradigm-in-malware-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fight Your Enemy Where They Aren&amp;rsquo;t - Sun Tzu&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cybersecurity Moneyball Part 2: Binary Defense’s New Paradigm in Malware Detection appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How New Year Traffic Stresses Your Cloud Security (And What to Do About It)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-new-year-traffic-stresses-your-cloud-security-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-new-year-traffic-stresses-your-cloud-security-and-what-to-do-about-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The New Year is here — a time for fresh beginnings, renewed goals, and ambitious business plans. However, it’s also a period where cybercriminals remain active, exploiting vulnerabilities that arise during high-traffic events and transitions into the new calendar year.  While your focus is on starting the year strong and setting goals for growth, hackers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How New Year Traffic Stresses Your Cloud Security (And What to Do About It)  appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Our Dedicated Resources Differ from Staff Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-our-dedicated-resources-differ-from-staff-augmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-our-dedicated-resources-differ-from-staff-augmentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Integrating Binary Defense Dedicated Security Resources into your team brings deeper insights and proactive defense, far beyond what staff augmentation can offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How Our Dedicated Resources Differ from Staff Augmentation  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Define Your Security Objectives Before Choosing an MDR Provider</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-define-your-security-objectives-before-choosing-an-mdr-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-define-your-security-objectives-before-choosing-an-mdr-provider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With nearly every MSSP and Security company claiming to do Managed Detection and Response (MDR) it’s more important than ever to choose the right MDR provider. Before you start evaluating potential partners, it’s crucial to step back and clearly define your organization’s security objectives. This not only helps in selecting the right provider but also […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to Define Your Security Objectives Before Choosing an MDR Provider  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From the Field: How a Hospital Turned Cyber Challenges Into a Success Story</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-field-how-a-hospital-turned-cyber-challenges-into-a-success-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-field-how-a-hospital-turned-cyber-challenges-into-a-success-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day, a renowned hospital serves the needs of over a million patients, delivering not only world-class care but also hope for healthier futures. But behind the scenes, the hospital’s small but mighty security team was feeling the strain. With two hospital campuses, multiple regional centers, and more than 50 care locations, the pressure to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Lessons From the Field: How a Hospital Turned Cyber Challenges Into a Success Story  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Field: How a Manufacturing Giant Transformed Its Security Posture</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-field-how-a-manufacturing-giant-transformed-its-security-posture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lessons-from-the-field-how-a-manufacturing-giant-transformed-its-security-posture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The complexities of cybersecurity often seem insurmountable for large enterprises. For one global manufacturing company, this was a lived reality. With a workforce of over 60,000 employees, more than 450,000 clients, and a steady stream of mergers and acquisitions, their security team faced challenges that felt increasingly impossible to solve. Yet, their journey toward building […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Lessons from the Field: How a Manufacturing Giant Transformed Its Security Posture  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Palo Alto PAN-OS Severe Vulnerability (CVE-2024-3393) Exploited</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/palo-alto-pan-os-severe-vulnerability-cve-2024-3393-exploited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/palo-alto-pan-os-severe-vulnerability-cve-2024-3393-exploited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Palo Alto announced a critical security vulnerability affecting its PAN-OS software. PAN-OS is the operating system developed by Palo Alto Networks for its network security devices, which is used to provide advanced security features.The vulnerability tracked as CVE-2024-3393 can cause a denial of services (DoS) condition on susceptible devices. Understanding the Vulnerability Rated as High, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Palo Alto PAN-OS Severe Vulnerability (CVE-2024-3393) Exploited appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhadamanthys Stealer Analysis for Detection Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rhadamanthys-stealer-analysis-for-detection-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rhadamanthys-stealer-analysis-for-detection-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written by ARC Labs contributor, Shannon Mong Threat Overview  Binary Defense ARC Labs’ threat researchers recently dissected a Rhadamanthys Stealer infection chain to uncover detection opportunities that defenders can leverage to strengthen organizational security. In this analysis, we provide general detection guidance and actionable queries for detecting Rhadamanthys Stealer.  Recent Campaign Insights  Rhadamanthys Stealer surfaced on underground […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Rhadamanthys Stealer Analysis for Detection Opportunities  appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shining a Light in the Dark – How Binary Defense Uncovered an APT Lurking in Shadows of IT</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/shining-a-light-in-the-dark-how-binary-defense-uncovered-an-apt-lurking-in-shadows-of-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/shining-a-light-in-the-dark-how-binary-defense-uncovered-an-apt-lurking-in-shadows-of-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written by ARC Labs contributors, John Dwyer, Eric Gonzalez at Binary Defense and Tyler Hudak at TrustedSec In cybersecurity, the threats we don’t see—or don’t expect—often pose the greatest danger. Recently, this became all too clear when three unmanaged AIX servers, sitting exposed on the internet, opened the door for a China-Nexus Threat Actor to launch an […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Shining a Light in the Dark – How Binary Defense Uncovered an APT Lurking in Shadows of IT appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Analysis: Killer Ultra Malware Targeting EDR Products in Ransomware Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technical-analysis-killer-ultra-malware-targeting-edr-products-in-ransomware-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/technical-analysis-killer-ultra-malware-targeting-edr-products-in-ransomware-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was written by John Dwyer, Director of Security Research at Binary Defense, and made possible through the contributions of TrustedSec Senior Research Analyst Kevin Haubris and Eric Gonzalez of Binary Defense. ARC Labs recently recovered a tool leveraged in Qilin ransomware attacks aimed at impairing defenses by disabling popular endpoint detection and response […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Technical Analysis: Killer Ultra Malware Targeting EDR Products in Ransomware Attacks appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Imperative of Threat Hunting for a Mature Security Posture</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-imperative-of-threat-hunting-for-a-mature-security-posture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-imperative-of-threat-hunting-for-a-mature-security-posture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Threat Hunting has transitioned from being a luxury to a fundamental necessity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post The Imperative of Threat Hunting for a Mature Security Posture   appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Open Source Firewall for Network Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-open-source-firewall-for-network-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-open-source-firewall-for-network-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A firewall is a security system that is used to control network traffic and prevent unauthorized access to a network. It acts as a machinery between a private network and the internet, allowing only authorized traffic to go through. Firewalls have evolved from simple packet filters to modern Next-Generation Firewalls with advanced features. Firewalls can be hardware or software-based either commercial or open-source.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In today’s interconnected world, network security is crucial for any business. Hackers are constantly trying to breach company networks and steal valuable data. One essential tool in securing network infrastructure is a firewall. A firewall is a network security system that monitors and controls incoming and outgoing network traffic based on security rules and parameters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding DDoS Attacks: A Comprehensive Guide</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-ddos-attacks-a-comprehensive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-ddos-attacks-a-comprehensive-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Businesses and services rely heavily on online presence, the threat of cyberattacks looms large. Among these threats, Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks stand out due to their ability to paralyze websites and online services. A DDoS attack occurs when multiple compromised systems target a single system, overwhelming it with traffic and rendering it inaccessible […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Understanding DDoS Attacks: A Comprehensive Guide appeared first on SecPod Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Signaling System 7 (SS7)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-signaling-system-7-ss7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-signaling-system-7-ss7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Signaling System 7&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;SS7&lt;/strong&gt;) is a set of protocol suite telecommunication networks used to share information across the global public switched telephone network (PSTN). It was developed in the 1980s and has been used ever since. The SS7 protocol is crucial to the functioning of telecom networks, as it helps to set up and end voice calls, data transfers, and other network services. However, over its use since its inception, security flaws in the SS7 protocol have been identified which enable hackers to execute a range of many virtualattacks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Sleep Obfuscation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-sleep-obfuscation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/understanding-sleep-obfuscation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Malware Uses Sleep Cycles to Avoid Detection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Understanding Sleep Obfuscation appeared first on Binary Defense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Malware and its types?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-malware-and-its-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-malware-and-its-types/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The term “malicious software” is shortened to “malware.” Malware is invasive software that is purposefully created to harm computers and computer networks. On the other hand, software that unintentionally causes harm is typically called a software bug.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, inquiries are made regarding the distinction between malware and viruses. The distinction is that ransomware, which encompasses various online threats such as viruses, spyware, adware, and ransomware, is referred to as malware. To put it simply, one kind of malware is a computer virus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is meant by “cybersecurity”?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-meant-by-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-meant-by-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The process of protecting networks, computers, servers, mobile devices, electronic systems, and data from malicious attacks is known as cybersecurity. It is also referred to as electronic information security or information technology security. The term can be categorized into a few common categories and is used in various contexts, including business and mobile computing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The process of safeguarding a computer network against trespassers, be they malevolent actors or malicious software, is known as network security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Dark web?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-the-dark-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-the-dark-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A portion of the internet known as the “dark web” cannot be found by search engines and must be accessed through the use of the anonymizing browser Tor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A portion of the internet known as the “dark web” is not indexed by search engines. You’ve likely heard of the “dark web” being a hub for illegal activity, and this is true. After classifying the contents of 2,723 active dark web sites over five weeks in 2015, researchers Daniel Moore and Thomas Rid of King’s College in London discovered that 57% of them hosted illegal content. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xerox Printers Vulnerability Puts Data Security at Risk</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/xerox-printers-vulnerability-puts-data-security-at-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/xerox-printers-vulnerability-puts-data-security-at-risk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity experts are raising concerns over a newly discovered vulnerability in Xerox printers that could potentially compromise sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability, which affects a variety of Xerox printer models, has the potential to allow unauthorized access to both the device and any data it handles. With businesses increasingly relying on digital solutions, this vulnerability poses a significant risk to organizations worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability was initially identified by cybersecurity researchers who discovered that the printers could be manipulated to bypass security protocols. Attackers could exploit this flaw to gain control over the printers and use them as a gateway to enter an organization’s internal network. This has left many businesses scrambling to implement countermeasures, as the printers are often linked to sensitive operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>60 Hurts per Second – How We Got Access to Enough Solar Power to Run the United States</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/60-hurts-per-second-how-we-got-access-to-enough-solar-power-to-run-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/60-hurts-per-second-how-we-got-access-to-enough-solar-power-to-run-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The electricity grid – the buzzing, crackling marvel that supplies the lifeblood of modernity - is by far the largest structure humanity ever built. It’s so big, in fact, that few people even notice it, like a fish can’t see the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until the grid goes down, that is. Then, like the fish dangling from the angler’s hook, we see our vulnerability. Modernity dissolves into a sudden silence, followed by the repeated flick of a light switch, and a howl of panic at the prospect of missed appointmen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI meets next-gen info stealers in social media malvertising campaigns</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-meets-next-gen-info-stealers-in-social-media-malvertising-campaigns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-meets-next-gen-info-stealers-in-social-media-malvertising-campaigns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The impact that AI has on society has steadily crept into the darkest nooks and crannies of the internet. So much so that cybercrooks are hitching free rides on the AI bandwagon by leveraging the increased demand of AI-powered software for content creators.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cybercriminal groups constantly adapt their operating methods and tools to stay a step ahead of potential victims. Highly focused on enhancing their deceptive practices, threat actors have, unfortunately, found a most reliable and powerful a&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Malware in Binaries and Executables with AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/analyzing-malware-in-binaries-and-executables-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/analyzing-malware-in-binaries-and-executables-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent post titled &amp;ldquo;From Assistant to Analyst: The Power of Gemini 1.5 Pro for Malware Analysis&amp;rdquo;, published on the Google Cloud Security blog, we explore the capabilities of Gemini 1.5 Pro, which enhances malware analysis by processing up to 1 million tokens. This advancement allows the tool to analyze large amounts of disassembled or decompiled code in a single pass, providing a complete view of the malware&amp;rsquo;s logic to produce verdicts and summary reports. The blog post highlights practical applications of this approach, using well-known malware such as WannaCry and also entirely new and previously undetected malware. These examples show that Gemini 1.5 Pro&amp;rsquo;s reports are not based on pre-trained data of those specific samples but on its ability to analyze the code itself. For more details on how Gemini 1.5 Pro operates in malware analysis, we encourage you to read the complete post here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio deepfakes: Celebrity-endorsed giveaway scams and fraudulent investment opportunities flood social media platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/audio-deepfakes-celebrity-endorsed-giveaway-scams-and-fraudulent-investment-opportunities-flood-social-media-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/audio-deepfakes-celebrity-endorsed-giveaway-scams-and-fraudulent-investment-opportunities-flood-social-media-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitdefender Labs has been keeping up with the latest modus operandi of cybercrooks who adapt emerging technologies to siphon money from consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence is just one of the many tools that help in the creation and successful dissemination of online schemes to extort money and sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This paper focuses on voice cloning (audio deepfakes) schemes and how they are proliferated via social media to trick unsuspecting victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before delving deeper into the main subj&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COM Objects Hijacking</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/com-objects-hijacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/com-objects-hijacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COM Hijacking technique is often utilized by threat actors and various malware families to achieve both persistence and privilege escalation in target systems. It relies on manipulating Component Object Model (COM), exploiting the core architecture of Windows that enables communication between software components, by adding a new value on a specific registry key related to the COM object itself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We studied the usage of this technique by different malware samples to pinpoint the most exploited COM objects in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourced AI &#43;= ByteDefend</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdsourced-ai-bytedefend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/crowdsourced-ai-bytedefend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the integration of a new solution into our Crowdsourced AI initiative. This model, developed by Dr. Ran Dubin from the Department of Computer Science at Ariel University and head of ByteDefend Cyber Lab at the Ariel Cyber Innovation Center, is designed to analyze suspicious macros in Microsoft Office files, including Word, Excel, and PowerPoint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VirusTotal&amp;rsquo;s Crowdsourced AI initiative leverages various AI models and community contributions to strengthen cyber defense strategies. Like any other security solution, AI-based models are not infallible, but they offer invaluable contributions by complementing other technologies in analyzing and detecting new threats. The integration of ByteDefend enhances VirusTotal&amp;rsquo;s Code Insight capabilities, currently with up to three independent AI engines for Microsoft Office documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Dive on Supplement Scams: How AI Drives ‘Miracle Cures’ and Sponsored Health-Related Scams on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deep-dive-on-supplement-scams-how-ai-drives-miracle-cures-and-sponsored-health-related-scams-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deep-dive-on-supplement-scams-how-ai-drives-miracle-cures-and-sponsored-health-related-scams-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sponsored social media content has become increasingly present on feeds. Sponsored ads can often be beneficial as they are customized to suit online personas, offering relevant content tailored specifically for you. While personalized ads can help enhance your online experience, not all are legitimate. In fact, scams originating from phony ads on social media have increased dramatically, with potentially severe consequences for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sponsored supplement scams on social media platforms&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Details on Apple’s Shortcuts Vulnerability: A Deep Dive into CVE-2024-23204</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/details-on-apples-shortcuts-vulnerability-a-deep-dive-into-cve-2024-23204/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/details-on-apples-shortcuts-vulnerability-a-deep-dive-into-cve-2024-23204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CVE-2024-23204 sheds light on the critical importance of continuous security vigilance. Apple&amp;rsquo;s Shortcuts application, designed to enhance user automation, can inadvertently become a potential vector for privacy breaches. This analysis aims to provide users, developers, and security professionals with insights into the nature of the vulnerability, its potential impact, and recommended mitigation measures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a glance:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;* We have discovered a vulnerability in Apple Shortcuts that lets a potent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CVE-2024-23204 sheds light on the critical importance of continuous security vigilance. Apple&amp;rsquo;s Shortcuts application, designed to enhance user automation, can inadvertently become a potential vector for privacy breaches. This analysis aims to provide users, developers, and security professionals with insights into the nature of the vulnerability, its potential impact, and recommended mitigation measures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the VirusTotal Dataset | An Analyst&#39;s Guide to Effective Threat Research</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-the-virustotal-dataset-an-analysts-guide-to-effective-threat-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exploring-the-virustotal-dataset-an-analysts-guide-to-effective-threat-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Aleksandar Milenkoski (SentinelOne) and Jose Luis Sánchez Martínez&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VirusTotal stores a vast collection of files, URLs, domains, and IPs submitted by users worldwide. It features a variety of functionalities and integrates third-party detection engines and tools to analyze the maliciousness of submitted artifacts and gather relevant related information, such as file properties, domain registrars, and execution behaviors. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VirusTotal dataset, the backbone of the platform, structures artifact-related information into objects and represents relevant relationships between them, providing contextual links between various artifacts. This makes VirusTotal a valuable resource for threat research, enabling users to perform activities such as clustering artifacts related to specific threat actors or campaigns, tracking malicious activities, and analyzing trends in the threat landscape. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Following MITRE&#39;s footsteps in analyzing malware behavior</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/following-mitres-footsteps-in-analyzing-malware-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/following-mitres-footsteps-in-analyzing-malware-behavior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;MITRE&lt;/strong&gt; framework helps all defenders speak the same language regarding attackers&amp;rsquo; modus operandi. VirusTotal provides multiple data points where MITRE&amp;rsquo;s Tactics and Techniques are dynamically extracted from samples when detonated in our sandboxes. In particular, samples&amp;rsquo; MITRE mapping can be found under the &lt;strong&gt;BEHAVIOR&lt;/strong&gt; tab of a file&amp;rsquo;s report. This data is searchable in &lt;strong&gt;VirusTotal Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; (VTI) with the help of a set of specific file search modifiers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate how security analysts can leverage MITRE for malware detection and &lt;strong&gt;behavior&lt;/strong&gt;-based hunting for ransomware and keylogger samples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hunting for malicious domains with VT Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hunting-for-malicious-domains-with-vt-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hunting-for-malicious-domains-with-vt-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please note that this blogpost is part of our #VTMondays series, check out our collection of past publications here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many cyberattacks begin by victims visiting compromised websites that host malware or phishing scams, threat actors use domains for different malicious purposes as part of their infrastructure, and malware communicates with external sites for command and control and exfiltration. Detecting suspicious domains and preemptively feeding corporate security systems can disrupt attacks before they happen, with VT Intelligence being the perfect platform to early detect them and monitor malicious campaigns’ evolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important Update: IP Address Change for VirusTotal</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-update-ip-address-change-for-virustotal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/important-update-ip-address-change-for-virustotal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re making a change to the IP address for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virustotal.com&#34;&gt;www.virustotal.com&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re currently whitelisting our IP address in your firewall or proxy, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to update your rules to maintain access to VirusTotal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting November 25th, we&amp;rsquo;ll be gradually transitioning the resolution of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virustotal.com&#34;&gt;www.virustotal.com&lt;/a&gt; to a new IP address: &lt;strong&gt;34.54.88.138&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have hardcoded the previous IP address (74.125.34.46) in your firewall or proxy, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to update your configuration to include the new IP address. This will ensure continued access to VirusTotal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Bitdefender Labs’ Investigation of a Malicious Facebook Ad Campaign Targeting Bitwarden Users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-bitdefender-labs-investigation-of-a-malicious-facebook-ad-campaign-targeting-bitwarden-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-bitdefender-labs-investigation-of-a-malicious-facebook-ad-campaign-targeting-bitwarden-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout 2024, Bitdefender Labs has been closely monitoring a series of malvertising campaigns that exploit popular platforms to spread malware. These campaigns use fake advertisements to lure users into installing malicious software disguised as legitimate apps or updates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the more recent campaigns Bitdefender Labs uncovered involves a fake Bitwarden extension advertised on Meta’s social media platform Facebook. The campaign tricks users into installing a harmful browser extension und&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Worldwide SMS Scams, and Tens of Millions of Dollars in Fraud</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/investigating-worldwide-sms-scams-and-tens-of-millions-of-dollars-in-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/investigating-worldwide-sms-scams-and-tens-of-millions-of-dollars-in-fraud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SMS services remain a critical part of telecommunications; they don&amp;rsquo;t require Internet access, and companies use them to inform their customers. This combination of features makes them incredibly useful for criminals who use the technology as a stepping stone in their never-ending campaigns. And if you think that the new RCS messaging standard will offer any protection, you would be wrong. These types of scams will continue to spread regardless of the messaging standard used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know your enemies: An approach for CTI teams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/know-your-enemies-an-approach-for-cti-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/know-your-enemies-an-approach-for-cti-teams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VirusTotal’s &lt;strong&gt;Threat Landscape&lt;/strong&gt; can be a valuable source of operational and tactical threat intelligence for CTI teams, for instance helping us find the latest &lt;strong&gt;malware trends&lt;/strong&gt; used by a given Threat Actor to adjust our &lt;strong&gt;intelligence-led security posture&lt;/strong&gt; accordingly. In this post, we will play the role of a CTI analyst working for a Singaporean financial institution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a first step, we search for threat actors that traditionally both targeted the &lt;strong&gt;financial industry&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Singaporean companies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering VirusTotal: Certification Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mastering-virustotal-certification-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mastering-virustotal-certification-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the partnership with The SOC Academy, a new startup dedicated to providing cybersecurity education, debuting with a VirusTotal Certification course. Founded by Laura, a passionate entrepreneur and especially a cybersecurity enthusiast, The SOC Academy aims to enhance the skills and expertise of professionals in the field. Below, we dive into a conversation with Laura, exploring the motivation behind this initiative, what it offers, and her vision for the future of The SOC Academy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring malware trends with VT Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-malware-trends-with-vt-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/monitoring-malware-trends-with-vt-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please note that this blogpost is part of our #VTMondays series, check out our collection of past publications here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VT Intelligence can be a powerful tool for monitoring malware trends, enhancing your detection capabilities and enabling proactive defense against evolving threats. To leverage it effectively, analysts can refine searches with threat indicators relevant to their business, technologies and to the malware trends occurring at the moment. Analysts can use this intelligence to identify and hunt emerging malicious samples and investigate new trends and capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New macOS Backdoor Written in Rust Shows Possible Link with Windows Ransomware Group</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-macos-backdoor-written-in-rust-shows-possible-link-with-windows-ransomware-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-macos-backdoor-written-in-rust-shows-possible-link-with-windows-ransomware-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following our initial release, we have been contacted by our fellow researchers at Jamf who were able to identify three more samples that act like first-stage payloads. They are responsible for downloading the backdoor:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;* e7cab6f2be47940bf36e279bbec54ec7 - Jobinfo.app.zip * 26d6a7e3507edf9953684d367dcd44bd - Jobinfo.zip * 775851f86cbde630808ff6d2cf8cedbf - Jobinfo.zip&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Combined with information in our previous research, the investigation of these samples revealed new components of t&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following our initial release, we have been contacted by our fellow researchers at Jamf who were able to identify three more samples that act like first-stage payloads. They are responsible for downloading the backdoor:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes on ThroughTek Kalay Vulnerabilities and Their Impact on the IoT Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/notes-on-throughtek-kalay-vulnerabilities-and-their-impact-on-the-iot-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/notes-on-throughtek-kalay-vulnerabilities-and-their-impact-on-the-iot-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, Bitdefender IoT researchers have been looking into the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular IoT devices, hunting for vulnerabilities and undocumented attack avenues. This report documents four vulnerabilities affecting devices powered by the ThroughTek Kalay Platform. Due to the platform’s massive presence in IoT integrations, these flaws have a significant downstream impact on several vendors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the interconnected landscape of the Internet of Things (IoT), the reliability and security of devices,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sigma rules for Linux and MacOS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sigma-rules-for-linux-and-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sigma-rules-for-linux-and-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR&lt;/strong&gt;: VT Crowdsourced Sigma rules will now also match suspicious activity for macOS and Linux binaries, in addition to Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We recently discussed how to maximize the value of Sigma rules by easily converting them to YARA Livehunts. Unfortunately, at that time Sigma rules were only matched against Windows binaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since then, our engineering team worked hard to provide a better experience to Sigma lovers, increasing Crowdsourced Sigma rules value by extending matches to macOS and Linux samples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sponsored Ad Fraud: Mystery Box Scams Flood Social Media</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sponsored-ad-fraud-mystery-box-scams-flood-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sponsored-ad-fraud-mystery-box-scams-flood-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Social media platforms are overflowing with scams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past couple of months, Bitdefender Labs has been monitoring a steep increase in fraudulent social media ads on Facebook promoting various swindles ranging from crypto-doubling to AI-generated celebrity-endorsed giveaways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our latest analysis has spotted a consistent trend, with fraudsters continuing to exploit Meta’s ad system to deceive consumers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hustle? A long-established ruse that involves peddling so-called mystery boxes from&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Social media platforms are overflowing with scams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stream-Jacking 2.0: Deep fakes power account takeovers on YouTube to maximize crypto-doubling scams</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/stream-jacking-2-0-deep-fakes-power-account-takeovers-on-youtube-to-maximize-crypto-doubling-scams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/stream-jacking-2-0-deep-fakes-power-account-takeovers-on-youtube-to-maximize-crypto-doubling-scams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of October 2023, researchers at Bitdefender Labs have been actively keeping tabs on steam-jacking attacks against high-profile YouTube accounts used to conduct a myriad of crypto doubling scams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2024; our investigation into the fraudulent takeovers and usage of YouTube accounts has rendered new findings, as financially motivated threat actors meticulously evolve their attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of months, stream-jacking attacks have steadily evolved, and our research show&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Threat Actors Using Images and Artifacts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tracking-threat-actors-using-images-and-artifacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tracking-threat-actors-using-images-and-artifacts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When tracking adversaries, we commonly focus on the malware they employ in the final stages of the kill chain and infrastructure, often overlooking samples used in the initial ones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we will explore some ideas to track adversary activity leveraging images and artifacts mostly used during delivery. We presented this approach at the FIRST CTI in Berlin and at Botconf in Nice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;hunting-early&#34;&gt;Hunting early&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In threat hunting and detection engineering activities, analysts typically focus heavily on the latter stages of the kill chain – from execution to actions on objectives (Figure 1). This is mainly because there is more information available about adversaries in these phases, and it&amp;rsquo;s easier to search for clues using endpoint detection and response (EDR), security information and event management (SIEM), and other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Hidden Threats with VirusTotal Code Insight</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-hidden-threats-with-virustotal-code-insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-hidden-threats-with-virustotal-code-insight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the constantly changing world of cybersecurity, generative AI is becoming an increasingly valuable tool. This blog post shows various examples that elude traditional detection engines yet are adeptly unveiled by Code Insight. We explore diverse scenarios, ranging from firmware patches in DJI drones that disable red flight lights, to the covert theft of WhatsApp session cookies, phishing targeting Tesla customers, automated login attempts on the Medtronic CareLink Network, Bitcoin wallet attacks, Tik-Tok viewbots, unauthorized Netflix account access, cheaters for Roblox, and automation of Tinder’s match-making, along with a range of other scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unfading Sea Haze: New Espionage Campaign in the South China Sea</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unfading-sea-haze-new-espionage-campaign-in-the-south-china-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unfading-sea-haze-new-espionage-campaign-in-the-south-china-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitdefender researchers investigated a series of incidents at high-level organizations in countries of the South China Sea region, all performed by the same  threat actor we track as Unfading Sea Haze. Based on the victimology and the cyber-attack’s aim, we believe the threat actor is aligned with China’s interests. As tensions in the region rise, they are reflected in the intensification of activity on behalf of the Unfading Sea Haze actor, which uses new and improved tools and TTPs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking the SYS01 Infostealer Threat: Bitdefender Labs Tracks Global Malvertising Campaign Targeting Meta Business Pages</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unmasking-the-sys01-infostealer-threat-bitdefender-labs-tracks-global-malvertising-campaign-targeting-meta-business-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unmasking-the-sys01-infostealer-threat-bitdefender-labs-tracks-global-malvertising-campaign-targeting-meta-business-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world ran by advertising, businesses and organizations are not the only ones using this powerful tool. Cybercriminals have a knack for exploiting the engine that powers online platforms by corrupting the vast reach of advertising to distribute malware en masse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While legitimate businesses rely on ads to reach new audiences, hackers exploit these platforms to trick users into downloading harmful software. Malicious ads often seem to promote legitimate software, streaming services, or produc&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Hidden Connections: JA4 Client Fingerprinting on VirusTotal</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unveiling-hidden-connections-ja4-client-fingerprinting-on-virustotal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unveiling-hidden-connections-ja4-client-fingerprinting-on-virustotal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VirusTotal has incorporated a powerful new tool to fight against malware: &lt;strong&gt;JA4 client fingerprinting&lt;/strong&gt;. This feature allows security researchers to track and identify malicious files based on the unique characteristics of their TLS client communications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ja4-a-more-robust-successor-to-ja3&#34;&gt;JA4: A More Robust Successor to JA3&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JA4, developed by FoxIO, represents a significant advancement over the older JA3 fingerprinting method. JA3&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness had been hampered by the increasing use of TLS extension randomization in https clients, which made fingerprints less consistent. JA4 was specifically designed to be resilient to this randomization, resulting in more stable and reliable fingerprints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirusTotal &#43;= Huorong</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotal-huorong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotal-huorong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome Huorong anti-malware engine to VirusTotal. In the words of the company:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Huorong is a Chinese information security company founded in 2011, which has been committed to the research and development of endpoint security products. Huorong anti-malware engine utilizes a builtin virtual sandbox to achieve generic scanning, generic unpacking and malicious behavior analysis capabilities. Huorong anti-malware engine supports scanning files of any format, and supports decomposition of a huge variety of compound archives, including but not limited to compressors, installers, self-extractors, OLE, MIME, PDF, RTF, AutoIT, ASAR, etc. Also, Huorong anti-malware engine is designed to be accurate, lightweight, cross-platform applicable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirusTotal AI-Generated Conversations: Threat Intel Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotal-ai-generated-conversations-threat-intel-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotal-ai-generated-conversations-threat-intel-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At VirusTotal, we&amp;rsquo;re constantly exploring new ways to make threat intelligence more digestible and available to a wider audience. Our latest effort leverages the power of AI to create easily understood audio discussions from technical information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Google NotebookLM&amp;rsquo;s innovative Audio Overview feature, we&amp;rsquo;re transforming technical content into accessible audio experiences to make threat intelligence engaging and understandable for everyone. Instead of just reading, now you can listen and learn about complex cybersecurity concepts, no matter your level of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirusTotal&#39;s Mission Continues: Sharing Knowledge, Protecting Together</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotals-mission-continues-sharing-knowledge-protecting-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/virustotals-mission-continues-sharing-knowledge-protecting-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the recent announcement of Google Threat Intelligence, I want to take this opportunity, as VirusTotal&amp;rsquo;s founder, to directly address our community and reiterate our unwavering commitment to our core mission.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I want to assure our entire community, from security researchers and industry partners to individual users, that VirusTotal&amp;rsquo;s core mission remains unchanged. We remain deeply dedicated to collective intelligence and collaboration, fostering a platform where everyone can come together to share knowledge, access valuable threat information, and contribute to the fight against cyber threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VT Livehunt Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vt-livehunt-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vt-livehunt-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are happy to announce the release of our “&lt;strong&gt;Livehunt Cheat Sheet&lt;/strong&gt;”, a guide to help you quickly implement monitoring rules in Livehunt. You can find the &lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;version&lt;/strong&gt; here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VirusTotal Livehunt is a service that continuously scans all incoming indicators and notifies you when any of them matches your rules. Livehunt not only monitors files, but also domains, URLs, and IP addresses. In this post we detail a few practical examples along with useful tips.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerabilities Identified in LG WebOS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerabilities-identified-in-lg-webos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerabilities-identified-in-lg-webos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the creator of the world’s first smart home cybersecurity hub, Bitdefender regularly audits popular IoT hardware for vulnerabilities. This research paper is part of a broader program that aims to shed light on the security of the world’s best-sellers in the IoT space. This report covers vulnerabilities discovered while researching the LG WebOS TV operating system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have found several issues affecting WebOS versions 4 through 7 running on LG TVs. These vulnerabilities let us gain root acces&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Made It, Together: 20 Years of VirusTotal!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/we-made-it-together-20-years-of-virustotal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/we-made-it-together-20-years-of-virustotal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We can hardly believe it, but VirusTotal is turning 20 on June 1st! As we sit down to write this, we’re filled with a mix of pride and gratitude. It&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible journey, and we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be here without the amazing community that has supported us every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we started VirusTotal, our goal was simple: to help make the internet a safer place. We never imagined that two decades later, we&amp;rsquo;d be here celebrating this milestone with all of you. From the early days to now, it&amp;rsquo;s always been about working together. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a user, a contributor, or a supporter, you&amp;rsquo;ve played a crucial role in our success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When Stealers Converge: New Variant of Atomic Stealer in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-stealers-converge-new-variant-of-atomic-stealer-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/when-stealers-converge-new-variant-of-atomic-stealer-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here at Bitdefender, we&amp;rsquo;re constantly working on improving detection capabilities for our macOS cyber-security products; part of this effort involves revisiting old (or digging up new) samples from our malware zoo. During routine verifications, we were able to isolate multiple suspicious and undetected macOS disk image files surprisingly small for files of this kind (1.3 MB per file).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short look into the code revealed that these files are significantly similar to other samples analysed in the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YARA is dead, long live YARA-X</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yara-is-dead-long-live-yara-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/yara-is-dead-long-live-yara-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For over 15 years, YARA has been growing and evolving until it became an indispensable tool in every malware researcher&amp;rsquo;s toolbox. Throughout this time YARA has seen numerous updates, with new features added and countless bugs fixed. But today, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce the biggest change yet: a full rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;YARA-X is a completely new implementation of YARA in Rust, and it has the following goals:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better user experience&lt;/strong&gt;: The new command-line interface is more modern and colorful, and error reports are now more explicative. More features aimed at improving the user&amp;rsquo;s experience will be incorporated in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
