<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Author on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/author/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Author on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Black Swan’ Event That Could Upend Life in 2025: The World’s Largest Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/black-swan-event-that-could-upend-life-in-2025-the-worlds-largest-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Story in Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 8, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 futurists, foreign policy analysts and other prognosticators provide Politico readers some explosive potential scenarios for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gary Marcus, author of the book “Taming Silicon Valley”, one of The New Yorker’s recommended books in 2024, warns 2025 could easily see the largest cyberattack in history, taking down, at least for a little while, some sizeable piece of the world’s infrastructure, whether for deliberate ransom or to manipulate people to make money off a short on global markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“WWI Fighter Plane Hack” Inspires Breakthrough in Cancer Treatment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/wwi-fighter-plane-hack-inspires-breakthrough-in-cancer-treatment3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Massachusetts Amherst have developed an innovative technology inspired by the synchronization mechanism of WWI fighter aircraft, which coordinated machine gun fire with propeller movement. This breakthrough allows precise, real-time control of the pH in a cell’s environment to influence its behavior. Detailed in &lt;strong&gt;Nano Letters&lt;/strong&gt;, the study opens exciting possibilities for developing new cancer and heart disease therapies and advancing the field of tissue engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;AWS re:Invent 2024 Highlights | Empowering Customers Through Innovations &amp; Security in Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-reinvent-2024-highlights-empowering-customers-through-innovations-security-in-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the latest technologies and innovations for cloud, container, and data security revealed at AWS re:Invent 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week marked another action-packed year at AWS re:Invent for the SentinelOne Team. Year after year, a consistent highlight from the event is the strong sense of community it builds with people from different backgrounds, geographies, and business types – all unified by their interest in innovating and doing business on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;CVE-2024-12854 - &#34;WordPress Garden Gnome Package Plugin Remote Code Execution File Upload Vulnerability&#34;&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12854&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Garden Gnome Package plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the functionality that automatically extracts &amp;lsquo;ggpkg&amp;rsquo; files that have been uploaded in all versions up to, and including, 2.3.0. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 Best Cybercrime Blogs and Websites in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-best-cybercrime-blogs-and-websites-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/20-best-cybercrime-blogs-and-websites-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Read the Full Feedspot Story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Jan. 2, 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FeedSpot named Cybercrime Magazine no. 1 on it’s list of 20 Best Cybercrime Blogs you should follow in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best Cybercrime blogs from thousands of blogs on the web are ranked by Feedspot for relevancy, authority, social media followers &amp;amp; freshness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“For news on the industry and worldwide cybersecurity research, turn to Cybersecurity Ventures,” says the editors at Feedspot. “They offer industry research, threat information, and cybersecurity trends on their website. With issues like data breaches, cybercrime, and developing technology covered, it’s a great tool for consumers, companies, and professionals that want to stay up to date on cybersecurity developments.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 NIST rules on minimum password length: Aim for 16 characters or more!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/2024-nist-rules-on-minimum-password-length-aim-for-16-characters-or-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Tuta our focus is to keep our users&amp;rsquo; data secure with quantum-safe encryption. To achieve maximum security, the importance of strong, secure passwords that are long enough cannot be overstated. Passwords and the password length are the first line of defense to make sure that no unauthorized access can bring harm to your data or yourself. While factors like complexity and unpredictability matter, experts emphasize that length is a critical element in ensuring password security. But given new threats of quantum computers, what is the optimal minimum password length recommended by NIST and CISA?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Cybersecurity Priorities for The Trump Administration</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://lifeboat.com/blog.images/5-cybersecurity-priorities-for-the-trump-administration.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024: A year when AI, quantum computing, and cybersecurity converged to redefine our digital landscape. For those navigating these complex technological frontiers, clarity became the most critical currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inside Cyber, Key moments that resonated with our community:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Cybersecurity Trends for 2025 Diving deep into the evolving threat landscape and strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• AI, 5G, and Quantum: Innovation and Cybersecurity Risks Exploring the intersection of emerging technologies and security challenges &lt;a href=&#34;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&#34;&gt;https://lnkd.in/ex3ktwuF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlueNoroff Hidden Risk | Threat Actor Targets Macs with Fake Crypto News and Novel Persistence</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bluenoroff-hidden-risk-threat-actor-targets-macs-with-fake-crypto-news-and-novel-persistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a suspected DPRK threat actor targeting Crypto-related businesses with novel multi-stage malware.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We assess with high confidence that the same actor is responsible for earlier attacks attributed to BlueNoroff and the RustDoor/ThiefBucket and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs observed the use of a novel persistence mechanism abusing the Zsh configuration file &lt;code&gt;zshenv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The campaign, which we dubbed ‘Hidden Risk’, uses emails propagating fake news about cryptocurrency trends to infect targets via a malicious application disguised as a PDF file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency-related businesses have been targets of North Korean-affiliated threat actors for some time now, with multiple campaigns aiming to steal funds and/or insert backdoor malware into targets. In April 2023, researchers detailed an APT campaign targeting macOS users with multi-stage malware that culminated in a Rust backdoor capable of downloading and executing further malware on infected devices. ‘RustBucket’, as they labeled it, was attributed with strong confidence to the BlueNoroff APT. In May 2023, ESET researchers discovered a second RustBucket variant targeting macOS users, followed by Elastic’s discovery in July that year of a third variant that included a LaunchAgent for persistence. In November 2023, Elastic also reported on another DPRK campaign targeting blockchain engineers of a crypto exchange platform with KandyKorn malware. Further analysis by SentinelLabs was able to connect the KandyKorn and RustBucket campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s Influence Ops | Twisting Tales of Volt Typhoon at Home and Abroad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/chinas-influence-ops-twisting-tales-of-volt-typhoon-at-home-and-abroad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s CVERC attempts to attribute Volt Typhoon activities to the U.S., but the fact-free claims reveal much about the PRC&amp;rsquo;s real agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The latest CVERC report reflects China’s ongoing efforts to undermine support for U.S. surveillance activities by attempting to fuel debate over Section 702.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The CVERC report also draws Microsoft into its crosshairs as part of an ongoing push to remove foreign technology from PRC government systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The report highlights previous intelligence from France and Germany regarding U.S spying in an attempt to deflect attention away from recent incidents of Chinese espionage in Europe, likely as a means to shape narratives amid ongoing political debates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;China’s Computer Virus Emergency Response Center has released part three of a running series claiming that the U.S. government is actually behind Volt Typhoon activity, rather than China. The latest CVERC report, whose front page includes an oddly edited photo with the text “Lie to Me,” provides no new evidence of these claims and rehashes old leaked U.S. intelligence documents. However, this CVERC report is not useless.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12431 - GitLab Unauthorized Issue Status Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12431-gitlab-unauthorized-issue-status-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12431-gitlab-unauthorized-issue-status-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12431&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; An issue was discovered in GitLab CE/EE affecting all versions starting from 15.5 before 17.5.5, 17.6 before 17.6.3, and 17.7 before 17.7.1, in which unauthorized users could manipulate the status of issues in public projects.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 4.3 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12853 - WordPress Modula Image Gallery Remote File Upload Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12853&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Modula Image Gallery plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the zip upload functionality in all versions up to, and including, 2.11.10. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54010 - Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches ICMP and UDP Packet Forwarding Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54010&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability in the firewall component of HPE Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches exists. It could allow an unauthenticated adjacent attacker to conduct a packet forwarding attack against the ICMP and UDP protocol. For this attack to be successful an attacker requires a switch configuration that allows packets routing (at layer 3). Configurations that do not allow network traffic routing are not impacted. Successful exploitation could allow an attacker to bypass security policies, potentially leading to unauthorized data exposure.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.4 | LOW&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybercriminals Are Targeting AI Agents and Conversational Platforms</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybercriminals-are-targeting-ai-agents-and-conversational-platforms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;emerging-risks-for-businesses-and-consumers&#34;&gt;Emerging risks for businesses and consumers&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Untitled-design-16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;– Shawn Loveland, Chief Operating Officer, Resecurity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;San Jose, Calif. – Dec. 11, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resecurity has identified a spike in malicious campaigns targeting &lt;strong&gt;AI agents&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Conversational AI platforms&lt;/strong&gt; that leverage chatbots to provide automated, human-like interactions for consumers. Conversational AI platforms are designed to facilitate natural interactions between humans and machines using technologies like &lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing (NLP)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning (ML)&lt;/strong&gt;. These platforms enable applications such as chatbots and virtual agents to engage in meaningful conversations, making them valuable tools across various industries. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity 2025 | Preparing for Tomorrow’s Threats, Challenges and Strategic Shifts</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-2025-preparing-for-tomorrows-threats-challenges-and-strategic-shifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore SentinelLabs&amp;rsquo; take on what 2025 may bring for cybersecurity, including emerging trends and actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crystal balls are notoriously fragile, and those who look into them are wise not to become fixated with the shadows cast by their refracted light, yet no business can function without some meaningful sense of what the future might hold. Reading the tea leaves of the past can offer no insight into novel and unexpected events to come, but it can help us prepare for that which is already forming in the shadows. Ultimately, the entire point of intelligence is to enable forward-looking decisions, and this means we’ll hit the mark with some and miss with others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CyberVolk | A Deep Dive into the Hacktivists, Tools and Ransomware Fueling Pro-Russian Cyber Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybervolk-a-deep-dive-into-the-hacktivists-tools-and-ransomware-fueling-pro-russian-cyber-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A loose collective of mostly low-skilled actors, CyberVolk absorbs and adapts a wide array of destructive malware for use against political targets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CyberVolk/GLORIAMIST is a hacktivist collective originating in India with pro-Russia leanings. Between June and October 2024, CyberVolk claimed responsibility for multiple ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The main objective of CyberVolk and related groups is to leverage geopolitical issues to launch and justify attacks on public and government entities, primarily in the service of Russian government interests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SentinelLabs has observed a shared codebase used by CyberVolk, AzzaSec and DoubleFace’s ransomware. Additionally, CyberVolk has promoted other ransomware families like HexaLocker and Parano. These groups and the tools they leverage are all closely intertwined.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These hacktivist groups are extremely dynamic and volatile. In-fighting, threats, and inflated political-posturing are common, leading to fragmentation and the rapid re-shaping of the hacktivist threat landscape.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CyberVolk is a politically motivated hacktivist collective which launched its own RaaS in June 2024. The group uses both DDoS and ransomware attacks in its efforts to undermine and disrupt the operations of those opposed to Russian interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exposing ‘Anom” – Inside The FBI’s Secret Encrypted Phone Company</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exposing-anom-inside-the-fbis-secret-encrypted-phone-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/exposing-anom-inside-the-fbis-secret-encrypted-phone-company/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;this-week-in-cybersecurity-from-the-editors-at-cybercrime-magazine&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week in cybersecurity from the editors at Cybercrime Magazine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://cybersecurityventures.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/icon-rss.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;–Listen To the Podcast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sausalito, Calif. – Dec. 19, 2024&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joseph Cox, author of the 2024 book “Dark Wire: The Incredible True Story of the Largest Sting Operation Ever“, came on the Cybercrime Magazine Podcast to share the inside story of the largest law-enforcement sting operation ever, in which the FBI made its own tech start-up to wiretap the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | A 30-Year Journey from Compilation Student to Decompilation Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-a-30-year-journey-from-compilation-student-to-decompilation-pioneer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Cristina Cifuentes, known as the Mother of Decompilation, reflects on three decades of innovation in reverse engineering in her LABScon 2024 keynote.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1990, Cristina Cifuentes worked on a machine code interpreter for the Modula-2 programming language as part of her Compilers project. That summer, she integrated it into a mixed GPM Modula-2 compiler/interpreter for the 8086 processor. This gave her hands-on experience with assembly language and the process of converting intermediate representations into executable code, laying the groundwork for her later research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | Let Them Eat Cake: “Secure by Upgrade” Software is a National Security Threat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-let-them-eat-cake-secure-by-upgrade-software-is-a-national-security-threat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kymberlee Price reveals the technical chaos facing SMBs as they struggle with solutions aimed at bigger fish in the face of expanding crimeware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware is doing more to change the security landscape than the last 20 years of Secure Development Lifecycle, DevSecOps, Zero Days, Breaches, or any corporate memo. Pair this with predatory pricing models from software vendors that sell security features as add-on products in premium or enterprise tier licenses, and you’ve got a perfect storm that hits small and medium sized businesses (SMBs) the hardest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | PKfail: Supply-Chain Failures in Secure Boot Key Management</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-pkfail-supply-chain-failures-in-secure-boot-key-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binarly’s Alex Matrosov and Fabio Pagani present PKfail, a firmware supply-chain security issue affecting major device vendors and hundreds of device models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern computing heavily relies on establishing and maintaining trust, which begins with trusted foundations and extends through operating systems and applications in a chain-like manner. This ensures that end users can confidently rely on the integrity of the underlying hardware, firmware, and software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most prevalent mechanisms for enforcing trust in the UEFI firmware ecosystem is Secure Boot, which ensures that only digitally signed and verified software is executed during the system boot process, safeguarding against attacks on “external” firmware components and boot loaders. A key component of Secure Boot is the Platform Key (PK), the root-of-trust key used for managing the cryptographic material that validates external components and bootloaders before execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises – providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data – if paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laravel IQ - Level 1 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ১&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Laravel কীভাবে MVC আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Laravel &lt;strong&gt;MVC&lt;/strong&gt; (Model-View-Controller) আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model:&lt;/strong&gt; ডাটাবেসের সঙ্গে কাজ করার জন্য ব্যবহৃত হয়। এটি ডাটাবেস কোয়েরি ও ডাটাবেস সম্পর্কিত লজিক পরিচালনা করে।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View:&lt;/strong&gt; ব্যবহারকারীর জন্য UI বা প্রেজেন্টেশন লেয়ার তৈরি করে। Blade টেমপ্লেট ইঞ্জিন ব্যবহার করে HTML পেজ তৈরি করা হয়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; এটি Model এবং View এর মধ্যে যোগাযোগ করায়। Controller ডাটাবেস থেকে ডেটা নিয়ে View-তে পাঠায়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ২&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Routing কী? Laravel-এ Route এবং Controller এর মধ্যে সম্পর্ক ব্যাখ্যা কর।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Routing ব্যবহার করে Laravel অ্যাপ্লিকেশনে &lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt; এবং এর সাথে সংযুক্ত ক্রিয়াকলাপ সংজ্ঞায়িত করা হয়।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operation Digital Eye | Chinese APT Compromises Critical Digital Infrastructure via Visual Studio Code Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/operation-digital-eye-chinese-apt-compromises-critical-digital-infrastructure-via-visual-studio-code-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure to target large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From late June to mid-July 2024, a suspected China-nexus threat actor targeted large business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe, an activity cluster that we dubbed ‘Operation Digital Eye’.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The intrusions could have enabled the adversaries to establish strategic footholds and compromise downstream entities. SentinelLabs and Tinexta Cyber detected and interrupted the activities in their initial phases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors used a lateral movement capability indicative of the presence of a shared vendor or digital quartermaster maintaining and provisioning tooling within the Chinese APT ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The threat actors abused Visual Studio Code and Microsoft Azure infrastructure for C2 purposes, attempting to evade detection by making malicious activities appear legitimate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our visibility suggests that the abuse of Visual Studio Code for C2 purposes had been relatively rare in the wild prior to this campaign. Operation Digital Eye marks the first instance of a suspected Chinese APT group using this technique that we have directly observed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tinexta Cyber and SentinelLabs have been tracking threat activities targeting business-to-business IT service providers in Southern Europe. Based on the malware, infrastructure, techniques used, victimology, and the timing of the activities, we assess that it is highly likely these attacks were conducted by a China-nexus threat actor with cyberespionage motivations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Web-Based Work</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-web-based-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog was originally published on Security Boulevard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;connecting-people-web-browsers-and-security&#34;&gt;Connecting People, Web Browsers and Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The web browser has transformed significantly in recent years, becoming one of the most used tools for work today. However, as organizations adopt hybrid work models and cloud-based operations, securing this work tool has proved a challenge. Security infrastructures haven’t evolved as fast as the browser, making them prone to cyberattacks. With browsers being the primary gateway to the internet, any security lapse can lead to broad opportunities for significant data breaches and operational disruptions. Understanding the risks and implementing robust security measures is crucial for safeguarding the work we do today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing AWS Lambda | How Misconfigurations Can Lead to Lateral Movement</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/securing-aws-lambda-how-misconfigurations-can-lead-to-lateral-movement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how several misconfigurations and user-defined code issues in AWS Lambda could lead to potential credential theft and lateral movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As serverless computing continues to revolutionize the cloud landscape, AWS Lambda has emerged as a pivotal service, offering a Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) model that allows developers to focus solely on code while AWS manages the underlying infrastructure. This shift towards serverless architectures brings new security challenges and considerations that security researchers and professionals must understand and address.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best, the Worst and the Ugliest in Cybersecurity | 2024 Edition</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-best-the-worst-and-the-ugliest-in-cybersecurity-2024-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we ring in the New Year, SentinelOne reviews and reflects on some of the most formative cyber news stories that occurred in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s almost time to wave goodbye to the year that was 2024, and as we look ahead to 2025 and the challenges that might bring, now is a good time to reflect on the best, the worst and the ugliest cybersecurity news stories over the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
