<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backdoors on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/backdoors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backdoors on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/backdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three questions about Apple, encryption, and the U.K.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-questions-about-apple-encryption-and-the-u-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-questions-about-apple-encryption-and-the-u-k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, the Washington Post reported that the U.K. government had issued a secret order to Apple demanding that the company include a “backdoor” into the company’s end-to-end encrypted iCloud Backup feature. From the article:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The British government’s undisclosed order, issued last month, requires blanket capability to view fully encrypted material, not merely assistance in cracking a specific account, and has no known precedent in major democracies. Its application would mark a significant defeat for tech companies in their decades-long battle to avoid being wielded as government tools against their users, the people said, speaking under the condition of anonymity to discuss legally and politically sensitive issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U.K. asks to backdoor iCloud Backup encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/u-k-asks-to-backdoor-icloud-backup-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m supposed to be finishing a wonky series on proof systems (here and here) and I promise I will do that this week. In the midst of this I’ve been a bit distracted by world events.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week the Washington Post published a bombshell story announcing that the U.K. had filed “technical capability notices” demanding that Apple modify the encryption used in their Advanced Data Protection (ADP) system for iCloud. For those who don’t know about ADP, it’s a system that enables full “end-to-end” encryption for iCloud backups, including photos and other data. This means that your backup data should be encrypted under your phone’s passcode — and critically, neither Apple nor hackers can access it. The U.K. request would secretly weaken that feature for at least some users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;New VPN Backdoor&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-vpn-backdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-vpn-backdoor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A newly discovered VPN backdoor uses some interesting tactics to avoid detection:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When threat actors use backdoor malware to gain access to a network, they want to make sure all their hard work can’t be leveraged by competing groups or detected by defenders. One countermeasure is to equip the backdoor with a passive agent that remains dormant until it receives what’s known in the business as a “magic packet.” On Thursday, researchers revealed that a never-before-seen backdoor that quietly took hold of dozens of enterprise VPNs running Juniper Network’s Junos OS has been doing just that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
