<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CA Practices: Key Updates in Mozilla Root Store Policy, v3.0</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-ca-practices-key-updates-in-mozilla-root-store-policy-v3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-ca-practices-key-updates-in-mozilla-root-store-policy-v3-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla remains committed to fostering a secure, agile, and transparent Web PKI ecosystem. The new Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) v3.0, effective March 15, 2025, introduces critical updates to strengthen Certificate Authority (CA) practices and enhance compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A major focus of &lt;strong&gt;MRSP v3.0&lt;/strong&gt; is tackling the long-standing challenge of &lt;strong&gt;delayed certificate revocation&lt;/strong&gt;—an issue that has historically weakened the security and reliability of TLS certificate management. The updated policy establishes &lt;strong&gt;clearer revocation expectations, improved incident reporting, subscriber education by CAs, revocation planning,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;automated certificate issuance&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure that certificate replacement and revocation can be handled promptly and at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Revises Firefox Terms of Use After Inflaming Users Over Data Usage</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mozilla-revises-firefox-terms-of-use-after-inflaming-users-over-data-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mozilla-revises-firefox-terms-of-use-after-inflaming-users-over-data-usage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to users’ feedback about the Firefox Terms of Use, Mozilla updated some of the language about data usage. Mozilla also updated its Privacy FAQ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is Apple Taking Legal Action Against UK’s Government?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-is-apple-taking-legal-action-against-uks-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-is-apple-taking-legal-action-against-uks-government/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple told TechRepublic it is “gravely disappointed” to remove Advanced Data Protection in the U.K., as it fights government demands for an iCloud backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy says Paragon spyware targeted victims in dozens of European countries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/italy-says-paragon-spyware-targeted-victims-in-dozens-of-european-countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/italy-says-paragon-spyware-targeted-victims-in-dozens-of-european-countries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seven Italians and victims in more than a dozen other European countries were targeted with spyware as part of a broad hacking campaign revealed by WhatsApp on Friday, the Italian government said.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backdoor in Contec CMS8000 monitors may allow faulty patient readings</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/backdoor-in-contec-cms8000-monitors-may-allow-faulty-patient-readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/backdoor-in-contec-cms8000-monitors-may-allow-faulty-patient-readings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agencies say firmware backdoor can cause an RCE, which could result in faulty readings on patients’ vital signs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Misconfigured server exposes AngelSense data</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/misconfigured-server-exposes-angelsense-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/misconfigured-server-exposes-angelsense-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TechCrunch reports that New Jersey-based assistive technology firm AngelSense was disclosed by cybersecurity firm UpGuard to have had its users&amp;rsquo; personally identifiable information and precise location details exposed online as a result of an unsecured server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over 1M individuals impacted by Valley News Live data leak</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/over-1m-individuals-impacted-by-valley-news-live-data-leak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/over-1m-individuals-impacted-by-valley-news-live-data-leak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;North Dakota-based TV station Valley News Live had more than 1.8 million files from its job portal leaked due to a misconfigured Amazon AWS S3 storage bucket, according to Cybernews.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wacom customer info potentially breached</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wacom-customer-info-potentially-breached/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/wacom-customer-info-potentially-breached/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Japanese graphics tablet manufacturer Wacom has disclosed the potential compromise of its customers&amp;rsquo; personal and credit card information following a breach of its online store that may have happened from Nov. 28, 2024 to Jan. 8, 2025, The Register reports.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Protect and Secure Your Data in 10 Ways</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-protect-and-secure-your-data-in-10-ways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use this comprehensive list of strategies to help you safeguard your company&amp;rsquo;s data from threats and data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>User location data exposure threatened by Cloudflare CDN vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/user-location-data-exposure-threatened-by-cloudflare-cdn-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/user-location-data-exposure-threatened-by-cloudflare-cdn-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Cloudflare conducting media resource caching at the data center closest in proximity to its users, security researcher Daniel discovered that an information-disclosure intrusion could be conducted through the delivery of a unique image hosted on Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s CDN to a vulnerable app, which would use the Cloudflare Teleport tool to route the requests to certain data centers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Privacy Pitfalls for Developers to Avoid</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-privacy-pitfalls-for-developers-to-avoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-privacy-pitfalls-for-developers-to-avoid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg1BM9Mqi1_2r34B27V2lS1KaekgvFgGVPuT_kNGRRdYMlOr3y0osyZ7Vbs6FcYmgbyJbb-RcQ3I-z6DZifKGhYE2b3NxS312wL-sjl0Nw-xVH81SYUx3rBCe_R2ydamcAEim2mToSHJ83otc7WPN1MlM3OYK6o_r0es7RbEqILrkqwFfrAMmcMvvs6IA/w640-h426/6privacy_front-1024x683-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While tech-savvy people are very concerned about privacy, knowing where to find metadata leaks can be nebulous even for developers. In this blog post, we will explore examples of unexpected user information leakage. We hope that the information shared in this blog will help developers assess and address potential privacy issues with their applications, as well as educate end-users about potential risks to their privacy that can result from information leaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 ways to enumerate WordPress Users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-ways-to-enumerate-wordpress-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-ways-to-enumerate-wordpress-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiJW387o-w66SJCmapiPp1JyKIgrFc25ZssYt1MFXl8forkpqmrZdyfIUGooaYM90l3QAxm-dEmDCDtaI7uWvO1hqYckKc1NL3IkIBjze0kasHT9EwO8obqr_mJpzcdc6XpOWyzhOokVdih0YIvud6LEGNHgozLyL7WMllxtmplkE0rEQh42FSxsp28kA/s320/wordpress-bypass_crop%5B1%5D.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are testing the security of WordPress websites, you will likely have to look at the REST endpoints. By default, users can be listed with the route “/wp-json/wp/v2/users”. On the latest WordPress version, out of the box, you will get the username and the hashed email. Experienced WordPress administrators and users are aware of the potential disclosure. Therefore, we can see various tutorials online on how to hide this information. The recommended ways are either to disable the REST API completely,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;install a security plugin which disables the specific route or block specific request paths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deanonymizing LinkedIn Users</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deanonymizing-linkedin-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deanonymizing-linkedin-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjg7aLzYD2_lxNFbzk2uImf0Id_uOXb45d-z_mkCoZD3wcD3vMy52PtEow16K6BcXZshnhi_5fpJBmwQRxAc-suHOiIMf6ZsxtwpsjNdi0qCv93lGUoszq1uxTUFjr_SpvPcpxgfrGFRSJZ/s320/linkedin_card_v2%255B1%255D.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will look at the privacy issues with some of LinkedIn’s external APIs. We will demonstrate how it is possible, with an email address, to find its associated LinkedIn profile. It is also possible from a LinkedIn profile to do the reverse path and find a person’s email address. To execute this deanonymization attack, documented features, like LinkedIn’s integration with Outlook and YahooMail, are used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disciplinary and special ed records of Toronto students may have leaked in PowerSchool breach</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/disciplinary-and-special-ed-records-of-toronto-students-may-have-leaked-in-powerschool-breach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/disciplinary-and-special-ed-records-of-toronto-students-may-have-leaked-in-powerschool-breach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data breach at the educational software company may affect millions of students at Toronto public schools — one of thousands of districts using PowerSchool tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emails Disclosure on WordPress</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/emails-disclosure-on-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/emails-disclosure-on-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgq2xqKk1ubaVqsHfi6sEA09BIrKp0tq5owY7LB4nlg8eNKmroRMqHEqFoTabFGi0ZLEQYie07RtSjDbve08MCwVdLisOINcEcnNfcPkHmWCRgAJXyMBOmDRhEc_o5G-ZRKVnxJbtBiMeaK/s320/blog-email-disclosure-wordpress-image-1%255B1%255D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Password brute force is one of the common most attack on WordPress. Only a few hours after the deployment of a new blog, we can see login attempts to /xmlrpc.php or /wp-login.php endpoints. While not being sophisticated, they remain strong attacks as they put pressure on the limited complexity passwords and potential password reuse from users. In this article, we are going to explain how the public&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;wordpress.com REST API makes it easier for brute-force attacks on millions of WordPress instances managed by wordpress.com or private instances with the Jetpack plugin installed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/no-siris-learn-from-this-app-setting-is-not-sending-data-from-your-apps-to-third-parties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People on social media who don&amp;rsquo;t understand how iPhones work have been spreading misinformation about some Siri settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post No, Siri’s “Learn from this app” Setting Is Not Sending Data From Your Apps to Third Parties appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN Security Council launches 1st discussion tackling commercial spyware</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/un-security-council-launches-1st-discussion-tackling-commercial-spyware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/un-security-council-launches-1st-discussion-tackling-commercial-spyware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The meeting, which was called for by the United States and 15 other nations, sought to address the proliferation and misuse of government and mercenary spyware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revocation Reason Codes for TLS Server Certificates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revocation-reason-codes-for-tls-server-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revocation-reason-codes-for-tls-server-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our continued efforts to improve the security of the web PKI, we are taking a multi-pronged approach to tackling some long-existing problems with revocation of TLS server certificates. In addition to our ongoing CRLite work, we added new requirements to version 2.8 of Mozilla’s Root Store Policy that will enable Firefox to depend on revocation reason codes being used consistently, so they can be relied on when verifying the validity of certificates during TLS connections. We also added a new requirement that CA operators provide their full CRL URLs in the CCADB. This will enable Firefox to pre-load more complete certificate revocation data, eliminating dependency on the infrastructure of CAs during the certificate verification part of establishing TLS connections. The combination of these two new sets of requirements will further enable Firefox to enforce revocation checking of TLS server certificates, which makes TLS connections even more secure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TikTok’s national security risk warrants ban, Supreme Court rules</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tiktoks-national-security-risk-warrants-ban-supreme-court-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tiktoks-national-security-risk-warrants-ban-supreme-court-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ruling could have implications for other foreign-owned applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barcelona gaining reputation as spyware hub</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/barcelona-gaining-reputation-as-spyware-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/barcelona-gaining-reputation-as-spyware-hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Barcelona is becoming a magnet for spyware and cybersecurity firms, attracting companies with its favorable living conditions, tax benefits, and accessibility to the global market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let’s talk about AI and end-to-end encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lets-talk-about-ai-and-end-to-end-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/lets-talk-about-ai-and-end-to-end-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across a fantastic new paper by a group of NYU and Cornell researchers entitled “How to think about end-to-end encryption and AI.” I’m extremely grateful to see this paper, because while I don’t agree with &lt;em&gt;every single one&lt;/em&gt; of it’s conclusions, it’s a good first stab at an incredibly important set of questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was particularly glad to see this paper, but this exact topic has been very much on my mind this past few months. On the one hand, my interest stems from the rapid deployment of new AI assistant systems like Google’s scam call protection and Apple Intelligence, both of which aim to put AI basically everywhere on your phone — even, potentially, right in the middle of your encrypted messages. On the other hand, it comes from a recent European debate over “mandatory content scanning” laws that would require AI to scan virtually every private message you send.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OneBlood reports data breach to state regulators after ransomware attack</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oneblood-reports-data-breach-to-state-regulators-after-ransomware-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oneblood-reports-data-breach-to-state-regulators-after-ransomware-attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blood donation organization notified regulators that sensitive data was stolen, nearly five months after a ransomware attack hampered its operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack of the week: Airdrop tracing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attack-of-the-week-airdrop-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wrote an “attack of the week” post, and the fault for this is entirely mine. I’ve been much too busy writing boring posts about Schnorr signatures! But this week’s news brings an exciting story with both technical &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; political dimensions: new reports claim that Chinese security agencies have developed a technique to trace the sender of AirDrop transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically my “attack of the week” posts are intended to highlight recent research. What’s unusual about this one is that the attack is not really &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt;; it was discovered way back in 2019, when a set of TU Darmstadt researchers — Heinrich, Hollick, Schneider, Stute, and Weinert — reverse-engineered the Apple AirDrop protocol and disclosed several privacy flaws to Apple. (The resulting paper, which appeared in Usenix Security 2021 can be found here.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
