<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/remote/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/remote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>• 🚀 Frontend Developer Ready for New Adventures | #OpenToWork</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/-frontend-developer-ready-for-new-adventures-opentowork/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/-frontend-developer-ready-for-new-adventures-opentowork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year begins full of possibilities, new professional chapter: Open to Work!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;After a journey of learning, challenges, and experiences, I am seeking new opportunities as a Front-end Developer to apply my knowledge and experiences in ways that allow me to expand my horizons even further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personal projects:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🪴Breath Natural - NestJS Chronicles Part 1 &amp;lt;- NestJS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Food Hut - Angular Chronicles - Part 1 &amp;lt;- AngularJs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🌿Github &amp;lt;- Github&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;💻 My core skills:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;CVE-2024-12854 - &#34;WordPress Garden Gnome Package Plugin Remote Code Execution File Upload Vulnerability&#34;&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12854-wordpress-garden-gnome-package-plugin-remote-code-execution-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12854&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Garden Gnome Package plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the functionality that automatically extracts &amp;lsquo;ggpkg&amp;rsquo; files that have been uploaded in all versions up to, and including, 2.3.0. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-12853 - WordPress Modula Image Gallery Remote File Upload Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-12853-wordpress-modula-image-gallery-remote-file-upload-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-12853&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 10:15 a.m. | 11 hours, 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; The Modula Image Gallery plugin for WordPress is vulnerable to arbitrary file uploads due to missing file type validation in the zip upload functionality in all versions up to, and including, 2.11.10. This makes it possible for authenticated attackers, with Author-level access and above, to upload arbitrary files on the affected site&amp;rsquo;s server which may make remote code execution possible.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13189 - ZeroWdd MyBlog Remote File Permission Bypass Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13189-zerowdd-myblog-remote-file-permission-bypass-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13189&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical has been found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This affects an unknown part of the file src/main/java/com/wdd/myblog/config/MyBlogMvcConfig.java. The manipulation leads to permission issues. It is possible to initiate the attack remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 7.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-13190 - ZeroWdd Myblog Xml Injection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-13190-zerowdd-myblog-xml-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-13190&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability classified as critical was found in ZeroWdd myblog 1.0. This vulnerability affects unknown code of the file src/main/resources/mapper/BlogMapper.xml. The manipulation of the argument findBlogList/getTotalBlogs leads to xml injection. The attack can be initiated remotely. The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 6.3 | MEDIUM&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54818 - SourceCodester Computer Laboratory Management System Unauthenticated Remote OS Command Injection</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54818-sourcecodester-computer-laboratory-management-system-unauthenticated-remote-os-command-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54818-sourcecodester-computer-laboratory-management-system-unauthenticated-remote-os-command-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54818&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; SourceCodester Computer Laboratory Management System 1.0 is vulnerable to Incorrect Access Control. via /php-lms/admin/?page=user/list.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-0291 - Google Chrome Type Confusion Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0291-google-chrome-type-confusion-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-0291-google-chrome-type-confusion-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-0291&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Type Confusion in V8 in Google Chrome prior to 131.0.6778.264 allowed a remote attacker to execute arbitrary code inside a sandbox via a crafted HTML page. (Chromium security severity: High)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.3 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22145 - Carbon PHP DateTime Remote File Include Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22145-carbon-php-datetime-remote-file-include-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22145&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Carbon is an international PHP extension for DateTime. Application passing unsanitized user input to Carbon::setLocale are at risk of arbitrary file include, if the application allows users to upload files with .php extension in an folder that allows include or require to read it, then they are at risk of arbitrary code ran on their servers. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.8.4 and 2.72.6.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Things First | SentinelOne Is A Fortune Best Workplace for Parents</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-things-first-sentinelone-is-a-fortune-best-workplace-for-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne is included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents, ranking among the top 70 companies worldwide for working parents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wellbeing comes first at SentinelOne – for our customers, our communities, and our colleagues. We are proud to foster a culture of diversity, equality, and understanding for all. Supporting our working parents and the notion of a family’s evolving needs is a key part of that philosophy, and that is why we are extremely proud to be included in this year’s Fortune Best Workplaces for Parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;hackers-exploit-keriocontrol-firewall-flaw-to-steal-admin-csrf-tokens&#34;&gt;Hackers exploit KerioControl firewall flaw to steal admin CSRF tokens&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.cvefeed.io/news/23037/thumbnail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hackers are trying to exploit CVE-2024-52875, a critical CRLF injection vulnerability that leads to 1-click remote code execution (RCE) attacks in GFI KerioControl firewall product. KerioControl is a &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Published Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 08, 2025 (2 hours, 48 minutes ago)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities has been mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote hacking is possible for Garrett walk-through metal detectors.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remote-hacking-is-possible-for-garrett-walk-through-metal-detectors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A network component in Garrett Metal Detectors contains a number of security flaws that could allow remote attackers to bypass authentication requirements, tamper with metal detector configurations, and even execute arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a disclosure released last week, Cisco Talos noted that an attacker could use this module to remotely monitor statistics on a metal detector, such as whether the alarm has been triggered or how many visitors passed through. “They could also alter device configurations, such as changing the sensitivity level, potentially posing a security risk to users of these metal detectors.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remotely Controlled Vehicles Over Starlink</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/remotely-controlled-vehicles-over-starlink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/starboat_feat.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern remote control (RC) radios are capable of incredible range, but they’re still only made for line-of-sight use. What if you want to control a vehicle that’s 100s of kilometers away, or even on the other side of the planet? Cellular is an option, but is obviously limited by available infrastructure — good luck getting a cell signal in the middle of the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what if you could beam your commands down from space? That’s what [Thingify] was looking to test when they put together an experimental RC boat using a Starlink Mini for communications. Physically, there was no question it would work on the boat. After all, it was small, light, and power-efficient enough. But would the network connection be up to the task of controlling the vehicle in real-time?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During early ground testing, the Mini version of the Starlink receiver worked very well. Despite being roughly 1/4 the size of its predecessor, the smaller unit met or exceeded its performance during benchmarks on bandwidth, latency, and signal strength. As expected, it also drew far less power: the Mini’s power consumption peaked at around 33 watts, compared to the monstrous 180 W for the larger receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the water, there was even more good news. The bandwidth was more than enough to run a high-resolution video feedback to the command center. Most of the time the boat was moving autonomously between waypoints, but when [Thingify] switched over to manual control, the latency was low enough that maneuvering wasn’t a problem. We wouldn’t recommend manually piloting a high-speed aircraft over Starlink, but for a boat that’s cruising along at 4 km/h, the lag didn’t even come into play.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside? Starlink is a fairly expensive proposition; you’d need to have a pretty specific mission in mind to justify the cost. The Mini receiver currently costs $599 USD (though it occasionally goes on sale), and you’ll need at least a $50 per month plan to go with it. While this puts it out of the price range for recreational RC, [Thingify] notes that it’s not a bad deal if you’re looking to explore uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running AI Locally Without Spending All Day on Setup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/LargeLanguageModel.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many AI models out there that you can play with from companies like OpenAI, Google, and a host of others. But when you use them, you get the experience they want, and you run it on their computer. There are a variety of reasons you might not like this. You may not want your data or ideas sent through someone else’s computer. Maybe you want to tune and tweak in ways they aren’t going to let you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
