<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tls on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/tls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tls on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/tls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weakness in Java TLS Host Verification</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/weakness-in-java-tls-host-verification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/weakness-in-java-tls-host-verification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjNfphy82Pua1WHsihHar7aITooIPp_m5k0rm3TQcJ1yvrxbIFz2F-FicOyTfMSRck8-fLd17HcSGV-UQz3b5U0YmvTtU10hMRI1uQXi_hsPJkK3lsSIxgP1c3H3uxuKEC-53WIBmsUHdTz/w400-h169/oracle_thumbnail_feature%255B1%255D.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unicode-related vulnerabilities have seen an increase in momentum in the past year. Last year, a Black Hat presentation by Jonathan Birch detailed how character normalization NFC/NFKC can lead to glitches in URL and host manipulation. Recently, two vulnerabilities were found in password reset functionality. The two affected applications were Django and Github. In the previous blog post, we have presented API transforming code points with potential side effects. In this post, we present one of our findings: a vulnerability affecting Oracle JDK and Open JDK host verification in the TLS communication. We are also including details from a similar weakness in Apache HTTP client.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Mozilla’s Root Store Policy to Version 2.8</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upgrading-mozillas-root-store-policy-to-version-2-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upgrading-mozillas-root-store-policy-to-version-2-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the Mozilla Manifesto, which emphasizes the open development of policy that protects users’ privacy and security, we have worked with the Mozilla community over the past several months to improve the Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) so that we can now announce version 2.8, effective June 1, 2022. These policy changes aim to improve the transparency of Certificate Authority (CA) operations and the certificates that they issue. A detailed comparison of the policy changes may be found here, and the significant policy changes that appear in this version are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Version 2.9 of the Mozilla Root Store Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/version-2-9-of-the-mozilla-root-store-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/version-2-9-of-the-mozilla-root-store-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online security is constantly evolving, and thus we are excited to announce the publication of MRSP version 2.9, demonstrating that we are committed to keep up with the advancement of the web and further our commitment to a secure and trustworthy internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With each update to the &lt;strong&gt;Mozilla Root Store Policy&lt;/strong&gt; (MRSP), we aim to address emerging challenges and enhance the integrity and reliability of our root store. Version 2.9 introduces several noteworthy changes and refinements, and within this blog post we provide an overview of key updates to the MRSP and their implications for the broader online community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encryption in transit over external networks: AWS guidance for NYDFS and beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction to its Cybersecurity Resource Center, the Department explains that the revisions are aimed at addressing the changes in the increasing sophistication of threat actors, the prevalence of and relative ease in running cyberattacks, and the availability of additional controls to manage cyber risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tune TLS for hybrid post-quantum cryptography with Kyber</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 30, 2024: The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info. January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
