<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>38C3: It’s TOSLINK, Over Long Distance Fibre</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/38c3-its-toslink-over-long-distance-fibre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/fibre-toslink-featured.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve owned a CD player or other piece of consumer digital audio gear manufactured since the 1980s, the chances are it has a TOSLINK port on the back. This is a fairly simple interface that sends I2S digital audio data down a short length of optical fibre, and it’s designed to run between something like a CD player and an external DAC. It’s ancient technology in optical fibre terms, with a lowish data rate and plastic fibre, but consider for a minute whether it could be adapted for modern ultra-high-speed conenctions. It’s what [Ben Cartwright-Cox] has done, and he delivered a talk about it at the recent 38C3 event in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Customize the scope of IAM Access Analyzer unused access analysis</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/customize-the-scope-of-iam-access-analyzer-unused-access-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management Access Analyzer simplifies inspecting unused access to guide you towards least privilege. You can use unused access findings to identify over-permissive access granted to AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles and users in your accounts or organization. From a delegated administrator account for IAM Access Analyzer, you can use the dashboard to review unused access findings across your organization and prioritize the accounts to inspect based on the volume and type of findings. The findings highlight unused roles, unused access keys for IAM users, and unused passwords for IAM users. For active IAM users and roles, the findings provide visibility into unused services and actions. Recently, IAM Access Analyzer launched new configuration capabilities that you can use to customize the analysis. You can select accounts, roles, and users to exclude, and focus on the areas that matter the most to you. You can use identifiers such as account ID or scale configuration using tags. By scoping the IAM Access Analyzer to monitor a subset of accounts and roles, you can reduce noise from unwanted findings. You can update the configuration when needed to change the scope of analysis. With this new offering, IAM Access Analyzer provides enhanced controls to help you tailor the analysis more closely to your organization’s security needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-45345 - Cisco WebEx Data Placeholder Command Injection Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-45345-cisco-webex-data-placeholder-command-injection-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-45345-cisco-webex-data-placeholder-command-injection-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-45345&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 1 hour, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Rejected reason: reserved but not needed&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-52869 - Teradata SUSE Enterprise Linux Server Elevated Privilege Group Misassignment</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-52869-teradata-suse-enterprise-linux-server-elevated-privilege-group-misassignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-52869&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Certain Teradata account-handling code through 2024-11-04, used with SUSE Enterprise Linux Server, mismanages groups. Specifically, when there is an operating system move from SUSE Enterprise Linux Server (SLES) 12 Service Pack (SP) 2 or 3 to SLES 15 SP2 on Teradata Database systems, some service/system user accounts, and possibly systems administrator created user accounts, are incorrectly assigned to groups that allow higher system-level privileges than intended for those user accounts. Depending on the usage of these accounts, this may lead to full system compromise.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-54010 - Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches ICMP and UDP Packet Forwarding Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-54010-aruba-networking-cx-10000-series-switches-icmp-and-udp-packet-forwarding-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-54010&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 9:15 p.m. | 29 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; A vulnerability in the firewall component of HPE Aruba Networking CX 10000 Series Switches exists. It could allow an unauthenticated adjacent attacker to conduct a packet forwarding attack against the ICMP and UDP protocol. For this attack to be successful an attacker requires a switch configuration that allows packets routing (at layer 3). Configurations that do not allow network traffic routing are not impacted. Successful exploitation could allow an attacker to bypass security policies, potentially leading to unauthorized data exposure.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.4 | LOW&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2024-55656 - Redis RedisBloom Probabilistic Data Structures Integer Overflow Information Leak Out-of-Bounds Write</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2024-55656-redis-redisbloom-probabilistic-data-structures-integer-overflow-information-leak-out-of-bounds-write/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2024-55656&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 4:15 p.m. | 5 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; RedisBloom adds a set of probabilistic data structures to Redis. There is an integer overflow vulnerability in RedisBloom, which is a module used in Redis. The integer overflow vulnerability allows an attacker (a redis client which knows the password) to allocate memory in the heap lesser than the required memory due to wraparound. Then read and write can be performed beyond this allocated memory, leading to info leak and OOB write. The integer overflow is in CMS.INITBYDIM command, which initialize a Count-Min Sketch to dimensions specified by user. It accepts two values (width and depth) and uses them to allocate memory in NewCMSketch(). This vulnerability is fixed in 2.2.19, 2.4.12, 2.6.14, and 2.8.2.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22140 - WeGIA SQL Injection Vulnerability (Authenticated)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22140-wegia-sql-injection-vulnerability-authenticated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22140&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A SQL Injection vulnerability was identified in the /html/funcionario/dependente_listar_um.php endpoint, specifically in the id_dependente parameter. This vulnerability allows attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands, compromising the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the database. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-22141 - WeGIA Web Manager SQL Injection Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22141-wegia-web-manager-sql-injection-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-22141-wegia-web-manager-sql-injection-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-22141&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 8, 2025, 7:15 p.m. | 2 hours, 28 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; WeGIA is a web manager for charitable institutions. A SQL Injection vulnerability was identified in the /dao/verificar_recursos_cargo.php endpoint, specifically in the cargo parameter. This vulnerability allows attackers to execute arbitrary SQL commands, compromising the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the database. This vulnerability is fixed in 3.2.8.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0 | NA&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term &lt;em&gt;real-world&lt;/em&gt; data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to learn quickly without needing to venture into the world of data cleaning, but real-world data has problems and is messy. Real-world data needs cleaning before it can give us useful insights, and that’s the subject of this blog post. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here’s why Julia is THE language in scientific programming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/heres-why-julia-is-the-language-in-scientific-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best things about working in quantum computing is being exposed to a whole new set of skills and tools. For those of us coming from the software engineering side, discovering the things our academic peers are using is an interesting experience. One of the best for me personally was coming across the Julia programming language, and learning why it has become the go-to language for serious scientific programming in some circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is your organization ready for the future? Why skills matter</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-your-organization-ready-for-the-future-why-skills-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/is-your-organization-ready-for-the-future-why-skills-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The drive toward AI-enabled transformation is causing organizations to focus on upskilling, reskilling and reconnecting their IT teams. Recent data from IDC1 shows that 58% of CEOs are concerned about whether their organization’s skill sets can meet the demands of AI initiatives. This IDC report reinforces the need to invest in building an organization with the skills that will support productivity, efficiency and competitiveness.Organizations across all industries and regions are facing a growing shortage of IT skills, whether in security, cloud, IT service management or AI. Fast-changing t&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laravel IQ - Level 1 - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/laravel-iq-level-1-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ১&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Laravel কীভাবে MVC আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Laravel &lt;strong&gt;MVC&lt;/strong&gt; (Model-View-Controller) আর্কিটেকচার অনুসরণ করে।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model:&lt;/strong&gt; ডাটাবেসের সঙ্গে কাজ করার জন্য ব্যবহৃত হয়। এটি ডাটাবেস কোয়েরি ও ডাটাবেস সম্পর্কিত লজিক পরিচালনা করে।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View:&lt;/strong&gt; ব্যবহারকারীর জন্য UI বা প্রেজেন্টেশন লেয়ার তৈরি করে। Blade টেমপ্লেট ইঞ্জিন ব্যবহার করে HTML পেজ তৈরি করা হয়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller:&lt;/strong&gt; এটি Model এবং View এর মধ্যে যোগাযোগ করায়। Controller ডাটাবেস থেকে ডেটা নিয়ে View-তে পাঠায়।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;প্রশ্ন ২&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Routing কী? Laravel-এ Route এবং Controller এর মধ্যে সম্পর্ক ব্যাখ্যা কর।&lt;br&gt;&#xA;উত্তর:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Routing ব্যবহার করে Laravel অ্যাপ্লিকেশনে &lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt; এবং এর সাথে সংযুক্ত ক্রিয়াকলাপ সংজ্ঞায়িত করা হয়।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running AI Locally Without Spending All Day on Setup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/running-ai-locally-without-spending-all-day-on-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://hackaday.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/LargeLanguageModel.jpg?w=800&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many AI models out there that you can play with from companies like OpenAI, Google, and a host of others. But when you use them, you get the experience they want, and you run it on their computer. There are a variety of reasons you might not like this. You may not want your data or ideas sent through someone else’s computer. Maybe you want to tune and tweak in ways they aren’t going to let you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Engineering: Hack Week 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/web-engineering-hack-week-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Canonical, the work of our teams is strongly embedded in the open source principles and philosophy. We believe open source software will become the most prevalent method of software development and delivery in the future. Being open source is more than making the source of your software available, it’s also about contributing to other open source projects and helping to build communities. With this in mind, the web engineering team recently had the privilege of dedicating a week solely to contribute to external open source projects. We do this every year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
