<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ios on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ios on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semgrep Rules for iOS Application Security (Swift)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/semgrep-rules-for-ios-application-security-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/semgrep-rules-for-ios-application-security-swift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEj6C9bCj_OW9A2TBw17WVTTFITXAYIqKMz_nzV4EYVXRRdmBxh0a5XEbnmJ6h85kj2CIDlI-G1yhYYul3YQmFZR0Vh5TqNBOxEWX5jlA5hl-00x0smkwZvR59bPsu91BWMaIOGyYfys88Q3WaiopDNn8VQ0KDZOq-TP0XuJ3LXuxH9gGHU0qht15AJPBcw/w200-h155/swift_sec2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Swift_security&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Swift_security&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, millions of people rely on iOS mobile applications for almost everything. As a result iOS devices manage a significant amount of data including sensitive ones, such as: &lt;em&gt;credentials&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;health data&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;payment data&lt;/em&gt; and so on. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For these reasons ensuring the security of iOS applications is more critical than ever when developing iOS applications. Securely handling sensitive data and minimizing vulnerabilities are essential core concepts for developers when coding iOS applications, using &lt;strong&gt;Swift&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Objective-C&lt;/strong&gt; languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;New Possibilities with Purple AI | Third-Party Log Sources &amp; Multilingual Question Support&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-possibilities-with-purple-ai-third-party-log-sources-multilingual-question-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-possibilities-with-purple-ai-third-party-log-sources-multilingual-question-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about the all-new third-party log sources and multilingual question support features just released for SentinelOne&amp;rsquo;s Purple AI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As cyber threats grow more sophisticated, security teams need the right tools powered by generative AI (GenAI) to detect and protect at machine speed. At SentinelOne, we’re already making this future a reality with Purple AI, equipping security teams with the AI-powered tools to help stay ahead of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purple AI is the industry’s most advanced AI security analyst: It streamlines threat hunting, query writing, investigations, and navigates complex data schemas within SentinelOne and across partner log sources. By optimizing workflows, Purple enables your team to focus on solving problems rather than managing processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 takeaways from red teaming 100 generative AI products</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-takeaways-from-red-teaming-100-generative-ai-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-takeaways-from-red-teaming-100-generative-ai-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s AI red team is excited to share our whitepaper, “Lessons from Red Teaming 100 Generative AI Products.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The AI red team was formed in 2018 to address the growing landscape of AI safety and security risks. Since then, we have expanded the scope and scale of our work significantly. We are one of the first red teams in the industry to cover both security and responsible AI, and red teaming has become a key part of Microsoft’s approach to generative AI product development. Red teaming is the first step in identifying potential harms and is followed by important initiatives at the company to measure, manage, and govern AI risk for our customers. Last year, we also announced PyRIT (The Python Risk Identification Tool for generative AI), an open-source toolkit to help researchers identify vulnerabilities in their own AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AV-Comparatives Crowns McAfee as 2024’s Leader in Online Protection and Speed</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/av-comparatives-crowns-mcafee-as-2024s-leader-in-online-protection-and-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/av-comparatives-crowns-mcafee-as-2024s-leader-in-online-protection-and-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mcafee.com/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/300x200_Blog_AV-Gold-Blog-300x200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;McAfee Total Protection users can feel even more secure online knowing that AV-Comparatives has named it the best in 2024 for both real-world protection and overall speed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two awards – the &lt;strong&gt;2024 Real-World Protection Gold Award&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Best Overall Speed Gold Award&lt;/strong&gt; – underscore McAfee’s commitment to providing powerful security without compromising PC performance, a critical combination at a time &lt;strong&gt;when 59% of people globally report falling victim to an online scam&lt;/strong&gt; or knowing someone who has, &lt;strong&gt;with 87% of these individuals losing money&lt;/strong&gt;—an astounding average loss of $1,366 USD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2025-23532 - MyAnime Widget CSRF Privilege Escalation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-23532-myanime-widget-csrf-privilege-escalation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cve-2025-23532-myanime-widget-csrf-privilege-escalation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CVE ID :&lt;/strong&gt; CVE-2025-23532&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Published :&lt;/strong&gt; Jan. 16, 2025, 8:15 p.m. | 9 hours, 45 minutes ago&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt; Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) vulnerability in Regios MyAnime Widget allows Privilege Escalation.This issue affects MyAnime Widget: from n/a through 1.0.&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;Severity:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.8 | HIGH&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Visit the link for more details, such as CVSS details, affected products, timeline, and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Strategies to Boost Mobile Event App Downloads</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effective-strategies-to-boost-mobile-event-app-downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/effective-strategies-to-boost-mobile-event-app-downloads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced world, mobile apps play a crucial role in ensuring event success. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a conference, trade show, festival, or any other event, a well-designed mobile app can significantly enhance the attendee experience. However, creating an amazing app is just half the battle. The real challenge is ensuring that your event app gets downloaded by your target audience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With hundreds of thousands of event apps available, getting noticed in a crowded marketplace can be tough. But don’t worry—there are proven strategies you can implement to boost &lt;strong&gt;mobile event app&lt;/strong&gt; downloads and increase engagement. In this article, we’ll explore effective techniques to encourage more attendees to download your event app and use it to its full potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New gadgets unveiled at CES 2025, and their impact on security | Kaspersky official blog</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-gadgets-unveiled-at-ces-2025-and-their-impact-on-security-kaspersky-official-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-gadgets-unveiled-at-ces-2025-and-their-impact-on-security-kaspersky-official-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity trends at the Consumer Electronics Show: from AI glasses to biometric locks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s premier tech events traditionally takes place every year in Las Vegas in early January. Sure, the Consumer Electronics Show (CES) pays attention to cybersecurity, but by no means is it top of the agenda. Looking for a giant monitor or AI washing machine? You’re in luck! Smart home protection against hackers? Might have to shop around a bit…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Short-Form Content Creation with AI Video Tools</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revolutionizing-short-form-content-creation-with-ai-video-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revolutionizing-short-form-content-creation-with-ai-video-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced digital world, short-form video content reigns supreme. Platforms like Instagram Reels, TikTok, and YouTube Shorts have become essential for creators, brands, and businesses to connect with their audiences. However, creating high-quality, engaging short-form videos can often be time-consuming and resource-intensive. Enter AI video tools — the game-changer that simplifies content creation while maintaining top-tier production quality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With tools like the &lt;strong&gt;free AI video generator&lt;/strong&gt;, creators can streamline the video creation process, allowing them to focus more on storytelling and strategy rather than the nitty-gritty of editing. These AI-powered platforms are not only accessible but also intuitive, making them ideal for seasoned creators and beginners alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Software Development and Web Development: Trends to Watch in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-software-development-and-web-development-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-future-of-software-development-and-web-development-trends-to-watch-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there! So, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the future of software development and web development, looking ahead to 2025. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy how fast things are changing, right? With AI making coding easier, blockchain adding security, and cloud computing transforming everything, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to keep up with. Not to mention, progressive web apps and low-code platforms are making waves too. Let&amp;rsquo;s break down what&amp;rsquo;s coming up and why it matters for anyone in the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a handy article on how to implement Face/Biometric Lock in your iOS App</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/this-is-a-handy-article-on-how-to-implement-face-biometric-lock-in-your-ios-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/this-is-a-handy-article-on-how-to-implement-face-biometric-lock-in-your-ios-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F2230009%2Fb6487413-d056-4763-9a33-dd38e24cacf2.png&#34; alt=&#34;divyeshvekariya&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-integrate-facebiometric-id-in-your-ios-app&#34;&gt;How to Integrate Face/Biometric ID in Your iOS App🚀&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;divyesh-vekariya--jan-13&#34;&gt;divyesh vekariya ・ Jan 13&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#ios #swift #mobile #swiftui&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone and iPad Acquisition Methods: Yet Another Comparison</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/iphone-and-ipad-acquisition-methods-yet-another-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/extraction-methods-2_1200x630.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of mobile forensics, where extracting data is the first (and arguably the most critical) step. Whether you’re working with an ancient Apple device or attempting to break into the latest iPhone 16 Pro Max, there is a method for every gadget – each with its own share of challenges. We love explaining the differences between the extraction techniques, detailing their pros and contras, but sometimes you are limited to the one and only method that is the most likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
