<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber-Security-Awareness on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-security-awareness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyber-Security-Awareness on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/cyber-security-awareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Detailed Guide to SOAR and SIEM</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/detailed-guide-to-soar-and-siem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Is SOAR?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR stands for &lt;strong&gt;Security Orchestration, Automation, and Response&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a cybersecurity tool designed to simplify and enhance the efficiency of IT teams by automating responses to various security threats. With SOAR, organizations can customize workflows to meet their specific needs, allowing IT teams to save time, reduce manual effort, and focus on critical tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-features-of-soar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Features of SOAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SOAR connects multiple security tools into a unified system, enabling smoother workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding the Backbone of the Global Economy: OT/ICS Security in the Oil and Gas Industry</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/safeguarding-the-backbone-of-the-global-economy-ot-ics-security-in-the-oil-and-gas-industry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oil and gas industry is an essential pillar of the global economy, enabling energy production, transportation, and storage that fuel every aspect of modern life. At the core of these operations lie Operational Technology (OT) and Industrial Control Systems (ICS), critical systems responsible for monitoring and controlling key industrial processes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the industry embraces digitization to improve efficiency and productivity, the reliance on OT/ICS has grown. However, this digital transformation comes at a cost—these systems have become prime targets for cyberattacks, with increasingly severe consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Security Operation Center Guidelines for best practices SOC Design</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-security-operation-center-guidelines-for-best-practices-soc-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cyber-security-operation-center-guidelines-for-best-practices-soc-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber Security is become most needed services for all business and industries in 2024. Every business is concerned about Cyber Security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security operations (SecOps) leaders face a multifaceted challenge: detecting elusive and novel threats using outdated tools, mitigating the risks posed by unexplored dark data, and managing the resource-intensive nature of staying ahead of evolving cyber threats, all while contending with a talent shortage in the field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to these challenges, organizations rely on Security Operations Centers (SOCs) as a cornerstone of their security strategy. A SOC serves as a centralized hub manned by dedicated experts equipped with a suite of sophisticated tools aimed at fortifying defenses against an array of threats. These experts employ proactive measures to identify and address system vulnerabilities, swiftly detecting, analyzing, and responding to potential threats in near real-time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft announces recipients of academic grants for AI research on combating phishing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/microsoft-announces-recipients-of-academic-grants-for-ai-research-on-combating-phishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day in the ever-changing technology landscape, we see boundaries shift as new ideas challenge the old status quo. This constant shift is observed in the increasingly sophisticated and connected tools, products, and services people and organizations use on a daily basis, but also in the security that needs to be built into these technologies to protect them against adversaries intent on abusing the same technologies for nefarious purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Microsoft, we are committed to harnessing the immense potential of AI to help solve many of our technology concerns today. We believe that working on the “bleeding edge” offers one of the best ways to serve our customers and the broader ecosystem, and AI is key to advancing our understanding and technical capabilities in many complex areas of cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations for Parents about Cyber Bullying</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/recommendations-for-parents-about-cyber-bullying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/recommendations-for-parents-about-cyber-bullying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some dedicated tips for keeping younger children safe online. One of these training tips goes into the risks of young children on the Internet, covers cyber bullying and other risky Internet behavior.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the suggestions parents should take into account regarding kids online.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Talk with your kids about online safety and the dangers of communicating with strangers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Put the computer your children use in a public part of your house so you can supervise their Internet access. Act immediately if they seem to be hiding something from you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a cyberattack?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-cyberattack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-a-cyberattack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-cyberattack&#34;&gt;What is a cyberattack?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks aim to damage or gain control or access to important documents and systems within a business or personal computer network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks are distributed by individuals or organizations for political, criminal, or personal intentions to destroy or gain access to classified information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of cyberattacks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Malware&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attack&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phishing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQL injection attacks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cross-site scripting (XSS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Botnets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ransomware&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using reliable software and a solid cyber strategy can lower the chances of a business or personal database being affected by a cyberattack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is SIEM ?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-siem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-siem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Security information and event management, SIEM for short, is a solution that helps organizations detect, analyze, and respond to security threats before they harm business operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SIEM, pronounced “sim,” combines both security information management (SIM) and security event management (SEM) into one security management system. SIEM technology collects event log data from a range of sources, identifies activity that deviates from the norm with real-time analysis, and takes appropriate action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
