<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esi on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/esi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Esi on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/esi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ESI Injection Part 2: Abusing specific implementations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/esi-injection-part-2-abusing-specific-implementations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/esi-injection-part-2-abusing-specific-implementations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjg9YTRZYJsxOkN9MuSd8YwYjeMF5PP2nWM55_oRKYFOcqmUqM0UYmKDH3ikglqhPya8EDEd7e6LtwSARKjnx5UCjr-NL1XqvdEatYso82fwe_62GsEzLjWLzEOmBfoO7cC8VnqUGqHvUl3/s320/injection%255B1%255D.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last year, we published a blog post about the injection of ESI tags in pages to fool the web cache proxy, and in August 2018, our colleague Louis Dion-Marcil spoke at Defcon about the discovery of the ESI Injection uncovered by the GoSecure intrusion testing team. For those interested, the presentation has been released on the Defcon YouTube channel. Defcon and Black Hat gave us an opportunity to unveil how ESI implementations can lead to session leakage through the client web browser without any malicious JavaScript. ESI is a specification that defines statements in the form of XML tags that are interpreted by the caching server. Those statements describe the content assembly of web pages by composing various HTML fragments from external resources. An attacker can abuse this mechanism by injecting a malicious tag inside an intercepted web page.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The current post&amp;rsquo;s objective is to follow up with items discovered after the first publication. Those discoveries are attack vectors that apply to specific implementations. It will also be an excellent platform to describe the proper mitigation for each of those findings.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Three new ESI tricks will be presented:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
