<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beginners on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/beginners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beginners on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/beginners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debugging 2024: Lessons learned, wins, and achievements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debugging-2024-lessons-learned-wins-and-achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/debugging-2024-lessons-learned-wins-and-achievements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a submission for the 2025 New Year Writing challenge: Retro’ing and Debugging 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who love looking back on a year. Reflecting on what I&amp;rsquo;ve done, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and what I want to achieve in the following year. This year—like many others—I jumped on Twitch to recap my year, review the stats, and talk about what I want to do moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the stats, things I learned, and goals I have for 2025. The main reason I like sharing these things is to inspire and motivate others. I hope you find it interesting ❤️.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to build your first model using DSS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-your-first-model-using-dss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-build-your-first-model-using-dss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GenAI is everywhere, and it’s changing how we approach technology. If you’ve ever wanted to dive into the world of large language models (LLMs) but felt intimidated, there’s good news! Hugging Face recently launched a self-paced course that’s perfect for beginners and more experienced enthusiasts alike. It’s hands-on, approachable, and designed to work on standard hardware thanks to the small footprint of the models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As soon as I heard the news, I decided to give it a go using Canonical’s Data Science Stack (DSS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Tailwind CSS</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/learning-tailwind-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/learning-tailwind-css/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-tailwind-css-a-comprehensive-guide-for-beginners&#34;&gt;Learning Tailwind CSS: A Comprehensive Guide for Beginners&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tailwind-css&#34;&gt;What is Tailwind CSS?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tailwind CSS is a utility-first CSS framework that allows developers to create custom designs without having to leave their HTML. Unlike traditional CSS frameworks that offer pre-designed components and styles, Tailwind provides a comprehensive set of utility classes (small, single-purpose classes) that you can combine to build any design directly in your markup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of web development, CSS libraries or UI libraries are collections of pre-defined styles and components that help developers style their applications quickly and efficiently. Tailwind CSS distinguishes itself from these by encouraging a utility-first approach, making it exceptionally flexible and adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;If you&#39;re trying to add collaborative features inside your app? Check this article!&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/if-youre-trying-to-add-collaborative-features-inside-your-app-check-this-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/if-youre-trying-to-add-collaborative-features-inside-your-app-check-this-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media2.dev.to/dynamic/image/width=800%2Cheight=%2Cfit=scale-down%2Cgravity=auto%2Cformat=auto/https%3A%2F%2Fdev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fuploads%2Fuser%2Fprofile_image%2F647287%2Fb72ea6c2-a966-40c4-bce6-badefc1face6.png&#34; alt=&#34;astrodevil&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;build-real-time-presence-features-like-figma-and-google-docs-in-your-app-in-minutes&#34;&gt;Build Real-Time Presence Features Like Figma and Google Docs in Your App in Minutes🚀🔥🧑‍💻&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;astrodevil--dec-26-24&#34;&gt;Astrodevil ・ Dec 26 &amp;lsquo;24&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#webdev #javascript #beginners #programming&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
