<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;12 Months of Fighting Cybercrime &amp; Defending Enterprises | SentinelLABS 2024 Review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/12-months-of-fighting-cybercrime-defending-enterprises-sentinellabs-2024-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From ransomware repurposed for espionage to increased exploitation of cloud platforms, learn about the key trends from SentinelLABS research in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the convergence of cybercrime and nation-state espionage to the strategic misuse of trusted platforms like Microsoft Azure and SaaS APIs, the cybersecurity landscape has grown more complex than ever in 2024. SentinelLABS has been at the forefront of these challenges, analyzing trends, uncovering campaigns, and equipping organizations with actionable intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure App Service Exposed Hundreds of Source Code Repositories after four years.</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/azure-app-service-exposed-hundreds-of-source-code-repositories-after-four-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A security flaw has been discovered in Microsoft’s Azure App Service that exposed source code for customer applications written in Java, Node, PHP, Python, and Ruby for at least four years since September 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Wiz researchers, the vulnerability, codenamed “Not Legit,” was first reported to the tech giant on October 7, 2021, and mitigations were implemented to fix the bug in November. Microsoft said “a limited subset of customers” are at risk. “Customers who deployed code to App Service Linux via Local Git after files had already been created in the application are the only impacted customers.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protecting AI Infrastructures | Introducing SentinelOne’s AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/protecting-ai-infrastructures-introducing-sentinelones-ai-security-posture-management-ai-spm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SentinelOne’s new AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution helps organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of AI introduces unique security considerations. Misconfigurations in AI infrastructure and unsecured APIs can create weaknesses that cybercriminals will exploit. In this blog post, we dive deep into how SentinelOne’s agentless AI Security Posture Management (AI-SPM) solution addresses these challenges by offering AI inventory automation, misconfiguration detection, and attack path analysis to help organizations secure their AI workloads effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why security teams rely on Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR for managed detection and response</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-security-teams-rely-on-microsoft-defender-experts-for-xdr-for-managed-detection-and-response/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The expanding attack surface is creating more opportunities for exploitation and adding to the pressure on security leaders and teams. Increasingly, organizations are investing in managed detection and response services (MDR) to bolster their security operations center (SOC) and meet the challenge. Demand is growing rapidly: according to Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan, the market for MDR is expanding at a rate of 35.2% annually.1   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While there are new vendors launching MDR services regularly, many security teams are turning to Microsoft Defender Experts for XDR, a recognized leader, to deliver comprehensive coverage.1 Employed worldwide by organizations across industries, Microsoft’s team of dedicated experts proactively hunts for cyberthreats and triages, investigates, and responds to incidents on a customer’s behalf around the clock across their most critical assets. Our proven service brings together in-house security professionals and industry-leading protection with Microsoft Defender XDR to help security teams rapidly stop cyberthreats and keep their environments secure.2 &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
