<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaboration on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaboration on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How DevOps would benefits for IT operations?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-would-benefits-for-it-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-devops-would-benefits-for-it-operations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-1024x581.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps, a fusion of “Development” and “Operations,” represents a cultural and professional movement that emphasizes collaboration, communication, and integration among all stakeholders involved in the development, operations, and delivery of software. By fostering a culture of collaboration, automation, and continuous improvement, DevOps seeks to shorten the software development lifecycle while delivering high-quality software. This methodology is characterized by a continuous cycle of integration, delivery, and deployment, which helps organizations adapt quickly to changing market demands and improve overall efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS launches AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications. The Android Team Awareness Kit (ATAK)—also known as Android Tactical Assault Kit for military use—is a smartphone geospatial infrastructure and situational awareness application. It provides mapping, messaging, and geofencing capabilities to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
