<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bestpractices on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/bestpractices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bestpractices on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/bestpractices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to use DevOps for DevSecOps?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-devops-for-devsecops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-devops-for-devsecops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/image-52-1024x550.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In any software development or DevOps environment, &lt;strong&gt;scope management&lt;/strong&gt; (or descoping) is an essential part of ensuring that the project is delivered on time, within budget, and aligns with business objectives. Descoping involves adjusting the scope of a project—either by removing non-essential features, prioritizing key requirements, or shifting resources—to make sure the development process stays on track without sacrificing quality or user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps plays a significant role in &lt;strong&gt;descoping&lt;/strong&gt; by leveraging its core principles: collaboration, automation, continuous feedback, and continuous delivery. These principles help DevOps teams quickly identify areas of scope that may not align with business goals or technical constraints, allowing them to make adjustments in real time without slowing down the development lifecycle. By embracing DevOps practices, teams can maintain agility and ensure that only the most valuable features make it to production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
