<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ca-Program on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/ca-program/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ca-Program on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/ca-program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing CA Practices: Key Updates in Mozilla Root Store Policy, v3.0</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-ca-practices-key-updates-in-mozilla-root-store-policy-v3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhancing-ca-practices-key-updates-in-mozilla-root-store-policy-v3-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla remains committed to fostering a secure, agile, and transparent Web PKI ecosystem. The new Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) v3.0, effective March 15, 2025, introduces critical updates to strengthen Certificate Authority (CA) practices and enhance compliance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A major focus of &lt;strong&gt;MRSP v3.0&lt;/strong&gt; is tackling the long-standing challenge of &lt;strong&gt;delayed certificate revocation&lt;/strong&gt;—an issue that has historically weakened the security and reliability of TLS certificate management. The updated policy establishes &lt;strong&gt;clearer revocation expectations, improved incident reporting, subscriber education by CAs, revocation planning,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;automated certificate issuance&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure that certificate replacement and revocation can be handled promptly and at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Quality of Publicly Trusted Intermediate CA Certificates with Enhanced Oversight and Automation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improving-the-quality-of-publicly-trusted-intermediate-ca-certificates-with-enhanced-oversight-and-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improving-the-quality-of-publicly-trusted-intermediate-ca-certificates-with-enhanced-oversight-and-automation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In keeping with our commitment to the security and privacy of individuals on the internet, Mozilla is increasing our oversight and adding automation to our compliance-checking of publicly trusted intermediate CA certificates (“intermediate certificates”). This improvement in automation is important because intermediate certificates play a critical part in the web PKI (Public-Key Infrastructure). Intermediate CA keys directly sign server certificates, and we currently recognize nearly 3,000 intermediate certificates, which chain up to approximately 150 root CA certificates embedded as trust anchors in NSS and Firefox. More specifically, we are updating the Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) and associated guidance, improving the public review of third-party intermediate certificates on the Mozilla dev-security-policy list, and enhancing automation in the Common CA Database (CCADB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revocation Reason Codes for TLS Server Certificates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revocation-reason-codes-for-tls-server-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/revocation-reason-codes-for-tls-server-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our continued efforts to improve the security of the web PKI, we are taking a multi-pronged approach to tackling some long-existing problems with revocation of TLS server certificates. In addition to our ongoing CRLite work, we added new requirements to version 2.8 of Mozilla’s Root Store Policy that will enable Firefox to depend on revocation reason codes being used consistently, so they can be relied on when verifying the validity of certificates during TLS connections. We also added a new requirement that CA operators provide their full CRL URLs in the CCADB. This will enable Firefox to pre-load more complete certificate revocation data, eliminating dependency on the infrastructure of CAs during the certificate verification part of establishing TLS connections. The combination of these two new sets of requirements will further enable Firefox to enforce revocation checking of TLS server certificates, which makes TLS connections even more secure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Mozilla’s Root Store Policy to Version 2.8</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upgrading-mozillas-root-store-policy-to-version-2-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/upgrading-mozillas-root-store-policy-to-version-2-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In accordance with the Mozilla Manifesto, which emphasizes the open development of policy that protects users’ privacy and security, we have worked with the Mozilla community over the past several months to improve the Mozilla Root Store Policy (MRSP) so that we can now announce version 2.8, effective June 1, 2022. These policy changes aim to improve the transparency of Certificate Authority (CA) operations and the certificates that they issue. A detailed comparison of the policy changes may be found here, and the significant policy changes that appear in this version are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Version 2.9 of the Mozilla Root Store Policy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/version-2-9-of-the-mozilla-root-store-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/version-2-9-of-the-mozilla-root-store-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online security is constantly evolving, and thus we are excited to announce the publication of MRSP version 2.9, demonstrating that we are committed to keep up with the advancement of the web and further our commitment to a secure and trustworthy internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With each update to the &lt;strong&gt;Mozilla Root Store Policy&lt;/strong&gt; (MRSP), we aim to address emerging challenges and enhance the integrity and reliability of our root store. Version 2.9 introduces several noteworthy changes and refinements, and within this blog post we provide an overview of key updates to the MRSP and their implications for the broader online community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
