<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Threat-Lab on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/threat-lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Threat-Lab on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/threat-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MDR for MSPs: Navigating EDR compatibility</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mdr-for-msps-navigating-edr-compatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mdr-for-msps-navigating-edr-compatibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to endpoint detection and response (EDR) compatibility within an MDR offering, managed service providers (MSPs) are weighing two key priorities: native EDR integration or the flexibility to support multiple solutions. According to a recent OpenText survey, opinions are split almost evenly. While 52% of MSPs view native compatibility as moderately or very important, 48% place greater value on flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This divide reflects the unique demands MSPs face. On one hand, native compatibility ensures a tight integration. On the other, the ability to work seamlessly with various EDR tools is critical for MSPs managing diverse client environments. For MSPs managing a mix of EDR tools across their customer base, this adaptability can be the difference between a smooth operation and a logistical headache.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenText Secure Cloud: Streamline workflows with integrations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/opentext-secure-cloud-streamline-workflows-with-integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/opentext-secure-cloud-streamline-workflows-with-integrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simplifying security management is an important step toward better protection without sacrificing operational efficiency. With the added capability of automating processes by integrating with popular tools, security management can also deliver streamlined workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenText&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png&#34; alt=&#34;™&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA; Secure Cloud provides billing reconciliation by integrating with popular tools such as HaloPSA, ConnectWise PSA, AutoTask, and Kaseya BMS so you can automate many of the processes that would typically require manual input. These integrations help boost efficiency and reduce human error.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passkeys: The future of secure and seamless authentication</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/passkeys-the-future-of-secure-and-seamless-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/passkeys-the-future-of-secure-and-seamless-authentication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-passkeys&#34;&gt;What are passkeys?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may have seen the term “passkeys” appearing more frequently in tech news, app updates, and security discussions. Major companies like Apple, Google, and Microsoft are rolling out passkeys as a replacement for passwords, promising both enhanced security and a smoother user experience. But what exactly are passkeys, and why are they considered the future of authentication?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Password Day coming up this Saturday, it’s the perfect time to discuss the future of authentication. Passwords have long been the foundation of online security, but they come with significant downsides: they can be stolen, guessed, or reused across multiple sites. Enter passkeys, a next-generation authentication technology designed to replace passwords entirely with a more secure and user-friendly alternative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 ways to get the most from Data Privacy Week</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-ways-to-get-the-most-from-data-privacy-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-ways-to-get-the-most-from-data-privacy-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Privacy Week (Jan. 27-31) is an excellent opportunity to reflect on the importance of protecting one of your most valuable assets: your personal information. Whether you’re browsing online as a consumer or running a business, data privacy is paramount in an environment where cyber threats can lurk around every corner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of Data Privacy Week, here are six ideas to help you protect yourself—and your data:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-understand-your-level-of-risk&#34;&gt;1. Understand your level of risk&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get acquainted with the phrase personally identifiable information. This includes any data that can be used to identify you, and it ranges from your name and address to more sensitive information like   health and financial records. Here are some common examples:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Managed Detection and Response: Key trends MSPs can’t afford to ignore</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/managed-detection-and-response-key-trends-msps-cant-afford-to-ignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/managed-detection-and-response-key-trends-msps-cant-afford-to-ignore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber threats have never been more relentless, and businesses of all sizes are feeling the pressure. That’s where Managed Detection and Response (MDR) comes in—a lifeline for overburdened security teams navigating a threat landscape that’s growing more sophisticated by the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its core, MDR is about augmenting, complementing, and upskilling internal security operations. It’s not just about tools—it’s about the expert humans behind those tools. MDR providers bring battle-tested security practitioners and capabilities with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
