<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating Agile workflows with the gitlab-triage gem&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-agile-workflows-with-the-gitlab-triage-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-agile-workflows-with-the-gitlab-triage-gem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to our &amp;ldquo;Getting started with GitLab&amp;rdquo; series, where we help newcomers get familiar with the GitLab DevSecOps platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post dives into the &lt;code&gt;gitlab-triage&lt;/code&gt; gem, a powerful tool that lets you create bots to automate your Agile workflow. Say goodbye to manual tasks and hello to streamlined efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-automate-your-workflow&#34;&gt;Why automate your workflow?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Efficiency is key in software development. Automating repetitive tasks like triaging issues and merge requests frees up valuable time for your team to focus on what matters most: building amazing software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Beautifying our UI: Enhancing GitLab&#39;s deployment experience&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beautifying-our-ui-enhancing-gitlabs-deployment-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/beautifying-our-ui-enhancing-gitlabs-deployment-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At GitLab, we’ve implemented an innovative approach to improving our experience called Beautifying our UI. This unique initiative pairs one product designer with a frontend engineer for a milestone or two, and empowers them to make self-directed usability improvements across the platform. Ultimately, this helps build a more polished product experience, as these pairs can quickly address pain points, refine interactions, and deliver thoughtful improvements that make the platform more efficient and enjoyable to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Build a new website in a few easy steps with GitLab Pages&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-a-new-website-in-a-few-easy-steps-with-gitlab-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-a-new-website-in-a-few-easy-steps-with-gitlab-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A personal website is more than just a utility for digital creators and professionals in tech. It&amp;rsquo;s a representation of your brand. But creating one from scratch can be time-consuming and expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With GitLab Pages, you can host your website with built-in features, including SSL certificates and a GitLab-provided domain. All of this is available on GitLab&amp;rsquo;s free tier, making it an efficient solution for hosting your professional presence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to take you on a fun journey to craft a stunning personal website using GitLab Pages! We’ve got a super simple, versatile template that you can easily jazz up to reflect your unique style. So grab your favorite snack, get comfy, and let’s turn your online presence into something truly fabulous!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Build and run containers in Remote Development workspaces&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-and-run-containers-in-remote-development-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/build-and-run-containers-in-remote-development-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Development environments often require the ability to build and run containers as part of their local development. Securely running containers within containers can be challenging. This article will provide a step-by-step guide to securely build and run containers in a workspace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a Kubernetes cluster on AWS EKS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure Sysbox&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure GitLab agent for Kubernetes and GitLab Workspaces Proxy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure sudo access for a workspace with Sysbox&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configure Ingress Controller&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build containers inside a workspace&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run containers inside a workspace&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get started today&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-aws-eks&#34;&gt;Create a Kubernetes cluster on AWS EKS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the AWS CLI on your local machine. Next, configure a named profile and export it to ensure all the following &lt;code&gt;aws&lt;/code&gt; commands use the set credentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Create a workspace quickly with the GitLab default devfile&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/create-a-workspace-quickly-with-the-gitlab-default-devfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/create-a-workspace-quickly-with-the-gitlab-default-devfile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Software development environments can be complex to set up and maintain. Developers often spend a significant amount of time configuring their local environments with the right dependencies, tools, and settings. GitLab aims to solve this by providing a default devfile that enables you to create workspaces and to start developing quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-workspaces&#34;&gt;GitLab Workspaces&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab Workspaces provide isolated development environments for making changes to your GitLab projects without the complexity of setting up local dependencies. Workspaces ensure reproducible development setups, allowing developers to share their environment configurations effortlessly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab achieves PCI DSS Attestation of Compliance&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-achieves-pci-dss-attestation-of-compliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-achieves-pci-dss-attestation-of-compliance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compliance with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard (DSS) helps to alleviate security vulnerabilities and protect cardholder data. The PCI standard is required of any enterprise handling credit card and related authentication data or whose services could impact the security of the cardholder data environment. GitLab, as the most comprehensive AI-powered DevSecOps platform, provides the tools and resources to support our customers’ security posture, including those handling PCI-relevant data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab Duo Self-Hosted: Enterprise AI built for data privacy&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-self-hosted-enterprise-ai-built-for-data-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-self-hosted-enterprise-ai-built-for-data-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the general availability of GitLab Duo Self-Hosted for Code Suggestions and Chat. An optional capability for self-managed customers with a GitLab Duo Enterprise subscription, GitLab Duo Self-Hosted supports deployment flexibility across multiple platforms, including on-premises infrastructure or in private clouds and secure cloud environments through AWS Bedrock and Azure OpenAI. GitLab Duo Self-Hosted empowers teams to innovate with AI while helping them maintain control over sensitive data and intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab Duo Workflow: Enterprise visibility and control for agentic AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-workflow-enterprise-visibility-and-control-for-agentic-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-workflow-enterprise-visibility-and-control-for-agentic-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the opening of the waitlist for the private beta of GitLab Duo Workflow: &lt;strong&gt;agentic AI built on top of the most comprehensive DevSecOps platform.&lt;/strong&gt; The next step in our AI roadmap, GitLab Duo Workflow will help development teams navigate everything from project bootstrapping to deployment processes, from debugging issues to cross-team coordination, all within the IDE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab Duo Workflow leverages the GitLab platform&amp;rsquo;s structure for collaboration, continuous integration, continuous deployment, security, and compliance to help organizations as they accelerate their development process with AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How GitLab measures Red Team impact: The adoption rate metric&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-measures-red-team-impact-the-adoption-rate-metric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-measures-red-team-impact-the-adoption-rate-metric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2024, we started a journey to implement better metrics for our internal Red Team. Our first iteration focused on what we now call the adoption rate metric, which measures how often the recommendations our team makes are accepted and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choosing this metric was very deliberate. While there are many ways to measure a Red Team&amp;rsquo;s impact, we wanted to start with something fundamental: Are we actually driving meaningful security improvements? The adoption rate directly ties our work to real security outcomes, and we could measure it using tools and processes we already had in place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Introducing GitLab’s Open Source Security Hub&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlabs-open-source-security-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlabs-open-source-security-hub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we’re excited to announce the launch of GitLab’s Open Source Security Hub — a central repository of security-focused projects developed by GitLab’s internal security team. These tools are designed to help developers, security practitioners, and organizations build safer, more secure software, and more resilient security programs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Securing systems is an ongoing challenge for businesses as threat actors continually adapt to new technologies and find creative ways to exploit organizations. Not only are they evolving their tactics, techniques and procedures, but they’re also collaborating through criminal networks, sharing strategies, stolen data, and malicious tools to launch coordinated attacks at scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Self-service security alert handling with GitLab&#39;s UAM&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/self-service-security-alert-handling-with-gitlabs-uam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/self-service-security-alert-handling-with-gitlabs-uam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The GitLab Security Operations team prioritizes automation that enables security engineers to focus on high-impact work rather than routine tasks that can be automated. A key innovation in this automation strategy is creation of the User Attestation Module (UAM), which allows GitLab team members to directly respond to and verify security alerts flagged as potentially malicious. When the GUARD framework detects suspicious activity, it routes the alert to the relevant team member for review. The team member can then attest whether they recognize and authorize the activity. Their response is recorded for audit purposes, and, based on their input, the system either closes the alert or escalates it to the Security Incident Response Team (SIRT).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The GitLab AI Security Framework for security leaders&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-gitlab-ai-security-framework-for-security-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-gitlab-ai-security-framework-for-security-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As companies rapidly adopt AI technologies, CISOs face a new frontier of security challenges. Many security leaders find themselves grappling with unfamiliar questions: How do we evaluate AI vendors differently from traditional software vendors? What security controls matter most? Where does vendor responsibility end and customer responsibility begin? How do we evaluate AI security risks within the context of the service provided? To help answer these questions, we’ve created the GitLab AI Security Framework to show security leaders how GitLab and customers enable secure AI-powered development using GitLab Duo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The ultimate guide to token management at GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-token-management-at-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-token-management-at-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine this: You are an engineer at a growing tech company, and it’s 2 a.m. when you get an urgent call. A critical deployment pipeline has failed, and your team is scrambling to figure out why. After hours of digging, you realize someone revoked a personal access token belonging to an engineer who left the company a week ago. This token was tied to several key automation processes, and now your entire system is in chaos. How do you make sure it does not happen again?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Vulnerability risk prioritization made simple with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerability-risk-prioritization-made-simple-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/vulnerability-risk-prioritization-made-simple-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Development and security teams are often overwhelmed by the number of vulnerabilities they need to remediate. Many organizations remediate less than 16% of their known vulnerabilities monthly. Vulnerability management teams face a constant challenge: which security flaws deserve immediate attention? Three key frameworks help answer this question: Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS), Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV), and Exploit Prediction Scoring System (EPSS). The GitLab 17.9 release adds support for these frameworks. In this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to use these frameworks within GitLab to efficiently prioritize risk across your dependency and container image vulnerabilities using this data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What&#39;s new in Git 2.49.0?&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-49-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-49-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Git project recently released Git 2.49.0. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a few notable highlights from this release, which includes contributions from GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Git team and the wider Git community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s covered:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;git-backfill(1) and the new path-walk API&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduction of zlib-ng&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Continued iteration on Meson&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deprecation of .git/branches/ and .git/remotes/&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rust bindings for libgit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New name-hashing algorithm&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Promisor remote capability&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thin clone using &lt;code&gt;--revision&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-backfill1-and-the-new-path-walk-api&#34;&gt;git-backfill(1) and the new path-walk API&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;code&gt;git-clone(1)&lt;/code&gt; a Git repository, you can pass it the &lt;code&gt;--filter&lt;/code&gt; option. Using this option allows you to create a &lt;em&gt;partial clone&lt;/em&gt;. In a partial clone the server only sends a subset of reachable objects according to the given object filter. For example, creating a clone with &lt;code&gt;--filter=blob:none&lt;/code&gt; will not fetch any blobs (file contents) from the server and create a &lt;em&gt;blobless clone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Code Completion: Less Is More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-code-completion-less-is-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-code-completion-less-is-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following our journey, you might’ve read our recent blog post on the Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs. From that post, you might remember this cool chart on code completions. In April, something exciting happened: our acceptance rate went up while the explicit cancel rate dropped. In […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following our journey, you might’ve read our recent blog post on the Complete the Un-Completable: The State of AI Completion in JetBrains IDEs. From that post, you might remember this cool chart on code completions. In April, something exciting happened: our acceptance rate went up while the explicit cancel rate dropped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CLion 2025.1 Goes Beta With Enhanced CLion Nova, Debugger, and Embedded Development</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/clion-2025-1-goes-beta-with-enhanced-clion-nova-debugger-and-embedded-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/clion-2025-1-goes-beta-with-enhanced-clion-nova-debugger-and-embedded-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Beta version of CLion 2025.1 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 251.23774.112 for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu. DOWNLOAD CLION 2025.1 BETA Read the full release notes on YouTrack. Below […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Beta version of CLion 2025.1 is now available with key improvements and changes announced for the upcoming release. You can download build 251.23774.112 for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four steps toward building an open source community</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-steps-toward-building-an-open-source-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/four-steps-toward-building-an-open-source-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three maintainers talk about how they fostered their open source communities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Four steps toward building an open source community appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source projects generally begin with a problem to be solved. If it’s a problem a lot of people have, it may gain traction. Eventually you might have many people contributing. Before you know it, your project might turn into more than just a project, but a community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full exposure: A practical approach to handling sensitive data leaks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-exposure-a-practical-approach-to-handling-sensitive-data-leaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/full-exposure-a-practical-approach-to-handling-sensitive-data-leaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Treating exposures as full and complete can help you respond more effectively to focus on what truly matters: securing systems, protecting sensitive data, and maintaining the trust of stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Full exposure: A practical approach to handling sensitive data leaks appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post originally appeared in Infosecurity Magazine, and is republished here with permission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced world of software development, accidents can happen—even to the best of us. One such unfortunate event is the accidental leakage of sensitive data such as private or internal source code. When this occurs, companies often find themselves in a frantic rush to assess the situation, leading them down the rabbit hole of trying to determine just how exposed their sensitive data really is. However, this quest for degrees of exposure is a futile endeavor. There’s no such thing as “just a little bit exposed.” Instead, it’s better to opt for the more pragmatic approach: treat the exposure as full and complete from the moment it happens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Availability Report: February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Availability Report: February 2025 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In February, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 25 14:25 UTC (lasting 2 hours and 19 minutes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On February 25, 2025, between 14:25 UTC and 16:44 UTC, email and web notifications experienced delivery delays. At the peak of the incident, the delay resulted in ~10% of all notifications taking over 10 minutes to be delivered, with the remaining ~90% being delivered within 5-10 minutes. This incident was caused by worker pools running too close to capacity at peak times, resulting in a delay in queue processing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub for Beginners: Essential features of GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-for-beginners-essential-features-of-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-for-beginners-essential-features-of-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Get the most out of Copilot with code completion, inline chat, slash commands, Copilot code review, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub for Beginners: Essential features of GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our second GitHub for Beginners series, where we are diving into the world of GitHub Copilot. In our previous episode, we introduced you to GitHub Copilot and gave you some guidance on getting started. Hopefully you’ve had a chance to give it a try! Today we’re going to be looking at some of the essential features of Copilot, and provide you with tips on how to make the most out of your AI coding assistant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Git 2.49</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-49/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.49. Here is GitHub’s look at some of the most interesting features and changes introduced since last time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Highlights from Git 2.49 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.49 with features and bug fixes from over 89 contributors, 24 of them new. We last caught up with you on the latest in Git back when 2.48 was released.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How GitHub engineers learn new codebases</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-github-engineers-learn-new-codebases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-github-engineers-learn-new-codebases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strategies to quickly get up to speed, whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned engineer or a newcomer to the field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How GitHub engineers learn new codebases appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter where you are in your coding career, you will likely come across a new codebase or problem domain that is completely unfamiliar to you. Because codebases can be filled with many layers of design patterns, bugfixes, and temporary workarounds, learning a new one can be a time-consuming and frustrating process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the IntelliJ Infrastructure Team Cuts Build Execution Time by 30% With TeamCity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-the-intellij-infrastructure-team-cuts-build-execution-time-by-30-with-teamcity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-the-intellij-infrastructure-team-cuts-build-execution-time-by-30-with-teamcity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction JetBrains is known for developing some of the world’s most popular IDEs, including IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and WebStorm. Supporting this development is a dedicated infrastructure team that ensures hundreds of developers can efficiently build, test, and release these products. At the core of their workflow is TeamCity, JetBrains’ own CI/CD solution, which powers build […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is known for developing some of the world’s most popular IDEs, including IntelliJ IDEA, PyCharm, and WebStorm. Supporting this development is a dedicated infrastructure team that ensures hundreds of developers can efficiently build, test, and release these products.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.5 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-5-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-5-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve released another update for v2024.3! You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website. This new version that brings the following valuable improvements:  To see the full list of issues addressed in this […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve released another update for v2024.3!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can update to this version from inside the IDE, using the Toolbox App, or by using snaps if you are a Ubuntu user. You can also download it from our website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IssueOps: Automate CI/CD (and more!) with GitHub Issues and Actions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/issueops-automate-ci-cd-and-more-with-github-issues-and-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/issueops-automate-ci-cd-and-more-with-github-issues-and-actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A look into building IssueOps workflows on GitHub to do everything from CI/CD to handling approvals and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post IssueOps: Automate CI/CD (and more!) with GitHub Issues and Actions appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Software development is filled with repetitive tasks—managing issues, handling approvals, triggering CI/CD workflows, and more. But what if you could automate these types of tasks directly within GitHub Issues? That’s the promise of &lt;strong&gt;IssueOps&lt;/strong&gt;, a methodology that turns GitHub Issues into a command center for automation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 24 and IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-24-and-intellij-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-24-and-intellij-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA has supported Java 24 since an earlier release, with more enhancements being added in the later releases! I’m often asked, “What’s the best feature of Java 24?” My answer? Why pick just one? 🙂 Java 24 continues to enhance the language with improvements like Simple source files and instance main methods, Primitive Types […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA has supported Java 24 since an earlier release, with more enhancements being added in the later releases!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Xdebug Helper Browser Extension</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-xdebug-helper-browser-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-xdebug-helper-browser-extension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years, PHP developers have relied on the popular Xdebug Helper Chrome extension to simplify their debugging experience with Xdebug. Unfortunately, this extension may soon no longer be supported, potentially disrupting developers’ workflows. To ensure that PHP developers can continue debugging without interruptions, we’re collaborating with Fraser Chapman on the official Xdebug Helper extension for […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, PHP developers have relied on the popular Xdebug Helper Chrome extension to simplify their debugging experience with Xdebug. Unfortunately, this extension may soon no longer be supported, potentially disrupting developers’ workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the JetBrains Team at GDC 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-the-jetbrains-team-at-gdc-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-the-jetbrains-team-at-gdc-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From March 17–21, 2025, the Game Developers Conference (GDC) will bring together professionals from across the game industry at the Moscone Center in San Francisco. JetBrains is excited to once again be part of this event, and we invite you to visit our booth to explore how our tools can enhance your game development workflow. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From March 17–21, 2025, the Game Developers Conference (GDC) will bring together professionals from across the game industry at the Moscone Center in San Francisco. JetBrains is excited to once again be part of this event, and we invite you to visit our booth to explore how our tools can enhance your game development workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shout-Out to Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/shout-out-to-kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/shout-out-to-kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Kotlin for server-side development and sharing your experiences – whether through blog posts, videos, or sample projects – know that we see you, and we want to highlight your work! Recent picks from the community 📖 [Article] From Java to Kotlin — a practical example of how to convert code – Paul […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re using Kotlin for server-side development and sharing your experiences – whether through blog posts, videos, or sample projects – know that we see you, and we want to highlight your work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sign in as anyone: Bypassing SAML SSO authentication with parser differentials</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sign-in-as-anyone-bypassing-saml-sso-authentication-with-parser-differentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/sign-in-as-anyone-bypassing-saml-sso-authentication-with-parser-differentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Critical authentication bypass vulnerabilities (CVE-2025-25291 + CVE-2025-25292) were discovered in ruby-saml up to version 1.17.0. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll shed light on how these vulnerabilities that rely on a parser differential were uncovered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Sign in as anyone: Bypassing SAML SSO authentication with parser differentials appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Critical authentication bypass vulnerabilities (CVE-2025-25291 + CVE-2025-25292) were discovered in ruby-saml up to version 1.17.0. Attackers who are in possession of a single valid signature that was created with the key used to validate SAML responses or assertions of the targeted organization can use it to construct SAML assertions themselves and are in turn able to log in as any user. In other words, it could be used for an account takeover attack. Users of ruby-saml should update to version 1.18.0. References to libraries making use of ruby-saml (such as omniauth-saml) need also be updated to a version that reference a fixed version of ruby-saml.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support for Game Consoles in JetBrains Rider</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-game-consoles-in-jetbrains-rider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-game-consoles-in-jetbrains-rider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big news for console game developers! As part of the 2024.3 release, JetBrains Rider added support for PlayStation®5 and Xbox consoles, allowing you to build, deploy, and debug your Unreal Engine and custom game engines directly on your preferred game consoles. Rider has excellent built-in support for working with C++, with lots of great functionality […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big news for console game developers! As part of the 2024.3 release, JetBrains Rider added support for PlayStation®5 and Xbox consoles, allowing you to build, deploy, and debug your Unreal Engine and custom game engines directly on your preferred game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Roadmap 2025: Updating the UI, TeamCity Recipes, and Much More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-roadmap-2025-updating-the-ui-teamcity-recipes-and-much-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-roadmap-2025-updating-the-ui-teamcity-recipes-and-much-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, the TeamCity team is working on a number of new initiatives, including updating the UI, TeamCity recipes, Jenkins migration tools, and many others. Read on to learn what our focus is for 2025. Modernizing the TeamCity Enterprise interface In 2025, we’re taking a major step forward in enhancing the TeamCity experience. The modern […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, the TeamCity team is working on a number of new initiatives, including updating the UI, TeamCity recipes, Jenkins migration tools, and many others. Read on to learn what our focus is for 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using AI Agents for Notebook Debugging</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-ai-agents-for-notebook-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/using-ai-agents-for-notebook-debugging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Debugging computational notebooks can be quite frustrating for a variety of reasons, including issues like out-of-order cell execution, missing data files, and library conflicts. Traditional AI tools often struggle with these problems due to the interactive nature of notebooks, but at JetBrains, we are exploring new solutions. Our research team has developed a prototype of […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debugging computational notebooks can be quite frustrating for a variety of reasons, including issues like out-of-order cell execution, missing data files, and library conflicts. Traditional AI tools often struggle with these problems due to the interactive nature of notebooks, but at JetBrains, we are exploring new solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: How to create checklists in Markdown for easier task tracking</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/video-how-to-create-checklists-in-markdown-for-easier-task-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/video-how-to-create-checklists-in-markdown-for-easier-task-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how to create checklists in your GitHub repositories, Issues, and PRs? Make task lists more manageable in your GitHub repositories, issues, and pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Video: How to create checklists in Markdown for easier task tracking appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how the cool cats of the internet make Markdown checklists in their GitHub repositories, issues, and pull requests? Me too. And I’m here to say: you too can be a cool cat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WebStorm 2025.1 Beta Is Here With AI Enhancements, Framework Improvements, and a Better User Experience</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/webstorm-2025-1-beta-is-here-with-ai-enhancements-framework-improvements-and-a-better-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/webstorm-2025-1-beta-is-here-with-ai-enhancements-framework-improvements-and-a-better-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The EAP cycle for WebStorm 2025.1 is over, and we’re excited to share what’s included in the Beta builds. The Toolbox App is the easiest way to get the Beta builds and keep both them and your stable versions up to date. You can also manually download the Beta builds from our website. DOWNLOAD WEBSTORM […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The EAP cycle for WebStorm 2025.1 is over, and we’re excited to share what’s included in the Beta builds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Java endures: The foundation of modern enterprise development</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-java-endures-the-foundation-of-modern-enterprise-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-java-endures-the-foundation-of-modern-enterprise-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For 30 years, Java has been a cornerstone of enterprise software development. Here’s why—and how to learn Java.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Why Java endures: The foundation of modern enterprise development appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a true story: I learned Java after pretending to be an Android developer when I first started out in software development. While doing that, I quickly learned something important: Java isn’t just a convenient entry point into tech, it’s a strategic career choice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to harmonize Agile sprints with product roadmaps&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-harmonize-agile-sprints-with-product-roadmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-harmonize-agile-sprints-with-product-roadmaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture this: Product and Development teams are working in isolation. Product has created a 12-month roadmap and communicated it to internal stakeholders but didn&amp;rsquo;t review it with their development team. Dev starts building the features planned for the upcoming sprint without considering the broader product roadmap, leading to missed opportunities to optimize timing, like running projects in parallel, accounting for team capacity, or building reusable APIs that could serve multiple initiatives. The lack of coordination results in inefficiencies and delayed value delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to scan a full commit history to detect sensitive secrets&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-scan-a-full-commit-history-to-detect-sensitive-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-scan-a-full-commit-history-to-detect-sensitive-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Secrets left exposed in outdated repositories pose significant risk for data breaches. For example, a still-active secret key can be exposed, leaving it vulnerable to exploitation. Secrets include access keys, API tokens, private keys, and other sensitive values.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to use GitLab Secret Detection to scan a repository’s full commit history, including all branches, to detect sensitive secrets. In addition, you will discover how to view the results directly within the GitLab UI without the need for any integration. All it takes is just a couple of lines of code in your &lt;code&gt;.gitlab-ci.yml&lt;/code&gt; pipeline file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tutorial: Security scanning in air-gapped environments&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-security-scanning-in-air-gapped-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-security-scanning-in-air-gapped-environments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air-gapped environments are computer networks or systems that are physically isolated from unsecured networks, such as the public internet or unsecured local area networks. This isolation is implemented as a security measure to protect sensitive data and critical systems from external cyber threats by providing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enhanced security: By physically isolating systems from external networks, air-gapped environments help prevent remote attacks, malware infections, and unauthorized data access. This is crucial for highly sensitive data and critical systems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data protection: Air-gapping provides the strongest protection against data exfiltration since there&amp;rsquo;s no direct connection that attackers could use to steal information.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Critical infrastructure protection: For systems that control vital infrastructure (like power plants, water treatment facilities, or military systems), air-gapping helps prevent potentially catastrophic cyber attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compliance requirements: Many regulatory frameworks require air-gapping for certain types of sensitive data or critical systems, particularly in government, healthcare, and financial sectors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Malware protection: Without network connectivity, systems are protected from network-based malware infections and ransomware attacks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though air-gapped systems are isolated, they can still have vulnerabilities. Regular security scanning helps identify these weaknesses before they can be exploited. In this article, you will learn the different security scanners GitLab provides and how they can be added/updated in a limited-connectivity environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 tips for promoting your open source project</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-tips-for-promoting-your-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-tips-for-promoting-your-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three open source experts offer their advice on sharing open source projects with the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post 5 tips for promoting your open source project appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After months or years of hard work, you’ve just pushed your open source project to GitHub and made it public. Now it’s time to tell the world about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chances are you’d rather spend time writing code than getting the word out about your project. Maybe your project will go viral and you won’t have to spend much time on marketing. But chances are you’re going to need to do some work to build awareness, at least in the early days. Fortunately, there are plenty of people who have been down this path and are willing to help. In this article, experienced maintainers offer their advice on sharing open source projects with the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code in Kotlin: Winners and Community Highlights</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-winners-and-community-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/advent-of-code-in-kotlin-winners-and-community-highlights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2024 in Kotlin! It was great to see so many of you sharing solutions to algorithmic puzzles and enjoying the holiday coding spirit with experts and the community. From December 1–12, we hosted livestreams with Kotlin Developer Advocate Sebastian Aigner and fantastic guests who shared […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who participated in Advent of Code 2024 in Kotlin! It was great to see so many of you sharing solutions to algorithmic puzzles and enjoying the holiday coding spirit with experts and the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Steps in Game Development With Rust and Bevy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/first-steps-in-game-development-with-rust-and-bevy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of us might remember this 15-year-old Abstruse Goose comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/unnamed.png&#34; alt=&#34;Game Development vs Computer Science&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Some of us might remember this 15-year-old &lt;em&gt;Abstruse Goose&lt;/em&gt; comic about our choices in life. Learning the theory of computations might not be the most direct path to video game development. However, you still need to learn programming, some math (at least geometry), and mechanics – or as it’s often somewhat erroneously labeled – physics. Many years ago, I did a course on rigid body dynamics that was definitely a part of the theoretical mechanics curriculum, not physics! Then, you’ll probably also need a bit of materials science, optics, and a smattering of other subjects. The good news is you’ll have loads of fun along the way. And while you’re still learning, game development engines and libraries can help you keep on top of some of the accidental complexity and give you enough functionality to implement the things you want, albeit at a fairly basic level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot: The agent awakens</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-copilot-the-agent-awakens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-copilot-the-agent-awakens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introducing agent mode for GitHub Copilot in VS Code, announcing the general availability of Copilot Edits, and providing a first look at our SWE agent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Copilot: The agent awakens appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we introduced GitHub Copilot back in 2021, we had a clear goal: to make developers’ lives easier with an AI pair programmer that helps them write better code. The name reflects our belief that artificial intelligence (AI) isn’t replacing the developer. Instead, it’s always on their side. And like any good first officer, Copilot can also fly by itself: for example, when providing pull request feedback, autofixing security vulnerabilities, or brainstorming on how to implement an issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Cheuk Ting Ho – New Developer Advocate</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-cheuk-ting-ho-new-developer-advocate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team. My home community […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, I am Cheuk, your AI Assistant assistant! Jokes aside, I am the new AI Developer Advocate here at JetBrains. My background is in data science and Python, although I have also recently started learning Rust. I am based in London, UK, and I am very excited to join the team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – February 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-february-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this latest edition of Java Annotated Monthly! As we start 2025, we bring you a roundup of the latest advancements in the world of tech. Stay in the loop with a curated list of must-attend events coming up in February, so you can plan your next learning and networking opportunities. Plus, we’re thrilled to introduce Isabel Garrido to our &lt;em&gt;Featured Content&lt;/em&gt; section – packed with handpicked articles, insights, and thought-provoking reads to keep you inspired. Let’s dive in and explore what’s shaping the technological ecosystem!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – January Digest</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-january-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-january-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2025 is here, and it’s brought lots of new educational content. Dive into the latest tech trends, learning opportunities, insightful events, and nifty plugins to boost your productivity. Happy reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-ahead-of-the-trends&#34;&gt;Stay Ahead of the Trends&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cs_learning_curve_2024.webp&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;explore-global-trends-in-tech-education&#34;&gt;Explore Global Trends in Tech Education&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 23,000 learners from 16 countries and 7 regions shared their insights on the future of tech education. What motivates them? What are the most exciting new developments? Get all the answers in our detailed report.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains AI Assistant Now Supports Claude Models via Amazon Bedrock</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-ai-assistant-now-supports-claude-models-via-amazon-bedrock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉 With the rise of high-quality language models, each excelling in different tasks, developers need flexible options to meet diverse challenges. That’s why we’re focused on providing multi-model support, helping you create workflows that fit your needs. Anthropic’s […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wait is over! Anthropic’s Claude models are here for JetBrains AI Assistant, provisioned in Amazon Bedrock 🎉&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models now available in JetBrains AI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openai-o1-o1-mini-and-o3-mini-models-now-available-in-jetbrains-ai-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks. Now, we’ve added access to OpenAI o1, o1-mini, and o3-mini models to offer an even more adaptable and personalized experience with AI Assistant. What’s special about OpenAI o1? OpenAI’s o1 series of models are designed […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains AI Assistant streamlines your workflow and lets you focus on problem-solving instead of writing boilerplate and performing repetitive tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Option to Cancel Continuity Discounts for Paid Plugins</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/option-to-cancel-continuity-discounts-for-paid-plugins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins. What is the continuity discount? The continuity discount is a […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace is introducing changes to how continuity discounts are handled for paid plugins, giving plugin authors more flexibility in managing their pricing strategies. Here’s everything you need to know about the new option to cancel the continuity discount and how it affects your plugins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The JetBrains Platform Gets a New Community Space</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-jetbrains-platform-gets-a-new-community-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains products, including JetBrains IDEs, YouTrack, TeamCity, and others, are designed with extensibility in mind. While we try to provide our users with a wide feature set, it is impossible to cover all technologies and use cases in a dynamic market like software development. Many ecosystems get new frameworks and libraries every day, and developers are constantly trying to improve their work by adopting new approaches requiring tooling adjustments. This is where our incredible community of plugin and extension developers takes the initiative and develops great products, helping to meet the needs of even more users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The State of PHP 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-php-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-php-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like? To uncover deeper insights and trends shaping the ecosystem, we’ve turned to our in-house expert, Brent […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PHP continues to be a cornerstone of web development, powering millions of websites around the world. Its vibrant and dedicated community values its flexibility and ease of use. But what does the current state of PHP development look like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-ultimate-guide-to-django-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps. If you’re new to the framework and looking to set up your first Django project, grasping templates is vital. In this guide, you’ll […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;The Ultimate Guide to Django Templates&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Django templates are a crucial part of the framework. Understanding what they are and why they’re useful can help you build seamless, adaptable, and functional templates for your Django sites and apps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is DAST? A Guide to Dynamic Application Security Testing</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-dast-a-guide-to-dynamic-application-security-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-is-dast-a-guide-to-dynamic-application-security-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev. Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was brought to you by Matt Keib, draft.dev.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic application security testing (DAST) is a security testing method designed to identify vulnerabilities in applications while running. Unlike static testing methods, which analyze code at rest, DAST interacts with live applications and mimics real-world attacks to uncover security flaws. This makes DAST particularly effective for detecting issues that only occur when an application is running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating cybersecurity threat detections with GitLab CI/CD&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-cybersecurity-threat-detections-with-gitlab-ci-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-cybersecurity-threat-detections-with-gitlab-ci-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog post is the second post in a series about GitLab Universal Automated Response and Detection (GUARD).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Writing and deploying security threat detections in an organization’s security information event management platform (SIEM) is a critical component of a successful cybersecurity program. Moving from manual detection engineering to a fully automated process by implementing Detections as Code (DaC) ensures detection consistency, quality, auditing, and automated testing. At GitLab, we’ve embedded DaC capabilities into GUARD, our fully automated detection and response framework.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How GitLab uses prompt guardrails to help protect customers&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-uses-prompt-guardrails-to-help-protect-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-uses-prompt-guardrails-to-help-protect-customers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine introducing a powerful new AI tool that boosts your team&amp;rsquo;s productivity — accelerating code development, resolving issues faster, and streamlining workflows. The excitement is palpable, but questions about security and compliance quickly arise. How do you manage the risk of AI inadvertently exposing sensitive data or responding to malicious prompts? This is where prompt guardrails play a crucial role.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prompt guardrails are structured safeguards – combining instructions, filters, and context boundaries – designed to guide AI models toward secure and reliable responses. Think of them as safety rails on a bridge, working to keep data and interactions on the correct path while supporting your organization&amp;rsquo;s security protocols. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how GitLab implements these guardrails, the risks they address, and their importance for security-conscious enterprises and compliance-focused teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Improve AI security in GitLab with composite identities&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-ai-security-in-gitlab-with-composite-identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-ai-security-in-gitlab-with-composite-identities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) is quickly becoming the backbone of modern software development, fueling developer efficiency and accelerating innovation. With the emergence of AI agents implementing code based on instructions from humans, we are learning that implementing AI-based features has its own unique set of security challenges. &lt;strong&gt;How do we protect access to the resources AI needs, protect confidentiality, and avoid privilege escalation&lt;/strong&gt;? Few organizations are ready to answer these questions today. At GitLab, we are. We are introducing a new paradigm for identity management: composite identities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Improve security auditing with GitLab Operational Container Scanning&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-security-auditing-with-gitlab-operational-container-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/improve-security-auditing-with-gitlab-operational-container-scanning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conducting security scans is a regular part of any software development process. Whether scanning source code (e.g., Java, Python, or other languages), configuration files (e.g., YAML files), or container images, these scanning tools help development teams be proactive about understanding and addressing security threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, developers run these security scans as part of CI/CD pipelines. By including these scans in CI/CD, every change to a project will be reviewed to see if any vulnerabilities are introduced. Understanding security concerns during development helps to assure that changes are addressed before they are deployed to a live environment, but there are many additional benefits to conducting container vulnerability scans post deployment as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The Co-Create Program: How customers are collaborating to build GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-co-create-program-how-customers-are-collaborating-to-build-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-co-create-program-how-customers-are-collaborating-to-build-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past year, over 800 community members have made more than 3,000 contributions to GitLab. These contributors include team members from global organizations like Thales and Scania, who are helping shape GitLab&amp;rsquo;s future through the Co-Create Program — GitLab&amp;rsquo;s collaborative development program where customers work directly with GitLab engineers to contribute meaningful features to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through workshops, pair programming sessions, and ongoing support, program participants get hands-on experience with GitLab&amp;rsquo;s architecture and codebase while solving issues or improving existing features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 steps to building a natural language search tool</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-steps-to-building-a-natural-language-search-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/4-steps-to-building-a-natural-language-search-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Empowering humanitarian action with open source: A natural language search tool for UN Resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post 4 steps to building a natural language search tool appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We have a problem. Our current search method for sifting through PDFs is extremely manual and time consuming. Is there an easier way?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a developer, this is one of those questions that really gets me excited. I was tasked with finding a way to transform a cumbersome, archival process into an efficient, intuitive search experience. It’s a way to make a group of people’s lives easier, and because of the organizations they work for, help them be more effective in providing humanitarian assistance to people in need around the world. I couldn’t imagine a better project to be working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips for Productive Java Development With Databases in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/9-tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/9-tips-for-productive-java-development-with-databases-in-intellij-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one. Get IntelliJ IDEA Ultimate Create data sources automatically from properties IntelliJ IDEA makes it easy to create a data source for your […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll share nine time-saving ways IntelliJ IDEA can boost your productivity when developing Java applications with databases – whether you’re starting a new project or diving into an ongoing one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Django Views</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-introduction-to-django-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/an-introduction-to-django-views/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered.  Gaining a better understanding of views will help […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;An Introduction to Django Views&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Views are central to Django’s architecture pattern, and having a solid grasp of how to work with them is essential for any developer working with the framework. If you’re new to developing web apps with Django or just need a refresher on views, we’ve got you covered. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Busy Plugin Developers Newsletter – Q4 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/busy-plugin-developers-newsletter-q4-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;⭐️ Marketplace updates Granular plugin feedback In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories: Aggregated ratings are shown in the Reviews tab. Find more details in our documentation.  Perpetual licenses for paid plugins JetBrains Marketplace now offers perpetual […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-marketplace-updates&#34;&gt;⭐️ Marketplace updates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;granular-plugin-feedback&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granular plugin feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the general star rating of plugins, we’re introducing detailed ratings for more granular feedback. Users can now rate plugins across five categories:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity researchers: Digital detectives in a connected world</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-researchers-digital-detectives-in-a-connected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/cybersecurity-researchers-digital-detectives-in-a-connected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the exciting world of cybersecurity research: what researchers do, essential skills, and actionable steps to begin your journey toward protecting the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Cybersecurity researchers: Digital detectives in a connected world appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered yourself a detective at heart? Cybersecurity researchers are digital detectives, uncovering vulnerabilities before malicious actors exploit them. To succeed, they adopt the mindset of an attacker, thinking creatively to predict and outmaneuver threats. Their expertise ensures the internet remains a safer place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faster Debugging for Massive C&#43;&#43; Projects in Rider</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/faster-debugging-for-massive-c-projects-in-rider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/faster-debugging-for-massive-c-projects-in-rider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for Step Over, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute.  These delays occur in LLDB Debugger, the engine behind Rider’s debugging capabilities for C++ and other native languages. After months of focused […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you work on large Unreal Engine projects in Rider, you’ve likely experienced the dreaded debug-step delay – hit F10 for &lt;em&gt;Step Over&lt;/em&gt;, contemplate making coffee, then finally see the next line execute. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Developer Population Reaches 19.6 Million in 2024: Explore the Updates in Our Data Playground</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/global-developer-population-reaches-19-6-million-in-2024-explore-the-updates-in-our-data-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/global-developer-population-reaches-19-6-million-in-2024-explore-the-updates-in-our-data-playground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, we launched the Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends. What’s New? To make it easier to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Featured-1280x720-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, we launched the &lt;strong&gt;Developer Ecosystem: Data Playground&lt;/strong&gt;, an interactive dashboard offering insights into the global developer landscape. Today, we’re excited to introduce a significant update that enhances the dashboard with refined data, salary ranges, and even more granular insights into developer demographics and market trends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3: Kotlin K2 Mode Updates, Enhanced Logical Code Structure View, and More</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3-kotlin-k2-mode-updates-enhanced-logical-code-structure-view-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-3-kotlin-k2-mode-updates-enhanced-logical-code-structure-view-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available! You can download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, or install it via snap packages for Ubuntu.  Download IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 3 We’re covering all of the […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 Early Access Program is in full swing, and build #3 is now available!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and LinkedIn Partner to Launch a Professional Certificate</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-and-linkedin-partner-to-launch-a-professional-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning. With over 1 billion members on the platform and 7 people hired every minute, LinkedIn provides unmatched access to professional growth opportunities. Together, with our expertise in software development and education, we’re combining the best of both worlds: […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with LinkedIn to offer the Java Foundations Professional Certificate, exclusively available on LinkedIn Learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JITWatch4i: Analyzing IntelliJ IDEA’s Startup</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-ideas-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jitwatch4i-analyzing-intellij-ideas-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A typical Java or Kotlin programmer spends most of their productive time either creating application code in an editor or searching for bugs in a debugger. Occasionally, they might dive into a profiler when looking for places where the application spends too much time. However, they almost never venture into the Java C1 or C2 compilers and their resulting products – low-level assembly code. For the most part, the Java compilers are black boxes that typically remain closed under normal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHP Annotated – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/php-annotated-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/php-annotated-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you. Highlights PHP 8.4 PHP 8.4 was officially released on November 21, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/ps-featured_blog_1280x720_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;PHP Annotated&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the January edition of PHP Annotated! This recap is carefully handcrafted and brings you the most interesting developments in the PHP community over the past couple of months, so you don’t have to sift through the noise, we’ve done it for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Developer Advocate – Will Vincent</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/python-developer-advocate-will-vincent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:william.vincent@jetbrains.com&#34;&gt;william.vincent@jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;. Background I’m a former Django Board Member and the author of three books on Django. Since 2019, I’ve co-hosted the Django Chat podcast […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/headshot_smile_smaller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m a new Python Developer Advocate, focusing especially on web development. If you have any questions or want to share ideas around JetBrains products, most notably PyCharm, say hi at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:william.vincent@jetbrains.com&#34;&gt;william.vincent@jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Java Conferences and Events in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-java-conferences-and-events-in-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration. As the IDE of choice for professional development in Java and Kotlin, IntelliJ IDEA is built to support developers […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Planning your 2025 tech calendar? Java conferences offer more than just technical sessions – they’re your gateway to connecting with a vibrant community of professionals and passionate Java fans, exploring new cities, and finding fresh inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTrack 2025 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtrack-2025-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/youtrack-2025-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our commitment to you We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/yt-featured_blog_1280x720_en-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-commitment-to-you&#34;&gt;Our commitment to you&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We remain fully committed, as we have been all these years, to developing YouTrack as a platform that evolves with your needs. Our promise to you is to ensure that YouTrack continues to be available in both Server and Cloud versions, giving you the freedom to choose the hosting option that best fits your organization and data governance policies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Deploy a server using Go with GitLab &#43; Google Cloud&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-server-using-go-with-gitlab-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-server-using-go-with-gitlab-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploying an application to the cloud often requires assistance from production or DevOps engineers. GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Google Cloud integration empowers developers to handle deployments independently. In this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to deploy a server to Google Cloud in less than 10 minutes using Go. Whether you’re a solo developer or part of a large team, this setup allows you to deploy applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;youll-learn-how-to&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a new project in GitLab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a Go server utilizing &lt;code&gt;main.go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the Google Cloud integration to create a Service account&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the Google Cloud integration to create Cloud Run via a merge request&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Access your newly deployed Go server&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Clean up your environment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Owner access on a Google Cloud Platform project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Working knowledge of Golang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Working knowledge of GitLab CI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-by-step-golang-server-deployment-to-google-cloud&#34;&gt;Step-by-step Golang server deployment to Google Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-create-a-new-blank-project-in-gitlab&#34;&gt;1. Create a new blank project in GitLab.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We decided to call our project &lt;code&gt;golang-cloud-run&lt;/code&gt; for simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;From code to production: A guide to continuous deployment with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-code-to-production-a-guide-to-continuous-deployment-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/from-code-to-production-a-guide-to-continuous-deployment-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuous deployment is a game-changing practice that enables teams to deliver value faster, with higher confidence. However, diving into advanced deployment workflows — such as GitOps, container orchestration with Kubernetes, or dynamic environments — can be intimidating for teams just starting out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At GitLab, we&amp;rsquo;re committed to making delivery seamless and scalable. By enabling teams to focus on the fundamentals, we empower them to build a strong foundation that supports growth into more complex strategies over time. This guide provides essential steps to begin implementing continuous deployment with GitLab, laying the foundation for your long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Getting started with GitLab: How to import your projects to GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-import-your-projects-to-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-import-your-projects-to-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to our &amp;ldquo;Getting started with GitLab&amp;rdquo; series, where we help newcomers get familiar with the GitLab DevSecOps platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to import your projects to GitLab is an essential skill to make the most of the GitLab DevSecOps platform. You’ve set up your account, invited users, and organized them based on your use case or team structure. Now, you need to bring your existing projects into GitLab and start collaborating. These projects can be local files on your computer or hosted on a different source code management platform. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Secure, compliant, and AI-powered: Get to know 3 new GitLab features&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-compliant-and-ai-powered-get-to-know-3-new-gitlab-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-compliant-and-ai-powered-get-to-know-3-new-gitlab-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI capabilities are rapidly reshaping how teams build, secure, and deploy applications. As part of our ongoing commitment to helping you navigate the evolving marketplace, GitLab has introduced more than 440 improvements in the past three releases. We&amp;rsquo;re excited to spotlight three standout features making an immediate impact on how teams approach AI-powered DevSecOps. In addition, we announced we are partnering with AWS to launch GitLab Duo with Amazon Q, combining our strengths to transform software development. We&amp;rsquo;re creating an experience, together, that makes AI-powered development feel seamless and upholds the security, compliance, and reliability that enterprises require.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for making a tree view component accessible</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/considerations-for-making-a-tree-view-component-accessible/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/considerations-for-making-a-tree-view-component-accessible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A deep dive on the work that went into making the component that powers repository and pull request file trees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Considerations for making a tree view component accessible appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tree views are a core part of the GitHub experience. You’ve encountered one if you’ve ever navigated through a repository’s file structure or reviewed a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/github-repo-browser.png?w=1024&amp;amp;resize=1024%2C653&#34; alt=&#34;Browsing files on Primer&amp;rsquo;s design repository. A tree view showing the repositories directory structure occupies a quarter of the screen. The other three quarters are taken up by the content of the content subdirectory. The tree view shows expanded and collapsed directories, as well as files nested at multiple levels of depth.&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Curious About The State of Software Quality?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/curious-about-the-state-of-software-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/curious-about-the-state-of-software-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready. To […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-social_share_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;State of Software Quality Report 2024&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the first edition of the JetBrains Qodana Software Quality Report which looks at key findings from 2024. We decided to conduct this research to gain a deeper understanding of best practices for delivering quality software today, and how companies of different sizes and maturity levels determine when their product is production-ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.45 Is Here With Auto-Import for Gradle, Improved Preview for Markdown, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-45-is-here-with-auto-import-for-gradle-improved-preview-for-markdown-and-more-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-45-is-here-with-auto-import-for-gradle-improved-preview-for-markdown-and-more-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.45 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using our Toolbox App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin for Server-Side Content Creators</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/kotlin-for-server-side-content-creators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More and more developers are using Kotlin for server-side development, building reliable and efficient backend systems. Many of them also share their experiences through articles, videos, and sample projects. If you’re one of these creators, we want to recognize your work! Sharing your knowledge helps others solve real problems, improve their skills, and discover better […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More and more developers are using Kotlin for server-side development, building reliable and efficient backend systems. Many of them also share their experiences through articles, videos, and sample projects. If you’re one of these creators, we want to recognize your work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Livestream alret: Programming Prep Guide for the CSAI Entrance Test</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/livestream-alret-programming-prep-guide-for-the-csai-entrance-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/livestream-alret-programming-prep-guide-for-the-csai-entrance-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to study computer science in Europe? Enroll in the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos. Exclusive JetBrains scholarships are up for grabs! Join us on February 11, at 4:00 pm UTC, for a special preparation session to help you ace the entrance test for this program. You’ll get first-hand tips […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/edu-email_photo_650x144-2x_en.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to study computer science in Europe? Enroll in the Computer Science and AI bachelor’s program at Neapolis University Pafos. Exclusive JetBrains scholarships are up for grabs!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open source AI is already finding its way into production</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-ai-is-already-finding-its-way-into-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/open-source-ai-is-already-finding-its-way-into-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open source AI models are in widespread use, enabling developers around the world to build custom AI solutions and host them where they choose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Open source AI is already finding its way into production appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source has long driven innovation and the adoption of cutting-edge technologies, from web interfaces to cloud-native computing. The same is true in the burgeoning field of open source artificial intelligence (AI). Open source AI models, and the tooling to build and use them, are multiplying, enabling developers around the world to build custom AI solutions and host them where they choose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PyCharm 2024.3.2: uv Package Management Support and More!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pycharm-2024-3-2-uv-package-management-support-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/pycharm-2024-3-2-uv-package-management-support-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements! Get the latest version from our download page or update through our free Toolbox App.  Read this blog post to learn more about new features. Support for uv package management Take your environment management to the next level with uv […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;PyCharm 2024.3.2&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PyCharm 2024.3.2 is here with uv package management support, flame graph visualization, and other improvements!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy: Top Courses and Projects of 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-top-courses-and-projects-of-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong.  To mark this impressive milestone, we’re looking back at the most popular JetBrains Academy offerings of 2024 – including JetBrains IDE courses (designed exclusively for IDEs) and Hyperskill projects (available […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This International Day of Education, we’re celebrating that in 2024 over 340,000 new coders joined JetBrains Academy, making our community almost 1.5 million members strong. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New to open source? Here’s everything you need to get started</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-to-open-source-heres-everything-you-need-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-to-open-source-heres-everything-you-need-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our simple guide to finding projects, understanding guidelines, and making an impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post New to open source? Here’s everything you need to get started appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve heard about open source. You know it’s a great way to learn new skills, build up your resume, and give back to the developer community—but maybe you’re not sure where to begin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting involved in open source can raise all sorts of questions: Are there specific contribution guidelines? Or a certain level of involvement required before tackling issues? Don’t worry, we’ve got your back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity Is Now Available on AWS Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-is-now-available-on-aws-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS). TeamCity interface Whether you’re already an AWS user or exploring AWS for your next project, TeamCity on AWS Marketplace […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TeamCity is officially listed on AWS Marketplace! This milestone makes it even easier for teams to integrate the power of TeamCity into their CI/CD pipelines while leveraging the scalability and flexibility of Amazon Web Services (AWS).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated: Now in limited availability&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hosted-runners-for-gitlab-dedicated-now-in-limited-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/hosted-runners-for-gitlab-dedicated-now-in-limited-availability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated, our single-tenant SaaS solution, have transitioned from beta to limited availability, marking a significant milestone in our commitment to simplifying CI/CD infrastructure management for our customers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;streamlined-cicd-infrastructure-management&#34;&gt;Streamlined CI/CD infrastructure management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Managing runner infrastructure has traditionally been a complex undertaking, requiring dedicated resources and expertise to maintain optimal performance. Hosted runners for GitLab Dedicated eliminates these challenges by providing a fully managed solution that handles all aspects of runner infrastructure. This allows your teams to focus on what matters most – building and deploying great software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How-to: GitLab Single Sign-on with SAML, SCIM, and Azure’s Entra ID&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-gitlab-single-sign-on-with-saml-scim-and-azures-entra-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-gitlab-single-sign-on-with-saml-scim-and-azures-entra-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As organizations increase in size, it becomes increasingly difficult and critical to ensure that the right team members have access to the right groups and projects within their development platform. GitLab offers some powerful methods to manage user access, especially now with custom roles, but performing this at scale through a point-and-click user interface can be frustrating. However, all is not lost. You can use Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) and System for Cross-domain Identity Management (SCIM) as a solution. (There are moments where I’m grateful for acronyms.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attacks on Maven proxy repositories</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attacks-on-maven-proxy-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/attacks-on-maven-proxy-repositories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how specially crafted artifacts can be used to attack Maven repository managers. This post describes PoC exploits that can lead to pre-auth remote code execution and poisoning of the local artifacts in Sonatype Nexus and JFrog Artifactory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Attacks on Maven proxy repositories appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As someone who’s been breaking the security of Java applications for many years, I was always curious about the supply chain attacks on Java libraries. In 2019, I accidentally discovered an arbitrary file read vulnerability on search.maven.org, a website that is closely tied to the Maven Central Repository. Maven Central is a place where most of the Java libraries are downloaded from and its security is paramount for all companies who develop in Java. If someone is able to infiltrate Maven Central and replace a popular library, they can get the key to the whole kingdom, as almost every large tech company uses Java.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2: Containerfile Support and Updates for Dockerfiles</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2-containerfile-support-and-updates-for-dockerfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-2-containerfile-support-and-updates-for-dockerfiles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out! With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios. You can now download this version from our website, update directly from within the IDE, use the free Toolbox App, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP 2 is out!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a focus on improving workflows for environments like Docker containers and other remote solutions, this build introduces updates that simplify setup and enhance productivity in these scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Junie, Your Coding Agent by JetBrains</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/meet-junie-your-coding-agent-by-jetbrains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Blog_1280x720.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At JetBrains, we aim to enable and scale the next generation of technologies to make software development a more productive and enjoyable experience. To empower and support developers, we build a variety of products for professional development, including powerful AI tools and features that have already enhanced productivity and opened new horizons for creativity. But can we go beyond that and boost productivity even further – improve code quality, unlock future innovations, help execute complex tasks, and change the way you work with code? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to modernize legacy code with GitHub Copilot with real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Modernizing legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about legacy code—you know, the code that’s old enough to drive and definitely old enough to haunt your dreams. Maybe it’s a sprawling COBOL system or an early version of C++ written back when “Y2K” was a serious concern. Now, decades later, you’re being asked to “look into it” and modernize it (while wondering if you need to send a note to that person who retired a few years ago and may know how this thing works).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That’s a wrap: GitHub Innovation Graph in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thats-a-wrap-github-innovation-graph-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thats-a-wrap-github-innovation-graph-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Discover the latest trends and insights on public software development activity on GitHub with the release of Q2 &amp;amp; Q3 2024 data for the Innovation Graph.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post That’s a wrap: GitHub Innovation Graph in 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is our first GitHub Innovation Graph data release in 2025 and our first data release after celebrating the Innovation Graph’s first birthday, so we’d like to reflect a bit on how things have gone so far and share our hopes and dreams for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ReSharper and Rider 2024.3.4 Bug-Fix Updates Are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4-bug-fix-updates-are-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-resharper-and-rider-2024-3-4-bug-fix-updates-are-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download.  ReSharper 2024.3.4 For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our issue tracker. Rider 2024.3.4 We’ve also fixed several issues affecting .NET MAUI development: For the full list of changes included in this build, please refer to our […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new bug fixes for the 2024.3 release are available to download. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resharper-202434&#34;&gt;ReSharper 2024.3.4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve fixed local privilege escalation in the ETW Host Service (CVE-2025-23385).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Guide to fulfilling SOC 2 security requirements with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-fulfilling-soc-2-security-requirements-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/guide-to-fulfilling-soc-2-security-requirements-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For businesses that handle sensitive customer information, achieving SOC 2 (System and Organization Controls 2) compliance is not just a good practice — it&amp;rsquo;s often a necessity. SOC 2 is a rigorous auditing standard developed by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants that assesses a service organization&amp;rsquo;s controls related to security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While SOC 2 is not legally mandated, it has become increasingly important, in part due to breaches consistently seen in news headlines. Obtaining SOC 2 compliance allows customers to build trust with service organizations because they know their data is being properly stored and security controls have been assessed by a third party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Introducing GitLab Advanced Vulnerability Tracking&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlab-advanced-vulnerability-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-gitlab-advanced-vulnerability-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DevSecOps streamlines software development by allowing teams to ship features quickly and providing short feedback cycles for customers. These short feedback cycles can be used to monitor the impact of a feature from the time it is shipped and to inform developers and product managers about the success or failure of a given deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab, as an agnostic DevSecOps platform, can act as an integration point for different CI/CD tools that often contribute to user-facing functionality. For example, the vulnerability report, which displays all detected vulnerabilities, is visible as a single functionality, but the data in the report may come from a number of different tools in various pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Secure and publish Python packages: A guide to CI integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-and-publish-python-packages-a-guide-to-ci-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-and-publish-python-packages-a-guide-to-ci-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Supply chain security is a critical concern in software development. Organizations need to verify the authenticity and integrity of their software packages. This guide will show you how to implement a secure CI/CD pipeline for Python packages using GitLab CI, incorporating package signing and attestation using Sigstore&amp;rsquo;s Cosign.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why sign and attest your Python packages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pipeline overview&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complete pipeline implementation: Setting up the environment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Environment configuration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Configuration breakdown&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 6 stages&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Tutorial: Advanced use case for GitLab Pipeline Execution Policies&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-advanced-use-case-for-gitlab-pipeline-execution-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/tutorial-advanced-use-case-for-gitlab-pipeline-execution-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pipeline execution policies are a newer addition to the GitLab DevSecOps platform and a powerful mechanism to enforce CI/CD jobs across applicable projects. They enable platform engineering or security teams to inject jobs into developers’ YAML pipeline definition files, guaranteeing that certain CI/CD jobs will execute no matter what a developer defines in their `.gitlab-ci.yml` file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article will explain how to utilize pipeline execution policies to create guardrails around the stages or jobs that a developer can use in their pipeline definition. In regulated environments, this may be necessary to ensure developers adhere to a standard set of jobs or stages in their GitLab pipeline. Any job or stage that a developer adds to their pipeline that does not adhere to a corporate standard will cause the pipeline to fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-time-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anomaly Detection in Time Series&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you identify unusual patterns in data that might reveal critical issues or hidden opportunities? Anomaly detection helps identify data that deviates significantly from the norm. Time series data, which consists of data collected over time, often includes trends and seasonal patterns. Anomalies in time series data occur when these patterns are disrupted, making anomaly detection a valuable tool in industries like sales, finance, manufacturing, and healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Unreal Engine Project Issues With Qodana</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fixing-unreal-engine-project-issues-with-qodana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fixing-unreal-engine-project-issues-with-qodana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-featured_blog_1280x720_en-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you saw our blog post about using Qodana in Unity and .NET projects, you know that we’ve been striving to explore Qodana’s potential for game development. What’s our next stop on this mission? Seeing our code quality platform in action with Unreal Engine, one of the most popular engines for different types of projects – from virtual reality prototypes to triple-A games. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing  Perpetual Licenses on JetBrains Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-perpetual-licenses-on-jetbrains-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing. Licensing options on JetBrains Marketplace The current licensing schemes available on JetBrains Marketplace include: The licensing type (with or without fallback) and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains Marketplace provides various licensing models for paid plugins to suit different user preferences. Now, we are introducing a new option that may change how your users purchase your plugins – perpetual licensing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Code Security in JetBrains IDEs and Qodana With Mend.io</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/maximize-code-security-in-jetbrains-ides-and-qodana-with-mend-io/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2. Why Mend? Trusted by industry giants […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains has partnered with Mend.io, a trusted name in application security. This collaboration will help us continue providing the tools you need to develop secure applications with ease and confidence in our IDEs and Qodana. For the best user experience, make sure to use the latest stable version 2024.3.2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPS 2024.3 Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mps-2024-3-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/mps-2024-3-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 What’s new Let’s check out the new features we’ve prepared for you in this release. Top-level folder […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this release, you’ll find improvements to the UI, reworked internals for various components, and a binary-enabled textgen. MPS 2024.3 also brings enhanced support for icons, an applicability condition for quick-fixes, and numerous platform updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Results of Google Summer of Code 2024 With the Kotlin Foundation</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/results-of-google-summer-of-code-2024-with-the-kotlin-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/results-of-google-summer-of-code-2024-with-the-kotlin-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains. Join our Slack channel […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 marked another exciting year with respect to the Kotlin Foundation’s participation in Google Summer of Code (GSoC). GSoC is a global online program that introduces new contributors to open-source development. This year, contributors worked to expand the Kotlin ecosystem under the guidance of mentors from Google, Gradle, Microsoft, and JetBrains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven years of open source: A more secure and diverse ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/seven-years-of-open-source-a-more-secure-and-diverse-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/seven-years-of-open-source-a-more-secure-and-diverse-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore insights into open source community growth, innovation, and inclusivity with an updated survey dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Seven years of open source: A more secure and diverse ecosystem appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seven years ago, we surveyed 5,500 open source contributors to understand the people who use, build, and maintain open source software. This year, we repeated the effort to understand how the open source ecosystem has evolved in the face of the seismic technological and social shifts we’ve seen since 2017. We received 8,400 responses from visitors to open source repositories, and we’re once again sharing the insights with the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1&lt;/strong&gt;, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 2024.12.1 Bug Fix Is Now Available</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/teamcity-2024-12-1-bug-fix-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines. Some highlights of this release include: We recommend upgrading to apply the latest improvements and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;TeamCity On-Premises 2024.12.1&lt;/strong&gt;, a bug fix update that resolves over 80 issues reported by users. This version includes crucial fixes across multiple areas, ensuring enhanced performance, stability, and security for your CI/CD pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we evaluate AI models and LLMs for GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-evaluate-ai-models-and-llms-for-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-evaluate-ai-models-and-llms-for-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We share some of the GitHub Copilot team&amp;rsquo;s experience evaluating AI models, with a focus on our offline evaluations—the tests we run before making any change to our production environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How we evaluate AI models and LLMs for GitHub Copilot appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are so many AI models to choose from these days. From the proprietary foundation models of OpenAI, Google, and Anthropic to the smaller, more open options from the likes of Meta and Mistral. It’s tempting to hop immediately to the latest models. But just because a model is newer doesn’t mean it will perform better for your use case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Files View in Solution Explorer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-files-view-in-solution-explorer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In modern development, repositories are much more than just .NET solutions. From TypeScript end-to-end tests and Docker compose files to global.json and Playwright configs – your codebase contains numerous essential files that live outside of your C# projects.While these files are fully supported in Rider, they can be hard to find when viewing your solution structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting the next generation of developers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-the-next-generation-of-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/supporting-the-next-generation-of-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s your opportunity to empower the teen in your life to get a start in open source development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Supporting the next generation of developers appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe that software is at the center of human progress and that all software builds on the work of others, especially open source, through an interconnected community of developers. We need to level the playing field to spark innovation on a global level, and that includes helping early developers get the best start possible. We believe that all developers can solve problems, innovate, and create collaboratively through code. This is why we aspire to empower 1 billion individuals to become developers, and work to help break down barriers to entry for those who wish to join the field and participate in the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for ReSharper and the .NET Tools 2025.1 Is Here!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-1-is-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-resharper-and-the-net-tools-2025-1-is-here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce the launch of the Early Access Program (EAP) for the next major release of ReSharper and the .NET Tools! This initial EAP build is now available for download and offers a preview of the upcoming features and enhancements. Your feedback is crucial in helping us refine these updates, so we encourage you to try out the new build and share your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 Is Now Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-1-is-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-early-access-program-for-rider-2025-1-is-now-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider.  There are several ways for you to get your hands on the first preview build: To see […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program for Rider 2025.1 has just begun. This is your chance to preview the new features and enhancements we’ve been working on and share your feedback to help us shape the future of JetBrains Rider. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-rubymine-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on. What’s coming in RubyMine 2025.1? AI Assistant The 2024.3 release introduced enhanced cloud-based completion for Ruby code. The upcoming release will […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re starting this year off with the opening of the RubyMine 2025.1 Early Access Program. In this blog post, you’ll find details about the new features and improvements we’ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;DevSecOps &#43; Agentic AI: Now on GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate on AWS&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devsecops-agentic-ai-now-on-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/devsecops-agentic-ai-now-on-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce the GitLab Duo with Amazon Q offering, previously shared at AWS 2024 re:Invent, is now available in Preview (Beta) for GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate users, at no additional cost. This milestone brings AI agentic experiences to organizations that maintain their own GitLab instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-this-mean-for-gitlab-self-managed-ultimate-customers&#34;&gt;What does this mean for GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate customers?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beginning in our 17.8 release, GitLab Self-Managed Ultimate customers can now take advantage of the GitLab Duo with Amazon Q Preview (Beta) capabilities. There are three key experiences you will be able to access:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Google Cloud integrations for secure Cloud Run deployments at GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-cloud-integrations-for-secure-cloud-run-deployments-at-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/google-cloud-integrations-for-secure-cloud-run-deployments-at-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This tutorial is from a recent Arctiq, GitLab, and Google in-person workshop. The goal was to explore common security challenges faced by organizations as they journey to the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will help you learn about the Google Cloud integrations in GitLab. These features are meant to help accelerate and improve security of deployments to Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://images.ctfassets.net/r9o86ar0p03f/75hahkyZZ8T7tCKDuTZ4eI/6ba8dbc29e97c1440d201b5f9794075e/image2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google integrations list&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google Cloud project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appropriate IAM permissions for security, Artifact Registry, and Cloud Run usage. For this tutorial, ensure you have the &amp;ldquo;Owner&amp;rdquo; role with the aforementioned project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-workload-identity-federation&#34;&gt;Setting up Workload Identity Federation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this step, we configure GitLab to connect Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Workload Identity Federation to reduce the need for service accounts and let the two platforms use short-lived credentials on-demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What the Digital Operational Resilience Act means for banks&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-digital-operational-resilience-act-means-for-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-digital-operational-resilience-act-means-for-banks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developers play a critical role in ensuring banks remain competitive and compliant. One framework gaining significant attention is DORA. If you’re thinking of the DevOps Research and Assessment (DORA) metrics, this is something different. The Digital Operational Resilience Act is a new regulatory framework focused on safeguarding financial institutions against digital disruptions. For developers, understanding DORA regulations is not just a regulatory necessity; it’s an opportunity to drive innovation and enhance the overall stability of their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/anomaly-detection-in-machine-learning-using-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is anomaly detection – processes that enable […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Anomaly Detection in Machine Learning Using Python&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, many of our applications have been driven by the high volume of data that we are able to collect and process. Some may refer to us being in the age of data. One of the essential aspects of handling such a large amount of data is &lt;strong&gt;anomaly detection&lt;/strong&gt; – processes that enable us to identify outliers, data that is outside the bounds of expectation and demonstrate behavior that is out of the norm. In scientific research, anomaly data points could be a cause of technical issues and may need to be discarded when drawing conclusions, or it could lead to new discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documenting and explaining legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/documenting-and-explaining-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/documenting-and-explaining-legacy-code-with-github-copilot-tips-and-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how to document and explain legacy code with GitHub Copilot with real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Documenting and explaining legacy code with GitHub Copilot: Tips and examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why did the developer bring a flashlight to the legacy codebase? Because every time they tried to refactor it, they found more bugs hiding in the dark corners.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is, working with legacy code can also be bad—worse than that joke even! Whether you’ve inherited a decades-old codebase or are revisiting your own past work, working with a legacy codebase can be a time-consuming and overwhelming process—especially if there’s no documentation. Having well-documented code, legacy or otherwise, is critical for maintaining software quality and informing future development work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dotInsights | January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dotinsights-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/dotinsights-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know? The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing. Fears of disruptions in critical systems like banking and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you know?&lt;/strong&gt; The Y2K bug, or “Millennium Bug,” was a programming issue caused by storing years with only two digits (e.g., “1999” as “99”) to save memory. As 2000 approached, systems risked interpreting “00” as 1900, leading to potential errors in calculations and data processing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Availability Report: December 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-december-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-december-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Availability Report: December 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December, we experienced two incidents that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 17 14:17 UTC (lasting 17 minutes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On December 17, 2024, between 14:33 UTC and 14:50 UTC, users experienced intermittent errors and timeouts when accessing github.com. The error rate was 8.5% on average and peaked at 44.3% of requests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-built-the-github-skyline-cli-extension-using-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-we-built-the-github-skyline-cli-extension-using-github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub uses GitHub to build GitHub, and our CLI extensions are no exception. Read on to find out how we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How we built the GitHub Skyline CLI extension using GitHub appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December 2024, we announced gh-skyline, a GitHub CLI extension that allows our developer community to generate a 3D version of their GitHub Contribution Graph into an STL file ready for printing on a 3D printer, just in time to capture all of those contributions!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3.2 Is Out</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-2-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2024-3-2-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – v2024.3.2. You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website. This release includes the following improvements: To find out more about the resolved issues, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve just released the next minor update for IntelliJ IDEA 2024.3 – v2024.3.2.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can update to this version from inside the IDE, via the Toolbox App, or by using snaps for Ubuntu. You can also download it from our website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1 EAP Is Open!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/intellij-idea-2025-1-eap-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever. You can download this version from our website, update directly from […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re kicking off the new year with the first Early Access Program (EAP) build for IntelliJ IDEA 2025.1! This is your chance to get an exclusive first look at the upcoming features and improvements designed to make your coding workflow more efficient than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Named a Customers’ Choice Again for Integrated Development Environment Software</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-named-a-customers-choice-again-for-integrated-development-environment-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-named-a-customers-choice-again-for-integrated-development-environment-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year.  Read the Report A trusted vendor We believe JetBrains’ consistent innovation and developer-first approach have earned […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JetBrains is honored to be recognized as a Customers’ Choice in the 2024 Gartner® Peer Insights™ Voice of the Customer for Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Software – a distinction we are proud to receive for the second consecutive year. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Support for .env Files: Now Built into PhpStorm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-env-files-now-built-into-phpstorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/support-for-env-files-now-built-into-phpstorm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.env files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code. Previously, developers using PhpStorm had to manually install the .env Files Support plugin, originally created by Adel Faizrakhmanov, to unlock dedicated features for working with these […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; files are widely used to configure applications by storing configuration settings, environment variables, and sensitive information. This eliminates the need to hardcode these values into the application code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CLion 2025.1 Early Access Program Is Open</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-clion-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-clion-2025-1-early-access-program-is-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for CLion 2025.1 has officially launched. The first EAP build, 251.14649.40, is here to provide an early look at some of the improvements coming in the next major release. You can download the build for free from the link below, via the Toolbox App, or as a snap package if you’re using Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GoLand 2025.1 Early Access Program Has Started!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-goland-2025-1-early-access-program-has-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers. The first EAP build can be downloaded via the Toolbox App, from our website, or as a […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Early Access Program (EAP) for GoLand 2025.1 is now open! In this release cycle, we’re focusing on enhancing Go language support, improving code analysis, and boosting stability to provide a seamless development experience for all the gophers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Deploy a NodeJS Express app with GitLab&#39;s Cloud Run integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-nodejs-express-app-with-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/deploy-a-nodejs-express-app-with-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking to deploy your NodeJS app to Google Cloud with the least maintenance possible? This tutorial will show you how to utilize GitLab’s Google Cloud integration to deploy your NodeJS app in less than 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, deploying an application often requires assistance from production or DevOps engineers. This integration now empowers developers to handle deployments independently. Whether you’re a solo developer or part of a large team, this setup gives everyone the ability to deploy their applications efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Getting started with GitLab: How to manage users&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-manage-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/getting-started-with-gitlab-how-to-manage-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to our &amp;ldquo;Getting started with GitLab&amp;rdquo; series, where we help newcomers get familiar with the GitLab DevSecOps platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensuring a safe, compliant, and collaborative environment starts with the most basic of tasks - managing users. In this tutorial, we show you how to establish project members, assign roles and permissions, and create groups and subgroups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: To follow along with this tutorial, you should have a GitLab account either through GitLab.com or your organization&amp;rsquo;s self-managed instance. If you need help, visit our fundamentals area on GitLab University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git security vulnerabilities announced</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-security-vulnerabilities-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-security-vulnerabilities-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new set of Git releases were published to address a variety of security vulnerabilities. All users are encouraged to upgrade. Take a look at GitHub’s view of the latest round of releases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Git security vulnerabilities announced appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, the Git project released new versions to address a pair of security vulnerabilities, CVE-2024-50349 and CVE-2024-52006, that affect all prior versions of Git.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cve-2024-50349&#34;&gt;CVE-2024-50349&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Git needs to fill in credentials interactively without the use of a credential helper, it prints out the hostname and asks the user to fill in the appropriate username/password pair for that host. However, Git prints out the hostname after URL-decoding it. This allows an attacker to craft URLs containing ANSI escape sequences that may be used to construct an intentionally misleading prompt. The attacker may then tweak the prompt to trick a user into providing credentials for a different Git host back to the attacker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing CodeCanvas 2024.3</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-codecanvas-2024-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead! CodeCanvas 2024.3, last year’s final release, went live just before the holidays. To avoid adding to the busy year-end rush, we delayed the announcement until now, ensuring it gets the attention […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we enter 2025, we hope you had an amazing holiday season filled with joy, relaxation, and plenty of inspiration for the year ahead!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;What’s new in Git 2.48.0?&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-48-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-new-in-git-2-48-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Git project recently released Git 2.48.0. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a few notable highlights from this release, which includes contributions from GitLab&amp;rsquo;s Git team and the wider Git community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meson-build-system&#34;&gt;Meson build system&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, Git could be built using either a Makefile-based build system or an Autoconf-based build system. Git developers have been using mostly the Makefile-based build system, so the Autoconf-based build system has lagged behind in features and maintenance. Another issue was that a lot of Windows developers use integrated development environments (IDEs) that don’t have good support for Makefile- and Autoconf-based build systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Off 2024 winners</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/game-off-2024-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/game-off-2024-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Secrets spilled, discovered, and hidden again—Game Off 2024 brought over 500 jaw-dropping submissions that redefined creativity in gaming. From cult quests for free furniture to spellbinding mysteries, these games will have you hooked. Ready to uncover the winners?!?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Game Off 2024 winners appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another year, another incredible GitHub Game Off—and this one was &lt;em&gt;secrets&lt;/em&gt;-ational! With over 500 submissions, participants turned the theme of “secrets” into an extraordinary showcase of creativity, humor, and mind-boggling mechanics. Over the course of a month, developers not only built games but also dove into each other’s creations, reviewing, rating, and leaving comments that ranged from “This is genius!” to “I laughed so hard I fell out of my chair.” From mind-erasing gadgets to cult quests for free furniture, these games had it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Git 2.48</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/highlights-from-git-2-48/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.48. Here is GitHub&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the most interesting features and changes introduced since last time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Highlights from Git 2.48 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The open source Git project just released Git 2.48 with features and bug fixes from over 93 contributors, 35 of them new. We last caught up with you on the latest in Git back when 2.47 was released.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab supports banks in navigating regulatory challenges&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-supports-banks-in-navigating-regulatory-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-supports-banks-in-navigating-regulatory-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The risk of cyber attacks in the banking industry has reached unprecedented levels. Studies by the International Monetary Fund reveal that the financial sector is particularly vulnerable to cyber threats, with nearly one-fifth of reported incidents in the past two decades targeting this industry alone. As these threats continue to escalate, they drive the need for a regulatory response, prompting the banking and financial services industry to prepare for significant changes. GitLab enables financial institutions to proactively tackle these challenges, supporting banks on their regulatory journey while ensuring the operational resilience needed to protect the sensitive data pervasive throughout the banking ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to secure your GitHub Actions workflows with CodeQL</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-github-actions-workflows-with-codeql/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-github-actions-workflows-with-codeql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we secured 75+ GitHub Actions workflows in open source projects, disclosing 90+ different vulnerabilities. Out of this research we produced new support for workflows in CodeQL, empowering you to secure yours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to secure your GitHub Actions workflows with CodeQL appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we secured more than 75 GitHub Actions workflows in open source projects, disclosing more than 90 different vulnerabilities. Out of this research, we produced new support for workflows in CodeQL, empowering you to secure yours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Reduce supply chain risk with smarter vulnerability prioritization&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reduce-supply-chain-risk-with-smarter-vulnerability-prioritization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reduce-supply-chain-risk-with-smarter-vulnerability-prioritization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Application Security teams face a constant uphill battle in risk reduction due to the ever-growing number of vulnerabilities. This year alone, 36,000 Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVEs) have been reported — a 25% increase from last year. The sharp rise intensifies the challenge of prioritization in vulnerability management, especially for lean AppSec teams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To help, we’ve introduced several new enhancements to our Software Composition Analysis (SCA) solution. These improvements are available for all GitLab Ultimate customers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Streamline the path to CMMC Level 2 compliance with GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-the-path-to-cmmc-level-2-compliance-with-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-the-path-to-cmmc-level-2-compliance-with-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification (CMMC) Program is a framework developed by the U.S. Department of Defense (DoD) to enforce cybersecurity requirements and protect sensitive unclassified information shared by the DoD with contractors and subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the release of the CMMC final rule, DoD contractors can begin to assess and align their controls and processes to be compliant with CMMC’s requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explains how GitLab customers can leverage the GitLab platform to help satisfy relevant NIST SP 800-171 R2 requirements to achieve CMMC Level 2 compliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building LATAM’s future tech workforce with AI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-latams-future-tech-workforce-with-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/building-latams-future-tech-workforce-with-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git Commit 2024 and our new AI course in Spanish&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Building LATAM’s future tech workforce with AI appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read this post in Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estamos emocionados de celebrar el tercer año de Git Commit, nuestro programa anual dedicado a cerrar la brecha de habilidades tecnológicas y empoderar a estudiantes de todo el país. Este año, también nos enorgullece lanzar Git Commit 101, nuestro primer curso gratuito de IA en línea en español, disponible para estudiantes y educadores durante todo el año.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Cleaning in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/data-cleaning-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term real-world data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Data Science blog post series, we’ve talked about where to get data from and how to explore that data using pandas, but whilst that data is excellent for learning, it’s not similar to what we will term &lt;em&gt;real-world&lt;/em&gt; data. Data for learning has often already been cleaned and curated to allow you to learn quickly without needing to venture into the world of data cleaning, but real-world data has problems and is messy. Real-world data needs cleaning before it can give us useful insights, and that’s the subject of this blog post. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-github-copilot-what-it-can-do-and-real-world-examples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Copilot can generate unit tests, refactor code, create documentation, perform multi-file edits, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post How to use GitHub Copilot: What it can do and real-world examples appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the free version of GitHub Copilot launched last month, you’ve asked lots of questions, like “Is it free for everyone?” (Yes!), “Can Copilot make changes to multiple files?” (Yes again!), “What’s the name of Copilot’s mascot?” (It doesn’t have a name…yet.), and most of all: “What can GitHub Copilot &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; do?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Annotated Monthly – January 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/java-annotated-monthly-january-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge! Featured Content  Greetings, Java Annotated Monthly readers! […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new year has arrived, and we’re kicking it off with another handpicked selection of must-read tutorials and the latest news you won’t want to miss. This issue starts with an amazing featured content section with Donald Raab. Settle in and scroll your way to some fresh knowledge!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rider 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rider-2025-1-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/rider-2025-1-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date. With that in mind, let’s dive […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The start of the new year is the perfect time to share our plans for JetBrains Rider 2025.1. These plans are subject to change based on available resources, evolving development priorities, and shifts in the .NET landscape. Some features and improvements may be postponed to a later release date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab&#39;s 2024 bug bounty year in review&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlabs-2024-bug-bounty-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlabs-2024-bug-bounty-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s that time again when everyone reflects on the year that just passed, and the Application Security team at GitLab is no different. We run the bug bounty program at GitLab, and every year we summarize our stats for those who are curious. We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where we are without the collaboration of our bug bounty community, and we consider these awards hugely beneficial and money well spent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-bug-bounty-program-by-the-numbers&#34;&gt;GitLab Bug Bounty Program by the numbers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Awarded over US$1 million in bounties across 275 valid reports.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Received a total of 1,440 reports from 457 researchers in 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our busiest month was July, when we paid out over US$193,000!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Data is accurate as of 31st of December, 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Ultimate guide to CI/CD: Fundamentals to advanced implementation&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ultimate-guide-to-ci-cd-fundamentals-to-advanced-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ultimate-guide-to-ci-cd-fundamentals-to-advanced-implementation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuous integration/continuous delivery (CI/CD) has revolutionized how software teams create value for their users. Gone are the days of manual deployments and integration headaches — modern development demands automation, reliability, and speed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its core, CI/CD is about creating a seamless pipeline that takes code from a developer&amp;rsquo;s environment all the way to production and incorporates feedback in real time. CI helps teams catch issues early — before they become costly problems — by ensuring that code changes are frequently merged into a shared repository, automatically tested, and validated. CD extends this by automating the deployment process, making releases predictable and stress-free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Courses for Java Developers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-courses-for-java-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/best-courses-for-java-developers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I.  I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake. After months of intensive research and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tired of the same predictable and monotonous Java tutorials? So was I. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to think all Java courses were the same. Endless tutorials where someone talks about getters and setters in a monotonous, robotic voice while you put all of your effort into just trying to stay awake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/7-reasons-you-should-use-dbt-core-in-pycharm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/7-reasons-you-should-use-dbt-core-in-pycharm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions. In this blog post, we’ll talk about […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pc-featured_blog_1280x720_en-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;7 Reasons You Should Use dbt Core in PyCharm&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;dbt Core is a modern data transformation framework. It doesn’t extract or load data and is only responsible for the T in the ELT (extract-load-transform) process. dbt connects to your data warehouse and helps you prepare your data so it can later be used to answer business questions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Inspires Learners, IDEs Drive Them: Computer Science Education Trends 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-inspires-learners-ides-drive-them-computer-science-education-trends-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-inspires-learners-ides-drive-them-computer-science-education-trends-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than 23,991 learners from 16 countries and seven broader regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cs_learning_curve_2024.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computer science education and literacy are skyrocketing in demand worldwide. To understand the latest trends, challenges, and motivations driving learners, as well as other factors shaping the field, we conducted the 2024 Computer Science Learning Curve Survey. More than &lt;strong&gt;23,991 learners from 16 countries&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and seven broader&lt;/strong&gt; regions completed our detailed questionnaire – equivalent to over a year of collective effort. Dive in to discover what we’ve learned!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Dedication and Innovation: Highlights from SAFECode Day 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-dedication-and-innovation-highlights-from-safecode-day-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/celebrating-dedication-and-innovation-highlights-from-safecode-day-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://safecode.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/SAFECode_Day_Email_header.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over 50 SAFECode members and industry leaders came together for a dynamic SAFECode Day 2024! The event featured exciting project updates, lively discussions, and an inspiring keynote from Anne Neuberger, Deputy Assistant to the President, who emphasized the crucial role of cybersecurity in today’s digital landscape. It was great to hear our members share their successes and ideas for enhancing software security. Here are some highlights from the event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleet 1.44 Is Here With New UI, Zig Language Support, and More Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/fleet-1-44-is-here-with-new-ui-zig-language-support-and-more-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App. Let’s take a closer look at the highlights. Download Fleet 1.44 New features Improvements Bug fixes We’ve also fixed several bugs: See the full release notes for more details about Fleet […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explore our latest release, which introduces many new features designed to improve your development experience. You can update to this version using Toolbox App.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Fleet’s New Islands UI</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-fleets-new-islands-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive. New islands layout The […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We envisioned Fleet as a coding tool with a clear minimalist design that doesn’t overwhelm and helps keep you focused. Today we’re introducing a new, bolder look for Fleet. We believe that this new direction in Fleet’s UI will help make your developer experience more cohesive, intuitive, and, of course, productive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing klibs.io: A New Way to Discover Kotlin Multiplatform Libraries</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-klibs-io-a-new-way-to-discover-kotlin-multiplatform-libraries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kotlin Multiplatform is growing rapidly, with its ecosystem expanding and the number of libraries increasing by 35% in 2024 alone. However, with more libraries available than ever, finding the right one for your use case and target platforms can still be a challenge. Whether you’re looking for a solution to handle permissions on iOS and Android or searching for a Compose Multiplatform calendar component that supports both mobile and web, the challenge isn’t just finding one library – it’s having all of the options clearly presented so you can compare and choose the best fit. Today, we’re excited to introduce klibs.io – our new service designed to make finding Kotlin Multiplatform libraries faster and easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains Academy – December Digest</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-december-digest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/jetbrains-academy-december-digest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the new year, the JetBrains Academy team wants your IT skills to shine brighter than a Christmas tree! 🎄 This newsletter is packed with global trends in computer science education, must-read books, tips for university entrance exams, IT contests, and some holiday presents to help you level up your skills. 🎁 Enjoy the gift, and let the festive celebrations begin! Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Joins SAFECode; Raytheon Accepts Board Seat</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-joins-safecode-raytheon-accepts-board-seat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/oracle-joins-safecode-raytheon-accepts-board-seat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Members Work Together to Improve and Promote&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Effective Software Security Practices&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WAKEFIELD, MA. – July 28, 2022&lt;/strong&gt; – The Software Assurance Forum for Excellence in Code (SAFECode) recently welcomed Oracle as an associate member and elevated Raytheon Technologies to a seat on the SAFECode Board of Directors as a charter member. Along with Oracle, other recent new associate members include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudyrion GmbH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imperva&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secure Code Warrior&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Siemens Energy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SAFECode is a non-profit, global industry forum where business leaders and technical experts come together to exchange insights and ideas on creating, improving, and promoting scalable and effective software security programs. Through its Technical Leadership Council and focused working groups, SAFECode members collaborate on ways to address today’s most pressing software security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Post-Quantum Cryptography: Key Takeaways from SAFECode’s Working Group</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/preparing-for-post-quantum-cryptography-key-takeaways-from-safecodes-working-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/preparing-for-post-quantum-cryptography-key-takeaways-from-safecodes-working-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As we mentioned in a previous blog&lt;/em&gt;_, SAFECode’s post-quantum cryptography (PQC) working group has reached a milestone. NIST has standardized its first wave of post-quantum encryption algorithms, and our working group has identified key activities that will enable our members to manage the transition to quantum-resistant cryptography and adapt to the emergence of new algorithms that may be standardized by NIST or other national agencies._&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of wrapping up the working group’s activities for now, working group members Judy Furlong of Dell and Brian Rosenberg of RTX presented a webinar for SAFECode members that shared valuable insights on how organizations can prepare for this crucial transition. The following is a brief summary of the webinar to complement&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;we released a few weeks ago.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qodana 2024.3 Is Here Along With a Special Offer for New Users!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/qodana-2024-3-is-here-along-with-a-special-offer-for-new-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail.  To […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jetbrains.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/qd-featured_blog_1280x720_en-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! In case you missed it, the Qodana team ended 2024 with a bang and released Qodana 2024.3. What’s in the latest release? New security functionality, a fresh set of Android linter rules, and more to help your team prioritize code excellence. Let’s take a look at what’s available in more detail. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure by Design? The U.S. Government and Requirements for Secure Development</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-by-design-the-u-s-government-and-requirements-for-secure-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/secure-by-design-the-u-s-government-and-requirements-for-secure-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last two months have seen the release of three new U.S. Government documents related to software security:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The National Cybersecurity Strategy released in early March covers the landscape of cybersecurity concerns and introduces the concept of shifting the liability for insecure software products and services from consumers to suppliers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In mid-April, The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) of the Department of Homeland Security, in collaboration with the National Security Agency, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and cybersecurity agencies of several other countries, released a paper titled “Shifting the Balance of Cybersecurity Risk: Principles and Approaches for Security-by-Design and -Default.”, which reinforced some aspects of the National Cybersecurity Strategy but also added additional requirements and expectations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And in late April, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and CISA released a “Secure Software Development Attestation Form” that organizations that supply software to the government will be required to complete.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These documents could have a significant impact on the operations of software developers that sell to the government, both in the near term and for the foreseeable future. In this blog, we’ll review some key points of each and discuss their relationship to each other, to the US Presidential Executive Order 14028 released in May 2021 on improving the nation’s cybersecurity, and to the NIST Secure Software Development Framework (SSDF). Then we’ll provide some SAFECode comments on the relationship among the documents, and recommendations on the way that the government should use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities to Support Code Integrity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-capabilities-to-support-code-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/security-capabilities-to-support-code-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Kelly FitzGerald, Raytheon Technologies; Altaz Valani, Security Compass; Elena Kravchenko, Imperva; Matthew Lyon, Dell Technologies; Ashwini Siddhi, Dell Technologies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our previous blog posts, we defined the code integrity problem statement and the basic principles of code integrity. As our series continues, we will define a framework of layered security capabilities to support code integrity. The framework is based on security capabilities that involve an intersection of tools, people, and processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Spring Boot Applications Using Testcontainers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/testing-spring-boot-applications-using-testcontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/testing-spring-boot-applications-using-testcontainers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing is a crucial part of software development, verifying that a system functions as intended. Developers create unit tests to validate the behavior of individual components, isolating them from external dependencies such as file systems, databases, message brokers, and third-party APIs. However, since many applications rely on these external components, developers write integration tests to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Testing is a crucial part of software development, verifying that a system functions as intended. Developers create unit tests to validate the behavior of individual components, isolating them from external dependencies such as file systems, databases, message brokers, and third-party APIs. However, since many applications rely on these external components, developers write integration tests to ensure an application interacts correctly with its dependencies in a more complete environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The IntelliJ Scala Plugin in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-intellij-scala-plugin-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Year in Review Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-year-in-review&#34;&gt;The Year in Review&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time flies. Only a year ago, we saw the release of Scala 3.4.0-RC1, and now we’re trying out Scala 3.6.2 with many new experimental features. The last 12 months have brought many new features to the IntelliJ Scala Plugin as well. A year ago we introduced X-Ray mode, which lets you easily augment the code you see in the editor with information about inferred types and other details. We’ve improved Scala 3 support, compiler-based highlighting, and the debugger. We’ve improved auto-completion, both the standard and the AI-powered versions. We’ve introduced support for named tuples, which are still an experimental feature, and we’ve implemented a new way to work with sbt projects. On top of all that, this year, JetBrains joined the Scala Advisory Board. You can read about those changes in our release notes and other blog posts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The MPS 2024.3 Release Candidate Is Ready</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-mps-2024-3-release-candidate-is-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-mps-2024-3-release-candidate-is-ready/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality. DOWNLOAD MPS 2024.3 RC You can learn about the new features in more detail in this blog post. The full list of fixed issues can be found here. Your JetBrains MPS team&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Release Candidate for MPS 2024.3 is now available for download! Grab it and be among the first to experience the new functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PQC Algorithm FIPS are Published  – Now What?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-pqc-algorithm-fips-are-published-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-pqc-algorithm-fips-are-published-now-what/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By Brian Rosenberg, RTX Corporation and Judith Furlong, Dell Technologies with Matthew Lyon, Dell Technologies; Steve Lipner, SAFECode&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We made it – this far! The U.S National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) recently published the Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) for three post-quantum cryptography (PQC) algorithms, marking the end of the beginning of the journey to quantum resiliency. In this blog post, we will briefly recap how we arrived at this point, take a quick look at the standardized algorithms, and point out a few areas of future work and challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Executive Order 14028: Attestation and Software Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thoughts-on-executive-order-14028-attestation-and-software-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/thoughts-on-executive-order-14028-attestation-and-software-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks, SAFECode has been discussing a number of government initiatives related to software security assurance. This is the first of several blogs that we will be publishing to share our perspective and recommendations for approaches that will help governments and other organizations gain confidence in the software that they acquire and use.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the release of Executive Order (EO) 14028 in 2021, SAFECode has been tracking the U.S. Government’s plans and statements about how the portions of the EO dealing with secure software development and supply chain security would be put into action. This brief paper provides a SAFECode perspective on attestation that we believe will be important for software development organizations, end users, and government policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threat Modeling at Scale</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-modeling-at-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/threat-modeling-at-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Threat Modeling Manifesto, Threat Modeling is an activity “for analyzing representations of a system to highlight concerns about security and privacy and if applicable, safety characteristics”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Threat modeling is a crucial activity of the secure development lifecycle (SDL) for identifying and mitigating weaknesses and potential security vulnerabilities. Threat modeling is most effective when performed as part of a Design Phase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the publication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Threat Modeling at Scale appeared first on SAFECode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated System Requirements for  Linux GNU C Library (glibc)</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/updated-system-requirements-for-linux-gnu-c-library-glibc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting with v2025.1, IntelliJ-based IDEs will require glibc 2.28 or higher on Linux x64 systems. This change is being made to address potential security vulnerabilities associated with building and running our software on outdated systems and to ensure our products evolve with modern frameworks and technologies. By enforcing a more recent glibc version, we aim to provide a more secure and stable development environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s Next for CLion: The 2025.1 Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-clion-the-2025-1-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/whats-next-for-clion-the-2025-1-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development: 🚀 The CLion Nova language engine 🛠️ The debugger  🤖 Embedded development 🏗️ Project formats and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun work on our next major release, 2025.1, which we’ll introduce early next year. After reading through your valuable feedback and feature requests, and taking into account our own strategic goals, we’ve prioritized the following areas for development:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;3 signs your team is ready to uplevel security controls in GitLab&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-signs-your-team-is-ready-to-uplevel-security-controls-in-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/3-signs-your-team-is-ready-to-uplevel-security-controls-in-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most teams start with basic security practices, such as branch protection and simple access controls. But, there&amp;rsquo;s often a moment when teams realize they need more. It could be when they land their first enterprise client, when they start handling sensitive data, or when they experience their first security incident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure whether you’re ready to upgrade your security, here are a few signs you’ve outgrown your security needs:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;5 GitLab Premium features to help your team scale&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-gitlab-premium-features-to-help-your-team-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/5-gitlab-premium-features-to-help-your-team-scale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As development teams grow, what once worked for a small team often becomes a bottleneck. Code standards become inconsistent, operational silos develop, and technical debt accumulates faster. What was a well-oiled machine is now dysfunctional as more team members, projects, and tools are added on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many teams experience these challenges as they grow, but how you handle and address these growing pains can save you time, energy, and money in the long run. In this article, we’ll explore the common pitfalls growing teams face and how successful organizations address them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Ask a hacker: A conversation with ahacker1&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ask-a-hacker-a-conversation-with-ahacker1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ask-a-hacker-a-conversation-with-ahacker1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At GitLab we have a tradition: Every year, we invite a bug bounty hunter to join us for an AMA. This year, we met with Alexander Siyou Tan, also known as ahacker1, and did a deep dive into all aspects of bug bounty hunting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-alexander-ahacker1&#34;&gt;About Alexander (ahacker1)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alexander is passionate about hacking complex SaaS applications, with a particular interest in authorization-based vulnerabilities. Currently, he&amp;rsquo;s focusing on SAML and SSO research. His hacking journey began during the Covid-19 pandemic, when he transitioned from gaming to exploring game hacks and easter eggs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating with GitLab Duo, Part 2: Complex testing&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-2-complex-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-2-complex-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of our three-part series on test generation with GitLab Duo focused on how to automate code testing. Now, we will share the lessons we learned while using AI for test generation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;situations-we-encountered-and-how-we-handled-them&#34;&gt;Situations we encountered and how we handled them&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overall, we were pleased with the results using GitLab Duo to generate tests on our code. As is the case with any language generation, some cases required minor adjustments such as fixing import paths or editing contents in datasets. For the more complex cases, we had to remember that AI solutions often lack context. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we handled the more complex testing situations with GitLab Duo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Automating with GitLab Duo, Part 3: Validating testing&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-3-validating-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/automating-with-gitlab-duo-part-3-validating-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous entries in this series, we covered how we used GitLab Duo to generate tests for our code as well as what we learned while using GitLab Duo for generating automated tests. We also shared some of the ways we addressed making changes to GitLab Duo generated tests. This last article in the series will cover a test we ran to validate the impact of GitLab Duo on our team’s automated testing and discuss the impressive results we have achieved thus far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Git command line on Windows with Git Bash&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-command-line-on-windows-with-git-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/git-command-line-on-windows-with-git-bash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git commands allow developers to manage different versions of code and collaborate as a team. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a Windows environment, you may have heard of Git Bash, a Bash terminal emulator that includes a Windows-friendly version of Git. Discover everything you need to know about installing Git Bash in this guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-git-bash-work&#34;&gt;How does Git Bash work?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git Bash is an application that you can install on Windows operating systems using Git for Windows. This application acts as an emulator to use the Git version control tool on a Bash command terminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab Duo with Amazon Q: DevSecOps meets agentic AI&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-with-amazon-q-devsecops-meets-agentic-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-duo-with-amazon-q-devsecops-meets-agentic-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce GitLab Duo with Amazon Q, a joint offering that brings together GitLab&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive AI-powered DevSecOps platform with Amazon Q&amp;rsquo;s autonomous AI agents in a single, integrated solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitLab Duo with Amazon Q transforms software development by integrating powerful AI agents directly into your daily workflows. Instead of switching between multiple tools, developers can now accelerate key tasks — from feature development to code reviews — all from within GitLab&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive DevSecOps platform. Amazon Q’s AI agents act as intelligent assistants, automating time-consuming tasks like generating code from requirements, creating unit tests, conducting code reviews, and modernizing Java applications. By handling these complex tasks, this joint offering helps teams focus on innovation, while maintaining security and quality standards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;GitLab names Bill Staples as new CEO&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-names-bill-staples-as-new-ceo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/gitlab-names-bill-staples-as-new-ceo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This message from Sid Sijbrandij and Bill Staples was shared with GitLab team members earlier today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid:&lt;/strong&gt; On today’s earnings call, I announced that I am stepping down as CEO and will remain Executive Chair of the Board. I also introduced GitLab’s new CEO, Bill Staples.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Board, we routinely do succession planning. This includes conversations with a number of top executives. We’ve been having these conversations in greater earnest since my cancer returned. Through these discussions, we identified someone uniquely qualified to lead GitLab. I want more time to focus on my cancer treatment and health. My treatments are going well, my cancer is not metastatic, and I&amp;rsquo;m working towards making a full recovery. Stepping down from a role that I love is not easy, but I believe that it is the right decision for GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How GitLab empowers translators with more context&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-empowers-translators-with-more-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-gitlab-empowers-translators-with-more-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitLab is continuously translated by our global community of translators and proofreaders. Through Crowdin, they help make our product more accessible to the world by translating it into 78 languages. GitLab translation community members are volunteer translators, working professionals who are GitLab users, and even university students contributing to translators as part of their classroom projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-the-gitlab-open-core-model-supports-translators&#34;&gt;How the GitLab open-core model supports translators&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this community collaboration is powerful, translators often face a crucial challenge: understanding the full context of the text that they are translating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to deploy a PHP app using GitLab&#39;s Cloud Run integration&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-deploy-a-php-app-using-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-deploy-a-php-app-using-gitlabs-cloud-run-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing PHP application code and ensuring the application is running smoothly in production are often two different skills sets owned by two different engineers. GitLab aims to bridge the gap by enabling the engineer who has written the PHP application code to also deploy it into Google Cloud Platform with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether you own event-driven, long-running services or deploy containerized jobs to process data, Google Cloud Run automatically scales your containers up and down from zero — this means you only pay when your code is running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;How to leverage GitLab Duo for enhanced security reporting&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-leverage-gitlab-duo-for-enhanced-security-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-leverage-gitlab-duo-for-enhanced-security-reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good security reporting is crucial to maintain a good security posture because it provides detailed insights into incidents. With this information, organizations can better understand vulnerabilities, improve defenses, and prevent similar threats in the future. At GitLab, the Security division has created use cases for GitLab Duo to improve reporting capabilities and enhance operational efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gitlab-duos-security-capabilities&#34;&gt;GitLab Duo’s security capabilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The GitLab Security division uses GitLab’s built-in incidents to manage and report on security incidents. Incidents are handled, documented, and resolved in GitLab, enabling the use of AI-driven GitLab Duo as an assistant when performing security operations like incident response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;ICYMI: Key AI and security insights from our developer community&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/icymi-key-ai-and-security-insights-from-our-developer-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/icymi-key-ai-and-security-insights-from-our-developer-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our November LinkedIn Live broadcast, we brought together field CTOs, developer advocates, and community leaders to discuss industry trends and showcase features making a difference in developer workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are 5 key highlights:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-ai-adoption-trends-from-the-field&#34;&gt;1. AI adoption trends from the field&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our field CTOs shared insights on how organizations are embracing AI across their development workflows. For instance, Field CTO Cherry Han highlighted how financial organizations are thinking beyond individual developer tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Modernizing a simple C&#43;&#43; application to Java with GitLab Duo&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-a-simple-c-application-to-java-with-gitlab-duo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/modernizing-a-simple-c-application-to-java-with-gitlab-duo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Memory unsafe languages are those that do not handle any memory management on behalf of the developer. For example, when programming in C or C++, if you need memory during runtime, you will need to allocate and deallocate the memory yourself, running the risk of ending up with memory leaks in cases when you inadvertently forget to deallocate it. Other languages like Ada and FORTRAN provide some memory management but may not prevent memory leaks. Many organizations, including those in the public sector, have applications that have been developed using languages that are memory unsafe and are often looking to modernize these to a memory safe language, such as Java, Python, JavaScript, or Golang.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Streamline DevSecOps engineering workflows with GitLab Duo&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-devsecops-engineering-workflows-with-gitlab-duo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/streamline-devsecops-engineering-workflows-with-gitlab-duo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 9 a.m. somewhere, and a DevOps engineer is starting their day. They check their GitLab todo list to see any mentions or tasks assigned to them, collaborating with other stakeholders in their organization. These tasks can include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;managing infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining the configuration of resources&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining CI/CD pipelines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;automating processes for efficiency&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;maintaining monitoring and alerting systems&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ensuring applications are securely built and deployed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;modernizing applications with containerization&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To carry out these tasks, DevOps engineers spend a lot of time reading documentation, writing configuration files, and searching for help in forums, issues boards, and blogs. Time is spent studying and understanding concepts, and how tools and technologies work. When they don&amp;rsquo;t work as expected, a lot more time is spent investigating why. New tools are released regularly to solve niche or existing problems differently, which introduces more things to learn and maintain context for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Transform code quality and compliance with automated processes&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/transform-code-quality-and-compliance-with-automated-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/transform-code-quality-and-compliance-with-automated-processes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While manual code review processes may suffice for a small team, as DevSecOps teams scale, the processes create significant bottlenecks that impede software development velocity and quality. Often slow, inconsistent, and frequently failing to catch critical vulnerabilities, the manual approach leads to technical debt and increased security risks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To mitigate risks and drive innovation, organizations must prioritize automated code quality and compliance systems. The financial implications of poor code management are substantial, with technical debt consuming up to 40% of IT budgets (McKinsey Digital: Tech Debt Report) and software vulnerabilities costing an average of $4.88 million per security breach (IBM Cost of a Data Breach Report).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing 150M developers and a new free tier for GitHub Copilot in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-150m-developers-and-a-new-free-tier-for-github-copilot-in-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-150m-developers-and-a-new-free-tier-for-github-copilot-in-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come and join 150M developers on GitHub that can now code with Copilot for free in VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Announcing 150M developers and a new free tier for GitHub Copilot in VS Code appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GitHub has a long history of offering free products and services to developers. Starting with free open source and public collaboration, we added free private repos, free minutes for GitHub Actions and GitHub Codespaces, and free package and release storage. Today, we are adding GitHub Copilot to the mix by launching GitHub Copilot Free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing CodeQL Community Packs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-codeql-community-packs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-codeql-community-packs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce the new CodeQL Community Packs, a comprehensive set of queries and models designed to enhance your code analysis capabilities. These packs are tailored to augment…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Announcing CodeQL Community Packs appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to introduce the new CodeQL Community Packs, a comprehensive set of queries and models designed to enhance your code analysis capabilities. These packs are tailored to augment the standard set of CodeQL queries, providing additional resources for security researchers and developers alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance build security and reach SLSA Level 3 with GitHub Artifact Attestations</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhance-build-security-and-reach-slsa-level-3-with-github-artifact-attestations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enhance-build-security-and-reach-slsa-level-3-with-github-artifact-attestations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn how GitHub Artifact Attestations can enhance your build security and help your organization achieve SLSA Level 3. This post breaks down the basics of SLSA, explains the importance of artifact attestations, and provides a step-by-step guide to securing your build process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Enhance build security and reach SLSA Level 3 with GitHub Artifact Attestations appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The need for software build security is more pressing than ever. High-profile software supply chain attacks like SolarWinds, MOVEit, 3CX, and Applied Materials have revealed just how vulnerable the software build process can be. As attackers exploit weaknesses in the build pipeline to inject their malicious components, traditional security measures—like scanning source code, securing production environments and source control allow lists—are no longer enough. To defend against these sophisticated threats, organizations must treat their build systems with the same level of care and security as their production environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Availability Report: November 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-november-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/github-availability-report-november-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub Availability Report: November 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In November, we experienced one incident that resulted in degraded performance across GitHub services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 19 10:56 UTC (lasting 1 hour and 7 minutes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 19, 2024, between 10:56:00 UTC and 12:03:00 UTC, the notifications service was degraded and stopped sending notifications to all our dotcom customers. On average, notification delivery was delayed by about one hour. This was due to a database host coming out of a regular maintenance process in read-only mode.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub’s top blogs of 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/githubs-top-blogs-of-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/githubs-top-blogs-of-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explore GitHub’s top blogs of 2024, featuring new tools, AI breakthroughs, and tips to level up your developer game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post GitHub’s top blogs of 2024 appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As 2024 wraps up, we’re revisiting the highlights of a year packed with innovation, learning, and community. From unlocking the power of AI to mastering essential developer tools, these blogs reflect what makes GitHub the home for all developers. Ready? Let’s jump in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside the research: How GitHub Copilot impacts the nature of work for open source maintainers</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-the-research-how-github-copilot-impacts-the-nature-of-work-for-open-source-maintainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/inside-the-research-how-github-copilot-impacts-the-nature-of-work-for-open-source-maintainers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interview with economic researchers analyzing the causal effect of GitHub Copilot on how open source maintainers work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Inside the research: How GitHub Copilot impacts the nature of work for open source maintainers appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to share an interview with two researchers that I’ve had the privilege of collaborating with on a recently released paper studying how open source maintainers adjust their work after they start using GitHub Copilot:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Annotated Logger: A Python package to aid in adding metadata to logs</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-annotated-logger-a-python-package-to-aid-in-adding-metadata-to-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-annotated-logger-a-python-package-to-aid-in-adding-metadata-to-logs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re open sourcing Annotated Logger, a Python package that helps make logs searchable with consistent metadata.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Introducing Annotated Logger: A Python package to aid in adding metadata to logs appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-it-is&#34;&gt;What it is&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Annotated Logger is a Python package that allows you to decorate functions and classes, which then log when complete and can request a customized logger object, which has additional fields pre-added. GitHub’s Vulnerability Management team created this tool to make it easier to find and filter logs in Splunk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI’s latest o1 model now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openais-latest-o1-model-now-available-in-github-copilot-and-github-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/openais-latest-o1-model-now-available-in-github-copilot-and-github-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The December 17 release of OpenAI’s o1 model is now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models, bringing advanced coding capabilities to your workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post OpenAI’s latest o1 model now available in GitHub Copilot and GitHub Models appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey devs! We have some exciting news for ya.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, backstory first: in case you missed it, OpenAI launched its o1-preview and o1-mini models back in September, optimized for advanced tasks like coding, science, and math. We brought them to our GitHub Copilot Chat and to GitHub Models so you could start playing with them right away, and y’all seemed to love it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So many tokens, so little time: Introducing a faster, more flexible byte-pair tokenizer</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/so-many-tokens-so-little-time-introducing-a-faster-more-flexible-byte-pair-tokenizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/so-many-tokens-so-little-time-introducing-a-faster-more-flexible-byte-pair-tokenizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We released a new open source byte-pair tokenizer that is faster and more flexible than popular alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post So many tokens, so little time: Introducing a faster, more flexible byte-pair tokenizer appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Large language models (LLMs), such as those used by GitHub Copilot, do not operate directly on bytes but on &lt;em&gt;tokens&lt;/em&gt;, which can complicate scaling. In this post, we explain how we solved that challenge at GitHub to support the growing number of Copilot users and features since the first launching Copilot two years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering GStreamer secrets</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-gstreamer-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/uncovering-gstreamer-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’ll walk you through the vulnerabilities I uncovered in the GStreamer library and how I built a custom fuzzing generator to target MP4 files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Uncovering GStreamer secrets appeared first on The GitHub Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll show the results of my recent security research on GStreamer, the open source multimedia framework at the core of GNOME’s multimedia functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll also go through the approach I used to find some of the most elusive vulnerabilities, generating a custom input corpus from scratch to enhance fuzzing results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
