<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ios on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ios on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple and Google patch zero-day vulnerability used to hack iPhones</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-and-google-patch-zero-day-vulnerability-used-to-hack-iphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apple-and-google-patch-zero-day-vulnerability-used-to-hack-iphones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple has patched its third zero-day security vulnerability of 2025—and Google also patched the same flaw. Here is everything you need to know to keep your Mac, iPhone, iPad, and Vision Pro safe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post Apple and Google patch zero-day vulnerability used to hack iPhones appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forensic Implications of Apple’s “Stolen Device Protection”</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/forensic-implications-of-apples-stolen-device-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/forensic-implications-of-apples-stolen-device-protection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/passcodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the release of iOS 17.3, Apple introduced a new security feature called “Stolen Device Protection.” This functionality is designed to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive data in cases where a thief has gained knowledge of an iPhone’s passcode. While this feature significantly enhances security for end users, it simultaneously creates substantial obstacles for digital forensic experts, complicating lawful data extraction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-roadblock-to-logical-extraction&#34;&gt;A Roadblock to Logical Extraction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gaining access to data on Apple devices has historically been most feasible through standard mechanisms leveraged by many forensic tools, including iOS Forensic Toolkit, as part of an advanced logical extraction process. Alternative methods, such as low-level extraction, are either limited to older devices and iOS versions (currently, iOS 16.6.1 is the latest iOS build supported by iOS Forensic Toolkit) or legacy devices. Cloud-based analysis also presents challenges, as it requires full user credentials, and the device passcode is required on top of that to access end-to-end encrypted data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Lock Apps on iPad</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-lock-apps-on-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set your iPad into kiosk mode and pass it around without worrying about someone opening other apps or accessing unwanted content through an accessibility feature called Guided Access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iOS 18.3 and macOS Sequoia 15.3 patch first Apple zero-day of 2025</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-18-3-and-macos-sequoia-15-3-patch-first-apple-zero-day-of-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ios-18-3-and-macos-sequoia-15-3-patch-first-apple-zero-day-of-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple released critically urgent security updates this week for macOS, iOS, iPadOS, visionOS, and tvOS to address a bug that was actively exploited in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The post iOS 18.3 and macOS Sequoia 15.3 patch first Apple zero-day of 2025 appeared first on The Mac Security Blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of iOS Passcode Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-evolution-of-ios-passcode-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-evolution-of-ios-passcode-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/passcodes.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Apple has continuously refined its security mechanisms to deter unauthorized access to their devices. One of the most significant aspects of this evolution is the increasingly sophisticated passcode protection system in iOS devices. This article explores how the delay between failed passcode attempts has evolved over time, highlighting changes that have made iOS screen lock protection more secure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;early-stages&#34;&gt;Early Stages&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of iOS, passcode attempts were practically unlimited. The delay between failed attempts would increase over time, but in extreme cases, the wait time could reach absurd numbers -sometimes even displaying “Next attempt in 100 million years.” There are plenty of screenshots of these exaggerated lockout periods available on the net.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
