<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Securityidentitycompliance on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/securityidentitycompliance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Securityidentitycompliance on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/securityidentitycompliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcing AWS KMS Elliptic Curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) support</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-aws-kms-elliptic-curve-diffie-hellman-ecdh-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/announcing-aws-kms-elliptic-curve-diffie-hellman-ecdh-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When using cryptography to protect data, protocol designers often prefer symmetric keys and algorithms for their speed and efficiency. However, when data is exchanged across an untrusted network such as the internet, it becomes difficult to ensure that only the exchanging parties can know the same key. Asymmetric key pairs and algorithms help to solve […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When using cryptography to protect data, protocol designers often prefer symmetric keys and algorithms for their speed and efficiency. However, when data is exchanged across an untrusted network such as the internet, it becomes difficult to ensure that &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; the exchanging parties can know the same key. Asymmetric key pairs and algorithms help to solve this problem by allowing a public key to be shared over an untrusted network. And by using a key agreement scheme, two parties can use each other’s public key in combination with their own private key to each derive the same shared secret.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS launches AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-launches-aws-wickr-atak-plugin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications. The Android Team Awareness Kit (ATAK)—also known as Android Tactical Assault Kit for military use—is a smartphone geospatial infrastructure and situational awareness application. It provides mapping, messaging, and geofencing capabilities to […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce the launch of the AWS Wickr ATAK Plugin, which makes it easier for ATAK users to maintain secure communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP High authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-high-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the High impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Wickr achieves FedRAMP Moderate authorization</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/aws-wickr-achieves-fedramp-moderate-authorization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB). FedRAMP is a U.S. government–wide program that promotes the adoption of secure cloud services by providing a standardized approach to security and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is excited to announce that AWS Wickr has achieved Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) authorization at the Moderate impact level from the FedRAMP Joint Authorization Board (JAB).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enable post-quantum key exchange in QUIC with the s2n-quic library</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enable-post-quantum-key-exchange-in-quic-with-the-s2n-quic-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/enable-post-quantum-key-exchange-in-quic-with-the-s2n-quic-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated to only support Kyber. BIKE or other KEMs may still be added as the standardization proceeds. At Amazon Web Services (AWS) we prioritize security, performance, and […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 25, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated to only support Kyber. BIKE or other KEMs may still be added as the standardization proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encryption in transit over external networks: AWS guidance for NYDFS and beyond</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/encryption-in-transit-over-external-networks-aws-guidance-for-nydfs-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On November 1, 2023, the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) issued its Second Amendment (the Amendment) to its Cybersecurity Requirements for Financial Services Companies adopted in 2017, published within Section 500 of 23 NYCRR 500 (the Cybersecurity Requirements; the Cybersecurity Requirements as amended by the Amendment, the Amended Cybersecurity Requirements). In the introduction to its Cybersecurity Resource Center, the Department explains that the revisions are aimed at addressing the changes in the increasing sophistication of threat actors, the prevalence of and relative ease in running cyberattacks, and the availability of additional controls to manage cyber risks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to secure your SaaS tenant data in DynamoDB with ABAC and client-side encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-secure-your-saas-tenant-data-in-dynamodb-with-abac-and-client-side-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re a SaaS vendor, you may need to store and process personal and sensitive data for large numbers of customers across different geographies. When processing sensitive data at scale, you have an increased responsibility to secure this data end-to-end. Client-side encryption of data, such as your customers’ contact information, provides an additional mechanism that can help you protect your customers and earn their trust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to tune TLS for hybrid post-quantum cryptography with Kyber</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-tune-tls-for-hybrid-post-quantum-cryptography-with-kyber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 30, 2024: The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info. January 25, 2023: AWS KMS, ACM, Secrets Manager TLS endpoints have been updated to only support NIST’s Round 3 picked KEM, Kyber. s2n-tls and s2n-quic have also been updated […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 30, 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; The API in this blog post has been changed in newer version of the AWS CRT Client. See this page for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use AWS KMS RSA keys for offline encryption</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-aws-kms-rsa-keys-for-offline-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-aws-kms-rsa-keys-for-offline-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;October 28, 2022: This blog post has been updated to reflect that CBC has changed to CTR, as well as a few more modifications. This blog post discusses how you can use AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS) RSA public keys on end clients or devices and encrypt data, then subsequently decrypt data by using […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 28, 2022:&lt;/strong&gt; This blog post has been updated to reflect that CBC has changed to CTR, as well as a few more modifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use tokenization to improve data security and reduce audit scope</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-tokenization-to-improve-data-security-and-reduce-audit-scope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-to-use-tokenization-to-improve-data-security-and-reduce-audit-scope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April 25, 2023: We’ve updated this blog post to include more security learning resources. Tokenization of sensitive data elements is a hot topic, but you may not know what to tokenize, or even how to determine if tokenization is right for your organization’s business needs. Industries subject to financial, data security, regulatory, or privacy compliance […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 25, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; We’ve updated this blog post to include more security learning resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing s2n-quic, a new open-source QUIC protocol implementation in Rust</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-s2n-quic-a-new-open-source-quic-protocol-implementation-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-s2n-quic-a-new-open-source-quic-protocol-implementation-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security, high performance, and strong encryption for everyone are top priorities for all our services. With these priorities in mind, less than a year after QUIC ratification in the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), we are introducing support for the QUIC protocol which can boost performance for web applications that […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://d2908q01vomqb2.cloudfront.net/22d200f8670dbdb3e253a90eee5098477c95c23d/2022/02/17/S2N-QUIC-Blog-Announcement-Logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;At Amazon Web Services (AWS), security, high performance, and strong encryption for everyone are top priorities for all our services. With these priorities in mind, less than a year after QUIC ratification in the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), we are introducing support for the QUIC protocol which can boost performance for web applications that currently use Transport Layer Security (TLS) over Transmission Control Protocol (TCP). We are pleased to announce the availability of s2n-quic, an open-source Rust implementation of the QUIC protocol added to our set of AWS encryption open-source libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New eBook: 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-ebook-5-keys-to-secure-enterprise-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/new-ebook-5-keys-to-secure-enterprise-messaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce a new eBook, 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging. The new eBook includes best practices for addressing the security and compliance risks associated with messaging apps. An estimated 3.09 billion mobile phone users access messaging apps to communicate, and this figure is projected to grow to 3.51 billion users in […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS is excited to announce a new eBook, 5 Keys to Secure Enterprise Messaging. The new eBook includes best practices for addressing the security and compliance risks associated with messaging apps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three key security themes from AWS re:Invent 2022</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/three-key-security-themes-from-aws-reinvent-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations. Now in its 11th year, the conference featured 5 keynotes, 22 leadership sessions, […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS re:Invent returned to Las Vegas, Nevada, November 28 to December 2, 2022. After a virtual event in 2020 and a hybrid 2021 edition, spirits were high as over 51,000 in-person attendees returned to network and learn about the latest AWS innovations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 2022 AWS data protection service and cryptography tool launches</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-2022-aws-data-protection-service-and-cryptography-tool-launches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-2022-aws-data-protection-service-and-cryptography-tool-launches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February 28, 2023: We updated this blog to include AWS Wickr. Given the pace of Amazon Web Services (AWS) innovation, it can be challenging to stay up to date on the latest AWS service and feature launches. AWS provides services and tools to help you protect your data, accounts, and workloads from unauthorized access. AWS […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 28, 2023:&lt;/strong&gt; We updated this blog to include AWS Wickr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the pace of Amazon Web Services (AWS) innovation, it can be challenging to stay up to date on the latest AWS service and feature launches. AWS provides services and tools to help you protect your data, accounts, and workloads from unauthorized access. AWS data protection services provide encryption capabilities, key management, and sensitive data discovery. Last year, we saw growth and evolution in AWS data protection services as we continue to give customers features and controls to help meet their needs. Protecting data in the AWS Cloud is a top priority because we know you trust us to help protect your most critical and sensitive asset: your data. This post will highlight some of the key AWS data protection launches in the last year that security professionals should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
