<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>It-Service-Management on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/it-service-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in It-Service-Management on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/it-service-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reimagining service management with Atlassian customers the NRMA and Domino’s Pizza Enterprises Ltd</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reimagining-service-management-with-atlassian-customers-the-nrma-and-dominos-pizza-enterprises-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/reimagining-service-management-with-atlassian-customers-the-nrma-and-dominos-pizza-enterprises-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Atlassian held &lt;em&gt;High Velocity: ITSM&lt;/em&gt;, an event covering ways to reimagine service management to include teams beyond IT. Atlassian customers joined in to discuss their journeys to digital transformation by way of Jira Service Management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During High Velocity’s keynote address, Atlassian Co-Founder Scott Farquhar sat down for a chat with Domino’s Pizza Enterprises Ltd (Domino’s) Group Chief Technology Officer Matthias Hansen and the NRMA’s General Manager of Technology Engineering Andy McCarthy to discuss their ITSM journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlock enterprise knowledge with Atlassian Rovo</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unlock-enterprise-knowledge-with-atlassian-rovo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/unlock-enterprise-knowledge-with-atlassian-rovo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is critical to unleashing the potential of all teams, and we’re excited to use this revolutionary technology to improve the way teams work. A year ago, we launched Atlassian Intelligence to help teams boost productivity with AI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since then, we’ve turned our attention to using AI to solve the highly complex problem of enterprise search and knowledge discovery. Our goal is to enable you to turn Atlassian and third-party data from across your organization into actionable insights and knowledge-driven decisions. In this age of generative AI, every team member deserves to have superpowers, and we want to make sure we deliver them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
