<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Threat-Lab on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/threat-lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Threat-Lab on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/threat-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why MSPs need proactive, 24/7 threat hunting</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-need-proactive-24-7-threat-hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-need-proactive-24-7-threat-hunting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybercriminals are becoming increasingly sophisticated, agile, and fast. For managed service providers (MSPs) supporting small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) with cybersecurity services, staying ahead of these adversaries is crucial. One of the most effective ways to do so is through round-the-clock threat hunting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we’ll explore why constant threat hunting is essential, the challenges MSPs face in providing it, and how OpenText MDR can help overcome these challenges while offering SMBs the protection they need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why MSPs must offer 24/7 cybersecurity protection and response — and how OpenText MDR can help</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-must-offer-24-7-cybersecurity-protection-and-response-and-how-opentext-mdr-can-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/why-msps-must-offer-24-7-cybersecurity-protection-and-response-and-how-opentext-mdr-can-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s cyber threat landscape, good enough is no longer good enough. Cyberattacks don’t clock out at 5 PM, and neither can your security strategy. For Managed Service Providers (MSPs), offering customers 24/7 cybersecurity protection and response isn’t just a competitive advantage—it’s an essential service for business continuity, customer trust, and staying ahead of attackers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But delivering round-the-clock security coverage is easier said than done. It requires the right tools, expertise, and scale. This is why partnering with OpenText for offering managed detection and response (MDR) can help MSPs deliver on this critical need without overburdening their resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 steps to safeguarding your privacy online</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/10-steps-to-safeguarding-your-privacy-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The more devices, digital apps and online accounts you use, the more efficient and convenient your life becomes. But all that ease of use comes with a price. Your devices are constantly collecting your personal data to fine-tune your user experience. At the same time, hackers, and other cyber criminals are working round the clock to steal this sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of your digital identity as a confidential file full of high-value information – passwords, credit card numbers, bank account details, social security numbers and more. If you’re not taking the proper steps to guard your online privacy, you could end up handing over the files to a vast army of cybercriminals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 reasons why SMBs love OpenText MDR</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-reasons-why-smbs-love-opentext-mdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/6-reasons-why-smbs-love-opentext-mdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital-first world, small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) face cybersecurity challenges that grow more complex by the day. SMBs are prime targets for attackers hoping to gain a foothold inside any organization that doesn’t have extensive security measures. As threats increase, so does the need for comprehensive, reliable, and accessible protection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where managed detection and response (MDR) services come in. MDR combines threat detection, investigation, and response, offering businesses the support from a team of security experts who monitor the environment 24/7 to identify and respond to threats. For many SMBs, MDR is an ideal solution because it provides a level of protection and expertise that would otherwise require building an in-house security operations center (SOC).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Tips to protect your devices from malware attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/8-tips-to-protect-your-devices-from-malware-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/8-tips-to-protect-your-devices-from-malware-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, when your devices are infected with a virus, it’s not as easy as a little bed rest for them to recover, and the damage can be long-lasting. A cyberattack can compromise your computers, phones and tablets, and open the door for cyber thieves to steal your sensitive personal information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to a study by the University of Maryland’s A. James Clark School of Engineering, there is a cyberattack approximately every 39 seconds. The most common form of cyberattack is malware, a type of software that’s used to break into your computer system. Last year alone, there were more than 6 billion malware attacks detected worldwide. Some of the many forms of malware include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and deepfakes: How to be AI-savvy</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-and-deepfakes-how-to-be-ai-savvy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-and-deepfakes-how-to-be-ai-savvy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the apps on our smartphones to chatbot assistant services, artificial intelligence (AI) is transforming our lives in both big and small ways. But as exciting as AI can be, it’s also important to understand its potential risks. October is Cybersecurity Awareness Month, making it the perfect time to become more cyber-savvy about AI. Let’s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-ai&#34;&gt;What is AI?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AI is a technology that enables machines to perform tasks that typically require human intelligence, such as understanding language, recognizing patterns, and making decisions. In everyday life, AI is behind many of the technologies we use. It powers recommendations on streaming TV services like Netflix, improves photo quality on your smartphone, and even aids in driving cars. AI is like having a smart assistant that can process information quickly, automate daily tasks, and make technology more intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do you actually need a VPN? Your guide to staying safe online!</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/do-you-actually-need-a-vpn-your-guide-to-staying-safe-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/do-you-actually-need-a-vpn-your-guide-to-staying-safe-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the rise of online scams and privacy risks, virtual private networks (VPNs) are becoming more popular for day-to-day use. Or at least I feel like they are based on the number of ads I hear for them on my favorite podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So maybe you’ve heard of VPNs but aren’t actually sure what they are. Simply put, a VPN creates a safe, anonymous pathway for the data you send and receive over a Wi-Fi network, allowing you to browse anonymously and access content as if you were in a different location.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nastiest Malware 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nastiest-malware-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nastiest-malware-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Steam the Webinar on demand HERE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we look back on the cybersecurity landscape of 2024, it’s clear that the world of digital threats continues to evolve at an alarming pace in parallel with AI. This year has seen ransomware groups adapt and innovate, pushing the boundaries of their malicious capabilities and evasiveness from law enforcement. In our annual “Nastiest Malware” report, now in its sixth year, we’ve observed a steady increase in both the number and sophistication of malware attacks. The ransomware sector, in particular, has witnessed the emergence of “business models,” with ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) dominating the scene. Elite ransomware authors have concluded that profit sharing and risk mitigation are key contributors to their consistent success and evasion of authorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new Webroot PC Optimizer boosts computer performance</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-new-webroot-pc-optimizer-boosts-computer-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-new-webroot-pc-optimizer-boosts-computer-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Think back to when your brand new laptop or desktop ran the smoothest, operating at peak performance. Is it still that fast, or does even the simplest task seem to take forever? Before you ditch your current PC, there’s a way to get it running like new again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first, though—you have to understand why your PC is running slowly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-computers-slow-down-with-age&#34;&gt;Do computers slow down with age?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve had your PC for a while, you might think it’s running slower because of aging hardware. But not even brand-new computers run at their optimal speed due to preinstalled bloatware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The state of generative AI in 2024</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-generative-ai-in-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-state-of-generative-ai-in-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI has taken the world by storm, transforming how individuals and businesses interact with and trust this new technology. With tools like ChatGPT, Grok, DALL-E, and Microsoft Copilot, everyday users are finding new ways to enhance productivity, creativity, and efficiency. However, as the integration of AI into daily life accelerates, so do the concerns around privacy and security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore key findings from the 2024 Generative AI Consumer Trends and Privacy Survey and examine how these results are shaping the future of generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 reasons MSPs choose OpenText MDR</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-reasons-msps-choose-opentext-mdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-reasons-msps-choose-opentext-mdr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s an exciting time to be a managed service provider (MSP). More than ever, small and medium businesses (SMBs) are looking to MSPs as trusted advisors to help safeguard them from today’s growing cyber threats. One of the services in high demand right now? Managed detection and response (MDR). When asked about their biggest growth drivers, MSPs cite addressing clients’ cybersecurity concerns and awareness as the top new-business drivers (54%).1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 roadblocks for MSPs and how OpenText MDR clears the way</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-roadblocks-for-msps-and-how-opentext-mdr-clears-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/top-5-roadblocks-for-msps-and-how-opentext-mdr-clears-the-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The managed service provider (MSP) industry is booming with opportunities. At the same time, MSPs face the challenge of balancing customer satisfaction with profitability, making strategic decisions more important than ever. For 35% of MSPs, building cyber resiliency for customers is a top strategic priority, but that goal often runs up against resource constraints and rising operational costs.[i] To stay competitive, MSPs are focusing on improving operational efficiency (35%) and keeping costs under control (33%).[ii]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
