<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rtx on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/rtx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rtx on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/rtx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA Blackwell is Out: Should You Upgrade?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-blackwell-is-out-should-you-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-blackwell-is-out-should-you-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/nvidia-rtx-article_1200x630.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement and digital forensic specialists have long utilized GPUs for password recovery. GPUs excel at this task due to their thousands of parallel processing cores, enabling rapid hash computations. Tools like Elcomsoft Distributed Password Recovery leverage GPU acceleration to significantly outperform traditional CPUs in brute-force attacks. The new NVIDIA Blackwell architecture doubles the number of INT32 compute units compared to Ada and Ampere. How will this architectural change affect password recovery, and is it worth upgrading to a new GPU?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5090 Power Connectors Melting Again</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-power-connectors-melting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/nvidia-geforce-rtx-5090-power-connectors-melting-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.elcomsoft.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/rtx-5090-on-fire_1200x630-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a week ago, we published an article about NVIDIA’s new generation of Blackwell-based graphics cards. Despite a noticeable price hike, performance gains in this generation are minimal, with one notable exception: the flagship GeForce RTX 5090 significantly outperforms its predecessor in all key aspects. However, this GPU has also revealed a potential issue that could make its use in workstations running 24/7 problematic and potentially unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-new-connector&#34;&gt;The New Connector&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the root of the issue, let’s first understand how it arose. Modern GPUs require far more power than what can be delivered through the PCIe slot alone, forcing manufacturers to provide additional power via cables directly from the PSU. Antec, a well-known PSU manufacturer, has published a diagram illustrating the number of cables required to power high-performance graphics cards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
