<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Securing-the-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/securing-the-cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Securing-the-Cloud on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/securing-the-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;The Role of WAF in Fintech &amp; Financial Services&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-role-of-waf-in-fintech-financial-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-role-of-waf-in-fintech-financial-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/CNAPP-Solution-blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The financial sector serves as the backbone of the global economy, making it one of the most targeted industries for cyber attacks. As online banking, mobile transactions, and fintech innovations expand, cyber threats continue to evolve. Cyber criminals continuously exploit vulnerabilities in financial applications, making strong security measures essential for protecting sensitive customer data, transactions, and business operations. To mitigate these risks, efficient web application firewalls (WAFs) have become a crucial security mechanism for financial services. In recent GigaOm Radar for Application and API Security report, GigaOm emphasizes the critical role of integrated security measures in today’s digital landscape. The […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Powered Security Management for the Hyperconnected World</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/ai-powered-security-management-for-the-hyperconnected-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/WhatsApp-Image-2025-02-04-at-11.17.57-AM.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Check Point CPO Nataly Kremer announcing new AI capabilities at CPX 2025&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s security approach is siloed. Each deployed security tool is designed to provide a specific type of protection across different areas like the network, endpoints, email, and cloud environments. This hybrid methodology, often requiring dozens of systems, leads to several security and operational challenges for security operations center (SOC) and network operations center (NOC) teams. Adopting a hybrid environment is unavoidable, and Gartner[1] anticipates that “By 2025, over 50% of network firewall deployments will involve more than two deployment factors from the same vendor — up from less than 10% in 2023.” [1]  While the benefits of this new ecosystem are […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check Point Software Collaborates with AppDirect to Offer Streamlined Cyber Security Solutions</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/check-point-software-collaborates-with-appdirect-to-offer-streamlined-cyber-security-solutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Shifting-Paradigms-Cloud-Security-in-the-Post-Pandemic-Era-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cloud Security in the Post-Pandemic Era&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check Point Software and AppDirect, a B2B subscription commerce platform, have unveiled a strategic collaboration, allowing businesses to effortlessly obtain Check Point’s AI-powered cyber security solutions through the AppDirect marketplace. This partnership offers a unified procurement experience, ensuring more customers have access to the highest level of security they deserve. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, worldwide cyber attacks on organizations surged considerably in 2024. On average, organizations faced 1,673 attacks each week, marking a substantial 44% increase from the year before. As cyber attacks continue to escalate annually, it is crucial for every business to utilize advanced […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to Autonomous Cyber Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/the-journey-to-autonomous-cyber-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/Dan-v.1-e1737134156825.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of cyber security is no longer just about reacting to threats; it is about staying perpetually ahead in a world defined by complexity and speed. Autonomous cyber security represents a bold, transformative leap into the future—where intelligent, AI-driven systems operate at the edge of innovation, detecting, preventing, and responding to threats with unparalleled precision. This journey is more than technological advancement—it is a paradigm shift. By creating systems that think, reason, and act autonomously, organizations are poised to outpace adversaries and redefine what it means to be secure in an increasingly digitized world. The further along this journey […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WAF Security Test Results – How Does Your Vendor Rate?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/waf-security-test-results-how-does-your-vendor-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/waf-security-test-results-how-does-your-vendor-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/23167_blog_banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With cyber threats on the rise, organizations are increasingly concerned about their security posture. One area of prime concern is web applications and APIs that power key business processes. To protect mission-critical applications, efficient web application firewalls (WAFs) are required to block malicious traffic. A well-configured WAF acts as the first line of defense against external threats maintaining trust, achieving compliance, and ensuring uninterrupted operations. Periodic testing of security solutions ensures they are behaving as expected and are resilient enough to withstand complex and ever-evolving cyber threats. Often, resource-constrained security teams do not have the time to proactively test their […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuing to Pioneer Cyber Security Excellence and Shaping the Future</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/continuing-to-pioneer-cyber-security-excellence-and-shaping-the-future/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.checkpoint.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/shutterstock_2403416063-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a trusted leader in cyber security, Check Point proudly acknowledges its 2024 accolades from leading analysts and research firms. These accolades and recognitions showcase Check Point’s innovation and dedication to protecting the digital world and ensuring digital trust across networks, clouds, and endpoints. According to Check Point Research’s 2025 Security Report, global attacks against organizations significantly increased in 2024, with organizations experiencing an average of 1,673 attacks weekly—a significant 44% rise compared to the previous year. This increase emphasizes the escalating complexity and frequency of cyber threats, making it crucial for organizations to implement comprehensive security solutions to safeguard […]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
