<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Collection on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Collection on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/data-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BSides København – Meaningful Metrics in Information Security</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/bsides-kobenhavn-meaningful-metrics-in-information-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next BSides København will take place on 9 November 2024. There is one presentation in the schedule about the use of metrics in information security. Computers allow us to create documents, charts, and statistical values easily from any data collection we like. Therefore, the World Wide Web is full of graphs, tables with numbers, predictions, and all kinds of results. The problem is that not everything you can count is a suitable metric tied to real-life observations. Finding a metric is a science on its own. This presentation will give you some examples of how to measure meaningful attributes of computer systems and networks. You will also get to know the term metric more closely. Using proper metrics and assessing customer-provided reports will help you immensely when dealing with information security decisions. The&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some rough impressions of Worldcoin</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/some-rough-impressions-of-worldcoin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently a reader wrote in and asked if I would look at Sam Altman’s Worldcoin, presumably to give thoughts on it from a privacy perspective. This was honestly the last thing I wanted to do, since life is short and this seemed like an obvious waste of it. Of course a project &lt;em&gt;devoted to literally scanning your eyeballs&lt;/em&gt; was up to some bad things, duh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However: the request got me curious. Against my better judgement, I decided to spend a few hours poking around Worldcoin’s documentation and code — in the hope of rooting out the obvious technical red flags that would lead to the true Bond-villain explanation of the whole thing. Because surely there had to be one. I mean: eyeball scanners. Right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;div&gt;Apps That Are Spying on Your Location&lt;/div&gt;</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/apps-that-are-spying-on-your-location/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;404 Media is reporting on all the apps that are spying on your location, based on a hack of the location data company Gravy Analytics:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thousands of apps, included in hacked files from location data company Gravy Analytics, include everything from games like Candy Crush to dating apps like Tinder, to pregnancy tracking and religious prayer apps across both Android and iOS. Because much of the collection is occurring through the advertising ecosystem­—not code developed by the app creators themselves—­this data collection is likely happening both without users’ and even app developers’ knowledge&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
