<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National-Security on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/national-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National-Security on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/national-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Reflection Series on CCG’s Technology and National Security Law and Policy Seminar Course</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/introducing-the-reflection-series-on-ccgs-technology-and-national-security-law-and-policy-seminar-course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February 2022, CCG-NLUD will commence the latest edition of its Seminar Course on Technology and National Security Law and Policy (“the Seminar Course”). The Seminar Course is offered to interested 4th and 5th year students who are enrolled in the B.A. LL.B. (Hons.) programme at the National Law University, Delhi. The course is set […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to Source&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LABScon24 Replay | The Ransomware Trust Paradox</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/labscon24-replay-the-ransomware-trust-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Smeets explores how ransomware groups leverage public reporting and why we must disrupt the trust dynamic between threat actors and victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Keynote talk at LABScon 24, Max Smeets explores how ransomware operators build a unique relationship between themselves and their victims. In contrast to most other threat actors, ransomware operators rely on and leverage public visibility into their activities. Unlike APTs and other threat actors that prize stealth, ransomware gangs seek to publicize their attacks in order to convince future victims that they are trustworthy enough to deliver on their promises – providing a decryptor and deleting stolen data – if paid.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Cyber Trust Mark logo for smart devices is coming</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/us-cyber-trust-mark-logo-for-smart-devices-is-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White House announced the launch of the US Cyber Trust Mark which aims to help buyers make an informed choice about the purchase of wireless internet-connected devices, such as baby monitors, doorbells, thermostats, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity labeling program for wireless consumer Internet of Things (IoT) products is voluntary but the participants include several major manufacturers, retailers, and trade associations for popular electronics, appliances, and consumer products. The companies and groups said they are committed to increase cybersecurity for the products they sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
