<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/categories/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What the Best DevOps Tutorials?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-best-devops-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-the-best-devops-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/image-36.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps is an evolving field that combines &lt;strong&gt;development&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;operations&lt;/strong&gt; into one streamlined process, helping organizations improve collaboration, automation, and delivery of software. Whether you’re a beginner or an experienced practitioner, learning DevOps can significantly improve your workflow, especially if you’re focused on &lt;strong&gt;continuous integration (CI)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;continuous deployment (CD)&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;infrastructure automation&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;DevOps tutorials&lt;/strong&gt; are an excellent way to learn new skills, understand the tools and practices used in the field, and apply your knowledge in real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the devops Services on AWS?</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-are-the-devops-services-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/what-are-the-devops-services-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.bestdevops.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/image-1024x560.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) provides a robust set of tools and services that support the implementation of DevOps practices, enabling organizations to automate and streamline their software development, deployment, and operations. AWS DevOps services provide a fully managed environment to integrate continuous integration (CI), continuous delivery (CD), and continuous monitoring into the development lifecycle. These services empower teams to increase agility, improve software quality, and accelerate time-to-market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we will explore the key AWS DevOps services, their major features, and how they contribute to a more efficient, scalable, and secure DevOps pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
