<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Platform-Engineering on Gharib Personal Blog</title>
    <link>https://ghariib.ir/tags/platform-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Platform-Engineering on Gharib Personal Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alireza Gharib. All right reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ghariib.ir/tags/platform-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How observability, application security, and AI enhance DevOps and platform engineering maturity</title>
      <link>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ghariib.ir/posts/how-observability-application-security-and-ai-enhance-devops-and-platform-engineering-maturity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://dt-cdn.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/3d-render-abstract-graph-300x169.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Data privacy by design, CrowdStrike&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DevOps and platform engineering are essential disciplines that provide immense value in the realm of cloud-native technology and software delivery. However, these practices cannot stand alone. Rather, they must be bolstered by additional technological investments to ensure reliability, security, and efficiency. One of these key investments includes observability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Observability of applications and infrastructure serves as a critical foundation for DevOps and platform engineering, offering a comprehensive view into system performance and behavior. It goes beyond traditional monitoring—metrics, logs, and traces—to encompass topology mapping, code-level details, and user experience metrics that provide real-time insights. This real-time awareness enables teams to rapidly detect and resolve issues: both indispensable capabilities for maintaining the agility and reliability that are central to DevOps and platform engineering processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
